<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/americanlitmss/"
         >americanlitmss</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Preliminary Guide to the American Literary Manuscripts Records, 1930-1981
                  <num>RL.00034</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Library Staff; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Joshua A. Kaiser</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003157745</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-28 10:59:14
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>American Literary Manuscripts records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="ingest">American Literary Manuscripts</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00034</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11.5 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1930/1981" type="inclusive">1930-1981</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_2c748caac328ad65244a29b572f2d443">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <physdesc id="aspace_2f1166f7672ed680d5207e1a50e02dac">
            <extent>8598 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_d4fc7314c17e00176b05548040aa3298">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_8820a9ed1fbe9aae8c028420d6c1a46b">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_a96f1e0cb38af08994ff21253752bbdc">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_8653e0e22d83017a2b7ece0095bc49f3">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], American Literary Manuscripts Records, David M. Rubenstein
            Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_cea0ee014124d2c98057efc0036c5f95">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The American Literary Manuscripts Records was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare
            Book &amp; Manuscript Library as a gift in 1981 and 1989.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_1f2de04a482282c0e7bd6fc263e6cad3">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library Staff</p>
         <p>Completed September 27, 1989</p>
         <p>Encoded by Joshua A. Kaiser</p>
         <p>This collection is unprocessed: materials have not been ordered and described beyond
            their original condition.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_bc0efdef6cb0016086cf9ee3e4d1b715">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>In 1930 Professor Jay B. Hubbell proposed to the American Literature Group of the Modern
            Language Association of America that it should gather into an index or catalog a record
            of the enormous amount of manuscript materials in American literature so researchers and
            users could readily locate the materials needed. Dr. Hubbell was then asked to form a
            committee to formulate a plan. The committee, made up of Professors Hubbell, Kenneth B.
            Murdock, Ralph L. Rusk, and Robert Spiller contracted the American Historical
            Association, which was planning a similar program for history materials. The two groups
            decided to join forces and compile a document relating to manuscripts of American
            literature and to all phases of American history. Funding problems caused this venture
            to stalemate. </p>
         <p>The idea was kept alive, however, and in 1941 another committee chaired by Robert
            Spiller was formed and instructed to gather information on materials of American
            literary history. This committee prepared in essay form a <title type="simple"
               render="doublequote">Guide to Resources for Research in American Literary History: A
               Preliminary Survey</title> from data gathered informally--for the most part by
            personal interview and correspondence. The second World War caused plans for publication
            to be deferred.</p>
         <p> Using the material collected in the 1940s as a basis for renewed efforts, a new
            committee chaired by Lewis Leary was formed in 1950 to study the feasibility of
            continued work, since much of the previous work had been used in volume 3 of the <title
               type="simple" render="italic">Literary History of the United States</title>. The
            issue was discussed in a seminar, <title type="simple" render="doublequote">A Survey and
               Inventory of American Literary Manuscripts,</title> at the 1950 meeting of MLA. The
            result was formal agreement on the need for some form of guide to manuscript resources.
            The seminar recommended formation of a committee on literary resources with Leary as
            chairman.</p>
         <p> In 1951 a working committee was appointed to devise procedures and to commence
            gathering of data for eventual publication of such a guide. This committee was composed
            of Joseph Jones, chairman, University of Texas; Ernest Marchand, San Diego State
            College; H. Dan Piper, California Institute of Technology; J. Albert Robbins, Indiana
            University; and Herman E. Spivey, University of Tennessee.</p>
         <p>The purpose of this project was to provide for scholars a helpful new aid in their
            perpetual search for new material. The first edition published in 1960 indicates the
            nature and scope of American literary manuscripts in over 270 libraries pertaining to
            approximately 2,350 American writers. The specific primary purpose, as stated in the
            preface of this publication, <emph render="doublequote">is to assist scholars,
               librarians, dealers, and collectors in locating primary source materials relating to
               American authors; to locate primary manuscript sources with far greater use and
               accuracy than formerly; to encourage collectors to deposit manuscripts where they
               might be of greatest use and utility; and to encourage librarians to think creatively
               about their collections and to lend encouragement to manuscript departments.</emph>
         </p>
         <p>The project was begun by compiling an extensive list of writers, publishers, and
            critics, and then formulating eight categories distinguished by symbols that would
            accurately record the extent and variety of holdings--manuscripts, journals, letters by
            and to, documents, etc. A checklist containing some 2,000 names of American authors was
            then sent to American libraries--academic, fraternal, historical, public, etc.--with
            instructions as to how to apply and to list the eight categories of holdings. After the
            holdings were compiled on cards a preliminary draft was produced and circulated for
            rechecking. The resulting master file of reporting libraries formed the 1960 edition of
               <title type="simple" render="italic">American Literary Manuscripts.</title>
         </p>
         <p>With publication of this volume, the American Literature Section of MLA authorized
            continuance of the committee with J. Albert Robbins as chairman of the new group. In
            1969 it was felt that a revision and update were needed. The American Literature Section
            of MLA again sponsored the project with John Albert Robbins as chairman of the editorial
            board, which consisted of Professors A.W. Plumstead, University of Massachusetts; Joseph
            V. Ridgely, Columbia University; Kimball King, University of North Carolina, Chapel
            Hill; F. Warren Roberts, University of Texas; George Hendrick, University of Illinois;
            Edward P. Nolan, University of Colorado; and John Stafford, San Fernando Valley State
            College.</p>
         <p>The 1960 list of authors was retained as a base and expanded to include 2,750 authors,
            publishers, and critics whose names were to be checked for locations and holdings of
            manuscripts and other papers. The United States was divided into first seven, then
            later, eight regions, with each member of the editorial board acting as a regional
            chairman. Each regional chairman then chose regional associates within his region to
            solicit and coordinate the holdings of the area assigned to him. During the first year
            J. V. Ridgely and John Stafford resigned. The Middle Atlantic region was divided into
            two regions and Professors Alan Margolies of John Jay College of Criminal Justice, CUNY,
            and Leo Weigant of the University of Maryland were chosen to replace J. V. Ridgely.
            Professor Thomas Wortham, University of California, Los Angeles, replaced John Stafford
            in the Pacific Coast area. Sixty-three regional associates were chosen.</p>
         <p> The 1960 edition of <title type="simple" render="italic">American Literary
               Manuscripts</title> was put on computer tape and print-outs of the holdings reported
            by individual libraries were distributed by the regional chairmen for rechecking,
            updating, and revision along with instructions for listing new additions and new
            authors. A completely new list could be compiled if the library so desired. When all the
            participating libraries and depositories completed their listings they sent the
            compilations to the regional associates who, in turn, sent them to the regional
            chairmen. They edited the lists before sending them to Professor Robbins, who did the
            overall editing and transferring of the findings to computer tape. Print-outs were again
            sent to the libraries for verification, correction, and updating to 1975. When these
            were returned and all corrections and additions were listed, the data was inverted to
            provide an alphabetical list by author and the master tape was sent to the publisher for
            machine-set composition. The volume was printed from the computer tapes by the
            University of Georgia Press in 1977.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_5bbe8fd5206823bc94dcbee26875884f">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The <title type="simple" render="italic">American Literary Manuscripts</title> Records
            (accession #5-6-81) (8,098 items, 10.8 lf; dated 1930-1979) documents the process by
            which the guide was created. It contains the correspondence of J. A. Robbins with each
            of his editors for each region of the United States (the Regional Chairmen), copies of
            the directives sent to participating libraries, copies of the master list of names to be
            checked, minutes of editorial board meetings, descriptions of the project, a proposal
            for a computerized updating of the census of library holdings of American literary
            manuscripts, negotiations with the publisher, grant requests, and reports. The
            correspondence between Midwest Regional Chairman, George Hendrick, and his Regional
            Associates is included in order to demonstrate how the project operated. The
            questionnaires returned by the libraries in that region are included. There are also ten
            printouts, included as a random sampling of printouts required. Acquired as part of the
            Jay B. Hubbell Center for American Literary Historiography. </p>
         <p>The addition (accession #89-093) (500 items, 1 lf; dated 1962-1981) contains
            correspondence, background material, page proofs, post-publication additions and
            corrections, and publicity relating primarily to the 2nd edition of <title type="simple"
               render="italic">American Literary Manuscripts</title> published in 1977. It updates
            the earlier edition published in 1960.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Editors -- United States -- Correspondence</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Book editors -- United States -- Correspondence</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Catalogs, Union -- United States</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Proofs (printed matter)</genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">American literature -- Manuscripts</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Authors, American -- Manuscripts -- Catalogs</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Manuscripts, American -- United States</subject>
         <corpname source="ingest">Modern Language Association of America. American Literature
            Group. Committee on Manuscript Holdings. American literary manuscripts</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Modern Language Association of America. American Literature
            Section</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Hendrick, George</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Jay B. Hubbell Center for American Literary
            Historiography</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Robbins, J. Albert (John Albert), 1914-</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">American Literary Manuscripts</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref11_pfs" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Accession 5-6-81</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref12_mtr" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Historical</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref13_k52" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Historical File</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_0ac908dd4702427731b969925542df95" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_dace664aff134376eb9e38958d88235b">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>Contains historical matter beginning with Professor Hubbell's original
                        proposal and continuing through the first committee assigned to study the
                        feasibility of a guide to manuscripts of literary figures to the publication
                        of the first edition of <title type="simple" render="italic">American
                           Literary Manuscripts</title>.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_7q4" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>ALM II Project</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5270d86f87a3fd2c422a3b881a8d96f6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Contains material relating to the preparation and publication of the second
                     edition of <title type="simple" render="italic">American Literary
                        Manuscripts</title> in 1977.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref16_wsk" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellany I</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_c717ef212fbfe4dead09cc84c6840d17" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_174a46bde035ba39e5a2b5d93eaea7cd">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>Contains correspondence relating to the second edition's preliminary studies
                        as to the need for revision of the first edition, guidelines for revision,
                        formulary and varying drafts of procedures, a list of authors to be
                        surveyed, subvention of the project, negotiations with the publishers,
                        survey reports both to the committee and to the Fels Foundation whose grant
                        financed the beginnings, and a directory of the committee.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref18_fcq" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellany II</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_32e6c2f23ae045f5088cfe448bea0d85" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_49bc5b925fcec3a76363f498dde3c086">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>Contains minutes of committee meetings; lists of additional authors to be
                        considered for inclusion; progress reports; and letters from George Hendrick
                        to participating libraries relating to <emph render="doublequote"
                           >checkback</emph> or verification of data received. Also contains samples
                        of print-outs, a project summary, comments about the finished product,
                        clippings telling of special collections in certain libraries, and pamphlets
                        pertaining to bibliographies of manuscripts. There is an obituary clipping
                        about Inglis Fletcher among the clippings. </p>
                     <p>Articles-- <title type="simple" render="doublequote">What Happens to Author'
                           Manuscripts,</title> by John Carter; <title type="simple"
                           render="doublequote">Manuscript of 'The Waste Land;'</title> and <title
                           type="simple" render="doublequote">The Father of Black
                           Nationalism,</title> which appeared in the <title type="simple"
                           render="italic">New York Review of Books</title> for March 12, 1970. A
                        brochure on the <title type="simple" render="italic">Rise of Jewish
                           Literature</title> is also in this box. In the pamphlet folder are the
                        following pamphlets: <title type="simple" render="italic">Manuscripts for
                           Research</title>, <title type="simple" render="italic">The Ethical
                           Structure of Tamburlane</title>, <title type="simple" render="italic"
                           >Anne Goodwin Winslow: An Annotated Check List of Her Published Works and
                           of Her Papers</title>, <title type="simple" render="italic">A Letter from
                           the Jackson Committee</title>, a copy of the <title type="simple"
                           render="italic">CEAA Newsletter</title> for June 1970, and the <title
                           type="simple" render="italic">Bulletin of Bibliography</title>, Vol. 25,
                        No. 3, which contains George Hendrick's <title type="simple"
                           render="doublequote">American Literary Manuscripts in Continental
                           Libraries.</title> Miscellaneous letters concerning that article and a
                        typescript article <title type="simple" render="doublequote">A Checklist of
                           American Literary Manuscripts in Australia, Canada, India, Japan, and New
                           Zealand</title> complete Box 3.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref20_s0i" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Correspondence of Albert Robbins with miscellaneous people and his
                        regional chairmen, except for the Midwest region.</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_84d9fff591827011506c737e0a3a97cf" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">4</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_5779fd1e5a6403bea68cb3773461677c">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>These letters are arranged chronologically, first in a general folder for
                        the miscellaneous correspondents and then in separate folders for each
                        chairman.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref22_73l" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Correspondence between Albert Robbins and George Hendrick, regional
                        chairman of the Midwest region.</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_c8ada05cdd5a44ebd6b7a6d87ed86c3c" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_f911a950630dd22591ff5a670d5ca220">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>Arranged chronologically.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref24_rak" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Correspondence of George Hendrick and his regional
                        associates</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_26263804d127326ec0d9a18654fd7843" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">6-7</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_71cf8bfa163ec1c1cf069790331d7d74">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>These letters are chronological within folders for each associate.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref26_54m" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Reports of manuscript holdings in the Midwest region</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_34b5cb5bd1ee1a976166647283c07973" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="volume">1-2</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_5b7a1e559b8b7b3c5d0de9ae51af6390">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>These are arranged first by reporting library, then alphabetically by name
                        of the author whose holdings are being reported.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
