<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
         url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/andersonrobert/">andersonrobert</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Robert Anderson papers, 1735-circa 1878, 1908, and undated,
               bulk 1735-1859 <num>RL.10077</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Levi Crews and Paula Jeannet, January 2014.</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>September 2014</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">005836124</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-11-01 16:17:19
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Robert Anderson papers </unittitle>
         <origination label="source">
            <corpname role="col" source="ingest">John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and
               African American History and Culture</corpname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Anderson, Robert</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.10077</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">1 box, 1 oversize folder</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1735/1908" type="inclusive">1735-circa 1878, 1908 and undated, bulk
            1735-1859</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_04f373349fbc8b2e529807c64c06ec12">Collection comprises correspondence,
            documents and print materials belonging to merchant and land owner Robert Anderson of
            Williamsburg and Yorktown, Virginia. The materials date from 1735-1908, with the bulk
            dating from 1735 to 1859, and consist of over eighty letters, both incoming and
            outgoing, many legal and financial papers, other manuscript documents, and ephemeral
            print items such as broadsides and circulars. One folder contains military muster lists
            and fines stemming from Anderson's service as clerk of the 68th regiment of the Virginia
            militia. Topics in the correspondence include slavery and slave trade, particularly in
            Virginia, colonization efforts, emancipation, the status of mixed-race individuals,
            Virginia and U.S. politics, Virginia military history, religion and church affairs, and
            education. Of particular note are several letters and documents relating to Anderson's
            children, who he fathered with one or more slaves; one of these children, Haidee, was
            sent to Eaglewood, a boarding school run by abolitionists Angelina Grimké Weld and
            Theodore Dwight Weld. Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin Research Center for
            African and African American History and Culture.</abstract>
         <physloc id="aspace_2675f30bae8520ca912971d6a61aa37c">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_e08f19e056da0b553302a582bcda0f24">Materials in
            English</langmaterial>
      </did>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_679219ab8efb83ea9841026d592dac40">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>Robert Anderson papers, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation Library, Special Collections
            (35 vols, 4,728 items)</p>
         <p>Robert Anderson papers, 1790-1858, Firestone Library Manuscripts Division, Princeton
            University (1.2 linear feet) </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <prefercite id="aspace_135930936d23b85e89eb02691803af39">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Robert Anderson papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <arrangement id="aspace_e2815ce8bd29998b1605bdbe074277fa">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>Arranged in four groupings: correspondence, militia records, financial papers, and legal
            and printed papers.</p>
      </arrangement>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_a33e997228aa22259a8be9aa68455591">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <bioghist id="aspace_e34bf0eb29c05ae4c631dbe359d081d2">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Robert Anderson (1781-1859) was a merchant, insurance company agent, Whig politician,
            and planter residing in Yorktown and Williamsburg, Virginia. He served as Williamsburg's
            mayor from 1812 to 1813, 1820 to 1821 and finally 1828 to 1829, and was a militia
            captain in Williamsburg and Yorktown, Virginia until 1837. </p>
         <p>Anderson was a wealthy businessman with varied interests. He was an insurance agent,
            merchant, steamship company owner, and administrator and executor of several estates. He
            owned property in both James City and York counties, Virginia, and resided permanently
            in Yorktown. He was heavily involved and interested in local and state politics. He
            owned, bought, and sold slaves; at the same time he also subscribed to colonization
            efforts of emancipated slaves.</p>
         <p>Anderson married Helen Macauley Southall, widow of Peyton Southall, in 1814; they had no
            children, but Helen had four children from her previous marriage. Anderson fathered four
            children with one of his slaves: three daughters and one son. One of these daughters,
            Catherine Haidee Griffin, was sent to Eagleswood School in New Jersey, run by
            abolitionists and educators Angelina Grimké Weld and Reverend Theodore Weld. She then
            was educated in Massachusetts for a time, and was emancipated only after Anderson's
            death, and by his will was named the owner of her mother and two younger sisters. Robert
            Anderson died in 1859.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_97f23cd25b78e933ae824bc9ff92e20a">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Robert Anderson papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2013 and 2014.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_9f27b6602885850e678ce1bbc11b94b9">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by: Levi Crews and Paula Jeannet, January 2014. </p>
         <p>Accessions described in this finding aid: 2013-0057, 2014-0001.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_52293138ad85f0d1c44b1052c75e7956">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Collection consists of correspondence, documents and ephemera belonging to merchant and
            land owner Robert Anderson of Williamsburg and Yorktown, Virginia. The materials date
            from 1735-1908, with the bulk dating from 1735-1859. The earliest document is a deed of
            gift of land from Thomas Vine of York County, Virginia, to his grandson. </p>
         <p>There are over 100 pieces of incoming and outgoing correspondence dating from 1804 to
            1859, with a few letters dated much later. Many of the retained copies and drafts are
            written on small slips of paper and docketed, which appears to have been Anderson's
            idiosyncratic method of dealing with his correspondence. Topics include religion and
            church matters; U.S. and Virginia politics; Virginia history; mercantile transactions;
            education; and slavery, including prices for slaves in the Richmond market, and
            Anderson's correspondence referring to purchases and sales of individual slaves. A
            printed circular letter from 1850 concerns colonization efforts to send freed slaves to
            Liberia. </p>
         <p>Of note are several letters relating to children Anderson fathered with enslaved women,
            especially his daughter Haidee, who he sent to Eaglewood, the boarding school run by
            abolitionists Angelina Grimké and Theodore Dwight Weld; one long letter was written by
            Grimké to Anderson, exhorting him to emancipate Haidee and her mother. Eaglewood was
            part of the utopian community in Raritan Union Bay, New Jersey.</p>
         <p>Stemming from Anderson's work as clerk for the 68th Regiment of the Virginia militia in
            James City County (Jamestown), there are 39 items, some written by Anderson, some by the
            Sheriff of Williamsburg, which consist chiefly of detailed muster lists and fines
            (1806-1858), and two printed lists of individuals receiving military pensions received
            due to an Act of Congress in 1828. Other documents in the collection refer to Virginia
            history during the Revolutionary War and the War of 1812, and to the history of the
            Virginia Norfolk Junior Volunteers, founded in 1802, in which Anderson served.</p>
         <p>There are also deeds, wills, and other documents; several dozen financial receipts; and
            a few printed and partially printed ephemeral items. Family names appearing in the
            deeds, bonds, and other documents are Bryan, Coke, Moody, Dickeson, Nelson, White, and
            Chapman. Among the later documents is a list of medical expenses from 1852 that seem to
            relate to Anderson's slaves or servants, and an 1858 bill for boarding school expenses
            for Haidee, signed by Theodore Weld. A document from 1855 records citizens protesting a
            request from the ship "Seabird" to land cargo and passengers, due to an outbreak of
            yellow fever in the cities of Norfolk and Portsmouth.</p>
         <p>Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African
            American History and Culture.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_159830984e45426ae7bfd6c66ca80bd5">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Yorktown (Va.) -- History</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Slaveholders -- Virginia -- Correspondence</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Slave trade -- Virginia -- History</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Virginia -- Politics and government -- 1775-1865</geogname>
         <genreform source="aat">Deeds</genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people -- Virginia -- 19th century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Planters -- Virginia -- Correspondence</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Plantations -- Virginia</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Virginia -- Religion</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Virginia -- History -- 1775-1865</geogname>
         <genreform source="lcsh">Wills</genreform>
         <geogname source="lcsh">York County (Va.) -- History</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">James City County (Va.) -- History</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Child slaves -- United States -- History -- 19th century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Miscegenation -- Virginia</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (Va.) -- History</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Child slaves -- Virginia</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Antislavery movements -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Abolitionists -- New Jersey -- Correspondence</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Slavery -- Virginia</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Williamsburg (Va.) -- Politics and government</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Virginia</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">York County (Va.) -- Politics and government</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Education</subject>
         <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Virginia. Militia. Regiment, 68th</corpname>
         <persname source="naf">Grimké, Angelina Emily, 1805-1879</persname>
         <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Weld, Theodore Dwight, 1803-1895</persname>
         <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Raritan Bay Union (Eagleswood, N.J.)</corpname>
         <corpname role="col" source="ingest">John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and
            African American History and Culture</corpname>
         <famname rules="dacs" source="local">Anderson family (Virginia)</famname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref39_87q" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Robert Anderson papers</unittitle>
               <unitdate normal="1735/1908" type="inclusive">1735-1908</unitdate>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_wnn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Collection information folder</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_45c5a318eec51451fedad1bc4dab9b64" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_78ddaa19f6fcbbb9f65cda9e3a9c8d41"
                     parent="aspace_45c5a318eec51451fedad1bc4dab9b64" type="folder">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c3e2a4244abf437c70dced32bcd294d9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Folder contains dealer's biographical notes on Robert Anderson and his life and
                     activities. Also includes a set of selected transcriptions from notable pieces
                     of correspondence, also provided by the dealer.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref9_f4q" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1804-1815</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_d0e18d5166781ba41b02bb243ff8dbe6">6 items</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_261be6f8936e8ba7fae5ec979fd99946" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_25be4ed1fd1d55a63bbd544a0e506b5a"
                     parent="aspace_261be6f8936e8ba7fae5ec979fd99946" type="folder">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_870ab295e53caf15e6c89867da07c8d8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Letters of note include: a broadside announcement from Anderson to the citizens
                     of Williamsburg about his intention to run for State legislature as a
                     Republicand and Federalist, 1806; several descriptive letters, 1807 and 1814,
                     recounting travels in western and central-northern Virginia; and an
                     advertisement for the Williamsburg Ladies Seminary sent in a letter to
                     Anderson, 1815.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_4gk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1820-1829</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_5d45dbbf6ceb5c66f70ff319ee493867">16 items</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_5b4c7910d0b14b7677430d9a6426f5d6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b969428dbdc88224029988e61e6e9960"
                     parent="aspace_5b4c7910d0b14b7677430d9a6426f5d6" type="folder">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_592cd2848913c0425cea3b0b7d40dc48">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Of note is a subscription to the American Colonization Society, 1827; a poem
                     written by Anderson for the Williamsburg <title render="italic"
                     >Phoenix</title>, for the improvement of the College of William and Mary, 1825;
                     and a series of exchanges between Thomas Jones, Patent Office in Washington,
                     regarding questions about an estate, a Count Philip Barzizza, and Austrian
                     Consul Baron Lederer's efforts to mediate, 1828.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_uks" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1831-1839</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_ac6b120b3d8507e824b8026e9ab0ccef">8 items</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_45b3841268458a64a5e4575946bbc2ce" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_65cf77375935b0ecba37d1d3f3177f54"
                     parent="aspace_45b3841268458a64a5e4575946bbc2ce" type="folder">4</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ccc70e8110077f1c6e8851810cac279a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Of note in this series: item addressed to "Dear parents" in Liverpool, England,
                     1838, to a James M. from a daughter Martha M., who has recently been married
                     and living in Yorktown - she describes her new surroundings and her situation,
                     saying that she went to a "strange man by the name of Anderson" who provided
                     her with guidance and financial support during a time of difficulty.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_w3q" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1840-1849</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_da97a172703ce960260b6f0af9a1aea1">24 items</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_6e798220c9075aff837b2b10ed29c35b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_6eda97c8c7606bf82aa6d653fe73addc"
                     parent="aspace_6e798220c9075aff837b2b10ed29c35b" type="folder">5</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f10d8b5b8542ec3540c67fd226fe5ca9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Items of note: a note in which Anderson lists 1848 election returns; a circular
                     letter raising funds for the family of John Hamden Pleasants, founder of a Whig
                     newspaper in Richmond, killed in a duel by Thomas Ritchie, Jr. (1846); and a
                     letter from historian Henry Howe.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_e6c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1850-1854</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_89d8d6fd9f7bb2b302793e8099d37e01">29 items</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_47f1ca1bc6ece2c7fb21e5156f30b98a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_acc67645e760e6e9997ec902937540dc"
                     parent="aspace_47f1ca1bc6ece2c7fb21e5156f30b98a" type="folder">6</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c1c34a5ecfd5c572b518ef1de34dd91d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Topics include: slavery in Virginia; a plan before Congress to send former
                     slaves to Liberia (1850); Virginia politics and elections; and education,
                     including a letter from Patriot, Indiana (March 1851) describing the
                     "Universalist School," a utopian school in that area.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_t2t" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1855-1859, [1878?], 1908 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_5b7f3175f61396ca7fe21c092c54ea1a">38 items</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_2c1596f0aeb424e045520a949bc4ac16" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e1aa7e64a4ad3e6e00297cf8b2d1df36"
                     parent="aspace_2c1596f0aeb424e045520a949bc4ac16" type="folder">7</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8f574be442e8b6bea09b554b10f6cd10">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Of note in this series: several letters related to slavery, including a
                     detailed commentary on the sale of slaves in Richmond at "Myers," and
                     Anderson's wishes for a carpenter and plasterer, 1855, and a printed circular
                     on the market prices for slaves in Richmond, April 1858; letter by Anderson
                     detailing purchases and sales of a "wayward" slave, 1857; a letter from
                     Anderson to abolitionist and educator Theodore Weld, introducing his daughter
                     Haidee and her siblings, commenting on the status of slaves in Virginia and
                     elsewhere, and the wisdom of emancipating her, and asking for a place for
                     Haidee at Eaglewood; a letter from Anderson to his daughter Haidee at school,
                     instructing her in comportment and studying, and reporting on her siblings,
                     mother, family, and health, 1857; and a letter from Anderson to his nephew
                     William, on Haidee's health and arrangements to bring her back to Virginia,
                     April 1858. There is also a note from a Stafford G. Cooke of Edgehill,
                     Virginia, giving details of a suicide of Edward Russell, May 8, 1858.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_nsh" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Financial papers, 1804-1857 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_b9308ed1b1576fc2ae3970417e3f8f76">20 items</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_4ab28119d8b6c8ae2a7a6f935d86c75a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f211305e6921200861ef4c586e3f0f48"
                     parent="aspace_4ab28119d8b6c8ae2a7a6f935d86c75a" type="folder">8</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0740a9bd6392019280c92766164ae796">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Folder houses a variety of financial receipts, statements, and contracts. Of
                     note: Williamsburg Lunatic Hospital expenditures, 1839; a list of doctor's
                     visits which seem to include servant or slave names, 1852-1853; and a bill for
                     school expenses for Haidee Griffin, from Theodore Weld at Eaglewood, New
                     Jersey, 1858.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref10_ewq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Legal papers and printed materials, 1807-1872 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_357d9f884e7ca1870798d2d8837c0618">30 items</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_0d96ae8843587609bc76fc14f7400062" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7a77d5682044697122648c5f41f8fa21"
                     parent="aspace_0d96ae8843587609bc76fc14f7400062" type="folder">9</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8e031f8379aaa0dc22675d10e2b2fe33">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The series contains wills, deeds, bonds, and other legal documents, often
                     featuring individuals whose connection to Anderson is unclear. Family names of
                     York County that appear in these and other documents include Bryan, Coke,
                     Moody, Dickeson, Nelson, White, Vine, and Chapman. The two earliest legal
                     documents are both related to the Vine family of York County, Virginia: the
                     first, dated 1735, grants land from Thomas Vine to a grandson, the second,
                     dated 1739, outlines a financial bond between the Nelson and Vine families.
                     Also included is a copy of Thomas Nelson, Jr.'s will, 1788, and a peace bond
                     drawn up by Robert Anderson as mayor of Williamsburg in 1821. </p>
                  <p>Other materials include an undated copy of Yorktown lot owners as recorded in
                     the Commissioner's Book in 1798. There are also a few printed items such as a
                     public notice by Anderson of a robbery at his home in 1858, as well as legal
                     notes, quotations, and envelopes where some of Anderson's papers were once
                     stored.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref8_e6x" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Virginia militia records, 1806-1832</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_936852d6254b0d566d0755d9792fc887">39 items</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_f03ef7f9e03fe565ff5c55c7a8dc826c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_4309cb437bfd758763ae426021711d92"
                     parent="aspace_f03ef7f9e03fe565ff5c55c7a8dc826c" type="folder">10</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_616c9405f81cdacc06db2a29d04373b6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Stemming from Anderson's work as clerk for and captain of the 68th Regiment of
                     the Virginia militia in James City County (Jamestown), these 37 items date from
                     1806 to 1858. Most are receipts and lists written by the Sheriff or his
                     deputies in receipt of Robert Anderson's records of muster fines and
                     delinquencies, but there are also early documents created by Anderson listing
                     names and payments. There are also two printed lists of individuals receiving
                     military pensions received following an Act of Congress in 1828. Series ends
                     with Anderson's resignation letter, 1837.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
