<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/andersoncharlesroberts/"
         >andersoncharlesroberts</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Charles Roberts Anderson Papers, 1806-1993 and undated
                  <num>RL.00040</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Christian Ferney; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Christian Ferney</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">002878441</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-28 11:13:19
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Charles Roberts Anderson papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Anderson, Charles Roberts, 1902-1999</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00040</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">15.9 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1806/1993" type="inclusive">1806-1993 and undated</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_c7ea71980bc63ea595568ce1447006b2">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_428af146abe2a93cba93cc0aacc05272">Author and professor of American
            literature at Duke University and Johns Hopkins University. The Charles Roberts Anderson
            Papers span the dates 1806-1993 and document his active career as professor of American
            literature at Duke University and Johns Hopkins University. Included are research
            materials on the intellectual life of Charleston, S.C., and on American literary figures
            such as Paul Hamilton Hayne, Emily Dickinson, Henry James, Sidney Lanier (to whom
            Anderson was related), Herman Melville, Henry David Thoreau, and others. Additional
            material includes correspondence and files on Anderson's publications; lectures and
            files related to teaching; travel diaries and keepsakes; and other papers related to his
            family history and academic career. Copies of correspondence and other documents by
            Anderson's research subjects, particularly Hayne, detail elements of life in the South
            in the nineteenth century. In addition, material in this collection chronicles the
            academic life of Anderson and provides insight into the state of literary scholarship
            and publishing in the mid-twentieth century. Early dates usually reflect the dates of
            the content of original material photocopied by Anderson in the course of his research.
            Acquired as part of the Jay B. Hubbell Center for American Literary
            Historiography.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_508455b0bbbe4bad8cb5061c5883619e">
            <extent>Approximately 10,200 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_ae171ab99e76aa862f86f2569320bbe3">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_6925cb3a68b3c83c6cf142c58f7580c1">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>In addition, original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Technical Services
            staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_09914ff3f17090ad46c71c9d10435560">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_8e5593d75939127d3faa0300a53fd31d">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Charles Roberts Anderson Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_37817012f31a7d324fb97f687630890f">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Charles Roberts Anderson Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library as gifts in December 1984, January 1986, and May 2000.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_dab3dedca67f539a4347f83fd5e9391c">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Christian Ferney, April 2009</p>
         <p>Encoded by Christian Ferney, April 2009</p>
         <p>Accessions from 1985, 1986, and 2000-0261 were merged into one collection, described in
            this finding aid. </p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_2dc7f19f9494d3c06ca452ca84ba91c9">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <chronlist>
            <head>Chronology</head>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1902</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Charles Roberts Anderson born in Macon, Georgia</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1930</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Joined faculty of the English Department at Duke University</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1936</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Received doctorate from Columbia University; thesis was on Herman
                     Melville's naval career</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1939</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Published <title type="simple" render="italic">Melville in the South
                        Seas</title>
                  </event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1941</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Appointed to faculty of Johns Hopkins University, in part to serve as
                     general editor of the centennial edition of the collected works of Sydney
                     Lanier, published in 1946</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1949-1970s</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Became sought-after as an international lecturer on American literature,
                     traveling to Heidelberg University (1949), the University of Rome (1952-1953),
                     Japan (1954), and the University of Torino (1960); during the 1960s and 1970s
                     the U.S. Department of State engaged him for a lecture tour of Japan, Southeast
                     Asia, the Balkans, and other countries</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1960</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Published <title type="simple" render="italic">Emily Dickinson's Poetry:
                        Stairway of Surprise</title>, which received the Christian Gauss Book Award
                     from Phi Beta Kappa in 1962</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1965</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Edited the two-volume anthology, <title type="simple" render="italic"
                        >American Literary Masters</title>
                  </event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1968</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Publication of <title type="simple" render="italic">The Magic Circle of
                        Walden</title>
                  </event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1976</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Memorial to Henry James unveiled at Westminster Abbey</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1977</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Published <title type="simple" render="italic">Person, Place, and Thing in
                        Henry James's Novels</title>, for which he won a second Christian Gauss
                     award</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1999</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Died in Charleston, S.C.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
         </chronlist>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_290ce5abca6efa5c365f367c6b603f68">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The Charles Roberts Anderson Papers span the dates 1806-1993 and document the active
            literary career of Anderson, who was professor of American literature at Duke University
            and Johns Hopkins University and a reknowned international lecturer. Included are
            research materials on Paul Hamilton Hayne and other Southern literary figures. Also
            contains writings and research files on the subjects of Anderson's books and edited
            volumes, especially Emily Dickinson, Henry James, Sidney Lanier (to whom Anderson was
            related), Herman Melville, Henry David Thoreau, and other American literary figures,
            including Walt Whitman, William Faulkner, and Mark Twain. Additional material includes
            files on his research and publications on the intellectual life of Charleston, S.C.;
            correspondence and files on other publications; lectures and files related to teaching,
            including two audiotapes of Anderson's lectures on Dickinson; travel journals,
            keepsakes, and two films on Charleston, S.C. and Stratford, England; and other papers
            related to the Anderson family history and his academic career. Copies of correspondence
            and other documents by Anderson's research subjects, particularly Hayne, detail social
            conditions and life in the South in the nineteenth century. In addition, material in
            this collection chronicles the academic life of Anderson and provides insights into the
            state of American literary scholarship and publishing in the mid-twentieth century.
            Early dates usually reflect original material photocopied by Anderson in the course of
            his research. Acquired as part of the Jay B. Hubbell Center for American Literary
            Historiography.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_ac1f011b96a00a79f6a21be8c0396b6e">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
         <p>[Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Viewing or listening copies must be
            made before contents can be accessed.]</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <arrangement id="aspace_2eede3b7bbfc5628782e5b3e16dba2fc">
         <head>Arrangement note</head>
         <p>Arranged into the following series: Henry James Memorial Series; Personal Files;
            Teaching; Travel; Writings and Research; and Oversize Material.</p>
      </arrangement>
      <controlaccess>
         <genreform source="ingest">Film</genreform>
         <genreform source="aat">Sound recordings</genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">Travel -- Diaries</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Charleston (S.C.) in film</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Charleston (S.C.) -- Intellectual life -- 20th century</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Authors and publishers -- United States -- Correspondence</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">American literature -- Study and teaching</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">American literature -- Southen States -- History and
            criticism</subject>
         <persname source="ingest">Twain, Mark, 1835-1910</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Lanier, Sidney, 1842-1881</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Melville, Herman, 1819-1891</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Thoreau, Henry David, 1817-1862</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Jay B. Hubbell Center for American Literary
            Historiography</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Dickinson, Emily, 1830-1886</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Anderson, Charles Roberts, 1902-1999</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Anderson, Charles Roberts, 1902-1999</persname>
         <famname source="ingest">Anderson family</famname>
         <persname source="ingest">James, Henry, 1843-1916</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Hayne, Paul Hamilton, 1830-1886</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Faulkner, William, 1897-1962</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Faculty</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref15_san" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Henry James Memorial Series, 1975-1984 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_b2ce177d6a74499ee251c4ef97189fe5">
                  <extent>32 folders</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_646c093dc6f2ff52842a6287f89a6e3c">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Files relate to efforts spearheaded by Anderson to have a memorial to Henry James
                  placed in the Poets' Corner of Westminster Abbey. Includes correspondence with
                  officials and donors; financial and administrative material; and documentation of
                  the installation ceremony. Correspondents include prominent American and British
                  academics and creative writers such as Sir Frank Kermode, Iris Murdoch, Sir
                  Charles P. Snow, Anthony Powell, Stephen Spender, Sir Victor Pritchett, Ralph
                  Richardson, Leon Edel, C. Vann Woodward, Robert Penn Warren, Richard Ellman, and
                  Roger Asselineau.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_mu9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Henry James Memorial files</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_548916581d79b4c2ffb931f87d0babb9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref19_g5z" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Personal Files Series, 1865-1993 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_3b35dca45d87a891e2300ce4a3cad9f2">
                  <extent>18 folders</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_a8975cdfffcb99c3a20ad8b0ea96842e">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Personal papers of Anderson and his family. Includes personal correspondence--some
                  of which also contains elements germane to Anderson's research, photographs, and
                  family historical and geneological material. A file of Christmas cards featuring
                  new poetry by Robert Frost sent to Anderson by Holt, Rinehart and Winston is
                  included. Additional files created by his wife Mary Pringle Anderson and some
                  related to the disposition of Charles Anderson's mother's estate in Georgia also
                  appear in this series. Several sheets of slides complete the series.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_3z7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Personal files</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_eec30dba6342e2de31ecddee2f421358" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1-2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref23_b29" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Teaching Series, 1948-1980</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_998c94b0a5354371a0f3cd5c4439c4fd">
                  <extent>2.5 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_7ce97ca2e387809beec0f10bffb27f47">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Material related to Anderson's teaching and students. The bulk of the material
                  consists of files on individual students Anderson mentored. Additional files
                  include course lectures, student papers, and course syllabi. One file containing
                  minutes and recommendations from a planning conferences of the Modern Language
                  Association and three files of professional correspondence are also included in
                  this series.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_c4x" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Teaching files</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d3204e0eb59e786aaf37c86857cecc84" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2-4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref27_2qb" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Travel Series, 1949-1973 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_1f2a6970db69a2bcb93c09406f6516ab">
                  <extent>2 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_6ef4c08dfc47d418e96f3337c14e71b2">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Files on Anderson's international travels, most of which were connected to his
                  professional life. The bulk of the series contains travel diaries and writings
                  detailing more personal aspects of Anderson's travels with his wife Mary as well
                  as some keepsake printed material and ephemera. Includes some correspondence with
                  universities and granting institutions regarding securing funding for travel,
                  details of various international appointments and lectureships, and some copies of
                  lectures given abroad. Areas visited by Anderson include: Austria, England,
                  Germany, Iran, Ireland, Italy, Japan, Nepal, the Philippines, Romania, Russia,
                  Scandinavia, Singapore, Spain, Taiwan, Thailand, Turkey, and Yugoslavia.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_1kg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Travel files</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d2b981c8f98b3e0f35edc8178da853ff" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5-6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref31_ad5" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Writings and Research Series, 1806-1988 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_0b291218ea4c0d868a968acad6795506">
                  <extent>12 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_4e216de6ac9ff1060463cf8ee74091b3">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Comprises the bulk of the collection and provides a record of Anderson's
                  intellectual life, covering the scope of Anderson's writing and editing work,
                  including research files; drafts and proofs; lectures; and correspondence with
                  publishers. Organized into the following subseries: <emph render="bold">American
                     Literary Masters</emph>, <emph render="bold">Charleston</emph>, <emph
                     render="bold">Emily Dickinson</emph>, <emph render="bold">Paul Hamilton
                     Hayne</emph>, <emph render="bold">Henry James</emph>, <emph render="bold"
                     >Sidney Lanier</emph>, <emph render="bold">Herman Melville</emph>, <emph
                     render="bold">Henry David Thoreau</emph>, <emph render="bold">Other
                     Writings</emph>, and <emph render="bold">Research Files</emph>. Much of the
                  series consists of files either related to research or publishing. Research files
                  are chiefly copies or reprints of scholarly articles but also include a number of
                  copies of correspondence by research subjects. Copies of letters from Emily
                  Dickinson, and numerous letters by or to Paul Hamilton Hayne, to which the
                  earliest dates in this series refer, can be found in the subseries for each
                  author. Copies of letters by Thomas Gayarre, Flannery O'Connor, and between Sarah
                  Helen Whitman and James Wood Davidson are in the Research Files Subseries.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref33_ptk" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>American Literary Masters, 1957-1970 and undated</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5beba2188a62b6ac4ffdca585574d43a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Correspondence with Henry Holt and Company, Inc. (later Holt, Rinehart and
                     Winston, Inc.) relating to the two-volume <title type="simple" render="italic"
                        >American Literary Masters</title> anthology Anderson executive edited.
                     Includes contracts, royalty statements, and other correspondence. Also includes
                     drafts of essays by Anderson on Henry Adams, William Faulkner, F. Scott
                     Fitzgerald, and Robert Frost, written for inclusion in the anthology.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref34_qav" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>American Literary Masters files</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_1f1d6bd3df81cd977c18d7cc2abdd146" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">7</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref36_wel" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Charleston, 1941-1948 and undated</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_96af50bf3a2f894a2f98825af1c09157">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lectures on the intellectual life of Charleston as well as research files from
                     the same period. Also includes undated drafts of <title type="simple"
                        render="italic">Before It Became Historic Charleston</title>, a memoir by
                     Anderson eventually published as <title type="simple" render="italic"
                        >Charleston: A Golden Memory</title> in 1993.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref37_wrj" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Charleston files</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_79a11cd04df007c8dfea1693b8744d5d" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">7-8</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref39_d11" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Emily Dickinson, 1955-1986 and undated</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d2289dd5558581ea0b2b669f575bcde0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Primarily files related to the publication of Anderson's <title type="simple"
                        render="italic">Emily Dickinson's Poetry: Stairway of Surprise</title>,
                     including rejection letters; correspondence with publisher Holt, Rinehart and
                     Winston; and letters of criticism and encouragement from colleagues,
                     particularly Thomas H. Johnson; and clippings of favorable reviews from
                     newspapers. Additional files include a few photocopies of Dickinson
                     mansuscripts and correspondence; transcripts and notes of Anderson's lectures
                     on Dickinson; a file of suggested readings on Dickinson probably associated
                     with <title type="simple" render="italic">American Literary Masters</title>;
                     and correspondence with Duke University regarding the donation of these
                     papers.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <separatedmaterial id="aspace_1e3b533a6c823112034f470317a90be1">
                  <head>Separated Materials note</head>
                  <p>[Some items moved to Oversize Material.]</p>
               </separatedmaterial>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref40_gh4" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Dickinson materials</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_9a3257d6fb15ee083ef35852c48d3b92" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">8</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_sew" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Paul Hamilton Hayne, 1806-1938</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f3f6b0d7c52e79fca733a8a8f30f84fa">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Numerous photocopies of letters written to or by Paul Hamilton Hayne as well as
                     correspondence related to Hayne between Anderson and colleagues or archives.
                     Hayne's correspondents include Charles Gayarre and Henry Timrod. Unlike the
                     other major research files in this series, there is no published work by
                     Anderson in this group.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <separatedmaterial id="aspace_d14c09be651ad1209ac0beeebe80d500">
                  <head>Separated Materials note</head>
                  <p>[Some items moved to Oversize Material.]</p>
               </separatedmaterial>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref44_vcc" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Hayne files</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_bfeaf0694a18d53c5fa24e270ce1e28a" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">8-9</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_zgf" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Henry James, undated</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fb6c1ae757f4e97860844662662c94c7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Drafts and lectures on the works of Henry James; most are likely related to
                     Anderson's <title type="simple" render="italic">Henry James: A Tale of Two
                        Civilizations</title>.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref48_ofz" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>James files</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_f09686585c0a64dfaed83df021094396" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">9</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref50_5sv" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Sidney Lanier, 1940-1982, undated</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bb2ab4693b54fa6c03426e3cac34a70a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Research files include reproductions of Lanier letters, publisher
                     correspondence, clippings, and lectures. Most are dated around the publication
                     of the <title type="simple" render="italic">Centennial Edition of the Works of
                        Sidney Lanier</title> (1945) and <title type="simple" render="italic">Sidney
                        Lanier: Poems and Letters</title> (1969), both edited by Anderson.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref51_s27" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Lanier research files</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_a064878aedb4bd4d5a403fb507ea7b73" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">9</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref53_dbx" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Herman Melville, 1945-1973, undated</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b87f3d0ea011dd763a93ad169c66b198">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Correspondence with co-editors and correspondence related to Anderson's edited
                     and annotated manuscript of <title type="simple" render="italic">Typee</title>,
                     which was to have been part of the aborted <title type="simple" render="italic"
                        >Greylock Edition of Melville</title> series, as well as galley proofs of
                     the manuscript. Additional material related to Anderson's <title type="simple"
                        render="italic">Melville in the South Seas</title> and other articles and
                     lectures on Melville are also included. One article may be part of the <title
                        type="simple" render="italic">American Literary Masters</title>
                     anthology.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <separatedmaterial id="aspace_c225a48d3a9b86231e8b3a6ceeb69eef">
                  <head>Separated Materials note</head>
                  <p>[Some items moved to Oversize Material.]</p>
               </separatedmaterial>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref54_dpe" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Melville files</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_21563a632b15a324bd703c10a6baa16e" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">9-10</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref57_dca" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Henry David Thoreau, 1965-1971, undated</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_086e332502f0581715f2ae4d6e54daef">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Publisher correspondence, partial drafts, and articles on Henry David Thoreau.
                     Most center on Anderson's <title type="simple" render="italic">The Magic Circle
                        of Walden</title> and <title type="simple" render="italic">Thoreau's World:
                        Miniatures from his Journal</title>, which he edited. Files of clippings of
                     reviews of <title type="simple" render="italic">The Magic Circle of
                        Walden</title>, research files including a map of locations referenced in
                     Thoreau's journals, and an article likely related to <title type="simple"
                        render="italic">American Literary Masters</title> may be found at the end of
                     the group.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref58_y06" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Thoreau files</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_eaea9e0b264d78d994bf8c5176e8f659" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">10-11</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref60_qu7" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Other Writings, 1935-1984, undated</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_692eea1101ea0d5537177ce2373cf850">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Copies of most of Anderson's additional publications as well as other drafts,
                     lectures, and a short memoir entitled <title type="simple" render="italic">A
                        Georgia Boy in a Walled Garden</title>. Most are scholarly journal articles
                     on the same subjects as his major works. Additional topics include Southern
                     literature, black writers in the South, and Victorian literature.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref61_sbm" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Other writings</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_86f88e7451878c1d1116f87d1f0b3f16" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">11-12</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref63_0t7" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Research Files, 1859-1988, undated</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c40cedaadee88a3d715234cdd69423d6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Primarily composed of serials, scholarly articles, and index card files on
                     topics of professional significance to Anderson. Earliest dates refer to
                     photocopied archival material. Includes copies of correspondence between
                     Southern literary historian James Wood Davidson and Sarah Helen Whitman;
                     writings and some letters by Louisiana historian and playwright Charles
                     Gayarre; and several pieces of correspondence from Flannery O'Connor sent to
                     Anderson by a student (box 12). Some research material was either collected by
                     Anderson while abroad in Japan or sent by colleagues there. Thus, a few items
                     are in Japanese. Boxes 15-19 contain Anderson's index card files used to
                     organize his research. Includes research notes on the intellectual life of
                     Charleston, Paul Hamilton Hayne, and a large file on various major American
                     authors. Two boxes of cards of more varied material including post cards and
                     miscellaneous notes are also included.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref64_gno" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Research files</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_d1d88e484e4b2ca30b9a28259289ae39" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">12-14</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref65_8l8" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Research card files</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_2f37d619fcd58cc036ef4199f353ac21" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">15-18</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref68_ysa" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Oversize Material, 1825-1960 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_54fb3a9016a552512203ce30be9dcaa2">
                  <extent>3 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_d929512139817753829086b6c6c4c7fd">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Contains items from other series requiring separate housing. Early dates refer to
                  photocopied archival material. Chiefly consists of books of research files on Paul
                  Hamilton Hayne, which include additional copies of Hayne correspondence, as well
                  as records of Anderson's correspondence with libraries and archive repositories as
                  part of his Hayne bibliography project. Also included are film reels featuring the
                  cities of Charleston, S.C. and Stratford, England in the 1930s, possibly amateur
                  movies taken by Anderson; a reel of microfilm belonging to Mary Anderson;
                  audiotapes of lectures on Dickinson by Charles Anderson; and a book of clippings
                  of reviews of his book on Dickinson. Finally, photostats of Lanier research and
                  illustrations related to Anderson's Melville work round out this group of oversize
                  materials.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <accessrestrict id="aspace_cd9bdb8edce2931bd18ea5743aa50778">
               <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
               <p>[Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Viewing or listening copies
                  must be made before contents can be accessed.]</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref70_3il" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Personal Files, 1937-1938 and undated</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref71_xuo" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Film: <title render="doublequote">Charleston,</title>
                        1937</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_2eeef12466f8ca8780ace87850ec0871" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">19</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref72_6o4" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Film: <title render="doublequote">Stratford,</title>
                        1938</unittitle>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_d0512680639afde36a2259e131590c5d">
                        <extent>2 reels</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_b883e161a2a30d786aa77d91c13e1c9f" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">19</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref74_1pu" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Microfilm: <title render="italic">Mary Anderson</title>,
                        undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_eaab747a805dae1fa7a2bed5c8632996" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">19</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref75_315" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Writings and Research, 1825-1960 and undated</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref76_205" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Emily Dickinson, undated</unittitle>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_60ba8c67c2092ddf434d8518cd7084fe">
                        <extent>2 audiotape reels</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_b15049c956e6b15dfee39709db26b286" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">19</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref78_kxf" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">Emily Dickinson's Poetry: Stairway or
                           Surprise</title>, book review clippings scrapbook, 1960</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_b85191f184892b08b1d585b64e761bb6" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">21</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref79_zea" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Hayne correspondence files, 1825-1931</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_8af08649efbc9d16500de7688954649f" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">20</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref80_td2" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Hayne photostats, 1853-1884</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_de23443cb1221b829b0a9cffb1232f51" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">21</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref81_g23" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Lanier photostat, undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_e9c4fe87fd1f0f6675f303dbb0512a5d" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">21</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref82_5sc" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Melville map photostat, undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_6392e8b2c730adf215d8aaaaced21f65" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">21</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
