<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/anthonysusanbbaskin/"
      >anthonysusanbbaskin</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Susan B. Anthony Collection, 1870-1900
          <num>RL.11046</num></titleproper>
        <author>Alice L. Poffinberger</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>September 2015</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">006516418</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-08 09:48:10
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>September 2018</date>
        <item>revised to correct a typo in a name</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date>October 2018</date>
        <item>revised title</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Susan B. Anthony collection</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname role="crp" rules="dacs" source="naf">Anthony, Susan B. (Susan Brownell),
          1820-1906</persname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname role="crp" source="lcsh">Selden, Henry R. (Henry Rogers), 1805-1885</persname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname role="crp" source="lcsh">Studwell, Edwin A., 1837-1916</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.11046</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">13 items</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1870/1900" type="inclusive">1870-1900</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_62e610856f95e693a867cdb8496817bb">Collection comprises seven letters from
        Susan B. Anthony to various correspondents, one postcard written to her, a printed item, and
        a letter by S. J. S. Holden that mentions Anthony, Stanton, and the 1874 National Woman
        Suffrage Association (N.W.S.A.) convention. </abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_f91e0e9129ead552f439c83bd7ebb296">Materials are in
        English.</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_95f34b5fa9a8e2fd5c06b43db29c2765">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_bd3ec73ee28a5996b9abaf3c966f540c">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>Collection comprises seven letters from Susan B. Anthony to various correspondents, one
        postcard written to her, a printed item, and a letter by S. J. S. Holden that mentions
        Anthony, Stanton, and the 1874 National Woman Suffrage Association (N.W.S.A.) convention. In
        June 1870, Anthony wrote two letters to Edwin A. Studwell, who became her business manager,
        regarding payment for lectures in which she participated with Elizabeth Cady Stanton; her
        need to sell her serial, The Revolution, and plans for its continued success; competition
        with suffragists in Boston; her life insurance policies; and her general need for ready
        funds. There is also a Dec. 1873 letter from Anthony to Judge Henry R. Selden requesting
        copy for his argument made on Anthony's behalf regarding the Rights of Women in the U.S.
        District Court of New York, to be published in time for the upcoming N.W.S.A. convention.
        The postscript to this letter was written upon a flyer for a mass meeting of the New York
        Woman's Suffrage Society. Collection includes a copy of the final, printed version of
        Selden's argument, "Rights of women under the late constitutional amendments."</p>
      <p>In 1894, Anthony wrote two letters to a suffragist concerning problems in Kansas; she
        wished to identify the Republican, Progressive, or other person responsible for "stirring
        things up," for the Republicans failed to include suffrage in their platform. On 1900 April
        24, Anthony wrote to Rachel [Foster Avery?] regarding several publications in process,
        including forms for letters to the national conventions of the prohibition, Populist,
        Democratic, and Republican parties; a "memorial;" an appeal to the Ecumenical Council; along
        with other work to be shared by the suffrage leadership. A letter from Anthony 1900 July 22
        was written to an unnamed suffragist who likely requested an autograph, "Yes indeed--you
        shall have my pen tracks--not only--but also my wish that you both believe in work for the
        protection of women in the crowning right of citizenship--the right to vote--and so help to
        hasten the day when ours shall be a true republic in practice as it now is in theory."</p>
      <p>Collection also includes a postcard written to Anthony from Mary L. Lathrop in Jackson,
        [Miss.?] in 1874 regarding Lathrop's inability to send more money following Anthony's
        successful speaking engagement there; the money went toward advertising for the event.
        Another letter, from S. J. S. Holden to Rachel [Foster Avery?], in 1874 describes attendance
        at the N.W.S.A. convention, the speeches of Anthony and Elizabeth Cay Stanton, and other
        pastimes in Washington, D.C. Several of the letters in the collection are written on
        N.W.S.A. or National-American Woman Suffrage Association letterhead; Anthony's 1894 letters
        are stamped with the ownership mark of the Daughters of the Pioneers of Washington library.
        Collection includes dealer transcriptions for two of Anthony's letters.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <userestrict id="aspace_dee6e673d4ab8774881f72b2d41c1465">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_07cd5b784ef582bd3ddbc73a95ea3064">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Susan B. Anthony Collection, 1870-1900, David M. Rubenstein Rare
        Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <bioghist id="aspace_de8785ee32f6cdc63c4c3844dcbfc4a5">
      <head>Biographical Note</head>
      <p>Susan B. Anthony was born February 15, 1820 in Adams, Massachusetts. She was brought up in
        a Quaker family with long activist traditions. Early in her life she developed a sense of
        justice and moral zeal. After teaching for fifteen years, she became active in temperance.
        Because she was a woman, she was not allowed to speak at temperance rallies. This
        experience, and her acquaintance with Elizabeth Cady Stanton, led her to join the women's
        rights movement in 1852. Soon after, she dedicated her life to woman suffrage. Ignoring
        opposition and abuse, Anthony traveled, lectured, and canvassed across the nation for the
        vote. She also campaigned for the abolition of slavery, the right for women to own their own
        property and retain their earnings, and she advocated for women's labor organizations. In
        1900, Anthony persuaded the University of Rochester to admit women. Anthony, who never
        married, was aggressive and compassionate by nature. She had a keen mind and a great ability
        to inspire. She remained active until her death on March 13, 1906.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <processinfo id="aspace_51869fa65cc79a66377e9451598f14ce">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by: Alice L. Poffinberger, May, 2015.</p>
      <p>Accessions described in this finding aid: 2015-0050-LUBMSS099; 2015-0050-LUBMSS100;
        2015-0050-LUBMSS101; 2015-0050-LUBMSS102; 2015-0050-LUBMSS103; 2015-0050-LUBMSS104;
        2015-0050-LUBMSS105; 2015-0050-LUBMSS106; 2015-0050-LUBMSS281.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_1ba0e048e2ab9d69c78df1f71a5e42a7">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>The Susan B. Anthony Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Suffrage -- Kansas</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Suffrage -- United States -- History -- 19th century</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Suffragists -- United States -- History</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women's rights -- United States -- History</subject>
      <title source="lcsh">Revolution (New York, N.Y.)</title>
      <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Anthony, Susan B. (Susan Brownell), 1820-1906 --
        Correspondence</persname>
      <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Anthony, Susan B. (Susan Brownell), 1820-1906 --
        Correspondence</persname>
      <persname source="lcsh">Selden, Henry R. (Henry Rogers), 1805-1885 -- Rights of women under
        the late constitutional amendments</persname>
      <persname source="lcsh">Studwell, Edwin A., 1837-1916</persname>
      <corpname source="lcsh">National Woman Suffrage Association (U.S.)</corpname>
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">National American Woman Suffrage Association</corpname>
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">National American Woman Suffrage Association --
        History</corpname>
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Lisa Unger Baskin Collection (David M. Rubenstein Rare
        Book &amp; Manuscript Library)</corpname>
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and
        Culture</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_57556892d26e457b997549df435d4a5c" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Collection</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_693a0c820741f3678d6ef88eb4fcf88f" label="mixed materials"
            type="folder">1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
