<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD" url="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/m11g6p"
      >ashleymarydowdell</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Mary Dowdell Ashley Film Collection, 1937-1975
          <num>RL.10048</num></titleproper>
        <author>Craig Breaden</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>January 2014</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">005995468</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-12-15 15:49:36
          -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Mary Dowdell Ashley film collection</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname source="naf">Ashley, Mary Dowdell</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.10048</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">13 16mm film reels</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1970" type="inclusive">1937-1975</unitdate>
      <physloc id="aspace_1c0456d83b7e7d2d7f018789117e75ee">For current information on the location
        of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
      <abstract id="aspace_a415ab547bd152514baaf107e09da638">The collection consists of
        approximately 9,000 film feet (about 5.5 hours across 13 reels) of 16mm home movies, shot
        from the 1930s to the 1970s by Mary Dowdell Ashley. The footage consists primarily of
        Ashley's family and community life in Montgomery, Alabama and the Gulf Coast
        area.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language> . </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="aspace_b58498d6dabbdd8c8c15732e2faff4b0">
      <head>Biographical note</head>
      <p>Mary Barnett Dowdell was born in Montgomery, Alabama, in 1917, to Annie Solomon Dowdell and
        William Shapard "Shap" Dowdell. In 1919 the family moved to Pelham Manor, New York, where
        Shap Dowdell managed the New York office of the Montgomery firm Weil Brothers Cotton. Shap
        died unexpectedly in late 1937, and in 1938 the family returned to Montgomery. In 1941 Mary
        Dowdell married John Myrick Ashley, an independent insurance agent, in Montgomery. They had
        five children, Virginia, Ann, Bonnie, Rick, and Shap.</p>
      <p>On her 16th birthday, Mary Dowdell received a 16mm camera, and over the next 40 years
        recorded with it a very active life, which included managing a large household in Montgomery
        as well as a country property in Coosa County, maintaining membership in a variety of
        community organizations, and travelling. She died in 1983.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_96c5c84fbe0707d590755b3049cb2650">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Mary Dowdell Ashley films were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library as a gift between 2010, 2011, and 2013.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <arrangement id="aspace_745ee06102f4477fa133ea673f75f02e">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>The collection is arranged by original reel number.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_6b8f876098243417d1f0e6ab1cf0d3d9">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>The collection consists of approximately 9,000 film feet (about 5.5 hours across 13 reels)
        of 16mm home movies, shot from the 1930s to the 1970s by Mary Dowdell Ashley. The footage
        consists primarily of Ashley's family and community life in Montgomery, Alabama and the Gulf
        Coast area. Additionally, there is some documentation of African American life in the South
        in the mid-century: footage on Reel 6 shows an outdoor African American baptism in Shorter,
        Alabama, in 1939, as well as street scenes in Montgomery from that same year; footage on
        Reel 7 captures the circa 1950 Thanksgiving Day parade leading up to the Alabama State
        versus Tuskegee football game, an annual rivalry between the two historically black
        institutions; and there is footage on Reel 11 of cotton picking. Some commercial footage is
        mixed in with the longer compilation reels.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_99f6635bc2d6bcc3f2cd988e94ae3494">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      <p>Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require
        production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research Services before coming to
        use this collection.</p>
      <p>The collection may contain materials to which the Acknowledgment of Legal Responsibilities
        and Privacy Rights form applies. Patrons must sign this form before using the
        collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for
        research use.</p>
      <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_806561dbb10e16a1d522384844a0c46d">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <controlaccess>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Montgomery (Ala.)</geogname>
      <genreform source="ingest">Film</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Audiovisual materials</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">16mm</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Home movies</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref1_oa9" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Films</unittitle>
          <unitid>1</unitid>
          <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1936/1967"
            type="inclusive">1936-1967</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_e4d5b9c26ac8edb4841d794aac27d0a9">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Most of the films have a two-part description. The first part is comprised of the notes
            on the original film cans, created by Mary Dowdell Ashley. The children of Mary Dowdell
            Ashley created additional descriptions of the films, which are provided here verbatim.
            The first six reels are compilation reels containing multiple rolls of film spliced
            together, and the descriptions for these are subdivided into sequence (roll) number and
            scene number.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref2_jv4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 1, compilation, segments 1-12</unittitle>
            <unitid>1</unitid>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1952/1955"
              type="inclusive">1952-1955</unitdate>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r4ht2mb91"
              xlink:role="video-streaming" xlink:show="new"
              xlink:title="Reel 1, compilation, segments 1-12, 1952-1955"
              xpointer="ark:/87924/r4ht2mb91"/>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_8a1bf5f86c41be35344b4423175c64fe">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 1. Scene 1. Montgomery, AL, downtown: Dale's Penthouse outside
              restaurant on balcony (family went there after Myrick's christening): view of downtown
              Montgomery -capitol building, red tile dome of 1st Baptist Church; Bonnie (blue dress)
              with Ann (also blue dress) behind her; Joy Clark in yellow skirt; Daddy holding
              Myrick; Louise Clark in yellow skirt. Standing against railing: Louise, Joy, Ann,
              Bonnie, Ginny, Daddy holding Myrick. Panorama view of downtown.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 1. Scene 2. Hull Street, front yard: Easter egg hunt. Louise Clark?
              (red dress); Bonnie (red hair) &amp; Ann (both in blue dresses); multiple children;
              Laura Hutchinson? (blue coat with white stripes at collar; beside her in blue: Inge
              Hill; Bonnie again; Georgina Terry in light blue coat and next to her in white, Edith
              Johnston?; Laura Hutchinson again with brother Hank (in gray).</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 1. Scene 3. Hull Street, back yard: Daddy with Bonnie (green coat
              &amp; hat), Ann (red coat &amp; hat), &amp; Ginny (plaid coat).</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 1. Scene 4. Location? -- Graham Haven: Mother's friends -- Libby
              Foster? (in blue), ? (red/white plaid, several friends standing or sitting by table,
              Mother (in white) at back, Katie Seawell sitting with legs propped on table, Frances
              Hill (in glasses) sitting. View of water -- ? at end of pier; Eloise Virgin
              (red/gray/black top) walked onto pier. 4 women on pier: ?, Libby (blue dress)
              standing, Frances Nicrosi ? (pinkish shirt &amp; vest) sitting, Frances Lamb (in suit)
              standing, Mother (hat, light blue shirt, jeans) standing, Libby on chair &amp; Frances
              Lamb &amp; ? &amp; Eloise Virgin.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 1. Scene 5. Hull Street, sidewalk in front: Bonnie (horizontal
              striped shirt); Big Ann, holding Myrick; Ginny (in dress); Ann (white shirt &amp; blue
              shorts), Dear. Myrick crawling &amp; dragging left leg on sidewalk; Dear (white scarf)
              - dark.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 1. Scene 6. Hull Street, back yard: Myrick, barefooted &amp; sitting
              on grandfather (Shap Dowdell)'s chair; tried to walk.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 2. Scene 1. Montgomery, AL -- Helen Cottingham's kindergarten, Ann
              &amp; Bonnie's birthday (March 1953): sand - Ann (in blue); Ann holding rope &amp;
              jumping rope; Bonnie (in blue) swinging (can see 1949 green Plymouth (family car) in
              background). Ann jumping rope with each end held by friends. ? (in red), Charlotte
              Poyntz holding ukelele; behind Ann, Edith Johnston (blue dress &amp; slip showing)
              &amp; 2 others. Then see at left ? (in white sweater), ? (in green dress), next to ?
              (in red); Charlotte Poyntz ? on bike, Lila Ashley, Ann (in blue); then ? &amp; then
              Edith Johnston; Miss Cottingham may be behind, between Ann &amp; ?. Other side of
              Charlotte: male &amp; then Bonnie. </p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 2. Scene 2. Hull Street, front yard: Daddy holding Myrick's hand
              &amp; Ann holding beach ball; then Ann, Myrick, Bonnie. Good view of house with Daddy,
              Myrick, Ann in front. Same scene, another time: probably Easter Sunday, dressed for
              Sunday School: Ginny, Ann, &amp; Bonnie (all in hats). </p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 2. Scene 3. Oak Park (Montgomery city park): Myrick (sailor suit) on
              Merry Go-Round; roller coaster; Bessie Seawright holding Shap. Car ride. Airplane
              ride: Bonnie in airplane with ? behind her. Ann (same dress as Bonnie -- blue &amp;
              white with applique of red &amp; white strawberries). Bessie holding Shap. Ferris
              wheel: Ann &amp; Ginny probably next to her. Bonnie on Merry-Go-Round. Dark.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 2. Scene 4. Hull Street, back yard: Myrick on sliding board.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 3. Scene 1. Mary Esther, FL: back of Bonnie, Ginny (dark suit),
              &amp; Mary Ellis Carrere (light suit) climbing into boat; Daddy at back by motor in
              adjacent boat. Ann &amp; male climbing in. Other boat again -- Daddy at back, Bonnie
              &amp; Ginny. Mary Ellis &amp; Ginny diving off end of pier. Bonnie, Daddy. Little Ann
              on far left and male between her &amp; ?. 2 children &amp; 3 adults (1 female &amp; 2
              males) in boat. Back to boat with Daddy by motor &amp; Bonnie at other end. Bonnie
              onto pier with Little Ann &amp; ?. View of Santa Rosa Sound. East Pass Bridge or
              another bridge in Destin area. ? catching fish. Back to Santa Rosa Sound near
              pier.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 3. Scene 2. Mary Esther, FL (cont'd): in water (sound): Mother with
              Shap in inner tube -- Bonnie (in halter &amp; shorts) standing. Ginny &amp; Mary Ellis
              wrapped in sheets &amp; towels; Ann (in blue plaid shirt) wading. Dark. View of shore
              from boat -- pier with 2 houses in background. Bonnie &amp; Ann (in life jackets) at
              bow of boat; middle of boat: Myrick (in red life jacket); Ginny &amp; Mary Ellis (no
              life jackets). Close-ups of those on boat including Daddy. Bonnie &amp; Ann in shallow
              water: both swim. </p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 3. Scene 3. Mary Esther, FL: Gulf side of Santa Rosa Island: back of
              Bonnie in inner tube on sand; Ann building drip sand castle; Mary Ellis &amp; Ginny
              standing in water, &amp; then both swim. Daddy &amp; Myrick on sand. Mother in 2 piece
              bathing suit.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 4. Scene 1. Montgomery, AL: "Rose Mary," Inge Hill's home: Pony
              riding: Bonnie holding reins with Myrick in front of Ann on pony. Daddy leads pony
              around. View of house. Inge, jr. In tree with boy on ground. Daddy in bow tie with
              Myrick with boy behind him on pony. Frances Hill near head of pony &amp; Ann next to
              her, then Bonnie (white shirt &amp; dark pants) &amp; Inge, jr. beside her.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 4. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue, driveway &amp; side yard: Myrick &amp;
              Meri Wood. Myrick walks towards 3 girls in driveway. Back yard: little girl ? on
              swing. Myrick (cowboy hat &amp; boots) at top of sliding board &amp; slides down. Shap
              in taylor tot. View of back yard. Myrick, holding croquet stick, beside Shap in taylor
              tot. Bonnie (in dress) bats a croquet ball. Shap standing &amp; holding stick &amp;
              ball. Swing set: Bonnie is closest &amp; Gray Thames on other side of double swing --
              Myrick tries to stop them with croquet stick. Shap crawling. Shap on swing. Ginny
              (blue shorts). Myrick &amp; perhaps Shot Thames leaning on swingframe. Gray on swing
              &amp; Bonnie next to her. Shap on ground crying. Another view of swingframe with same
              people. Good view of back of house: clothes on clothesline drying on upstairs back
              porch. </p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 4. Scene 3. Mary Esther, FL: Shap in water with hands on boat; Meri
              Wood beside him. Bonnie in life jacket. Daddy on right of boat &amp; on other side:
              Bonnie, Meri, Shap. Myrick in life jacket in water &amp; Meri at edge of water with
              her back to the camera. Exie Lee Walker holding Shap? </p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 5. Scene 1. Mary Esther, FL: Aunt Mamie &amp; Uncle Phil's house. In
              water: Ann (tallest), Bonnie (pony tails) &amp; Myrick. Ann &amp; Bonnie swimming
              &amp; Myrick in large inner tube. Close-up of Bonnie, Ann, Myrick. Daddy in chair
              smoking.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 5. Scene 2. Mary Esther, FL: Gulf side of Santa Rosa Island: Bonnie
              &amp; Ann in water. Bonnie swimming. Daddy in water. Myrick digging in sand. Mother in
              2 piece bathing suit in water.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 5. Scene 3. Wolf River, MS, near Pass Christian &amp; Gulfport: pier
              -- Little Ann in reddish bathing suit with white trim holding Shap; swims across river
              holding Shap in inner tube. Myrick on pier holding inner tube. Views of river. Shap
              crying while walking towards camera. Little Ann in shorts. Ann (dark suit) &amp; girl?
              in blue or green suit near hammock. Mollie in white underpants &amp; 2 others? Little
              Ann in hammock holding Mollie, Bonnie standing. Shap at bottom of steps &amp; then
              beside hammock.View of Stauss Haus with hammock in front. </p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 6. Scene 1. Bankhead Avenue, back yard. Birthday party for Ann &amp;
              Bonnie (March 1955): pony rides. ? In pigtails on pony. Exie in green uniform near
              pony. Lots of children. Dirt piles in vacant lot next door. Driveway scene: one
              walking on stilts, others playing, etc., &amp; some roasting marshmellows. Bonnie (in
              white shirt) on pony. Children on swings, etc. Children playing on dirt piles next
              door.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 6. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue, back yard: another day. Birthday of ?,
              maybe Meri Wood. Meri Wood (in white dress) &amp; Bonnie on right. Little girl? beside
              small table. Shap in sailor suit. Myrick in sailor suit on rocking horse. Meri opening
              present.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 6. Scene 3. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Close-up of Bonnie, with
              Ginny in background. Myrick sucking thumb. Ginny with Ann into background. Front walk:
              Myrick at left, then Lila Ashley, Bonnie, Ann with Ginny behind.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 7. Scene 1. Montgomery Country Club: arbor-like area behind the old
              Country Club main building. Old big &amp; baby pools. Daddy &amp; Shap walking into
              baby pool. Lots of messy tables, probably from a party the night before. Ann (left)
              &amp; Bonnie (right) diving into big pool.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 7. Scene 2. Perdido, AL: Billy Thetford on boat. ? diving off board
              at end of pier. Few people &amp; then Bonnie at end of diving board from which she
              dives. Ginny (red suit). Close-up of Myrick holding onto life jacket &amp; Randolph
              Candler doing the same. Close-up of a Thetford (?), who ducks under water.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 7. Scene 3. "Huntingdon" Kowliga, near Wetumka, AL:. Large set of
              swings. Friends of Mother &amp; Daddy sitting. Close-up of a baby with pacifier in
              mouth. Close-up of Mildred Duncan (white collar).</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 7. Scene 4. location?: Big Ann (white hat) &amp; ??. Bruce &amp;
              Dorothy Thomas from San Antonio. Virginia Thomas on right of 2 sisters (Emily &amp;
              Dorothy).</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 7. Scene 5. Mary Esther, FL (?): rubber raft with Shap in front of
              Myrick. View of house our family rented. Children in water - hard to identify. Bonnie
              (navy suit with white trim) in an inner tube. Close-up of little girl? in inner
              tube.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 8. Scene 1. AEA holidays (Alabama Educational Association): Family
              trip to Florida via Georgia. Okefenokee Swamp (GA): otters, alligators. Ginny (white
              sweater &amp; designed skirt) walking with Myrick. Ann in pinkish peddle
              pushers.Myrick with ducks. Ginny with Ann &amp; Bonnie (latter 2 dressed alike) &amp;
              Myrick.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 8. Scene 2. AEA cont'd: Marineland, FL: dolphin feeding; underwater
              scene. Flippy the "educated" porpoise. Bonnie, Ginny, Ann, Mother, Myrick: standing
              with ocean in background. More underwater scenes.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 9. Scene 1. AEA cont'd: St. Augustine, FL: Castle of San Marcos --
              Ginny (light blue skirt), Daddy, then standing next to each other. Myrick &amp; Ann.
              Fountain. Far left: Ann, then Bonnie, &amp; Ginny &amp; Myrick to right. </p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 9. Scene 2. AEA cont'd: Cross Sewanee River on way to Wakulla
              Springs. DARK -- underwater. Views from glass-bottomed boat. Off boat: Mother, Myrick,
              Ginny, Ann, Bonnie.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 9. Scene 3. Bankhead Avenue: Shap in snowsuit &amp; red hat,
              barefooted. Myrick in red cowboy shirt. Another day: Myrick in Sunday clothes &amp;
              coonskin cap. Ginny (green dress); Margaret Harris (pink dress); Bonnie (white). Good
              view of Bankhead house.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 10. Scene 1. Mayland, TN: Camp Nakanawa: waterfront; some cabins;
              waterfront again. Daddy standing beside rowboats. Horse ring by fence: Minnie Lee
              Richardson, Ginny, Ginny Hubbard. Round house. Tennis courts. Waterfront: canoe
              contest; swim meet.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 10. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue: Shap &amp; Myrick in sailor suits.
              Close-up of Shap &amp; then Mollie. Ann &amp; Bonnie in back of Myrick &amp; Shap
              &amp; Mother. Station wagon (fake wood trim) &amp; green Plymouth. Between cars: Gray
              Thames, Bonnie &amp; Ann behind Myrick &amp; Shap &amp; then Exie.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 11. Scene 1. Mary Esther, FL: on boat in life jackets: Myrick, Shap,
              Ann with Bonnie behind. View from boat: houses along Santa Rosa Sound. Boat again.
              Another boat with Daddy on bow. Bubba Branson? driving boat. Mother or Ginny skiing.
              Male skiing.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 11. Scene 2. Mary Esther, FL: , sound side of Santa Rosa Island:
              Myrick, Ann, Bonnie in life jackets. Pier on sound side: Daddy, Myrick, Bonnie, Ann.
              Scallops underwater near pier; close-ups of scallops out of water. </p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 11. Scene 3. Mary Esther, FL: Gulf side of Santa Rosa Island: sea
              oats, sand, water. Jeep with Daddy lifting Shap out &amp; Myrick climbing out. Sunset
              over Gulf.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 11. Scene 4. Mary Esther, FL: sound side of Santa Rosa Island: Daddy
              &amp; Ann, Bonnie, Myrick in water.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 12. Scene 1. Bankhead Avenue: Ginny on stilts &amp; Uncle Eddie in
              background. Close-up of Mollie. Foreground: Bonnie, Mollie, &amp; Shap in toy fire
              engine. Backyard: Bonnie standing at top of sliding board; back of Ann on left.
              Driveway &amp; carport: Ginny (white top) &amp; Margaret Harris (plaid top) on stilts.
              To left: Uncle Eddie putting Mollie on swing. Myrick on adjacent swing. Uncle Eddie
              pushing Mollie -- Myrick on left &amp; Ann on right. Little Ann holding unhappy Shap.
              Shap walking &amp; crying.</p>
            <p>Reel 1. Sequence 12. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Bonnie holding doll, Ginny
              (red flower corsage). Daddy holding Shap, Myrick, Ann holding doll. Laundry basket
              full of presents. Mother in fur coat holding Shap; Myrick, Ann, Bonnie, Ginny (Daddy
              must be taking movie). DARK. Another day: Susan Candler (blond hair) ? Ann, Myrick,
              Randolph Candler. Bonnie using knife on wooden box. Gray Thames, then Bonnie holding
              cat. Dirt piles next door: Ann, Bonnie, Susan Candler, Gray Thames, Randolph Candler,
              Myrick. Green Plymouth in background.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref3_na0" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1300 film
                  feet</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1952/1955"
                type="inclusive">1952-1955</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d089477e3862e791eba97f6468f41b79"
                label="Moving Images [D04655538-]" type="box">1</container>
              <container id="aspace_e57f3134df582f949345cad8f7d9e0b5"
                parent="aspace_d089477e3862e791eba97f6468f41b79" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0001</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref5_6po" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 2, compilation, segments 13-24</unittitle>
            <unitid>2</unitid>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1956/1958"
              type="inclusive">1956-1958</unitdate>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r4rb71266"
              xlink:role="video-streaming" xlink:show="new"
              xlink:title="Reel 2, compilation, segments 13-24, 1956-1958"
              xpointer="ark:/87924/r4rb71266"/>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_c254c69ee6eec2a89048a908d90d3911">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Original notes on can: 13: Bankhead - Rick and Shap in cowboy suits - Spring 1956 -
              Mississippi River - New Orleans - Zoo, 3rd grade, Mrs. Haber, Ann; 14: Spring 1956 -
              Hull St. Big Ann - Stausses - Ann D. (baby) Bonnie and Gray - Bonnie, camp, Mary
              Esther 1956 - Mary Ellis and Dolphin. Gulf - all 5 children; 15: 1956 - Mary Esther -
              Mary Wood and Mary Ellis. Uncle Phil's boat. Perdido diving. Coosa. Country Club; 16:
              1955 - Bankhead - Tutsie's puppies - Shap and Mollie - Backyard on slide. Mother, Dad,
              Little Ann and Eddie. (Lots of blank) Coosa, falls; 17: Summer 1957 - Jamestown and
              Williamsburg. Boat trip - Ann, Bonnie, Rick (sleeping) Shap and Dad; 18: Summer 1957 -
              Ocracoke - Bird Island - Marshall and Exie; 19: Summer 1957 - Perdido, Garth pier.
              Lake Martin, Hubbard and Ellie; 20: 1957 - Von Gal pool. Perdido. Garth skiis - Rusty
              Seawell; 21: January 1958 - Coosa - Rick's Birthday party - Billy, Thomas, Joesph,
              Julian. Easter; 22: 1958 - Mary Esther - Deep sea fishing. Swim meet. East "Y". Hula
              contest - Murchinson; 23: Floyd School chearleading. Bankhead w/puppies. Backyard -
              Ann and Roselyn Weil - Coosa party for Bonnie - Jack's Creek; 24: Blue and Gray
              Tennis. Rick the Cowboy. Swim meet. Mary Esther. Exie.</p>
            <p>Additional description:</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 13. Scene 1. Bankhead Avenue, driveway: Mollie joined by Uncle
              Eddie; Myrick &amp; Shap in cowboy outfits with Tootsie in the background; Daddy,
              Little Ann, &amp; children: Emily Marks (?) on left &amp; Mollie beside Daddy; Uncle
              Eddie between Daddy &amp; Mollie; Bonnie walks towards Daddy; Mollie walks towards
              Uncle Eddie &amp; Bonnie; Myrick &amp; Shap, then Emily Marks (?) in red sweater;
              Shap; Bonnie's back &amp; Mollie on right.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 13. Scene 2. New Orleans, LA: Visit of Ashley family to New Orleans:
              Mississippi River -- steamboat; on ferry: Bonnie in pony tails &amp; Myrick in cowboy
              hat, then Daddy with hat on right; in front of Bonnie is Ann; Mother ? (has blue beret
              on); ? Blue cap with head down; Myrick in cowboy hat; shore scene -- boats, etc.; on
              same ferry?: Mother in white blouse with Ann &amp; Bonnie in chairs in front of her;
              see Lykes Line ship.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 13. Scene 3. New Orleans, LA: Visit cont'd at Audubon Zoo: Viewing
              apes: Daddy &amp; Ann on right, then Myrick beyond Daddy; Bonnie (red hair) behind Ann
              &amp; then beside her with back of Little Ann (brown shirt) on their right; Ann eating
              popcorn &amp; Bonnie on her right. Front of elephants: Ann on left &amp; Mollie (red
              pants) on right of screen; Ann on left &amp; Bonnie on right. To zebras,
              hippopotamuses, camels, buffaloes. Riding pony -- Mollie; also riding -- Myrick;
              buffaloes in a line walking, then flamingoes, small porpoises in pool, alligators. </p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 13. Scene 4. Location? woods or a park?: Miss Haber's (Floyd School)
              class - ? Ann or Bonnie's class.Ann in some close-ups of girls in class; eventually
              see Bonnie (red hair) next to someone in red, white &amp; blue skirt (another
              redhead).</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 13. Scene 5. Location ? Easter egg baskets, then Shap (white shirt)
              with others in background.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 14. Scene 1. Hull Street, front yard: Big Ann holding baby, probably
              Ann D. Stauss; Little Ann in short sleeved white blouse with Big Ann on right holding
              Ann D.; Uncle Eddie walking beside Mollie walking on low bMyrick wall.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 14. Scene 2. Location? Lake ?: Close-up of empty skiff &amp;
              adjacent one with Daddy (blue &amp; white checkered shirt) &amp; Myrick beside him; 2
              others about Myrick's age &amp; then male adult guiding small motorboat.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 14. Scene 3. Bankhead Avenue, back yard: Bonnie in yellow shorts
              with ? Beside her ?</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 14. Scene 4. Helena, AL: Camp Talahi: counselors &amp; campers in
              swim suits; Bonnie (dark blue suit) on right; Maybe Gray Thames (yellow suit) --
              blonde hair -- shorter of 2 in yellow; campers jumping off large blown-up raft; Bonnie
              diving. Woods? On left, Bonnie (brown shorts) on right</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 14. Scene 5. Location? Close-up of ?. On boat: ? In red life
              preserver, Myrick in blue life preserver, Daddy in blue &amp; white hat. Pier. Sting
              ray (large with white spots). Boat. Myrick walking towards camera with Shap in
              background &amp; ?. Seated: Mary Ellis Carrere &amp; Ginny; Shap in shirt with red
              &amp; blue stripes. Scene of houses on shore from boat. Daddy's back.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 14. Scene 6. Destin, FL: Gulf, deep-sea fishing: dolphin being
              caught by Mary Ellis Carrere with close-up of Mary Ellis &amp; then holding dolphin.
              Myrick in blue designed trunks. Mary Ellis, then Ann &amp; Bonnie &amp; behind them on
              right is Myrick. Shap in red designed trunks &amp; Myrick in blue &amp; Meri Wood in
              inner tube. On water's edge -- Meri in inner tube &amp; back of Ann ? On right is Mary
              Ellis (tall) &amp; then Ann. All above in water. Ginny in greenish suit on right, Mary
              Ellis on left &amp; Meri Wood with back to camera. at some point scene moves from Gulf
              to Santa Rosa Sound. </p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 15. Scene 1. Mary Esther or Destin FL: Back of boat "MeriWood";
              Destin: fishing boats; top of Meriwood; Mary Ellis Carrere -- Ann -- Ginny -- Bonnie;
              Meri Wood (red &amp; white striped suit) &amp; Shap; Uncle Phil with cigar; Daddy on
              left &amp; Myrick on right; Mother (yellow sleeveless shirt); dark glasses (?);
              fishing "official"? &amp; Daddy on right.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 15. Scene 2. Mary Esther, FL: sound side of Santa Rosa Island:
              Myrick swimming; Shap in water &amp; pier in background; Myrick jumping in &amp;
              swimming; diving board at end of pier.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 15. Scene 3. Perdido, AL: The Point: Bonnie at head, then Ann, then
              ?; Bonnie diving &amp; then Ann diving; female in red suit dives &amp; then Myrick who
              jumps off board; Bonnie does cartwheel off board; Myrick at end of board -- jumps off
              backwards; Bonnie &amp; Ann swimming; Shap in water -- swimming; female (in red suit)
              skiing.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 15. Scene 4. Location? Shap in shorts &amp; suspenders, holding hand
              of ? -- very DARK.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 15. Scene 5. Montgomery Country Club: Ginny on diving board; Myrick
              climbing out of pool; Ann goes off high dive.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 16. Scene 1. Bankhead Avenue, driveway: back of station wagon &amp;
              green Plymouth; Ann on bicycle &amp; Myrick &amp; Tootsie on right; Myrick holding
              black puppy &amp; Bonnie leaning on bike &amp; then Shap next to Ginny holding a
              puppy; Bonnie riding bike; Puppies eating; Shap holding puppy; DARK; puppy in clothes
              basket (bed for puppies); Bonnie beside basket with puppy.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 16. Scene 2. Location? Halloween costumes.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 16. Scene 3. Location? Mollie in white smock over green dress;
              Bonnie in lavender/purple dress</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 16. Scene 4. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Shap &amp; Myrick dressed
              for Sunday School; Ginny in white coat, Bonnie &amp; Ann with Shap, Mollie &amp;
              Myrick.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 16. Scene 5. Bankhead Avenue, backyard: sliding board &amp; swing
              set. Mother in dark jacket &amp; bermuda shorts &amp; others; then close-up of
              Mother.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 16. Scene 6. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Uncle Eddie, Little Ann,
              Mother &amp; Daddy. DARK.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 16. Scene 7. Coosa: Daddy cooking; Bonnie ?; 2 boys at creek: may be
              Myrick on right &amp; Randolph Candler on left; foreground: Shap; shots of foliage
              &amp; then "falls"; Myrick &amp; Randolph Candler at bottom of the "falls."</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 17. Scene . Family trip to Jamestown &amp; Williamsburg for 350th
              anniversary of landing at Jamestown. On the return trip, the family went to Ocracoke
              Island off the coast of North Carolina.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 17. Scene 1. Virginia Department of Highways car ferry: Myrick -
              Shap - Daddy - Ann, then Ginny on far left &amp; Bonnie on far right.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 17. Scene 2. Jamestown: Shap &amp; Bonnie; stocks, then Bonnie
              standing &amp; Shap in stocks; 3 ship replicas (the Susan Constant, the Godspeed, and
              the Discovery): Myrick in white short-sleeved shirt; miscellaneous???; Daddy (large
              checkered blue &amp; white shirt), then Mother in colored sleeveless dress with boat
              in background; back of Daddy walking away from camera; Myrick (barefooted), Shap &amp;
              Bonnie. </p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 17. Scene 3. On boat (CHECK ON WHICH BOAT): Bonnie's back &amp; Ann
              on right, Myrick on left and Bonnie on right; Daddy at back with Myrick's head in
              Daddy's lap; Shap sticking out tongue; Ginny &amp; Ann next to Daddy &amp; Bonnie
              sitting in bottom of boat; Bonnie on back.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 18. Scene . Family trip continued to Ocracoke after Jamestown.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 18. Scene 1. Ocracoke, NC: Bonnie, Shap, Daddy walking; inlet scene;
              Shap in foreground -- other family members plus some in background; large anchor with
              Shap on left &amp; Myrick on right; more inlet scenes; house, which might be one our
              family rented; store ?.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 18. Scene 2. Trip to Bird Island: Guide took family there in a small
              boat: Ginny in foreground; behind, Shap &amp; pelicans - young with mother; pelican
              eggs in nest; bird guide feeding a pelican; Ginny at back with Myrick &amp; Ann;
              pelicans; naked newborn pelican in nest; bird guide holding young herons; ? bird
              species; view of shoreline of Ocracoke or another island.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 18. Scene 3. Bankhead Avenue, side yard: Marshall &amp; Exie in
              front of banana plant.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 19. Scene 1. Perdido: scenes with boats &amp; people in water &amp;
              on boat.. Close-up of perhaps a member of the Garth family &amp; Daddy; girls with
              life waist supports - think Ann is on left.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 19. Scene 2. Lake Martin, AL?: on shore and then water; man in hat
              &amp; Ann Ely in straw hat; more people; Ann Ely &amp; perhaps her husband,
              Clauson.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 19. Scene 3. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Myrick; Ann in striped
              shirt &amp; friend in red; Shap at front door where Ann joins him.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 20. Scene 1. Von Gal's swimming pool: several people; Daddy in
              water; Ann on diving board from which she does a flip; Daddy in pool with Shap in
              large inner tube; Suzie von Gal holding fondu dish &amp; walking in front of banana
              plant beside pool; Shap in inner tube in pool; June von Gal in yellow (white trunks);
              pool: Daddy holding Shap &amp; Uncle Eddie holding Mollie; Shap &amp; Mollie swimming;
              Marney von Gal in raft with a child; Shap swims; pool scenes with many people.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 20. Scene 2. Perdido, AL: ? is skiing; beach: Rusty Seawell in
              multi-colored straw hat; Ginny ? in black suit skiing; Margaret Harris in strapless
              yellow bathing suit with Shap behind her, then Myrick on left; more water &amp;
              skiing; Ann doing a flip off diving board; canoe with Ginny at front - Margaret Harris
              may be at back - Myrick is in the water.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 21. Scene 1. Coosa, AL: probably birthday party for Myrick &amp;
              Shap: creek at base of falls; close-up of crawfish; woods: Daddy &amp; Shap in striped
              shirt; friends of Myrick &amp; Shap, toasting marshmellows; close-up of snagle-toothed
              Myrick; friends; Randolph Candler ? with marshmellow on foot' friends in woods. Jack's
              Creek: sandy beach on other side of creek; scenes of friends &amp; old mill site. </p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 21. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue, front porch: Julian Hart, Shap holding
              red hat, &amp; Billy Joseph; dressed for Sunday School: Ginny in red suit behind
              Myrick, Bonnie, Billy Joseph &amp; younger brother ? &amp; Ann</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 22. Scene 1. Mary Esther, FL,Deep Sea Fishing in Gulf: Ann fishing
              from back of boat; Ginny with Shap in lap, holding pole; Bonnie in pony tails &amp;
              Shap; Daddy holding fishing pole; Myrick eating; Ann catching fish again; Bonnie
              despondent; Ann, Daddy, &amp; Ginny on other side of Daddy; Jane Marks fishing. After
              fishing trip on pier on Sound: Shap, Ginny, Jane Marks, Ann, Bonnie - each holding a
              fish; close-ups, then Daddy beside Shap; ? &amp; Exie on pier; Shap holding fish;
              Myrick holding crab net; Shap swimming.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 22. Scene 2. Montgomery, AL: Swim meet at the "Y" ?</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 22. Scene 3. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Myrick OR SHAP? 2 friends
              on right -- all in football attire; playing football in yard.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 22. Scene 4. Montgomery, AL: Murchison's front yard: hula hoop
              contest -- Ann using hula hoop; DARK, but may be Bonnie in plaid; Shap using hula
              hoop; small female using hula hoop; back to Ann &amp; hula hoop.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 23. Scene 1. Montgomery, AL: Floyd School playground: football game
              &amp; cheerleaders.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 23. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Betty Seale, Ginny,
              Bonnie, Debbie Moorer, Myrick, all holding Tootsie's puppies; Myrick on bike; Debbie
              Moorer &amp; Bonnie with puppies &amp; Tootsie on ground.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 23. Scene 3. Bankhead Avenue, back yard: volleyball game -- Bonnie
              in pony tails; Exie on 2nd floor back porch; Ann &amp; Rosalind Weil on other side of
              fence in dresses.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 23. Scene 4. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Shap, Myrick, Julian Hart,
              &amp; Joe Thetford, each holding a puppy.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 23. Scene 5. Coosa, AL: front of house? Gray Thames? Ann -- more of
              Ann &amp;/or Bonnie's friends. Jack's Creek: on rock facing camera -- Debbie Moorer;
              Gray Thames &amp; Bonnie in water; scenes of friends, etc. on rocks &amp; in
              water.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 24. Scene 1. Montgomery Country Club: Blue-Gray Tennis Tournament;
              DARK; Ann as ball girl.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 24. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue; Myrick in cowboy hat carrying full
              laundry bag.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 24. Scene 3. Montgomery, AL: Von Gal's swimming pool: group of kids,
              but DARK.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 24. Scene 4. Montgomery, AL: "Y" or Maxwell Air Force Base swimming
              pool: swim meet.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 24. Scene 5. Mary Esther, FL: ? Skiing; Daddy on boat &amp; behind
              him, Myrick &amp; Ann &amp; Shap &amp; Ginny.</p>
            <p>Reel 2. Sequence 24. Scene 6. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Exie in front of house
              (good picture of house).</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref6_vtt" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1300 film
                  feet</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1956/1958"
                type="inclusive">1956-1958</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_7db4dd571f1538ab91b4ae07ae1442b9"
                label="Moving Images [D04655538-]" type="box">1</container>
              <container id="aspace_4059d3a71053113cca9caa8d2a4de89d"
                parent="aspace_7db4dd571f1538ab91b4ae07ae1442b9" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0002</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref8_qiy" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 3, compilation, segments 25-36</unittitle>
            <unitid>3</unitid>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" era="ce"
              normal="1960/1960" type="inclusive">circa 1960</unitdate>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r41r6s125"
              xlink:role="video-streaming" xlink:show="new"
              xlink:title="Reel 3, compilation, segments 25-36, circa 1960"
              xpointer="ark:/87924/r41r6s125"/>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_370efcb928af39eb08dd60ebedd10382">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Original notes on can:</p>
            <p>Montgomery, AL; Coosa County, AL; Mentone, AL; Perdido, AL; New England; New York;
              Farmington, CT; Lynchburg, VA; Destin, FL; Mexico City; Acapulco, Mexico</p>
            <p>Additional description:</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 25. Scene 1. Bankhead Avenue, front &amp; side yards: Tootsie &amp;
              her puppies; Shap in gray blazer, Ann in red coat, Ginny in white coat, Bonnie in
              lavender/purple dress, Myrick (snaggletoothed) in light blue blazer; Daddy with big
              box &amp; Myrick inside. Myrick &amp; Little Allen? (beige pants).</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 25. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue, vacant lot across street: group
              playing ball; view of our house.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 25. Scene 3. Montgomery, AL: Von Gal's yard: adults &amp; children;
              Myrick &amp; Little Ann; close-up of Suzy von Gal; June von Gal with cigarette in
              mouth; Ann in blue dress; Edith Johnston on right of screen; Marney von Gal in red,
              black, gray striped skirt; Ginny in corduroy jumper; view of our house; ? in red t
              shirt, lying on ground; Shap with basketball; Daddy in brown hat next to June von Gal;
              Bonnie in red, blue, white plaid shirt with back to camera; Shap playing with a
              football; Bonnie with Ann on her back; Marney von Gal &amp; Ginny; Bonnie with Edith
              Johnston on her back; close up of Edith Johnston (Mrs. Watt Johnston).</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 25. Scene 4. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Shap, Bonnie, Edith
              Johnston, Ann, Myrick.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 26. Scene 1. Montgomery, AL: downtown: Lanier Homecoming Parade.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 26. Scene 2. Montgomery, AL, Coliseum: horse show: presentation of
              awards -- Bonnie in green dress &amp; Carey Murchison in white dress; Mrs. Murchison
              in brown striped top. </p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 26. Scene 3. Coosa, AL: front of house: Thanksgiving Day: Aunt
              Jeanette, Ada, Big Ann, back of Little Ann in red plaid pants, holding Ann D, Aunt
              Annie in blue; close-up of Ada; Mollie holding Big Ann's hand, Aunt Minnie in blue to
              right; backs of station wagons with Daddy nearest cars; Myrick in white top, Bonnie
              with Uncle Eddie (dark glasses) behind her &amp; then Ginny.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 26. Scene 3. Coosa,AL cont'd: view of house; group walking down
              path, perhaps toward the "spout;" backs of station wagons with ball, pillows, thermos,
              drink jug, coolers; group playing to right of backs of station wagons &amp; in front
              of large dark car; Shap in white top holding sticks; close-up of Uncle Crawf (hat
              &amp; horn-rimmed glasses); Uncle Eddie; close-up of Daddy; Mollie &amp; Shap at back
              of station wagons.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 26. Scene 4. Montgomery, AL: Floyd School: Mrs. Haber's class of
              Shap &amp; his classmates: Shap in costume (purple cape); several of his classmates;
              Julian Hart (red shorts) dancing with ?. </p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 26. Scene 5. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Myrick, Bonnie, Shap
              playing ball; Shap &amp; Myrick with football; Bonnie in pastel dress.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 27. Scene 1. Montgomery, AL: "Y" swim meet: Shap may be in red
              trunks; Ann may be doing the butterfly.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 27. Scene 2. Montgomery Country Club, tennis courts: ball girls
              behind adult female ? Betty Carr?; at top of ball girls is Ann &amp; on right is
              Bonnie with pony tail &amp; headband; table with awards with Kitty or Peggy Shertzer
              seated on closest side of table; Barry Harmon may be behind Ann at top.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 27. Scene 3. Mentone, AL: Camp Skyline: waterfront: synchronized
              swimming with Ginny possibly one of swimmers; 2 in white on pier; Sydney Smith on left
              &amp; Ann may be on right; others (?) appear. DARK. Bonnie walking towards camera;
              cakewalk on tennis courts - little dark; Shap (orange &amp; black striped t shirt)
              drinking from cup; DARK, but Ginny ? on left &amp; Ann ? on right.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 28. Scene 1. Mentone, AL: Camp Skyline: waterfront: audience view;
              swimmers in water -- possibly playing water hockey; DARK; close-up of Ann in black
              swimsuit; canoe contest; small motorboat; large group in water.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 28. Scene 2. Mentone, AL: Camp Laney: Myrick in blue &amp; white
              striped shirt; Daddy in plaid Bermuda shorts.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 28. Scene 3. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Bonnie - Ginny- Ann;
              Bonnie swinging Ginsie &amp; then an older girl; Big Ann holding straw bag on porch;
              Ann D. ? playing football: Randolph Candler in black on left; Shap in blue/black/white
              striped t shirt &amp; Myrick in red/yellow/black striped t shirt; tall boy with the 3
              is Gene Thetford; Shap in contortionish position.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 28. Scene 4. Bankhead Avenue, back yard: concrete slab: 2 boys on
              right, Myrick with back to camera &amp; Shap. Ann ? In red vest sitting on stool or
              table; Bonnie in red plaid pants sitting; Mollie &amp; Ann D.; angle shot with banana
              tree on left; Daddy seated at table &amp; Myrick in foreground; Bonnie on back with
              Mollie standing or sitting on her feet (upstretched legs).</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 29. Scene 1. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: All dressed for Sunday
              School &amp;/or church: close-up of Shap, then Ann, then Myrick, then Bonnie, then
              Shap; Bonnie &amp; Mother in white hat - Ann, Shap, &amp; Myrick standing in front of
              Mother; then Shap, Ann, Daddy, Bonnie, Myrick.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 29. Scene 2. Perdido, AL: launching of Judge Thetford's boat; DARK,
              but group with Daddy in middle after boat launching; close-up of Judge Thetford
              driving boat with someone? skiing. DARK: cliffs beside water.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 29. Scene 3. Montgomery Country club: tennis courts: several playing
              tennis; ball boys &amp; girls but hard to distinguish who they are.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 29. Scene 4. Bankhead Avenue? ? In green top &amp; pants on left;
              Ann in navy shorts; back of ?</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 29. Scene 5. Bankhead Avenue, driveway: Bonnie on left and Susan
              Selman ? on right beside white &amp; blue Plymouth station wagon; front of rearview of
              green Plymouth; Shap in red wild hat or fake hair.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 29. Scene 6. Perdido, AL: Joe? Thetford &amp; Shap &amp; older boy
              &amp; little girl? in water; several children splashing.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 30. Scene 1. Perdido, AL: Small boat with motor: on left boys? &amp;
              back of ? In striped shirt &amp; orange life jacket covering his top; girl? on left;
              sailboat next to other boat; ? with dark hair at front with 2 girls behind her. Motor
              boat pulls sailboat. Briefly at Gulf near Perdido: fairly dark interior of boat. Back
              at Perdido: close-up of Daddy in white shirt holding a fish, Withers Davis, Sr. in
              dark glasses; close-up of Alice Davis in sleeveless white shirt; close-up of Raymond
              Boykin in straw hat.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 30. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue: Phoebe's kittens &amp; Myrick in blue
              striped t shirt holding a kitten; DARK: kittens &amp; close-up of Phoebe.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 30. Scene 3. Montgomery, AL: Von Gal's swimming pool: June von Gal
              in red plaid trunks by fire; pool scene: Bonnie? on raft; close-up of Myrick; Shap
              lying on raft; Bonnie sitting in raft chair. DARK. Mother holding white object in
              front of her; close-up of Daddy.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 31. Scene 1. Mother's trip to New England to attend the 25th reunion
              of her class at Miss Porter's School in Farmington, CT. New England coast: views from
              boat; clam digging by adult male , then adult female in background; young boy carrying
              bucket; scene of pier &amp; boats; adult male in plaid shirt; view of beach &amp;
              water; adult female on beach; boy in red jacket. Mother's notes indicate "lobsters,"
              but DARK.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 32. Scene 1. Mother's trip to New England (cont'd): Farmington, CT:
              friends &amp; classmates of Mother at Miss Porter's School; scenes of town; scenes of
              people; field hockey with current students.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 32. Scene 2. Lynchburg, VA: Randolph-Macon Woman's College (RMWC):
              On her return trip from New England, Mother visited Ginny in her sophomore year at
              college. Views of campus buildings.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 33. Scene 1. Montgomery, AL: Cloverdale School where football game
              between Cloverdale &amp; Floyd Schools took place: Floyd cheerleaders, including Ann;
              scene of game; view of Cloverdale (red bMyrick); Ann is closest to camera in scene
              where can see large "2" on school. </p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 33. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: close-up of Little Ann
              holding Edward as a baby; Ginsie on ground with red plastic bag; then Ann D. in
              short-sleeved yellow shirt; Mollie standing to side &amp; in front of magnolia tree;
              close-up of Shap (blue &amp; brown striped shirt) &amp; Mollie holding "July." </p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 33. Scene 3. Bankhead Avenue, back yard: "July" with Phoebe's
              kittens; laundry basket at back is bed for the kittens; Phoes is large tabby - near
              screen door of back porch. DARK. Concrete slab in back yard: Myrick in red shirt &amp;
              friend - Mark Johnson? playing ball. In background: Bonnie in blue &amp; Gray Thames
              in dark pink.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 34. Scene 1. Destin, FL: AEA vacation: close-up of Shap &amp; then
              Shap fishing; close-up of Daddy wearing hat &amp; red/white/blue plaid shirt. CLARITY
              NOT GOOD. Bonnie on left &amp; female?; male in striped shirt with back to camera;
              Mother in blue sweatshirt &amp; white sailor cap; male in red jacket &amp; female -
              maybe ? &amp; Frances Lamb.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 34. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Bonnie in huge flower hat;
              DARK, &amp; then Bonnie without hat; Shap in navy suit (short pants) holding flowers;
              Ann in turquoise outfit; Myrick to side on bike; Mother in flowered dress holding
              kitten; Myrick riding bike.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 34. Scene 3. Location? Lake ?: various people skiing; Myrick on pink
              raft; more skiing; boat; tree; Tullis ____(dark glasses) sitting next to Daddy; people
              in water; more skiing; Myrick in red plaid trunks on foldable rectangular lounge frame
              at end of pier; people in water.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 34. Scene 4. Bankhead Avenue, front of house: see front door; Shap
              holding present &amp; standing next to Bonnie.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 35. Scene 1. Family trip to Mexico: whole family at ancient ruin
              (pyramid); close-up of surface of ruin; landscape views; roadside views as driving in
              car; University playground?; huge concrete slab; Olympic swimming pool with
              extensions; University buildings; murals on buildings, some close-up.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 36. Scene 2. Family trip to Mexico (cont'd): Mexico City bull ring:
              ceremonial beginning; bullfight - lot is DARK. Driving with landscape views from
              car.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 36. Scene 3. Family trip to Mexico (cont'd): Acapulco: Myrick &amp;
              Shap at edge of water; view of hotel built into rocks beside water; Bonnie (back to
              camera) in water; views of water &amp; area near hotel.</p>
            <p>Reel 3. Sequence 36. Scene 4. Family trip to Mexico (cont'd): Highway: our car got
              stuck, causing traffic to stop &amp; back up; people out of cars; scene with backs of
              Ginny (short dark hair; in blue skirt &amp; blouse) &amp; Ann (orangish top &amp;
              light colored skirt); 2 Mexican males in front of them; white &amp; pale blue station
              wagon (car family traveling in ).</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref9_3i5" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1300 film
                  feet</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1959/1962"
                type="inclusive">1959-1962</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_485855cea1d17502034f3aed8782dd71"
                label="Moving Images [D04655538-]" type="box">1</container>
              <container id="aspace_433cc133ba86ba067c3a24d27accc0c7"
                parent="aspace_485855cea1d17502034f3aed8782dd71" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0003</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref11_d3f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 4, compilation, segments 37-48</unittitle>
            <unitid>4</unitid>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1962/1965"
              type="inclusive">1962-1965</unitdate>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r4sb41z61"
              xlink:role="video-streaming" xlink:show="new"
              xlink:title="Reel 4, compilation, segments 37-48, 1962-1965"
              xpointer="ark:/87924/r4sb41z61"/>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_8f7c20a8e8e38fd0abeeccc4c91dda37">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Original notes on can:</p>
            <p>37: Mexico 1962 - Taxco. Floyd cheerleading - Bonnie, Gray, Marcia Jackson, Julie;
              38: Fall 1962 - Football - Ginnie - Big Ann - Beach; 39: Bankhead - Ann, Edith,
              Priscilla Crommelin - Bloyd track meet. Gulf - Blue and Gray Tennis. Puppies. Von Gal
              pool; 40: Sept. 1963 - "Black Top" - Harmons, Davises, Wallers - Lanier parade -
              Floyd, Bonnie cheerleading. Shap's birthday ('64); 41: Spring 1964 - Floyd baseball -
              Randolph Macon, Ginny - Swim class, Neill; 42: Summer 1964 - July - Romar Beach -
              Stausses - Nan Holley - Backyard w/Bonnie's friends. Perdido - Mark Wilson, G. Harris;
              43: Fall 1964 - Lanier Homecoming Parade - Bonnie and Marcia Jackson. Coosa picking
              turnips - Bankhead cookout; 44: Spring 1965 - Coosa w/Rick, Mark and Bart Wilson.
              Jack's Creek w/Stausses and Big Ann. Gulf; 45: Gulf - Collecting sea oats. Coosa -
              Gulf - Gray T. Shap, Phillip and Eddie. Falls. Judge Thetford cooking; 46: Destin -
              Bankhead - Tennis - Ann - Horses - Shap and Friends; 47: Destin - Rick, John C.
              Trammel and Shap. Frontyard, Dressed Up; 48: Destin w/Stauss Family. Horses on
              Bankhead - Bonnie on Jabe - Frontyard football.</p>
            <p>Additional description:</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 37. Scene 1. Family trip to Mexico (cont'd): Taxco: buildings;
              street scenes; driving in car: views.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 37. Scene 2. Floyd cheerleaders: Gray Thames closest to camera; one
              person between her and Bonnie; close-up of some of audience: Rosalind Weil (?) in navy
              skirt &amp; maybe Ann next to her in white background dress with flowers or fruit;
              cheerleaders again: Bonnie second closest to camera; football being played; close-up
              of Edith Johnston (?), next to person in red &amp; white.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 37. Scene 3. Bankhead Avenue, vacant lot opposite 3516 Bankhead:
              Bonnie (red hair) on right; Marcia Jackson (?) with Gray Thames (blond hair) behind
              her.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 37. Scene 4. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Daddy (good shots) at
              front door; July with him; then Mother holding July, who must be pregnant.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 38. Scene 1. Floyd School sign; cheerleaders with school in
              background: Bonnie closest to camera &amp; Gray Thames closest to black dog;
              cheerleaders leading football team out; football game in action; cheerleaders;
              DARK.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 38. Scene 2. Hull Street, front yard: Ann D. Stauss on Bonnie's
              shoulder; Myrick on left in red shirt; Mollie on right; Bonnie swinging Mollie; Bonnie
              holding Ginsie in red shirt; trunk of car open &amp; ? leaning into it; back of Big
              Ann (gray suit) &amp; Ann on right; Mollie or Ann D. &amp; then Ann coming towards Big
              Ann; Little Ann in trench coat &amp; Uncle Eddie in background; Myrick in blue plaid
              shirt &amp; then with Uncle Eddie; Eddie with Little Ann in trench coat &amp; Mollie
              or Ann D.; then Big Ann next to Little Ann; Ginsie (?) in red knit hat; Ann looking at
              Uncle Eddie &amp; Ann D. (?).</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 38. Scene 3. Destin, FL: On beach, Daddy in chair; Bonnie on stomach
              &amp; Gray Thames on back on sand; Myrick on back on sand; Shap with straw hat at edge
              of water; Shap beating ? with stick; shallow water (Gulf) &amp; sea animal (?); Shap
              -- Bonnie -- Gray -- Myrick; close-up of Bonnie in straw hat; close-ups of Gray
              Thames, Myrick, Shap; views of sand.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 38. Scene 4. ? &amp; Myrick &amp; Joe Thetford (?).</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 39. Scene 1. Bankhead Avenue: Ann in white leaning on fence talking
              to? in plaid shorts with Bonnie to right holding onto ?; ? in plaid shorts standing by
              herself.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 39. Scene 2. Montgomery, AL: Floyd School: track meet: ???? viewing
              track meet; Ann leaning on fence and others (?); close-up of blonde (?) next to Ann in
              long-sleeved white shirt; Debbie Moorer &amp; Gray Thames with mouth open &amp; ?;
              close-up of Debbie next to Gray (faces only); Gray next to Daddy coming towards
              camera; then see Debbie behind Gray; maybe Debbie running &amp; long jump. </p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 39. Scene 3. Bankhead Avenue: Edith Johnston holding puppy; Ann's
              head; head down (white with red trim dress; then Priscilla Crommelin holding puppy
              &amp; Ann (orange shorts); then Edith Johnston in white blouse looking down; Priscilla
              (in yellow) holding 2 puppies &amp; Edith holding 2 puppies next to ? in white dress
              with red trim holding puppy; then Priscilla holding 2 puppies; ? in green blouse
              holding puppy; group scene holding puppies. </p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 39. Scene 4. Location ?: ? In Gulf, then 4 boys; ? -- Myrick -- Mike
              Harmon; Mike putting on t shirt; Myrick in plaid trunks.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 39. Scene 5. Montgomery Country Club: Blue Gray Tennis Tournament,
              but can't distinguish people.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 39. Scene 6. Bankhead Avenue: July's puppies; then with people;
              Bonnie (?) in blue shorts.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 39. Scene 7. Von Gal's swimming pool: Bonnie on raft; Ann with hands
              against each other; Myrick by side of pool; ? in pool; Suzy von Gal in white walking
              beside pool; Daddy in red socks walking beside pool; people in water: Myrick holding
              blue raft; Pat Thetford (?) getting out of pool &amp; Ann (?) in water; Bonnie leaning
              on blue raft; Annin bathing suit with black design &amp; white on bottom walking on
              side of pool.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 40. Scene 1. Destin, FL (?): Chris Craft boat; piers &amp; boats; on
              boat: Withers Davis &amp; Barry Harmon, Sr., each in dark glasses; Daddy, smoking,
              next to ? &amp; Betty Harmon, &amp; then Alice Davis talking to Withers; close-up of ?
              In white sleeveless shirt with Betty Harmon on her right &amp; ? (male); back of Daddy
              who is walking along side of boat &amp; ? in blue shirt &amp; Barry Harmon coming
              towards camera.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 40. Scene 2. Montgomery, AL, downtown: Sidney Lanier High School
              parade.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 40. Scene 3. Montgomery, AL: Floyd School: cheerleaders with Bonnie
              closest to camera; football being played; audience scenes.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 40. Scene 4. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Myrick, dressed-up wearing
              tie &amp; red blazer; Ann, dressed up &amp; holding purse &amp; Bonnie (behind Ann)
              dressed up &amp; has bouffant hair-do; Ann in vest with designs &amp; black skirt;
              Shap in navy blazer &amp; Myrick again; Daddy in grayish suit &amp; dark shirt.
              Schatzi (wirehead dachshund) in all of these scenes. Bankhead Avenue: Big Ann in short
              fur cape getting out of her car parked in front of house; greets Schatzi; Myrick &amp;
              Big Ann in driveway in front of a car;?? Car out on street: Myrick, Shap, Big Ann, Ann
              &amp; Bonnie.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 40. Scene 5. Bankhead Avenue, back yard: Shap and friends playing
              basketball -- ?? May be Shap's birthday.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 41. Scene 1. Montgomery, AL: Floyd School: girls playing
              softball.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 41. Scene 2. Lynchburg, VA: Randolph-Macon Woman's College (RMWC):
              Ginny's graduation: procession in gowns; procession of girls in white, called "daisy
              chain;" Rosie Pittman followed by Ginny (white headband) followed by Pat Nunnelley.
              Scene with Daddy (blue/gray suit), Shap (white jacket), with Big Ann behind him, then
              Ginny &amp; Pat Nunnelley; dark scenes; then Shap, Bonnie (blue jacket), Mother (white
              hat), &amp; Ginny; then see Ann behind Shap; scene with Bonnie, Big Ann (white skirt)
              &amp; Ginny; really dark stretch.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 41. Scene 3. Montgomery, AL, Thomas Avenue: Neill's pool with lots
              of kids ???</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 42. Scene 1. Romar Beach, AL (near Gulf Shores): Nan Holley (?) in
              2-piece bathing suit; Little Ann on beach &amp; Edward; Nan Holley in 2-piece suit on
              back on sand; Daddy in shorts &amp; shirt walking on beach to Little Ann &amp; Edward;
              Ann in red suit &amp; wrapped in black &amp; white striped towel, next to Nan Holley;
              Myrick &amp; ? in water with close-up of both; Ginsie (?) &amp; Uncle Eddie coming out
              of water; Ann in 2-piece red bathing suit walking into water. </p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 42. Scene 1. Romar Beach, AL (cont'd): Ginsie holding a fish with
              inner tube &amp; standing in the water; Daddy in trunks with towel on shoulders &amp;
              golf cap on, standing at the edge of the water; mother in dark swim suit on right,
              Little Ann in swim suit &amp; big hat &amp; Edward; Ann &amp; another standing in
              water; Myrick's friend on all 4's on sand with Little Ann &amp; others in background;
              Ginsie in inner tube in water; Myrick &amp; friend, etc. playing on sand -- close-up
              of Myrick and friend.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 42. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue: ? in dark glasses, Mother, Bonnie
              (horizontal striped top) &amp; ?; then on Bonnie's right, Susan Selman &amp; ? In dark
              glasses, Sydney Smith on Bonnie's left, then Mother &amp; Shap; Ann holding puppy with
              Sydney on her right &amp; Shap on her left; group: person holding dark glasses, Susan
              Selman, Sydney Smith, Ann, Bonnie.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 42. Scene 3. Perdido, AL: skiing at the Point; on boat: George
              Harris (no shirt), Bonnie, Ginny &amp; Ann climbing in; Ann sitting (can see her feet)
              &amp; Ginny on right; Myrick getting off ski; water scenes including skiing; boat: ?,
              Ann &amp; Bonnie; close-up of Bonnie (black thin straps to bathing suit); Myrick &amp;
              Ginny beside boat &amp; ? on boat. Note: could not identify Mark Wilson, who is listed
              as being in film.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 43. Scene 1. Montgomery, AL: downtown: Sidney Lanier High School
              Homecoming Parade -- Marshall Lumber Mill Co. truck --quite DARK.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 43. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue, front: Bonnie (?) on red bicycle;
              sidewalk to house: Bonnie (brown suit) &amp; Marcia Jackson (plaid coat), then at
              front door.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 43. Scene 3. Coosa, AL: Bottom: picking turnips --Myrick &amp; Shap
              &amp; friends; see Daddy in red plaid shirt; close-up of Myrick; scenes of friends of
              Myrick or Shap -- Julian Hart in bluejean shorts &amp; reddish shirt; loading car;
              Daddy talking with John A. Dunlap; close-up of Shap (in Camp Laney t-shirt) holding a
              turnip; Myrick &amp; ? holding box of turnips; red shirted friend leaning over
              Randolph Candler (?); car scene: Mother in yellowish top &amp; friend ? Henry Seawell?
              in striped shirt; fair amount of DARK.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 43. Scene 4. Bankhead Avenue, back yard: Daddy (blue/red plaid
              shirt) cooking in back yard; flowers &amp; plants in yard.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 44. Scene 1. Location?: 2 females.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 44. Scene 2. Coosa, AL: Myrick, Mark &amp; Bart Wilson ? sitting on
              white car -- white t-shirt &amp; blue jeans; front of house: Myrick's friends &amp;
              Daddy in hat; Myrick's friends eating; close-up of Shap? In blue jacket; Jack's Creek:
              Big Ann (gray hair); Uncle Eddie carrying 2 cokes; then Daddy &amp; Uncle Eddie;
              Little Ann &amp; Myrick; Jack's Creek area: Daddy, Uncle Eddie, etc.; shot of Mollie
              (pig tails) &amp; Ginsie; then Myrick sitting &amp; Ann D. next to Uncle Eddie; Big
              Ann standing -- her back to Daddy's back; Edward sitting &amp; pointing -- plate of
              food in front of him; several shots of Stausses; Ginsie (white shirt) kneeling next to
              food plate; some dark scenes; more of Stausses -- Ginsie &amp; Edward sitting on edge
              of rock.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 44. Scene 3. Location ?: Gulf (where exactly).</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 45. Scene 1. Location ?: Gulf (where exactly): ??, then see Ann on
              right holding white towel; on left: Daddy in trunks; dark but close-up of Myrick
              eating ice cream on stick; picking sea oats: Shap on left, Ann (design shorts &amp;
              blue top).</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 45. Scene 2. Coosa, AL: house -- ? on steps; DARK. </p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 45. Scene 3. Gulf (exactly where): Bonnie on low chair, Gray Thames
              (blue/green/white bathing suit) standing; Myrick &amp; Shap snorkeling; Bonnie
              standing; Shap coming out of water with snorkel; Shap holding arm out &amp; friend in
              red/white trunks.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 45. Scene 4. Bankhead Avenue, front porch: ? &amp; ? with school
              books &amp; then standing in front; Shap (plaid pants) &amp; John Springer ? &amp;
              Eddie Mosely? </p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 45. Scene 5. Coosa, AL: The Falls: Sitting on rock near the falls:
              Alice &amp; Withers Davis &amp; behind them Daddy &amp; Mother; ? standing; falls;
              group: Daddy (in glasses) &amp; ????</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 45. Scene 6. Bankhead Avenue, 2 doors down: Thetford home -- Judge
              Thetford cooking stew -- not good shot of him; Daddy in tie.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 45. Scene 7. Bankhead Avenue: back yard: red tile table -- Bonnie on
              right &amp; Myrick on left; Daddy with back wall in background; side yard: Mother by
              banana plant.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 46. Scene 1. Destin, FL: Gulf: Shap in dark glasses &amp; Bonnie
              lying on back; Gulf sand &amp; water scenes; ? in black bathing suit &amp; Ann on
              right; more water &amp; sand; Shap "acting up" &amp; then playing with ? in black
              bathing suit; Ann with towel around her.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 46. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Shap (plaid blazer) &amp;
              Ann &amp; Bonnie (blue dress) &amp; Daddy &amp; Myrick (white blazer); Mother at left
              of screen.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 46. Scene 3. Montgomery Country Club, tennis courts: Ann might be on
              closest court, where doubles match is being played.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 46. Scene 4. Location?: Horses.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 46. Scene 5. Bankhead Avenue, driveway: Mother beside truck &amp;
              Daddy beside her at back of truck; Myrick &amp;/or Shap &amp; friends???; Mother
              beside driver ? Daddy?; DARK.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 46. Scene 6. Gulf? In red, white, blue hat. </p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 47. Scene 1. Destin, FL: Gulf -- Jack Tar Motel: Myrick &amp; friend
              on beach; friend of Shap's flying kite on beach; Myrick's friend flying kite; Daddy
              &amp; Ginny (red bathing suit); Shap &amp; friend on sand.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 47. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue, back yard: flowers in bloom; Daddy,
              Bonnie, Shap, Myrick; Daddy &amp; Mother; Shap &amp; Bonnie; driveway: Bonnie ? riding
              bike to street; DARK stretch; chairs in driveway/carport; Joe or Pat Thetford playing
              with hunting dog; Shap playing ping pong; Myrick &amp; friends getting into car.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 47. Scene 3. Hull Street: Little Ann (blue denim dress) walking to
              car; Uncle Eddie at back of car, unloading; Daddy, Mollie or Ann D. hugging Big
              Ann.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 48. Scene 1. Destin, FL: Bonnie &amp; Shap beside car; Myrick
              (trunks with white waisteband); Daddy (blue/yellow/white, etc. shirt); Uncle Eddie
              walks towards car with cooler &amp; small suitcase; Edward on steps; Little Ann
              (white/gray/yellow dress) with back to camera; Daddy facing camera; back of Shap? in
              foreground; side of Bonnie's red hair (Bonnie in long t-shirt with 25 on back)???;
              Mother sitting on steps with camera case in lap.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 48. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue, front yard: Myrick &amp; horse; Bonnie
              with ? on horse; others walking around; Bonnie riding on lot across the street -- can
              see 3516 house in background; Bonnie, etc. playing touch football in lot across
              street; Myrick &amp;/or Shap's friends -- riding bikes on Bankhead; front yard: Mr.
              &amp; Mrs Hart. </p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 48. Scene 3. Location?: parking lot of ? Holiday Inn?; Margie
              Livingstone on left &amp; ? on right; ???parents of friend of Ann's; Mother in beige
              coat with purse on arm; Margie &amp; Ann.</p>
            <p>Reel 4. Sequence 48. Scene 4. Location?: Pat Thetford "acting up" with Myrick behind
              him.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref12_oso" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1300 film
                  feet</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1962/1965"
                type="inclusive">1962-1965</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_b1832e35f949b96232a3f1cef9cfff04"
                label="Moving Images [D04655538-]" type="box">1</container>
              <container id="aspace_67b844ce830e99c3f2135907142a6b36"
                parent="aspace_b1832e35f949b96232a3f1cef9cfff04" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0004</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref14_mhs" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 5, compilation, segments 49-58</unittitle>
            <unitid>5</unitid>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1960/1969"
              type="inclusive">1960s</unitdate>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r4pc2z88v"
              xlink:role="video-streaming" xlink:show="new"
              xlink:title="Reel 5, compilation, segments 49-58, 1960s"
              xpointer="ark:/87924/r4pc2z88v"/>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_b858d3b10540906cf01d6a2726b838bc">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Original notes on can: 49: Ann's graduation - Mary Baldwin College. Big Ann in
              swimsuit. Perdido; 50: Perdido - Big Ann diving at Point. Mother and Dad sailing.
              Coosa - frozen falls. Bull Fight - Spain. Coose w/Stausses at Spout; 51: Shap and
              Friends. Bonnie's graduation at Converse. Bankhead. Perdido; 52: Coosa House - dark.
              Washington and Lee - Rick's graduation. John A. at Coosa - Bonnie and Mike at Coosa;
              53: Southwest - S. New Mexico and California w/Darnelles Horse Races; 54: Shap's
              graduation at Duke. Shape and Exie; 55: Darnelles - Surfers in California. Bag Piper
              at Ross Clan Reunion; 56: Ann w/Patrick and Exie. Bonnie, Mike, Don and Ginny. Pond at
              Coosa w/Baby Patrick. Big Ann, Exie, Irma - Easter and egg hunt w/Dow. Mike, Bonnie,
              Dow and Ashley on boat; 57: Bonnie, Mike and Family at flower gardens. Mobile Bay.
              Cuernevaca, Mexico; 58: Cuernevaca, Mexico. Bankhead - Ginny, K.C. and Harris
              Family.</p>
            <p>Additional description: Reel 5. Sequence 49. Scene 1. Staunton, VA: Ann's graduation
              from Mary Baldwin: outdoor setting for the graduation ceremony. Procession of students
              across the stage &amp; followed by faculty; Ann crossing to receive diploma &amp;
              others receiving diplomas; close-ups of some, Ann holding hat on &amp; people mingling
              after ceremony.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 49. Scene 2. Location ?: Gulf (exactly where?): Big Ann (back to
              camera) in swim suit in water; facial view; close-up of fiddler crab &amp; close-up of
              scallop shell; boat &amp; then dog (German shepard variety) on beach; beach house with
              Big Ann (bathing cap) &amp; Ann ? coming down steps; front of beach house: Ann on
              left, Big Ann, ? male?</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 50. Scene 1. Perdido, AL: at the Point: Big Ann on pier &amp; then
              diving off diving board; sailboat with Mother &amp; Daddy; ?female? Standing on beach
              with same dog as on reel #49; males on beach; close-up of Daddy leaning against pole
              &amp; holding paper cup; beach prop-up: Daddy sitting on left with several female
              friends: Bonnie on his right &amp; Ann sitting on sand in front but back to
              camera.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 50. Scene 2. Coosa, AL: Daddy (?); close-up of ice in creek below
              falls &amp; then falls with ice.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 50. Scene 3. Spain: bullfight; lot of BLANK.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 50. Scene 4. Coosa, AL: Ginsie; Edward; at the Spout: Bonnie, Little
              Ann (striped pants), Uncle Eddie; Ginsie &amp; Edward in foreground with Big Ann on
              left with back to camera &amp; Uncle Eddie leaning to left; Little Ann sitting down;
              Big Ann on right with Bonnie to her right &amp; Daddy holding cup to her right;
              close-up of Little Ann in glasses &amp; holding cup; Uncle Eddie standing. Those
              listed eating lunch.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 50. Scene 5. Location? Someone's yard: person in chair may be Algie
              Neill</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 51. Scene 1. Location? Shap on left with friends on right; Julian
              Hart may be one in striped shirt.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 51. Scene 2. Spartanburg, SC: Bonnie's graduation from Converse
              College: Daddy in white on left &amp; Bonnie on his right with their backs to camera;
              Bonnie (lovely red hair in these shots) in graduation gown; Bonnie on left &amp;
              friend on right &amp; then Mother in white on right; ? in green/blue dress &amp; then
              Bonnie on her right; Converse buildings &amp; fountain; other people; Bonnie on left
              &amp; Daddy to her right.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 51. Scene 3. Bankhead Avenue, driveway: Backs to camera: Myrick to
              left &amp; Daddy on right with Shap behind him &amp; Exie on right; close-up of Myrick
              with mustache; Shap (brown pants) on left &amp; Exie on right &amp; then Myrick on
              right; Daddy with tie &amp; then to left, Myrick &amp; Shap.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 52. Scene 1. Coosa, AL: house -- DARK -- trees, etc. near house with
              some of trees not in darkness -- lot of darkness.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 52. Scene 2. Lexington, VA: Myrick's graduation from Washington
              &amp; Lee (W &amp; L): Myrick on lawn with crowd of people in background;
              people/building scene; ? in black tie &amp; spectacles on left; Myrick with mustache
              in red plaid coat; youth in gown &amp; tie &amp; ? on right; female (?) &amp; male in
              black tie again; youth in front; then some of Myrick's friends; to far left, Mother
              &amp; Ann; people sitting outside for ceremony; graduation procession: scene of
              graduating seniors; Myrick receiving diploma -- shakes hand of person giving it &amp;
              then walks off.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 52. Scene 3. Coosa, AL: John A. Dunlap on tractor -- maybe Myrick's
              head in foreground; behind house (John A.'s?) --John A. on tractor &amp; Myrick beside
              it; Tootsie leaning out car window; flowering tree &amp; bird's nest in tree; Coosa
              woods: backs of Mike &amp; Bonnie, Bonnie with bucket &amp; then Mike; Myrick (?) with
              backpack.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 53. Scene . California: Mother's trip to visit the Darnelles:
              highway scenes; rocky landscape scenes; station wagon on highway; Darnelles' (?)
              house: street scene with palm trees; rocky landscape scenes; station wagon on highway;
              ? House with red flowering ?; Darnelles' (?) dog; female &amp; male in parking lot;
              newspaper vendors -- maybe outside horse racing stadium; horse racing scenes.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 54. Scene 1. Durham, NC: Shap's graduation from Duke University;
              front of Chapel -- think see Ann &amp; Ginny in light colored dresses; Chapel; Shap
              (with glasses) in graduation gown with Ann on right &amp; Ginny (with glasses) on
              left; crowd of people -- Page Auditorium; Terry Sanford in academic robe -- Shap,
              Ginny, Ann (backs) on right &amp; then 3 turn around; Sanford; front of Chapel
              entrance -- ? shakes Sanford's hand &amp; they talk &amp; then someone puts medal with
              chain around his neck; procession of students to Chapel; Shap minus gown with Ann
              &amp; Ginny walking towards library -- crosswalk behind bus stop; football stadium
              (Wallace Wade Stadium) where graduation ceremony takes place. </p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 54. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue: Shap &amp; Exie.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 55. Scene 1. California trip (cont'd): surfers; male carrying red
              raft; female in green sitting on beach; surfing; 3 people on beach: male, female in
              pink/red suit &amp; male in rubber suit.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 55. Scene 2. Wetumpka, AL: Ross Clan reunion: bagpipes; tractor
              pulling trailer with hay &amp; kids on top; people walking -- think Bonnie (red hair);
              bagpipes again; people walking into woods; lots of darkness -- maybe in woods; outside
              of house (Crommelins?); lots of people.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 56. Scene 1. Birmingham, AL (?): Ann holding Patrick with Exie &amp;
              perhaps Ann's nurse behind; Exie with Ann &amp; Patrick &amp; nurse (?) to right;
              nurse (?) holding Patrick; Exie holding Patrick.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 56. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue: Bonnie holding Dow, &amp; Mike; Ginny
              on right of Bonnie &amp; Dow; Dow trying to walk.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 56. Scene 3. Coosa, AL: perhaps at pond on Ann's property: Ginny
              with Ann holding Patrick; Donald into scene from right.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 56. Scene 4. Bankhead Avenue: Exie taking Dow from Big Ann &amp;
              holding him; Irma behind Big Ann; Bonnie into scene; Exie holding Dow's hand as he
              walks; Bonnie (brown ?), Irma, Dow, Exie &amp; Big Ann.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 56. Scene 5. Location? Easter egg hunt: Dow holding egg; ? &amp;
              young girl in lacy white dress; Dow &amp; ?; Mike holding Ashley.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 56. Scene 6. Location? On boat: Mike with Dow behind &amp; Bonnie
              holding Ashley.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 57. Scene 1. Mobile, AL: Bellingrath gardens: Mike, Bonnie, Ashley
              &amp; Dow.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 57. Scene 2. Location?: Beach (?): Ashley with bucket on beach,
              Bonnie on right &amp; ? standing; another baby on left -- Ashley to right -- Dow
              coming out of water; Ashley on right &amp; ?baby on left; Mike in sunglasses in water
              with Dow; Ann in multi-colored suit holding Patrick (?); Ginny? in red, white, blue
              striped cover-up; Ann &amp; Patrick; Dow in front of Mike?; Bonnie with Ashley; back
              of Shap. Pier; close-up of Dow; Shap walking in water &amp; on right Ann holding
              Patrick; Bonnie holding Ashley on beach; close-up of Ginny's profile; Bonnie carrying
              Ashley. </p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 57. Scene 3. Cuernavac, Mexico: Bonnie, Ashley, Ann to right in
              pinkish skirt &amp; blouse; homes? In Cuernavaca; Bonnie (white dress), Ann in pinkish
              dress, Patrick?, Dow? On left &amp; Patrick? On right.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 58. Scene 1. Cuernavaca, Mexico: small pool; close-up of Shap?,
              Patrick? &amp; Ann on right; Shap in water &amp; Bonnie holding Ashley in water; shots
              of various in water; Mike? in chair beside pool; more shots of most in water; scene
              with Shap (green shirt) in chair by pool &amp; Bonnie beside Dow as he swims. Market
              scene; street scene with cars; marketplace; pool scene with no one there.</p>
            <p>Reel 5. Sequence 58. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue: Bonnie, Dow holding red umbrella,
              Ashley in dress with Bonnie behind her; Dow &amp; Ashley; Casey, Ginny, Bonnie, Mike
              in front of banana plant with Dow in front; Ashley.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref15_c5e" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1100 film
                  feet</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1960/1969"
                type="inclusive">1960s</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_8dbfa91e8b2cc3741f4482a15ed8faff"
                label="Moving Images [D04655538-]" type="box">1</container>
              <container id="aspace_cdc6158921dd1528f06918f95f717294"
                parent="aspace_8dbfa91e8b2cc3741f4482a15ed8faff" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0005</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref17_a2u" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 6, compilation, segments 59-62</unittitle>
            <unitid>6</unitid>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1939/1939"
              type="inclusive">1939</unitdate>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1967" type="inclusive">1967</unitdate>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r47944t9m"
              xlink:role="video-streaming" xlink:show="new"
              xlink:title="Reel 6, compilation, segments 59-62, 1939, 1967"
              xpointer="ark:/87924/r47944t9m"/>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_0a2c869e56bc2bb2c7c44b6488657e5a">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Original notes on can: 59: 1967 - AEA - Henry Seawell - Destin. Stausses at Bankhead.
              Destin w/Quisenberrys. Coosa - Exie and Shap; 60: Old Montgomery - Mule wagon -
              Baptism 1939 - Shorter, Alabama; 61: Kodak shorts; 62: Inaugural Parade - Montgomery -
              Governor Patterson (?)</p>
            <p>Additional description: Reel 6. Sequence 59. Scene 1. Destin, FL (?): Henry Seawell
              (red hair) &amp; Myrick standing; Myrick - flip; motel?; Myrick &amp; Henry in car
              &amp; then they walk from hotel; Daddy (plaid jacket) loading plymoth station wagon;
              beach -- Henry on left &amp; Myrick on right.</p>
            <p>Reel 6. Sequence 59. Scene 2. Bankhead Avenue: Stausses: Edward with red band around
              waist &amp; then Little Ann (beige sweater) in background; Ginsie with Edward;
              dachshund, "Peanut" (Stausses' dog) with Little Ann in background; Mollie in yellow,
              holding cat, probably Phoebe (Ashley's cat); Little Ann with Ann D. (blue sweater),
              partially hidden; driveway with Stausses' blue station wagon; Uncle Eddie &amp; Daddy;
              Bonnie (in white) on right &amp; then Ann D. to her right with Little Ann coming into
              scene, then with Edward &amp; Ginsie kneeling and eventually Mollie on right; "July,"
              Ashleys' chihuahua &amp; "Peanut," Stausses' dachshund; Edward, then Ann D., then
              Bonnie with Ginsie on shoulders &amp; Mollie in green sweater.</p>
            <p>Reel 6. Sequence 59. Scene 3. Destin, FL: Beach with Big Ann in swimsuit and towel on
              head, walking up steps; ? (male) Quisenberry with raft on head and then with female,
              maybe his wife,?, joined by Daddy on right; ? female sitting on sand with ?male
              Quisenberry on right &amp; then ? (female) Quisenberry &amp; Daddy; Bonnie lying on
              raft on stand &amp; ? in water.</p>
            <p>Reel 6. Sequence 59. Scene 4. Location?: Mother in chair</p>
            <p>Reel 6. Sequence 59. Scene 5. Coosa, AL: ? male friend of Shap or Myrick; Myrick in
              blue shirt; friends of Myrick &amp; Shap eating.</p>
            <p>Reel 6. Sequence 59. Scene 6. Bankhead Avenue: Driveway with Myrick; Exie &amp; Shap
              with banana plant on left; Myrick holding bird, then Pat Thetford on left with Ann or
              Bonnie ? &amp; Myrick.</p>
            <p>Reel 6. Sequence 60. Scene 1. Montgomery, AL: Street scenes in the vicinity of Perry
              Street: mule wagons, people walking &amp; near end of scene, a bicyclist (some DARK
              areas).</p>
            <p>Reel 6. Sequence 60. Scene 2. Shorter, AL: Black baptism with viewers on hillside and
              baptism in pond at bottom of hill.</p>
            <p>Reel 6. Sequence 61. Scene 1. Kodak shorts (commercial films): The Early Bird &amp;
              the Worm; Algiers; Felix in Hollywood; Charlie Chaplin in Easy Street; Wild Puppies;
              Rin Tin Tin in the High Country.</p>
            <p>Reel 6. Sequence 62. Scene 1. Montgomery, AL: Inaugural parade: Governor Patterson
              (?): downtown, at some point Dexter Avenue towards capitol with ceremony in front of
              capitol (very DARK in many places).</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref18_c1w" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">375 film
                  feet</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1939/1939"
                type="inclusive">1939</unitdate>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1967" type="inclusive">1967</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_c668b1e442bdda9de89fb3177e72a8d8"
                label="Moving Images [D04655538-]" type="box">1</container>
              <container id="aspace_3107deaa7881f3772888babaa1111cec"
                parent="aspace_c668b1e442bdda9de89fb3177e72a8d8" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0006</container>
            </did>
            <odd id="aspace_40765cc2dbeda29941e529cbc87a745d">
              <head>Preservation</head>
              <p>Sent to AV Geeks for Flashtransfer digitization on May 22, 2014. Returned from AV
                Geeks with raw video MOV and MP4 MOV, June 13, 2014. - Craig Breaden</p>
              <p>MD5: b5d5377765010a8a855709871cf44d60</p>
            </odd>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref20_sdr" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 7</unittitle>
            <unitid>7</unitid>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1950/1951"
              type="inclusive">1950-1951</unitdate>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r4gt5kg0w"
              xlink:role="video-streaming" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Reel 7, 1950-1951"
              xpointer="ark:/87924/r4gt5kg0w"/>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_1aa8258a0ac6fc79171ad7c9c80da1a0">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Original notes on can: 1950-51 - Gulf - Thetfords and Chandlers; Mother catching
              fish; Hull Street - Ginny, Ann Bonnie playing, Rick at 4 weeks; Easter Egg Hunt -
              Perdido - Dot and Billy fishing. Exie holding Rick in basket; Bonnie on sled, Perdido;
              Girl's camp (Talahi) Bonnie, Ann and Rick at Mary Esther; Ginny swimming. Thanksgiving
              Parade.</p>
            <p>Additional description: Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 1. Mary Esther, FL: Walking across
              Santa Rosa Island to the Gulf: Thetford, Candler, &amp; Ashley families. Gulf: in
              water -- Dot Thetford with Bill in background; Ginny in white front &amp; blue back
              swim suit; Louise Candler: arms? stretched out &amp; Randy walking in water in back;
              Daddy &amp; others in water; Ginny swimming; group in water.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 2. Destin, FL: scene of fishing boats at docks; Daddy in
              blue shirt; Mother sitting on top of boat reeling in a fish; skipper helped out when
              fish to boat; pier after fishing trip: Daddy holding fish caught.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 3. Mary Esther, FL: Ginny on diving board -- dives in
              &amp; swims; Ann in red inner tube &amp; Ginny in water; Daddy, etc. on beach.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 4. Montgomery Country Club: swim meet.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 5. Hull Street, back yard: DARK. Bonnie on left &amp; Ann
              on right eating at small table; Ann on swing; Bonnie (blue dress) walking; Ginny &amp;
              ? throwing ball.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 6. Hull Street, front yard: Bonnie in snowsuit, Ginny
              (yellow scarf) behind &amp; Ann in blue with red trim jacket; some DARK.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 7. Hull Street: Mother in chair holding Myrick; weather
              warmer than in previous scene.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 8. Hull Street, front &amp; back yards: Bonnie in white
              dress on white chair; Ann in yellow dress brings chair (striped canvas). Lots of
              grown-ups &amp; children: birthday party (Ann &amp; Bonnie's) egg hunt; table with
              birthday cake -- Ann &amp; Bonnie.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 9. Hull Street: Daddy holding Myrick.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 10. Location? Daddy dealing with bait in small boat; Anne
              &amp; Frank Harris &amp; Daddy on land adjacent to pier; Dot &amp; Billy Thetford in
              boat fishing; in another boat, Daddy at motor with Anne &amp; Frank Harris in
              boat.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 11. Hull Street, front yard: Big Ann (hat &amp; gloves)
              &amp; Exie holding clothes basket with Myrick in it; Bonnie with book in hands &amp;
              Ann; Myrick in clothes basket.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 12. Hull Street, front yard: Bonnie on sled using hose to
              wash feet.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 13. Perdido, AL?: group in water; water skiing scene.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 14. Oak Mountain State Park, AL: Camp Talahi (Girl Scout
              Camp): Visitors' day -- Margaret Harris kneeling; Ann, 3 girls (2 in Brownie uniforms)
              - plaid shirt: Kitty Poyntz?, green cap: Medora Powell, Charlotte Poyntz?; Ginny
              (tongue out); Bonnie; Ann (blue top); scene at waterfront.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 15. Hull Street, front yard: Easter?: Ginny, Ann, &amp;
              Bonnie dressed for Sunday School.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 16. Mary Esther, FL: Bonnie in straw hat &amp; orange life
              preserver; rest of family in small boat with attached motor: Daddy by motor, Ann in
              orange life preserver, Margaret Harris in blue &amp; pink cap, Ginny in red cap, Wiley
              Ashley, Jr. Later: Daddy with Myrick as baby on inner tube &amp; Ann to left, Bonnie
              with yellow/red/blue inflatable horse; Ann swimming; Wiley diving off diving board;
              Mother holding Myrick with Ann beside in water; Ann jumping off pier; Mother holding
              Bonnie's &amp; Ann's hands in shallow water beside pier; Ann swimming; Mother in green
              bathing suit on pier; Ann &amp; Bonnie on pier &amp; then with Daddy; Ginny on diving
              board - dives in &amp; swims - close-up of Ginny in red bathing suit; Ann swimming;
              Daddy in motor boat.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 17. Mary Esther, FL: Gulf: Daddy on beach next to Bonnie
              in inner tube; view of the Gulf.</p>
            <p>Reel 7. Sequence 63. Scene 18. Montgomery, AL: downtown: Thanksgiving Day parade
              (annual parade prior to Alabama State University vs. Tuskegee University - both
              historically Black institutions - football game) along Dexter Avenue: floats, marching
              band; majorettes; young girls as majorettes; classes of school children in uniforms;
              float with label: Races United for Defense.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref21_xdw" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">400 film
                  feet</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1950/1951"
                type="inclusive">1950-1951</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_511ddf69f724c1cd3936a5fd3106d317"
                label="Moving Images [D04655541U]" type="freezer">Smith</container>
              <container id="aspace_0d58cf057557714bbd61fdd60cf1276c"
                parent="aspace_511ddf69f724c1cd3936a5fd3106d317" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0007</container>
            </did>
            <odd id="aspace_cc257df6c32e2d9d0954bd65569a3b6f">
              <head>Preservation</head>
              <p>Sent to AV Geeks for Flashtransfer digitization on May 22, 2014. Returned from AV
                Geeks with raw video MOV and MP4 MOV, June 13, 2014. - Craig Breaden</p>
              <p>MD5: 92da81fe9a9326132a8d3cfcba7e66b8</p>
            </odd>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_5de96aaf122f1e919cecced481c2e6db" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 8</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1936" type="inclusive">1936</unitdate>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r4ft8jj9j"
              xlink:role="video-streaming" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Reel 8, 1936"
              xpointer="ark:/87924/r4ft8jj9j"/>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_3cd4de04e4f50bbd9f6a613c23e82cc7">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Europe 1936 color.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_4c0a275f9e074ec3899426d2a4b7a0ce" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1936" type="inclusive">1936</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_66116e0d84cefd3d97cb6f0ae14c66c4" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">2</container>
              <container id="aspace_6e05fa5598d6f2dbd641a3ba4e7e502d"
                parent="aspace_66116e0d84cefd3d97cb6f0ae14c66c4" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0014</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref26_ui3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 9</unittitle>
            <unitid>9</unitid>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1937/1938"
              type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r4dv1hn8c"
              xlink:role="video-streaming" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Reel 9, 1937-1938"
              xpointer="ark:/87924/r4dv1hn8c"/>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_ec9cc29c9018dfb44c52ac2f1a9e34dc">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Original notes on can: Riomar Club, Florida, winter 1937; Pelham, 1938; Mary Esther,
              Fall 1938, Montgomery</p>
            <p>Additional description: Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 1. Winter Haven, FL: Cypress
              Gardens: foliage; backs of Big Ann &amp; grandfather, who turn &amp; walk towards
              camera; bell tower; more foliage; backs of Big Ann &amp; grandfather at bottom of bell
              tower or some monument; skinny male ?Uncle Phil Branson? walks up to our grandfather;
              grandfather in white cap in position to hit golf ball -- hits it &amp; hits another; ?
              hitting golf ball; Uncle Phil (long legs) hitting golf ball &amp; then grandfather
              hitting.</p>
            <p>Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 2. Vero Beach, FL: Riomar Club -- beach: 4 men, 1st being
              our grandfather; in bathing suits with water in background; 2 of men &amp; 3 women
              lounging on beach; men &amp; women throwing ball on beach; 4 men standing/drinking in
              wooden structure; grandfather in white hat; close-ups of grandfather &amp; couple of
              others.</p>
            <p>Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 3. Pelham, NY: mother on left &amp; Little Ann on right;
              they walk in front of blooming bush/tree &amp; walk around more; close-up of Little
              Ann in front of ? DARK; playing badminton; mother? in blue shorts; view of yard with
              blooming trees.</p>
            <p>Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 4. Pelham, NY: snow scene of Monterey Avenue yard; see
              Little Ann &amp; Mother on &amp; near street.</p>
            <p>Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 5. Pelham, NY: no snow: Little Ann in blue shirt on left
              &amp; friend on right; 2 women dressed alike in pinkish skirts &amp; black blouses;
              little girl in black coat; close-up of little boy making a face; close-up of 1 of
              women, perhaps Little Ann; little girl; flower bushes in background.</p>
            <p>Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 6. Pelham, NY: convertible; little boy in car -- 1 or both
              of women in previous scene get into car; little girl also in car; adult female,
              perhaps Big Ann, with hand shading face sitting in chair in yard; back of adult male
              who plays badminton with another adult male;men walking &amp; then 1 sitting on ground
              &amp; drinking out of 2 glasses.</p>
            <p>Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 7. Destin, FL: bridge spanning large body of water; boat
              docks at one end of bridge; views of sand &amp; ocean; someone in white, perhaps
              Mother, walking at water's edge.</p>
            <p>Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 8. Mary Esther, FL: 2 adults on pier; shore &amp; large
              white building; house behind trees may be Aunt Mamie &amp; Uncle Phil Branson's; views
              of water &amp; shore; few people visible.</p>
            <p>Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 9. Montgomery, AL: downtown: celebration at Capitol where
              people on steps.</p>
            <p>Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 10. Montgomery, AL: Perry Street: back of convertible; man
              in white apron walks towards camera; porch of Perry Street apartment building: DARK: ?
              Walks towards camera; see women carrying loads on heads &amp; walking down street.</p>
            <p>Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 11. Location? Little Ann in bridesmaid's dress in front of
              white building; Little Ann walking around. </p>
            <p>Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 12. Montgomery, AL, near downtown: horse pulling wagon
              down street; close-up of young black female waling down street; black woman with
              decorative hat or bundle on head walking down street; street scenes; horse pulling
              wagon down street.</p>
            <p>Reel 9. Sequence 65. Scene 13. Location? Little Ann in graduation robe; street
              scenes; DARK.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref27_cd2" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">375 film
                  feet</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1937/1938"
                type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_02b74a2839d5d95bef71aee752ce5e6f"
                label="Moving Images [D04655539.]" type="freezer">Smith</container>
              <container id="aspace_0e5425a6a6fcba796faf18191b1344f5"
                parent="aspace_02b74a2839d5d95bef71aee752ce5e6f" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0009</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_c03ca9c299ffa64d055e2ca45ae81c5d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 10</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1936" type="inclusive">1936</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="aspace_c91163f9717a4302aa93cc47906867ef">Film is in the advanced stages of
              acetate decay, could not be digitized, and therefore is not viewable.</physdesc>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_b4699c8f31ba1e796b725b0f90b685d3">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Europe 1936, black and white</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_b40ab5409685fdf2cb41981561050ea1" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1936" type="inclusive">1936</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_3b3921b8b3da7556f8ebbf1dcc0a7245" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">2</container>
              <container id="aspace_d8ae35f492d91eba745aa8f98666e041"
                parent="aspace_3b3921b8b3da7556f8ebbf1dcc0a7245" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0015</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref32_omj" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 11</unittitle>
            <unitid>11</unitid>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1949/1949"
              type="inclusive">1949</unitdate>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r4xw4cw42"
              xlink:role="video-streaming" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Reel 11, 1949"
              xpointer="ark:/87924/r4xw4cw42"/>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_08b0b2c0df6c8c8da8277767c3f83263">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Original notes on can: 1949 - Tennis - Jack Kramer. Ginny and friend. Ann and Ginny -
              Cotton Picking Beach. Bonnie / baby. Ann w/Mother. Opelika.</p>
            <p>Additional description: Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 1. Tennis tournament with Jack
              Kramer vs. ?</p>
            <p>Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 2. Montgomery, AL: Helen Cottingham's kindergarten: Ginny
              in dance recital costume hanging upside down on swing; Ginny jumping rope; Kitty
              Poyntz, Ginny, ? Mary Lou Stuart, &amp; ?,? ?.</p>
            <p>Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 3. Location?: "? ford": swimming pool: Daddy with Myrick
              (?) on shoulder; Ginny jumping into water; 3 female friends of Mother &amp; Daddy on
              side of pool; Ginny swimming; Daddy in inner tube with Ginny in foreground &amp;
              female friend of Mother &amp; Daddy on porch in background; Myrick (CHECK ON DATE;
              VALID FOR Myrick TO BE IN SCENE??)standing on side of pool; Mother holding ball in
              pool with ? Ginny on side; Daddy, Ginny &amp; Myrick on inner tube.</p>
            <p>Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 4. Ginny &amp; Ann, &amp; then with Dear in background
              &amp; then Little Ann at left.</p>
            <p>Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 5. Mt. Meigs, near Montgomery, AL: Cotton picking:
              regular cotton pickers; soon Exie in blue skirt &amp; white shirt, more regular
              pickers, then Ann &amp; Ginny &amp; maybe Bonnie with Exie; weighing bales of cotton,
              after which cotton was emptied into a truck.</p>
            <p>Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 6. Mary Esther, FL: Walking across Santa Rosa Island from
              sound to the Gulf: male friend of Mother &amp; Daddy in red trunks Ginny with pigtails
              in white suit; Ann with yellow inner tube around neck; Daddy, tall female (?), Bill
              Thetford, Ginny &amp; ? Margaret Harris; in water: Bill Thetford &amp; Ginny swimming;
              Ann (in trunks) &amp; ? Margaret Harris in 2-piece suit. </p>
            <p>Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 7. Mary Esther, FL: Santa Rosa Sound in front of house
              renting: Ann sitting in water; Two plus Ginny on pier &amp; then swimming; ?Margaret
              Harris on pier; Ann in inner tube; Bill Thetford &amp; ?; Bonnie as baby.</p>
            <p>Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 8. Mary Esther, FL?: Gulf: Daddy; ? in inner tubes; Ginny
              on back in water; ???? Swimming.</p>
            <p>Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 9. Mary Esther, FL: Santa Rosa Sound: group in water --
              two swimming forward with Ginny on right; Ann in water, then holding ball &amp; ?;
              Mother in 2-piece suit walking behind Ann, then holding beach ball; group in water;
              Ann in yellow inner tube;?oOn left &amp; Ann on right; man in red trunks with child on
              other side; Ginny &amp; Ann with yellow inner tube; Ginny splashing Ann; child in
              foreground with Ann behind with yellow inner tube; group in water with pier in
              background; Mother in 2-piece suit; Mother with Ann in yellow inner tube, then Ginny
              on right.</p>
            <p>Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 10. Hull Street?: Bonnie, Ginny with corsage, ?, Ann in
              Sunday dress</p>
            <p>Reel 11. Sequence 67. Scene 11. Opelika, AL: Home of Aunt Annie &amp; Aunt Jeanette:
              front porch steps: back row: Aunt Virginia (Gin) with hands on face, Aunt Jeanette,
              Aunt Minnie, Aunt Annie; next row: Aunt Lettie in black &amp; Big Ann holding Bonnie
              &amp; Ginny standing in front of Daddy &amp; Ann with back to camera. Back yard:
              Bonnie on stomach on quilt on ground; Ann, close-up; chairs: Aunt Minnie with Aunt
              Virginia (Gin)on left, Aunt Annie leaning over Ann &amp; Bonnie on quilt.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref33_41s" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">350 film
                  feet</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1949/1949"
                type="inclusive">1949</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_2d5f669fa4dcf41ad848203c48b53244"
                label="Moving Images [D04655538-]" type="box">1</container>
              <container id="aspace_e0c5b38a69865a6686283eb99d007acb"
                parent="aspace_2d5f669fa4dcf41ad848203c48b53244" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0011</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref35_1az" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 12 and 13</unittitle>
            <unitid>12</unitid>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1950/1950"
              type="inclusive">1950</unitdate>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r4qc00570"
              xlink:role="video-streaming" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Reel 12 and 13, 1950"
              xpointer="ark:/87924/r4qc00570"/>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_8d79a2810d3d69ee61f28c0c7b7c8282">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Original notes on can: 12: Mary Esther - Ann and Bonnie w/half her hair. Ginny; 13:
              Katty w/crab - 1950. Ginny in boat - Hull St. Ginny, Ann and Bonnie. Margaret Day -
              Birthday Party. Joy, Louise, Ann, Ginny on horses, Easter Hunt. Bonnie walking.
              Fishing.</p>
            <p>Additional description: Reel 12. Sequence 68. Scene 1. Mary Esther, FL: Ginny (blue
              &amp; white striped shirt), Ann, &amp; Bonnie (baby) in hammock in front of house
              family renting; Santa Rosa Sound in front of house - small boat in which family went
              across sound, then left boat at pier &amp; walked across Santa Rosa Island to the
              Gulf; Bonnie (right) &amp; Ann (left) in straw hats in boat &amp; Ginny in back - ? on
              beach; Mother in red hat holding Myrick; Uncle Eddie Stauss &amp; Uncle Phil Branson?;
              Daddy sitting on edge of boat which is to right of a similar boat; ? comes towards
              boat; Ann? in red inner tube; little boy - Hank Hutchinson? in blue in inner tube in
              water; 2 people catching crab; Ginny's back (in bathing suit with blue back &amp;
              design on white background in front).</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 1. Mary Esther, FL (cont'd): Pier &amp; boat (possibly
              Uncle Phil's), probably in front of Aunt Mamie &amp; Uncle Phil's house: Bill?
              Thetford in mostly blue shirt ; Ginny in plaid shirt; Mother in blue checked shirt
              &amp; male leaning on boat; Bill? Thetford dove &amp; Ginny jumped off pier &amp;
              swam; both get on pier; on beach, Mother &amp; Bonnie (baby); close-up of Ann &amp;
              then Bonnie with almost no hair on left side of head (note: Bonnie went through stage
              of pulling out her hair on left side, probably when taking naps -- eventually overcame
              this practice); Bonnie playing in sand &amp; in shallow water; Daddy sitting on edge
              of small boat; Bonnie &amp; Ann standing in blue bathing suits; view of Santa Rosa
              Sound, pier &amp; house -- Ann &amp; Bonnie sitting on steps. 13* on original list,
              but contents of reel 13 are on reel 12.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 2. Union Springs, AL: Pond: Small boat with Emily Hobbie
              (?) in back &amp; Ginny, each with an oar; Jack &amp; Emily Hobbie (parents of Emily)
              standing beside Daddy (hat on); parents of Emily in boat with Emily in front &amp;
              Ginny in back.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 3. Hull Street, front yard: Ginny pushing Bonnie (pink
              snowsuit) in "taylor tot" along gravel path; Ann in navy appears.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 4. Hull Street, back yard: Ann (blue dress) &amp; Bonnie
              on some small rocking horse contraption &amp; Margaret Day in white dress &amp; pink
              sweater; other children at birthday party for Ann &amp; Bonnie; Ann guarding gifts on
              decorated table; view of back of house showing upstairs porch &amp; broad rectangular
              columns under porch, that is, back of first floor. Different day: Bonnie on rocking
              horse &amp; Louise Clark in blue dress (white stripe on front top center of dress);
              side wall of fire station (brick painted white) which was at end of back yard: Ann in
              blue dress watering hollyhocks; back of house: Daddy brings watering can with water to
              Ann; Big Ann in back behind Bonnie in taylor tot.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 5. Location?: Libby Foster (?), Lila Ashley, older girl
              (?), Ginny on fence, Wiley Ashley, Jr. on horse; Louise Clark, then Joy Clark on
              horse; then Ginny climbing onto horse; then Ann with Lila Ashley behind her on
              horse.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 6. Hull Street, front yard: Easter egg hunt; several
              small children; Sarah Lingham in white dress with yellow ribbon &amp; Ginny in blue
              dress, each holding basket of Easter eggs; DARK: Ann?; Ginny in jeans &amp; shirt
              holding basket of Easter eggs. DARK: hunting Easter eggs -- family wearing jeans.
              Later in day: Ann &amp; Ginny dressed for Sunday School, probably Easter; Ann in blue
              dress &amp; straw hat; on gravel path in front of banana shrub: Ginny, Bonnie, male,
              female, Louise &amp; Joy Clark -- most holding Easter baskets; all hunting eggs;
              close-up of Ann in blue smocked dress. At a later time: Bonnie standing up from small
              chair (had been grandfather Dowdell's), walks a few steps &amp; then crawls.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 7. Location? Pond: Mother &amp; Daddy's friends.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 8. Location? Beach: children swimming; adults &amp; Ginny
              in blue bathing suit with back to camera; ? With her; view of beach &amp; water.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 1. Sarajevo?: leg braces, etc. on ground -- memorial??;
              filmed in black &amp; white.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 2. Montgomery, AL: John &amp; Algie Neill's back yard
              with swimming pool: swimming lessons being taught.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 3. commercial film in black &amp; white: Castle Films
              presents Merry Christmas; titles before each scene; c. MCML, United World Films.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref36_vjs" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">300 film
                  feet</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1950/1950"
                type="inclusive">1950</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d714f43e2961163cfcefda6332d07474"
                label="Moving Images [D04655540T]" type="freezer">Smith</container>
              <container id="aspace_a6dc58ee89fbb47f8a6791715fa7cbba"
                parent="aspace_d714f43e2961163cfcefda6332d07474" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0012</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref23_2x5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 14</unittitle>
            <unitid>8</unitid>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1947/1947"
              type="inclusive">1947</unitdate>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r40v8fh57"
              xlink:role="video-streaming" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Reel 14, 1947"
              xpointer="ark:/87924/r40v8fh57"/>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_f463e467ab009b8464f149f18e33e809">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Original notes on can: 1947 - Ginny - Beach - Spout - Ginny Birthday Party. Baby Ann
              - Snow, Ann and Ginny on sled. Edgar Stuart and boat - Gulf w/Big Ann</p>
            <p>Additional description: Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 1. Location?: Beach (?): Ginny in
              trunks in water; then in inner tube; little boy (?) in inner tube; female (?) in
              2-piece white bathing suit wading; Daddy in water; Mother in 2-piece blue bathing suit
              &amp; bandage on knee; Mother holding Ginny's hand; little boy, his mother (white
              bathing suit with black design) &amp; his father.</p>
            <p>Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 2. Location?: Beach (?), new scene: close-up of Daddy on
              boat, couple mentioned in previous scene; Barnett Wood (?) in foreground; close-up of
              Mother in white top; close up of male (?); close-up of Mother; previous male &amp;
              another male.</p>
            <p>Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 3. Location?: Ginny dressed up in white dress &amp;
              pantaloons &amp; bonnet for birthday.</p>
            <p>Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 4. Coosa, AL: spout: back of Ginny next to back of Aunt
              Virginia; then DARK; see spout, made of wood: back of Aunt Annie or Aunt Jeanette on
              left &amp; ? on right; few people at end of spout where water spilling; Mother in
              2-piece bathing suit; Daddy with Ginny; Ginny &amp; Daddy standing with Mother
              sitting; Daddy &amp; Ginny walk around &amp; then sit down.</p>
            <p>Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 5. Montgomery, AL: Perry Street -- 600 block, back-yard
              of Hobbie family (1/2 block from 640 South Perry Street where Big Ann &amp; Ashley
              family lived): Ginny's 5th birthday party: large round table decorated with balloons;
              Exie with Ann in lap sitting in swing; Ginny in white pinafore rolls baby carriage to
              them &amp; beyond; Ginny taking gift from child in bonnet with ? next to her &amp;
              holding a little boy's hand; another boy (blonde hair) at left of screen; another part
              of yard: female in plaid dress in center with children on both sides; front left: ? in
              white dress; on right Margaret Harris (?) in white dress; back of little boy, probably
              Bill Thetford; children behind playing "pin the tail on the donkey.</p>
            <p>Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 5. Montgomery, AL: Perry Street (cont'd): back to table
              with birthday cake (5 lighted candles), showing Ginny blowing them out; children &amp;
              adults around table; children being served pieces of birthday cake; Ginny opening
              presents: Joy Clark (?) with pigtails next to her &amp; other children around; Melissa
              Folsom (?) with dark hair parted in middle, turns towards camera; more of Ginny
              opening gifts; Sammy Baker (?) holding handle of wagon stacked with gifts, &amp; Bill
              Thetford next to him; ? in front &amp; Ginny to side by wagon; Sammy pulls wagon with
              gifts falling off &amp; children picking them up.</p>
            <p>Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 6. Location? Ann on back drinking bottle of orange juice
              or milk in crib.</p>
            <p>Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 7. Location?: Beach (?): Daddy sitting in water &amp;
              holding Ann with Ginny in inner tube beside them; Ginny swimming; Exie holding Ann
              &amp; standing in water; Ginny jumping from edge of boat with Daddy in boat; on left
              is Big Ann, in center, Uncle Eddie holding a beach ball, &amp; on right, Little Ann in
              inner tube; Ginny swims towards them; ball throwing; Daddy into water; close-up of
              Aunt Virginia (black bathing cap) in inner tube; several in water throwing a ball.</p>
            <p>Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 8. Perry Street: Ginny on left; 2 males about the same
              age building a snow man; Ginny on sled in front with one of males behind her; another
              into picture; 2 on sled with 2 pulling; sledding &amp; playing in snow; car drives up
              &amp; parks behind another car on side street perpendicular to Perry; snowball
              throwing; apartment building in background; adult female at left; can see snow covered
              old Ford owned by Big Ann; another adult on right; more sledding;</p>
            <p>Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene . Perry Street (cont'd) - may be next day: very sunny;
              Daddy pulling sled, with Ann in front of Ginny, around front yard; corner with Mother
              behind Ginny &amp; Ann on sled &amp; going downhill; Mother pulling sled with Ann
              &amp; Ginny up the hill; front yard with Daddy pulling Ann &amp; Ginny on sled; Exie
              in background, also apartment building; Mother on left and then center with sled;
              Mother behind Ginny &amp; Ann on sled; also see Exie &amp; Daddy.</p>
            <p>Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 9. Perry Street, front of apartment: Ann in taylor tot
              with Adelaide Ashley holding handle; Ginny in red coat on left; opening present - ?
              Ann's birthday?; Louise Clark in yellow coat &amp; Joy Clark (long blond hair) in red
              coat standing next to Adelaide; all 5 in view.</p>
            <p>Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 10. Location? Beach: Edgar Stuart in motor boat; Little
              Ann sitting on seat in boat; then 2 adult males &amp; Edgar Stuart in boat waving; on
              pier, Boots Ashley (Sharman) in multi-colored shirt walking up steps from beach; Daddy
              carrying inner tube with Ginny in front of him &amp; ? in front of her.</p>
            <p>Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 11. Location? Gulf: Mother in 2 piece bathing suit; Daddy
              standing; Ginny or ? In water in inner tube; waves &amp; sand; close-up of Daddy on
              left; Wiley Ashley, Jr. ? &amp; Ginny with long hair; Big Ann in black bathing suit;
              all playing in water; Ginny swimming Big Ann, Ginny, Wiley, Jr. &amp; Mother in 2
              piece bathing suit all playing in waves.</p>
            <p>Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 12. Location? Picnic on towel; baby in center is Ann
              &amp; Ginny on right; ? On left in pigtails &amp; 2 boys?; birthday cake with 6
              candles on towel -- Ginny's birthday?</p>
            <p>Reel 14. Sequence 70. Scene 13. Location? Children in water with some in inner tubes;
              beach &amp; trees in one area; Mother in water in 2 piece bathing suit.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref24_yky" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">425 film
                  feet</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1947/1947"
                type="inclusive">1947</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_28467725a3defcedbb4d415554be159e"
                label="Moving Images [D04655538-]" type="box">1</container>
              <container id="aspace_c1f70599a629eb1c09fb48a1bad00c87"
                parent="aspace_28467725a3defcedbb4d415554be159e" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0008</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_939b900e2d54b916ab3ea89190186a69" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 15</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1944" type="inclusive">1942-1944</unitdate>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r46d5tb3t"
              xlink:role="video-streaming" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Reel 10, 1942-1944"
              xpointer="ark:/87924/r46d5tb3t"/>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_465d14106b355a347b316c256ac480fe">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Ginny - baby, Florida, Winter Park, Daytona, 1942, 43-44, Clearwater</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_cfec5b1bd4a865d026ce2f865256e576" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">400 film
                  feet</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1942/1944"
                type="inclusive">1942-1944</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_feec733cef189e0f0fcc6fd67e29aca3" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">2</container>
              <container id="aspace_05e731d596a75b80db62a0341f22d6d0"
                parent="aspace_feec733cef189e0f0fcc6fd67e29aca3" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0016</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref29_8yr" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 16</unittitle>
            <unitid>10</unitid>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1945/1945"
              type="inclusive">1945</unitdate>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r4zw1ds49"
              xlink:role="video-streaming" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Reel 16, 1945"
              xpointer="ark:/87924/r4zw1ds49"/>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_241fc7e3b6c50435244100b9e69560b2">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Original notes on can: Pelham 1945 - Pea Island - Ginny on Beach and ice skaing -
              Birthday Party - Fishing Ginny on horse - Coast - Ann (baby).</p>
            <p>Additional description: Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene 1. Pea Island, NY: Ginny's
              birthday -- Ginny behind cake; group of children sitting on ground &amp; tablecloth
              with plates, etc. on it; group of adult women standing &amp; 1 man to far right; Ginny
              with bangs &amp; in swim trunks; little girl beside her; adults sitting nearer camera
              &amp; 1 male adult standing to right; little boy flying kite with Ginny beside him;
              Ginny &amp; little girl playing in sand; Ginny runs into water &amp; then she &amp;
              little girl both run into water where there are others; sailboat &amp; another boat in
              background; view of water &amp; part of shore.</p>
            <p>Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene 2. Pelham, NY: Ginny in snowsuit on ice; skates on
              ice.</p>
            <p>Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene . Pelham, NY -- warmer time of year: Ginny in white
              blouse &amp; blue skirt beside wall; Ginny running; Ginny with adult female, probably
              Little Ann.</p>
            <p>Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene 3. Pelham, NY: Ginny in snowsuit going down steps in
              front of Monterey Avenue house; Ginny in snowsuit in snow.</p>
            <p>Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene 4. Location? Ginny's birthday party; table with gifts;
              Dear in pillbox hat; close-up of Scott Hereford; girls in background; Ginny in yellow
              dress opening gifts.</p>
            <p>Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene 5. Location? Pond: Boat with male on left; Ginny standing
              in center &amp; Daddy on right; Mills Thornton Sr. on left; Daddy gets fishing pole
              ready for Ginny to fish; another boat (red) with Ginny &amp; Mills Thornton Jr.</p>
            <p>Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene 6. Location? Ginny being put on horse; someone leads the
              horse around; Wiley Ashley Jr. in white shorts &amp; shirt on right; Ginny off horse
              &amp; Wiley on horse &amp; is led around; long wagon with Ginny, Wiley &amp; other
              children being pulled by horse; Wiley on horse again.</p>
            <p>Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene . Location? (cont'd) 4 children: far right -- Ginny in
              pinafore &amp; saddle oxfords; Mary Kennan Thetford in white pinafore next to her; on
              left, ?Bill &amp; Bob Thetford? In white shirts with blue collars &amp; blue shorts;
              Wiley Ashley Jr. appears; Ginny, Mary Kennan, Bill &amp; Bob; Ginny on horse again
              being led around.</p>
            <p>Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene 7. Mary Esther, FL: Daddy on far right in inner tube
              &amp; then female adult in white bathing cap &amp; Ginny on left paddling; male adult
              on left in inner tube; little boy &amp; probably his mother; mother in white 2 piece
              bathing suit with Ginny in front; on right same adult male in inner tube &amp; little
              boy; Ginny splashing/paddling again; Mother does back stroke; front of cottage (not
              visible) where staying -- gate with view of ? (Ginny's handwriting not legible). </p>
            <p>Reel 16. Sequence 72. Scene . Mary Esther, FL (cont'd): Ginny in overalls &amp; hat;
              bench on pier -- adult male's back, little boy or girl in pink cap &amp; Ginny? in
              straw hat &amp; horizontal striped t shirt; front view of 3 on bench (Ginny standing);
              female servant in all white &amp; white hat fishing beside the 3; to her right, Daddy
              fishing; Ann in white on striped beach towel being propped up by ? &amp; then on her
              stomach; Ann being held.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref30_k12" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">300 film
                  feet</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1945/1945"
                type="inclusive">1945</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_34fc9fcdb496dc43e9a29fc86a30b851"
                label="Moving Images [D04655538-]" type="box">1</container>
              <container id="aspace_2316354819eb9cf36d11318ca8e1d305"
                parent="aspace_34fc9fcdb496dc43e9a29fc86a30b851" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0010</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref38_39z" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reel 17</unittitle>
            <unitid>13</unitid>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1950/1950"
              type="inclusive">1950</unitdate>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r48915r1f"
              xlink:role="video-streaming" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Reel 17, 1950"
              xpointer="ark:/87924/r48915r1f"/>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_32a5bd21dd2220f7d723466a997f97f4">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Original notes on can: Sarajevo; Castle Films presents a Yuletide Movie, "Merry
              Christmas"</p>
            <p>Additional description: Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 1. Mary Esther, FL (cont'd); Pier
              &amp; boat (possibly Uncle Phil's), probably in front of Aunt Mamie &amp; Uncle Phil's
              house: Bill? Thetford in mostly blue shirt ; Ginny in plaid shirt; Mother in blue
              checked shirt &amp; male leaning on boat; Bill? Thetford dove &amp; Ginny jumped off
              pier &amp; swam; both get on pier; on beach, Mother &amp; Bonnie (baby); close-up of
              Ann &amp; then Bonnie with almost no hair on left side of head (note: Bonnie went
              through stage of pulling out her hair on left side, probably when taking naps --
              eventually overcame this practice); Bonnie playing in sand &amp; in shallow water;
              Daddy sitting on edge of small boat; Bonnie &amp; Ann standing in blue bathing suits;
              view of Santa Rosa Sound, pier &amp; house -- Ann &amp; Bonnie sitting on steps. 13*
              on original list, but contents of reel 13 are on reel 12.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 2. Union Springs, AL: Pond: Small boat with Emily Hobbie
              (?) in back &amp; Ginny, each with an oar; Jack &amp; Emily Hobbie (parents of Emily)
              standing beside Daddy (hat on); parents of Emily in boat with Emily in front &amp;
              Ginny in back.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 3. Hull Street, front yard: Ginny pushing Bonnie (pink
              snowsuit) in "taylor tot" along gravel path; Ann in navy appears.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 4. Hull Street, back yard: Ann (blue dress) &amp; Bonnie
              on some small rocking horse contraption &amp; Margaret Day in white dress &amp; pink
              sweater; other children at birthday party for Ann &amp; Bonnie; Ann guarding gifts on
              decorated table; view of back of house showing upstairs porch &amp; broad rectangular
              columns under porch, that is, back of first floor. Different day: Bonnie on rocking
              horse &amp; Louise Clark in blue dress (white stripe on front top center of dress);
              side wall of fire station (brick painted white) which was at end of back yard: Ann in
              blue dress watering hollyhocks; back of house: Daddy brings watering can with water to
              Ann; Big Ann in back behind Bonnie in taylor tot.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 5. Location?: Libby Foster (?), Lila Ashley, older girl
              (?), Ginny on fence, Wiley Ashley, Jr. on horse; Louise Clark, then Joy Clark on
              horse; then Ginny climbing onto horse; then Ann with Lila Ashley behind her on
              horse.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 6. Hull Street, front yard: Easter egg hunt; several
              small children; Sarah Lingham in white dress with yellow ribbon &amp; Ginny in blue
              dress, each holding basket of Easter eggs; DARK: Ann?; Ginny in jeans &amp; shirt
              holding basket of Easter eggs. DARK: hunting Easter eggs -- family wearing jeans.
              Later in day: Ann &amp; Ginny dressed for Sunday School, probably Easter; Ann in blue
              dress &amp; straw hat; on gravel path in front of banana shrub: Ginny, Bonnie, male,
              female, Louise &amp; Joy Clark -- most holding Easter baskets; all hunting eggs;
              close-up of Ann in blue smocked dress. At a later time: Bonnie standing up from small
              chair (had been grandfather Dowdell's), walks a few steps &amp; then crawls.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 7. Location? Pond: Mother &amp; Daddy's friends.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 8. Location? Beach: children swimming; adults &amp; Ginny
              in blue bathing suit with back to camera; ? With her; view of beach &amp; water.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 1. Sarajevo?: leg braces, etc. on ground -- memorial??;
              filmed in black &amp; white.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 2. Montgomery, AL: John &amp; Algie Neill's back yard
              with swimming pool: swimming lessons being taught.</p>
            <p>Reel 13. Sequence 69. Scene 3. commercial film in black &amp; white: Castle Films
              presents Merry Christmas; titles before each scene; c. MCML, United World Films.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref39_q90" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Original 16mm film</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">150 film
                  feet</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1950/1950"
                type="inclusive">1950</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_17a1a191300dcdca4c6ced686f5c2be7"
                label="Moving Images [D04655538-]" type="box">1</container>
              <container id="aspace_0fee5fd5eb8ff6f5c904361147070cb5"
                parent="aspace_17a1a191300dcdca4c6ced686f5c2be7" type="film-reel"
                >RL10048-F16-0013</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
