<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="https://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/ayodhyaindiaexhibitpanels/"
      >ayodhyaindiaexhibitpanels</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the "Hum Sab Ayodhya" exhibit panels on the Ayodhya region and
          destruction of the mosque, Uttar Pradesh, India, and related protest posters, after
          1993-2000 <num>RL.11630</num></titleproper>
        <author>Paula Jeannet</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>June 2018</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">008347016</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-07-17 11:52:35
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="hin">Hindi</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>"Hum Sab Ayodhya" exhibit panels on the Ayodhya region and destruction of the
        mosque, and related protest posters, Uttar Pradesh, India</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="naf">Rahman, Ram</persname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname source="naf">Safdar Hashmi Memorial Trust </corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.11630</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.5 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">3 oversize folders; 1 box</extent>
        <physfacet>84 items</physfacet>
        <dimensions>Approximately 17 x 21 3/4 to 28 1/4 x 38 1/4 inches</dimensions>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1993/2000" type="inclusive">after 1993-2000</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_4d0d8e886dfff5388deebee4be1f6db0">Collection consists of 37 large paper
        sheets bearing reduced-size reproductions of 83 panels that formed a 1993 exhibit narrating
        the history, culture, and customs of the Aydhoya region in India, now part of the state of
        Uttar Pradesh. It was organized by the curator Ram Rahman and SAHMAT (Safdar Hashmi Memorial
        Trust), a New Delhi-based collective of Indian artists, writers, and activists against
        communalism and violent extremism. Also includes 47 posters protesting extremist violence,
        created by the same organization. The exhibit illustrates the origins of the Babri Masjid
        mosque complex and its destruction by Hindu extremists in December 1992. The black-and-white
        and color reproductions, most without captions, include 16th century paintings; regional
        maps; plans and large color photographs of the mosque complex; details of sculptures,
        scripts, and reliefs; reproductions of English accounts; and photographs of area inhabitants
        as well as individuals associated with regional politics. There are also several texts in
        Hindi. The sheets measure approximately 28 1/4 x 38 1/4 inches. Posters are sized
        approximately 17 x 21 3/4 inches. Detailed information on the original 1993 exhibit and its
        historical context is found in a 2012 publication on the exhibit, available in the Duke
        Libraries.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_5055fb3a5cc262dda4867f97e61236a7">Materials in English and
        Hindi.</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="aspace_fd2e45a027460fe6648e47234467cd6a">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>The exhibit panels and the related group of protest posters all refer more broadly to the
        political, religious, and cultural conflicts in India that have continued into the 21st
        century.</p>
      <p>The exhibit from which the reproduction sheets in this collection were derived was titled
          <title render="doublequote">Hum Sab Ayodhya</title> ("We are all Ayodhya"), and was
        organized in August 1993 by SAHMAT (Safdar Hashmi Memorial Trust), a collective of Indian
        artists and writers against communalism and extremist violence, formed in 1989 and based in
        New Delhi. </p>
      <p>The exhibit was mounted simultaneously in twelve cities in India to protest the 1992
        destruction of a large and important mosque in the Ayodhya region. It explored the history,
        geography, and cultural life of the people of Ayodhya. Ayodhya, also known as Saket, is
        presently located in the district of Faizabad, in the State of Uttar Pradesh, India; it is
        believed to be the birth place of the Hindu deity Rama, and the setting of the epic
        Ramayana. </p>
      <p>The Ayodhya region became a focal point for disputes and violent clashes between Hindu
        extremists and Muslims over the Babri Masjid, a large mosque built in the 16th century by
        the Mughal emperor Babur. Hindus claimed the mosque was built by demolishing a Hindu temple
        dedicated to Rama. The mosque was eventually destroyed by a coalition of Hindu extremist
        groups in December 1992. </p>
      <p>The original exhibit included a reproduction of a 4-page text titled "Ram Katha" (the
        legend of the Hindu deity Rama), written by a controversial Indian historian, Romila Thapar,
        which offended the Hindu right, and led to a fierce debate in the Indian Parliament to ban
        the exhibit. This text is not present in the collection. The exhibit was seized by the Delhi
        police, but was later cleared by the court in response to a legal challenge by the
        organizers of the exhibit. </p>
      <p>More broadly, the exhibit panels and the related group of protest posters refer to the
        political, religious, and cultural conflicts in India that have continued into the 21st
        century.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_acdb6a4af7250920261fc163d47135b7">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
        research use.</p>
      <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_6a75ea028b953caeeed884f560596901">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_d96eb50b5f6c87176a812dcebd7539ab">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>The "Hum Sab Ayodhya" exhibit panels on the Ayodhya region and mosque, Uttar Pradesh, India
        and related protest posters were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library as a transfer in 2015.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <phystech id="aspace_dd896128fdf81646e9433cedd41314de">
      <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
      <p>The exhibit sheets are thin, very large, and need careful handling. They have some tears on
        the edges. Please contact the Rubenstein Library in advance before coming to use this
        collection.</p>
    </phystech>
    <prefercite id="aspace_b8fbf830079c5d8883a1e55e98951475">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], "Hum Sab Ayodhya" exhibit panels on the Ayodhya region and
        mosque, Uttar Pradesh, India, and related protest posters, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_94b6f188541b7b9ef56d6129d7f06043">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed and encoded by Paula Jeannet, June 2018 and June 2019.</p>
      <p>Accession(s) described in this finding aid: 2015-0146.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_6afeca77347fe00d69c248fa0c7766b7">
      <head>Content Description</head>
      <p>Collection consists of 37 oversize paper sheets bearing reduced-size reproductions of 83
        wall panels relating to the exhibit "Hum Sab Ayodhya" ("We are all Ayodhya") on the history
        and culture of the Ayodhya region and mosque, Uttar Pradesh, India. Also includes 47 protest
        posters relating to right-wing extremism and violence.</p>
      <p>The exhibit, organized by the curator Ram Rahman and Sahmat (Safdar Hashmi Memorial Trust,
        a Delhi-based collective of Indian artists and writers against communalism), explored the
        complex history, geography, and cultural life of Ayodhya, or Saket, presently located in the
        district of Faizabad, in the State of Uttar Pradesh, India. It focused specifically on the
        Babri Masjid mosque complex, built in the 16th century and an important religious site for
        India's Muslims, as well as a site for clashes between Hindu and Muslim communities.</p>
      <p>The exhibit was mounted in New Delhi shortly after the destruction of the Babri Masjid by
        Hindu extremists in December 1992, and there was fierce controversy over its content.</p>
      <p>The black-and-white and color exhibit sheets feature 16th century illustrations; large
        color and black-and-white photographs of the mosque complex; photographs of its
        inscriptions, reliefs, and sculptures; images of deities; maps of the region; photographs of
        individuals connected with regional politics and activism; and 20th century photographic
        portraits of local Ayodhya peoples. </p>
      <p>Exhibit texts include reproductions of several 19th century English accounts regarding the
        region's politics and geography, explanatory texts in Hindi, and an introductory title
        panel, also in Hindi. The sheets measure approximately 28 1/4 x 38 1/4 inches. The original
        sequence of the individual panels is indicated by numbers marked on the backs of the
        sheets.</p>
      <p>Detailed information on the exhibit and its historical context is found in a 2012
        publication on the exhibit, available in the Duke Libraries.</p>
      <p>The collection also includes a group of 47 posters created by the SAHMAT collective from
        the late 1990s, protesting right-wing extremist violence in India directed at secular,
        cultural, and religious groups. Many refer to specific acts of violence or political and
        cultural intimidation. Posters include text in Hindi and English, graphic design elements,
        photographs, eyewitness quotations, slogans, and artwork.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_c819b5ac7bb80f920bf1c916138a2375">
      <head>Related Materials</head>
      <p>The exhibit catalog, <title render="italic">Hum Sab Ayodhya</title>, published in digital
        format by Issuu, Inc. in December 2012, on the 20th anniversary of the destruction of the
        Babri Masjid. Available online.</p>
      <p><title render="italic">Muktnaad; Hum Sab Ayodhya: a selection of reports, editorials,
          discussions, comments from the press.</title> Safdar Hashmi Memorial Trust, New Delhi,
        1994. A compendium of commentary on the exhibit and related cultural programs. Available
        through the Duke University Libraries catalog.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Babari Masjid (Faizabad, India) </subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Communalism -- India</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Documentary Photography -- India</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Hindu temples -- India -- Ayodhya (Faizabad)</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Hindus -- India</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Mosques -- India -- Ayodhya (Faizabad)</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Muslims -- India</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Museum exhibits -- India</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Nationalism -- India</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Viśva Hindū Parishad -- Trials, litigation, etc.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Shrines -- India -- Ayodhya (Faizabad)</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Waqf -- India -- Ayodhya (Faizabad)</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Ayodhya (Faizabad, India) -- Politics and government</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">India -- Politics and government</geogname>
      <genreform source="gmgpc">Protest posters -- India -- 1990-2000</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Posters</genreform>
      <subject source="lcsh">Extremists -- India</subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_eaa27de8eb106df9c8ab136f130fcee3" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Exhibit panel reproductions</unittitle>
          <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11
              Sheets</extent><dimensions>Approximately 28 1/4 x 38 1/4
            inches</dimensions></physdesc>
          <container id="aspace_8340864b6d7f883100830aa973d2bf12" label="Mixed Materials"
            type="oversize-folder">1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_1a50df9142dc36c747db596a9b1eb0f2" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Exhibit panel reproductions</unittitle>
          <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">14
              Sheets</extent><dimensions>Approximately 28 1/4 x 40 1/4
            inches</dimensions></physdesc>
          <container id="aspace_2d46fb769be9b220048413300c7323ef" label="Mixed Materials"
            type="oversize-folder">2</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_01d3b92163733afaa79254a67f0b3385" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Exhibit panel reproductions</unittitle>
          <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12
              Sheets</extent><dimensions>Approximately 28 1/4 x 38 1/4
            inches</dimensions></physdesc>
          <container id="aspace_406916e447303feebc04be51df95390c" label="Mixed Materials"
            type="oversize-folder">3</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_967a370d041c3a6a75c7382a4c15350c" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Supplementary materials: SAHMAT protest posters</unittitle>
          <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">47
              items</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent></physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1997/2000" type="inclusive">1997-2000</unitdate>
          <container altrender="Flat-20x24x1.5" id="aspace_9957dcb7e687a1e9de6633d02a5fb998"
            label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_d29f764381b6e762660ed677781e72da">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This collection of protest posters was produced in the late 1990s by the SAHMAT
            collective, that also sponsored and curated the "Hum Sab Adoyhya" exhibit. The group is
            a collective of artists, activists, and writers who are dedicated to promoting freedom
            of expression and combating any form of right-wing extremism that has targeted secular
            and religious groups in India.</p>
          <p>Posters typically measure between 11 7/8 x 21 and 17 x 21 3/4 inches and feature text
            in Hindi and English, as well as colorful graphic design elements, photographs,
            eyewitness quotes, caricatures, and political cartoons. Frequent subjects include
            references to specific acts of violence or political and cultural intimidation. Most are
            in color.</p>
          <p>Most of the designs are typical of ephemeral protest posters with slogans and
            illustrations; there are also several more elegant exhibit-quality compositions
            featuring artwork and photography by Indian artists. Some posters feature a small corner
            logo commemorating the 50th anniversary of Indian independence.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
