<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
         url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/barbauldanna/">barbauldanna</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Anna Letitia Barbauld and William Allen poems, 1823 August
               23-30 <num>RL.11431</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Megan E. Lewis</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>April, 2017</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">007811351</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-04-06 14:34:29
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Anna Letitia Barbauld and William Allen poems</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname role="aut" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Barbauld, Mrs. (Anna Letitia),
               1743-1825</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname role="aut" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Allen, William, 1770-1843</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="n92076709" role="fmo" source="naf">Baskin, Lisa
               Unger</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.11431</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 Linear Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">1 item</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1823-08-23/1823-08-30" type="inclusive">1823 August 23-30</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_240c220326d98ffb0b01fb53692fa406">Anna Letitia Barbauld was an English
            woman of letters who had great professional success at a time when women writers were
            still something of an anomaly. She is remembered for her poetry, children's literature,
            essays, criticism, and editorial works. She was rediscovered when feminist literary
            critics examined her place in British literary history. Barbauld was also an
            abolitionist, something she had in common with fellow educator and Stoke Newington
            resident William Allen. This item is a single small sheet of paper with an autograph
            manuscript poem by Barbauld on the front dated August 23, 1823, and another one on the
            back by William Allen dated August 30, 1823. Both poems were aimed at a juvenile
            audience. It is likely that their common interests and close proximity led them to
            develop a friendship. Although this was written towards the end of Barbauld's life, it
            is evidence that they still had at least an epistolary relationship in 1823.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_ec073b6abbde0ce060f5472879d42ded">Materials in
            English</langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_c0858577bf65e70f5a3252032e483415">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_e02ff18783db4d28e62b644ae508f3cf">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Anna Letitia and William Allen poems were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare
            Book &amp; Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2015.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_5a68de170c549e83e44ec27a1a0bd8a0">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Anna Letitia Barbauld (1743-1825) was an English writer, teacher, and editor who
            published poetry, works for children, literary criticism, and essays. She was a
            successful writer at a time when women professional writers were an anomaly. Her first
            book of poems (1773) established her literary reputation in England, and her later
            essays were compared to Samuel Johnson. Along with her husband, Barbauld ran the boy's
            school Palgrave Academy for 11 years, during which time she established herself as a
            writer of children's pedagogical texts, as well as poetry for children. She is credited
            with establishing children's literature as a legitimate genre, and her editorial works,
            particularly The British Novelists series, helped establish the British literary canon.
            Barbauld was an abolitionist and was also against the Napoleonic Wars, two subjects she
            addressed in her political writing. Both her poetry and her political essays were
            occasionally subject to harsh contemporary criticism, which eventually caused her to
            retreat from the public eye. She lived in Stoke Newington from 1802 until her death in
            1825. Barbauld's literary legacy was largely forgotten until the rise of feminist
            literary criticism in the late 20th century, which helped resurrect her place in
            history. </p>
         <p>William Allen (1770-1843) was an English Quaker abolitionist, scientist, educator, and
            philanthropist who was active in various social reform movements of early 19th century
            England. He was trained as a chemist, and his pharmaceutical company, Allen &amp;
            Hanburys, grew into one of the UK's largest drug companies. One year after this poem was
            written, he founded the Newington Academy for Girls, a progressive school in Stoke
            Newington. Although Barbauld was near the end of her life at the time of this writing,
            is it evidence that she and Allen maintained at least an epistolatory friendship based
            on their common interests.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <prefercite id="aspace_6048a2baa34f5a27f2ec91c9deab3064">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Anna Letitia Barbauld and William Allen poems, David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_09bfe23de89686a1c9d8ae27a0991a5f">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Megan E. Lewis, April, 2017</p>
         <p>Accessions described in this collection guide: 2015-0050-LUBMSS113</p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_2bcb685b59ed24ccbaf905774f4c9eef">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Collection consists of a single piece of paper (20 x 12.5 cm) with an autograph
            manuscript poem by Anna Letitia Barbauld on the front and a poem called "Follow Me" by
            William Allen on the back. Barbauld's poem reads as follows: Born to the weighty honours
            of a name/Whose deeds of mercy England's shores proclaim/Yet know, you may inherit lands
            or pelf/But must, for praise - for love, be good yourself. It's signed A.L. Barbauld and
            dated August 23rd 1823. The verso contains a two-stanza autograph manuscript devotional
            poem by William Allen titled "Follow Me." It is signed Stoke Newington 30 of 8th month
            1823. Barbauld and Allen were both educators and abolitionists who lived in Stoke
            Newington at the time of this writing. These poems are evidence that they had at least
            an epistolary friendship.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_31a9ae03bc7031cf92f5660822aabcb9">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Abolitionists -- Great Britain -- History -- 19th century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Children's poetry, English -- 19th century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Educators -- Great Britain</subject>
         <corpname role="rps" rules="dacs" source="naf">Lisa Unger Baskin Collection (David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library)</corpname>
         <corpname role="rps" rules="dacs" source="naf">Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History
            and Culture</corpname>
         <persname rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Barbauld, Mrs. (Anna Letitia), 1743-1825</persname>
         <persname rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Allen, William, 1770-1843</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
