<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/barrierobert/">barrierobert</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Admiral Robert Barrie Papers, 1765-1953 <num>RL.00082</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: RBMBSL Staff; machine-readable finding aid created by: Noah
               Huffman</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000845083</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-28 11:49:39
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Admiral Robert Barrie papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Barrie, Robert, Sir, 1774-1841</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00082</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1765/1953" type="inclusive">1765-1953</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_9969428c241dccefd8db6f96c6061b3b">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_f7dade7c9d0d4aa7ab5dfbdeb609c608">Admiral Sir Robert Barrie
            (1774-1841) served in the British Navy and participated in the Vancouver expedition,
            1791-1795; the French Revolutionary and Napoleonic Wars; the War of 1812; and served as
            naval commissioner in Canada, 1819-1834. Collection includes papers relating to Admiral
            Barrie's experiences in the Vancouver expedition, 1791-1795; the French Revolutionary
            and Napoleonic Wars; the War of 1812; and his service as naval commissioner in Canada,
            1819-1834. Included is a small group of material relating to the 31st Regiment of Foot
            in Florida and Britain during the 1760s and 1770s when the Admiral's father, Dr. Robert
            Barrie, was surgeon's mate. Correspondents include Thomas Manby and James
            Macnamara.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_4892b3ad2187d2194e04bbfcef6a5dfa">
            <extent>735 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_9b9b3dad1ec02eaac2177b7fbd193d15">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_b33a10d7e64c80b797937f4e844c0b2e">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_99c1d396f927070f9e4b0902a057aa20">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_8165d04a5185b4923d9a7eead22e79de">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Admiral Robert Barrie Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_5905ae19729bc766bb432e17c1cb61e5">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Admiral Robert Barrie Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library as a purchase between 1966 and 1970.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_926323ab9b0cec3bbf3d67642030d942">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by RBMBSL Staff</p>
         <p>Encoded by Noah Huffman, November 2010</p>
         <p>Accessions were merged into one collection, described in this finding aid.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_3922ae3418c74d7fa26458f34b31a042">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Admiral Sir Robert Barrie (circa 1774-1841) of the British navy participated in the
            Vancouver Expedition, 1791-1795, the French Revolutionary and Napoleonic wars, the War
            of 1812, and served as the naval commissioner in Canada, 1819-1834. Barrie was appointed
            lieutenant in 1795, commander in 1801, captain in 1802, commodore in 1827, and rear
            admiral in 1837. He was nominated a Companion of the Bath (1815), a Knight Commander of
            the Royal Hanoverian Guelphic Order (1834), and a Knight Commander (1840).</p>
         <p>Admiral Barrie's father was Dr. Robert Barrie (d.1775) of Sanquhar, Scotland, who was
            appointed surgeon's mate to the 31st Regiment of Foot in 1765. During the early 1770s
            Dr. Barrie served with this regiment at Mobile, Pensacola, and St. Augustine, Florida.
            At St. Augustine in 1772 he married Dorothy Gardner, sister of Admiral Alan, First Baron
            Gardner. Dr. Barrie's death and the family's return to England occurred in 1775. Dorothy
            Barrie married secondly George Clayton of Lostock Hall, Lancashire</p>
         <p>Young Robert Barrie attended schools at Neston and Dedham, England, during the 1780s and
            began his naval career at the end of the decade. He and Harry Humphrys (d.1799), a first
            cousin, were members of the Vancouver Expedition, 1791-1795, of which Admiral Gardner
            was a patron. Some of Humphry's drawings can be found in the journals of the voyage
            published in 1798, and his own diary is at the Public Record Office in London. Another
            member of the expedition was Thomas Pitt, Second Baron Camelford, who later became one
            of Barrie's closest friends. Camelford was the brother-in-law of William, Baron
            Grenville, with whom Barrie also became friends </p>
         <p>The wars with France and the United States provided steady employment for the young
            officer. During 1796-1800 he was on board Admiral Gardner's flagship, the Royal
            Sovereign, and he, Humphrys and Gardner were witnesses to the naval mutiny at Portsmouth
            in 1797. During the next decade Barrie was an officer or commander of warships that
            fought the French in the North Atlantic, Mediterranean, and Caribbean. In 1810 he
            captured Lucien Bonaparte near Sardinia. During the War of 1812 he commanded the Dragon
            along the American coast where he participated in the blockade of Chesapeake Bay
            (1813-1814), the capture of Bangor and Hampden, Maine (1814), actions along the
            Rappahannock River, Virginia, including the battle at Fareham's Church (1814), and the
            battle at Point Petre, Georgia, with the capture of St. Marys (1815).</p>
         <p>After the war ended, Captain Barrie returned to England where he married (1816) Julia
            Wharton Ingilby, a member of the Ingilby family of Ripley Castle. The couple traveled in
            Europe during 1817-1818. In 1819 Barrie became commissioner of the navy in Canada, an
            office he held until the naval establishment was broken up in 1834. The family then
            returned to England and resided at the estate of Swarthdale in Lancashire.</p>
         <p>Captain Barrie unsuccessfully contested the seat for Preston in the House of Commons in
            1826. Admiral Gardner was the M.P. for Plymouth, 1790-1796, and for Westminster,
            1796-1806. Sir William Amcotts-Ingilby, Second Baronet, the brother of Lady Julia
            Barrie, was M.P. for East Retford, 1807-1812, and Lincolnshire, 1823-1834.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_019e294748d153252873dc2a1629884a">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The collection consists primarily of family papers in which some naval correspondence is
            intermingled. The letters of Sir Robert and Lady Julia Barrie are numerous. There are
            letters by Admiral Gardner, Dorothy (Gardner) Clayton, and various naval officers and
            members of the family. There are groups of legal papers, biographical sketches,
            genealogy, financial accounts, and photographs.</p>
         <p>Family relationships and associations are extensive and are represented by comment,
            legal documents, and genealogies. The families include: Clayton, Cornwall, Cracraft,
            Cririe, Dixon, Fothergill, Gardner, Humphrys, Ingilby, Lyon, Shuttleworth, and Uppleby.
            A small group of photographs includes Sir Robert Barrie, William Barrie, John and Olivia
            (Page) Fothergill, John and Kitty (Leadbetter) Uppleby, Leadbetter and Eliza (Barrie)
            Uppleby, Charles Clotworthy Wood, Swarthdale House, and others.</p>
         <p>The papers were still owned by the family as late as the 1950s. On Feb. 28, 1951,
            Charles John Ormond Barrie wrote about them to James S. Matthews of the Vancouver City
            Archives. Ten years earlier (Aug. 19, 1941) he listed several series of letters, some of
            which are no longer in the collection--correspondence from Lord Aylmer, Sir George
            Cockburn, Sir John Franklin, and George Vancouver. The covers for a few of these letters
            remain in the collection. The covers for letters by Admiral Gardner and copies of
            letters by Barrie indicate other absent manuscripts. Some papers may have been destroyed
            during Barrie's lifetime.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_6e0f552d888a67aa6b5ed88cac84154d">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>There is a collection of Barrie Papers at the Royal Military College, Kingston, Ontario,
            Canada.</p>
         <p>The William L. Clements Library has Barrie Papers from the War of 1812. They include his
            letters from H.M.S. Dragon during 1813-1815 and letters from Admiral Cockburn mostly
            during the same period.</p>
         <p>The University of British Columbia has letters of Georgiana Barrie (Sister Mary Gonzaga)
            from the Crimea.</p>
         <p>Correspondence from the Napoleonic wars is at the National Maritime Museum, Greenwich,
            England.</p>
         <p>The diary (34 years) of Barrie's mother, Dorothy (Gardner) Clayton, is in the Lancashire
            Records Office.</p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Napoleonic Wars, 1800-1815</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Canada -- History -- 1791-1841</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Florida -- History -- To 1821</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- War of 1812</geogname>
         <persname source="ingest">Manby, Thomas, 1769-1834</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Macnamara, James, 1768-1826</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Great Britain. Royal Navy -- Officers</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Great Britain. Army -- Medical care</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Barrie, Robert, Dr</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Barrie, Robert, Sir, 1774-1841</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref13_zv6" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Admiral Robert Barrie Papers, 1765-1953</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_580d340699a9108b9d3fe98bc8ff340c">
                  <extent>6 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_0y0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Genealogy</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_12518c14788dd8affa5abdf142e2af3f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_8hj" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Legal papers, 1765-1894</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3e4ee723a1067cfb5649f4e3944354c2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_e5x" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellany</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ca8090b18eac2b3d6dab5fdb2027cfb8" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_xaj" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f3df462a4fa38ffa107fb22b9ac96c3e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_4yi" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Biographical sketches</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3fd687ad8ea395df5be4f75ff7b27c7e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_yo8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Financial accounts, 1816-1885</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8d5c141674ba0e3087a44250bd3e8857" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_cx9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1767-1794</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c496e8eb496836bb190f6533bfa77e0b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_ohf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1795-1804</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1a2102221aed782c7fd8638be8b1b899" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_79m" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1805-1822</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_bfbf8a4f83504b21da442dbd13331ddf" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_1en" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1823-1953 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_85de111886353b8bde1a2ddd9ea2105a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
