<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/bensonthompson/">bensonthompson</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Benson-Thompson Family Papers, 1803-1936
          <num>RL.00105</num></titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: RL Staff; machine-readable finding aid created by: Meghan
          Lyon</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>2012</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000845044</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-08-20 16:47:57
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2014</date>
        <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported to
          Archivists Toolkit</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Benson-Thompson Family papers</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <famname source="ingest">Benson-Thompson family</famname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.00105</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1803/1936" type="inclusive">1803-1936</unitdate>
      <physloc id="aspace_9700e405599a57d6fce2fc8aebd36da1">For current information on the location
        of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
      <abstract id="aspace_9f81ef10972d8513b700502507d0990f">Recorded earlier as the Benson Family
        Papers. Includes materials from the related families of Elias Benson, physician, of Marion
        Co., Alabama, and John Ford Thompson, officer of the Alabama Militia. The families emigrated
        from Greenvilee and Spartanburg counties, S.C., to Alabama in the early 1800s. Personal
        correspondence and business papers of the Benson, Thompson, and Moore families who migrated
        from Greenville County and Spartanburg County, South Carolina, to Alabama. Correspondence
        between the groups in South Carolina and Alabama is concerned for the most part with family
        matters. However, political events are occasionally discussed, and a number of letters,
        1836-1840, deal with the Alabama militia. The collection includes letters reflecting
        conditions in Alabama during the Civil War; several items on medical education at the
        University of Louisiana (Tulane University), 1866-1868; and records of the Marion (Alabama)
        Grange, No. 95, 1873-1876.</abstract>
      <physdesc id="aspace_1e6416f3065ecf0aed85f03ac30afab3"><extent>864 Items</extent></physdesc>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_a12002fc6de2d6ba06595a7f975a6470">Material in English </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_1959fb2f60176999e46d2ed10fee74d2">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_9dbf971fa7e252cd1c753b78d8906ad3">
      <head>Copyright Notice</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_ce3e9d9296f33758f33a45dca34c562e">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Benson-Thompson Family Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_6a9ad0ff0bd3f2835f510f6dc0728290">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Benson-Thompson Family Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1959.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo id="aspace_7ee3052a0550e37ebb01b95d3b851182">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by RL Staff, 1960s</p>
      <p>Encoded by Meghan Lyon, 2012</p>
      <p>Materials may not have been ordered and described beyond their original condition.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_d769d8aeb9080b122fa215a470f2cdd4">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>Members of the related Benson, Moore, and Thompson families moved to Alabama from the
        region of Greenville and Spartanburg, SC. In Alabama several men achieved prominence. Nimrod
        Earle Benson was a legislator, mayor of Montgomery, and receiver of public moneys in the
        Alabama land office. John Ford Thompson was a brigadier general in the state militia. Andrew
        Barry Moore was a governor for two terms, 1857-1861. The collection consists primarily of
        the personal correspondence and business papers of the Bensons and Thompsons and includes a
        small group of items for the Moores. However, there is considerable official correspondence
        among commanders of the militia during 1836-1840. The families in both Alabama and South
        Carolina are represented. The papers have a wide chronological distribution, but they are
        more extensive for the period of the 1820s through the 1860s.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_01bcc61a7ae0b7cea50f1f8f8ddd7d6d">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>This collection is arranged into 5 series, based on format: Printed Matter and Volumes,
        Bills and Receipts, Legal Papers, Miscellany, and Letters and Correspondence. Each of these
        series is arranged chronologically. </p>
      <p>Dr. Elias Benson (1788-1843) was a native of Spartanburg District, S. Carolina, from which
        he and two brothers, Abner (d. 1836) and Nimrod Earle (1794-1854), moved to Alabama early in
        the 1800s. Another brother, Williss, remained in South Carolina. Elias Benson was at Marion
        at least by 1821 when the first letter of the collection is addressed to him there. A
        biographical sketch of Nimrod Earle Benson appears in Thomas McAdory Owen's History of
        Alabama and Dictionary of Alabama Biography (Chicago, 1921). </p>
      <p>The correspondence and other papers of the 1820s and 1830s are especially extensive for
        Elias Benson and his relatives in Alabama and South Carolina. Elias and Abner Benson have
        numerous letters, and Williss and Nimrod Earle Benson are also represented, especially in
        the 1830s. The correspondence usually concerns personal and business matters, but several
        notable exceptions relate to politics in South Carolina and a manufacturer and politicians
        in Alabama. On Dec. 5, 1831, Andrew Barry Moore (d. 1847 or 1848), cousin of Gov. Andrew
        Barry Moore of Ala., writes from South Carolina about the nullification controversy and the
        agitation throughout the state by the Free Trade Association. On July 23, 1832, Abner Benson
        is in South Carolina where he comments on the political battle between nullifiers and their
        opponents. Later on Jan. 15, 1835, Thomas N. Dawkins comments from Union Court House on the
        discord among the nullifiers in his county. He notes a general approval of the late
        compromise but expects the old party divisions to continue. On Oct. 2, 1838, Williss Benson
        of Greenville District, S.C., describes the circumstances of the shooting of Richardson
        Earle by William Lowndes Yancey who was then living near Greenville. A number of other
        letters are from either Greenville or Spartanburg. On Oct. 10, 1829, Nimrod E. Benson writes
        about a young attorney who is a candidate for circuit solicitor. This attorney, George
        Thomas Goldthwaite, later served as Chief Justice of Alabama and U.S. Senator.</p>
      <p>The Bensons were closely related to the family of Gov. Andrew Barry Moore. He was a nephew
        of General Thomas Moore, whose daughter Patsy married a Benson; this is indicated by his
        will. Family letters indicate that Patsy was the wife of Dr. Elias Benson. The early Moore
        family correspondence represents part of the family in the Spartansburg District, S.C., and
        is scattered from about 1827 into the mid-1830s. The most frequent correspondent is Andrew
        Barry Moore, cousin of Gov. Moore of Alabama. Benson and Moore letters of the 1820s concern
        the settlement of the estate of General Thomas Moore (1759-1822), father of A.B. Moore of
        S.C. and Mrs. Benson. Gov. Moore was a principal official of the Marion Steam Mill Company
        when it was organized in Sept. 1836; a copy of its preliminary articles of association is
        filed with the Legal Papers. </p>
      <p>John Ford Thompson married Mary Eleanor Benson, daughter of Elias Benson. He lived at or
        near Greenville, S.C., prior to his migration to Perry County. Letters are addressed to him
        and his mother at Greenville in the 1820s. He and a brother were educated at Greenville
        College in Tennessee during the mid-1820s. By at least the mid-1830s he was in Alabama. He
        engaged in farming, surveying, and business. From 1836-1840, Thomas was Brigadier General in
        command of the 14th Brigade of the Alabama Militia. He died in the early 1850s. </p>
      <p>Thompson has letters and business and legal papers throughout the first half of the 1800s,
        and they become numerous by the late 1830s. Various members of the Thompson family are
        represented. The most significant part of his letters concerns the Alabama Militia. He was
        commissioned Brigadier General of the 14th Brigade on Oct. 17, 1836. Thompson held this
        position until his resignation was accepted by Gov. Arthur P. Bagby on Sept. 26, 1840.
        During 1836-1840 the correspondence relates to various aspects of the militia and includes
        letters from a number of superior and subordinate officers. Topics include the militia code,
        militia organization, its effectiveness, finances, encampments, and future development. </p>
      <p>During August 1849 and 1850, John F. Thompson visited Talladega Springs because of his bad
        health. He comments on the accommodations and the company at this resort.</p>
      <p>On June 9, 1846, Thomas Benson discusses the raising of volunteer companies in Perry County
        for the Mexican War.</p>
      <p>Although there are only a few scattered soldiers' letters, the Civil War is well
        represented on the home front by the letters of Mrs. John F. Thompson. Letters are numerous
        for the early years and scarce later on. Mary Eleanor (Benson) Thompson writes to two sons
        and a brother, and her letters are interesting for their descriptions of wartime Marion. Her
        reaction to the secession crisis of 1860-1861 appears in letters to son Elias at the
        University of Alabama.</p>
      <p>The Thompsons attended St. Wilfred's Episcopal Church at Marion, and Mrs. Thompson's
        letters have comments upon it and the rector and bishop between 1859 and 1863. </p>
      <p>The young Bensons and Thompsons were educated at various colleges and universities which
        are represented in this collection. During 1823-1826, John F. Thompson and his brother,
        Beverly J. Thompson, attended Greeneville College in Greeneville, TN. Among the
        correspondence from this period are letters from their fellow students and the college
        president. There is also an itemized account of their school expenses. In the 1840s, Thomas
        Benson with to the University of Nashville, and correspondence from that period reveals
        tuition charges, political engagement on campus, and public events he attended. Elias Benson
        Thompson, son of John F. Thompson, graduated from the University of Alabama in 1861. During
        1859-1861 he wrote several letters, and his career is reflected in an extensive series of
        letters from his mother at Marion. Reach to the secession crisis is often expressed in these
        letters. After the Civil War, Elias Thompson studied medicine, which he later practiced at
        Marion. His medical degree was from the University of Louisiana at New Orleans. Elias wrote
        several letters from medical school in the 1866-1868 period, commenting on the Medical Dept.
        and its professors. </p>
      <p>The correspondence is not extensive after the 1860s, and consists of letters from various
        members of the family. Robert Benson Evins, grandson of John F. Thompson and a lawyer and
        legislator, has some personal and family letters in the later decades. Elias B. Thompson was
        an officer of Marion Grange, No. 95, of the Patrons of Husbandry. The collection's
        Miscellany includes records of the Marion Grange, 1873-1876, with quarterly reports and
        accounts from the period. </p>
      <p>John F. Thompson's diary dates from Jan. 1-Dec. 19, 1841, and includes a few entries for
        Oct. 1844-Jan. 1845. It is a detailed account of his activities and includes references to
        many people in the community. </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges -- Southern States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Governors -- Alabama</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Alabama -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Alabama -- Militia</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Medical education -- Southern States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Migration, Internal -- Southern States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Secession -- Alabama</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Nullification (States' rights) -- Southern States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Family life -- Alabama</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">South Carolina -- History</geogname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Tulane University</corpname>
      <persname source="ingest">Thompson, John Ford</persname>
      <famname source="ingest">Thompson family</famname>
      <persname source="ingest">Moore, Andrew Barry</persname>
      <corpname source="ingest">University of Alabama</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Tusculum College</corpname>
      <persname source="ingest">Benson, Elias</persname>
      <famname source="ingest">Benson family</famname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref20_jxe" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Letters, 1821-1844</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_f2aa5841b0a76bd0280104a43d841c02" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref21_uxw" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Letters, 1845-1936 and undated</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_216957935f750d641555877bf54772d1" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >2</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref14_84v" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Printed Matter and Volumes</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1840s-1910s</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_5506da6935a31ccf97fbe3119f74661a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >3</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_086a73f2d7b6031be67d02e7ba6a950d">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>Two folders: Printed Matter and John Ford Thompson Diary, 1841, 1844-1845. Box also
            contains 7 loose items: a fragile daybook/account book from 1836-1847; yearbook programs
            from the Inter Se Circle of Marion, Alabama; cashbook of John Ford Thompson (1840s);
            constitution of Carlisle Fortnightly Club (1907).</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref18_m7w" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Legal papers, 1803-1898</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_0fb31a13593a8a31183cfa86adeda112" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >4</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref19_bjd" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Miscellany, 1826-1919 and undated</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_005769bb2baaa6f97b0b2b164df9ee07" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >4</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref16_5vq" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Bills and receipts</unittitle>
          <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
              folders</extent></physdesc>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1820s-1870s</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_be180b8b1aba4c03088d353e85b2d18c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >5</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
