<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
         url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/bullock/">bullock</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Bullock family papers, 1784-1940s and undated
                  <num>RL.00173</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Don Sechler; machine-readable finding aid created by: Lisa
               Stark</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>1999</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000847110</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-11-01 16:16:46
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2017</date>
            <item>Reprocessed; description amplified and subject headings added to reflect topics on
               slavery, African Americans, images, and Civil War, by Paula Jeannet Mangiafico</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Bullock family papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <famname source="ingest">Bullock family</famname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00173</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 Linear Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">3 boxes</extent>
            <physfacet>Approximately 1200 items</physfacet>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1784/1949" type="inclusive">1784-1940s and undated</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_a0dcb68f8d417eddefc62f2ada5de539">Papers of several generations of a
            family of southern Virginia and central North Carolina, including Williamsboro,
            Granville County (now Vance), and southern Virginia. Fourteen photographs added at a
            later date represent bi-racial descendants of this family who lived in Nutbush and
            Manson, NC. The bulk is comprised of correspondence, 1820-1920, between John and William
            H. Bullock, a second John Bullock and his wife, Susan M. (Cobb) Bullock, their sons and
            daughters, and other children and grandchildren. Topics include family relationships and
            genealogy; illnesses and deaths; farming; slaves and tenants (including some lists of
            slave names); campus life at the University of North Carolina, 1850s; plantation
            management; market prices, 1850s-1860s; secessionist and Union sentiments in Granville
            County; religious life; the Spanish-American War; and the Civil War in North Carolina
            and Virginia, with details on camp life, troop movements, and the Battle of Kinston and
            the siege of Petersburg. Volumes include two ledgers, a travel diary, 1848, from a
            business trip to Tennessee, and Susan Bullock's diary, 1869-1871. Included are legal and
            financial papers dating from 1784-1876.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_446597f9caf707a67d4f0aba0e10fc89">English. </langmaterial>
         <physdesc id="aspace_38423c8d0f5a8f76a969d9771edd8c32">
            <extent>Approximately 1200 items</extent>
         </physdesc>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_d7c2732181d1e5616bed890652196edc">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>There are two families represented in the papers: a white family of farm and plantation
            owners, and a bi-racial family whose members were descendants of Bullock family slaves.
            The chief locations of both families were Williamsborough or -boro (Granville County,
            now part of Vance County), North Carolina, and the nearby towns of Nutbush, Henderson,
            Manson, and Bullocksville. Other locations where family members lived and moved to
            include Warrenton, Tarboro and Rocky Mount, NC; Clarksville and Soudan, Virginia; and
            Tennessee, and Mississippi, where the Bullocks owned land. </p>
         <p>The majority of the papers were assembled by John Bullock (1799-1866) and Susan (Cobb)
            Bullock (1803-1875), who raised a large family of children in Williamsborough, NC. Their
            sons and daughters, and their spouses, are also well-represented in the correpondence to
            and from their parents, and there are many letters from their own children.</p>
         <p>The influence of a large network of inter-related families from the same county and the
            same region is reflected in the correspondence and other papers: these names include
            Boyd, Eaton, Farrar, Goode, Hamilton, Tarry, and Taylor. Other names appearing are
            Harrison, Pearson, Martin, Morton, Paschall, Satterwhite, and Yancey. </p>
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_557cb8fbbb23883769046975b810e245">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research. The negatives are closed to general use; photographic
            prints are available.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_c71f4751d2bc7b91ef39359f701ea20f">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_5f5472d55da4e3b528e4d856f5349c73">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library purchased the John Bullock
            papers in 1942; a gift addition was received in 1998, and the name changed to the
            Bullock family papers.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <prefercite id="aspace_b6caf57bd3e0ca1491ca4b5c6f978588">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Bullock family papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_d13a9f4a5de381a9869bab1bc5fee054">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Don Sechler, April 1999; encoded by Lisa Stark.</p>
         <p>Reprocessed and description expanded by Paula Jeannet, December 2017</p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_adfb9b19194107c191d8924435047325">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Collection houses the papers of several generations of a family of southern Virginia and
            central North Carolina, including Williamsboro, Granville County (now Vance), and
            southern Virginia. Fourteen photographs added at a later date represent bi-racial
            descendants of this family who lived in Nutbush and Manson, NC. </p>
         <p>The bulk of the collection is comprised of correspondence, 1820-1920, between John and
            William H. Bullock, a second John Bullock and his wife, Susan M. (Cobb) Bullock, their
            sons and daughters, and other children and grandchildren. Topics include family
            relationships and genealogy; illnesses and deaths; farming; slaves and tenants
            (including some lists of slave names); campus life at the University of North Carolina,
            1850s; plantation management; market prices, 1850s-1860s; secessionist and Union
            sentiments in Granville County; and religious life. Of interest are 46 letters relating
            to the Civil War in North Carolina and Virginia, with details on camp life, troop
            movements, and the Battle of Kinston in 1862 and the siege of Petersburg in late 1864. A
            few letters are send from Johnson Island, Ohio, and a few give some details on the final
            months of the war in North Carolina.</p>
         <p>Volumes include two ledgers, a travel diary, 1848, from a business trip to Tennessee,
            and Susan Bullock's diary, 1869-1871. Also included are legal and financial papers
            dating from 1784-1876, and assorted other papers, including a list of about 40 slave
            names from 1857, and medical receipts and accounts.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <arrangement id="aspace_464fc999641929f30cec435ba9e169f8">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>Materials are arranged in the following series: Correspondence, Diaries, Financial
            Papers, Legal Papers, Other Papers, and Photographic Materials.</p>
      </arrangement>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Families -- North Carolina -- Granville County</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Family life -- North Carolina -- 19th century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Plantations -- Mississippi</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Plantations -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people -- North Carolina -- Photographs</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Racially mixed people -- North Carolina -- Vance County</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Slavery -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Slaves -- North Carolina</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Granville County (N.C.) -- History</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Vance County (N.C.) -- History</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Virginia -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
         <genreform source="lcsh">Black-and-white photographs</genreform>
         <genreform source="aat">Negatives (photographs)</genreform>
         <corpname source="ingest">University of North Carolina -- Faculty</corpname>
         <famname source="ingest">Taylor family</famname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Presbyterian Church</corpname>
         <famname source="ingest">Boyd family</famname>
         <famname source="ingest">Bullock family</famname>
         <famname source="ingest">Farrar family</famname>
         <famname source="ingest">Goode family</famname>
         <famname source="ingest">Hamilton family</famname>
         <famname source="ingest">Pearson family</famname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_d12204eefc8a53d54c777d1df2b94540" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11 folders</extent>
                  <physfacet>Approximately 600 items</physfacet>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate normal="1820/1920" type="inclusive">1820-1920 and undated</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_8beac7ddf5f3fa48226b21e09a1a9167">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>About one third of the correspondence dates from the 1820s to 1865, and two-thirds
                  dates from after the Civil War to the early 20th century. Included are 46 letters
                  from the Civil War period to and from members of John and Susan Bullock's family,
                  chiefly concerning their son Walter Bullock's service in the Confederate Army.</p>
               <p>Topics in the correspondence typically include family matters such as schooling,
                  illnesses, courtship and marriage, deaths in the family and in the community,
                  farming, sales of agricultural crops, religious life, visitors and local events,
                  and some business matters. There is also some mention of the Spanish-American War
                  in later letters. </p>
               <p>There are many letters from the daughters and sons of John and Susan Cobb,
                  especially from William, James, Richard, Walter, Alfred, George, Sally, Lucy, and
                  Beck. Grandchildren's letters and many letters from Beck to her mother Sally
                  (Tarry) Hamilton make up the bulk of the late 19th and early 20th century
                  letters.</p>
               <p>Family names also appearing in the papers include: Boyd, Goode, Eaton, Farrar,
                  Hamilton, Harrison, Tarry, Taylor, and Watkins. There are also frequent mention of
                  Andersons, Grahams and Hendersons. </p>
               <p>Place names associated with the Bullocks and their relatives are: Williamsborough
                  (or -boro), Granville County, NC (now Vance County), the principal home place for
                  the Bullocks; Wheatland, Tarboro, Warrenton and Rocky Mount, NC; Petersburg,
                  Soudan, Boydton, and Skipwith, VA. There are some letters from Tennessee and
                  Mississippi, where the Bullocks owned land. Other place names appearing include
                  Grassy Creek and Oak Hill, Granville County.</p>
               <p>The Civil War letters mostly were sent to and from Walter Bullock and his parents,
                  but there are a few from his brothers, several of whom apparently also served for
                  a time, and other people. They give details about camp life, food and diet, health
                  issues, weather, furloughs, troop movements, and rumors about events. There are
                  frequent requests for supplies from home. One letter bears a long description of
                  the battle of Kinston, NC, 1862; another from an encampment "near Norfolk" dated
                  March 1862 mentions a major naval engagement at the mouth of the James River. A
                  letter from June 1862 brings the news that a Bullock son was taken prisoner.
                  Another letter from John Bullock to a friend announces that Walter was taken
                  prisoner in June 1864, probably when Captain George W. Kirk and Union cavalry
                  overran Camp Vance (Burke Cty.). There is one letter from Walter writing from
                  Johnson's Island, Ohio, September 1864; he then writes several letters from
                  Kenansville, NC in early 1865, and describes the last months of the war. Camp
                  Vance (Burke County), figures most prominently in Walter's letters, who seems to
                  have been by then in the 68th Regiment, and Camp Holmes, near Raleigh. Other place
                  names include Camp Mangum, NC; Camp Arrington, VA, 1862; "in the trenches,"
                  Petersburg, VA, November 29, 1864; and Kenansville, NC, December 1864. There are a
                  few letters relating to Captain William Wallace White, who also appears at the
                  head of a militia roll in the Other Papers series.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_c9082f90d0e9b8d32dcef9d99e6f0475" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1820/1849" type="inclusive">1820-1849</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_867c02496bc9e99047fe66cc82b2e17c"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_43fa9e7700d2ae839001c1b876b1896d" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1852/1860" type="inclusive">1852-1860</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_15ef53ddbe67d876ee57d21939b204d2"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_3f3ade38b14c4ac5e89422bdc76a01f0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1861/1865" type="inclusive">1861-1865</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_ac9cef9858a044ae9a242af509b5ac61"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_8ea49a87787e68b408ffe90ec595d858" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1866/1878" type="inclusive">1866-1878</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_8f57ed9071b2d36b78b9fb43569ad493"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_1efcb9f2ba9ce45bb983ca2c08a680fb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1881/1889" type="inclusive">1881-1889</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_9bf16d7c44d755b85800b22dac55ad97"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_8609f7b17757331e2b31300a5eb7d6e9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1890/1892" type="inclusive">1890-1892</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_fb4c6aed8c3043c82c196460e01510e6"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_4ffaaac9295051db25f20d51b092eb54" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1893/1894" type="inclusive">1893-1894</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_025a7b8f2777c01ceec5d842147db119"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_9863183047573cf14bf165a32952778f" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1895/1898" type="inclusive">1895-1898</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_97f225496ee73885b303dbeead72d0eb"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_38821f4f61a9a80f04c0a241991f85b4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1899/1899">1899</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_cade9ad9b09aa843afc25030d5a2d1dc"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_04e3f2bdd86fdf8f7486cc51dba394f3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1900/1920" type="inclusive">1900-1920</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_8eb6dcb63976cceaac27181267faac4c"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_88a5ac3a75eb40072b50d5a2ce62d983" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, undated and fragments</unittitle>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_efc637fde318d826606665d0590954db"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e398fb8a6c0906260914f4d09ae5327b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>From the names and handwriting, the undated letters (2 folders) seem to date
                     almost entirely from the late 19th century. There are also some fragments in
                     the form of single leaves or half-sheets.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_39bcf5a202e0fca52724a85ad21960fb" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Diaries</unittitle>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Volumes</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate normal="1839/1871" type="inclusive">1839-1871</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_63f5e8151753a04369c3c0c16589b0fa">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Two volumes: a travel diary by an unknown person, probably a Bullock family
                  member, recounting a business trip in 1848 from Warrenton, North Carolina west to
                  Knoxville, Tennessee; and a personal diary (1869-1871) kept by Susan Cobb Bullock,
                  along with earlier entries (1839-1841) from a general store or other similar
                  business, probably run by her husband John Bullock, whose name faintly appears on
                  the cover of the volume.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_9cb1faffd93bd6e358a199cfe8cf12dd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Travel diary</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Volumes</extent>
                     <physfacet>46 pages</physfacet>
                     <dimensions>6 1/4 x 4 1/8 inches</dimensions>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate normal="1848-11-27/1848-12-23" type="inclusive">November 27-December 23,
                     1848 and undated</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_f6fbc2a7de018025943910a4667d2071"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9a1d293a0fb421566d5b5625047505f9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Travel diary by an unknown person, probably a Bullock family member, recounting
                     a business trip from Warrenton, North Carolina west to Knoxville, Tennessee.
                     The entries fill eleven pages and run from November 26 to December 23, 1848.
                     They chiefly concern the weather, distances traveled, who he lodged with,
                     landmarks noted (Pilot Mountain being one), rivers crossed, and the meals and
                     expenses. He traveled until Sparta, Tennessee with a Dr. Cunningham, a Mr.
                     Stamper, and a guide, a Mr. Ellis from Tennessee. They then took the Nashville
                     road, and he the McMinnsville road. There are few if any details of the
                     business that took him on this trip. </p>
                  <p>A list of county seats following the diary entries, and a separate chronology
                     in the first few pages of the volume of miles covered and expenses for each leg
                     (tolls, meals, and feed for the horses) appear to match the diary's entries.
                     From the chronology, the traveler seems to have continued through Atlanta and
                     then home to Warrenton, arriving the last days of December.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_86bcbe5f9ed0e1fe536bc35c6952a119" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Diary and account book</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Volumes</extent>
                     <physfacet>Approximately 150 pages</physfacet>
                     <dimensions>Approximately 9x6 inches</dimensions>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate normal="1839/1871" type="inclusive">1839-1871</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_161d83acd643f2db1d9cd4d13d056da0"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_17a694492d746a5a7ab451179f05c0ac">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>A multi-purpose volume, initially begun as an account book owned by John
                     Bullock, with entries from 1839 to 1841. The accounts, most likely from his
                     general store, are listed by the names of individuals, men and women, local to
                     Warrenton, NC, in what was formerly Granville County (now Vance). </p>
                  <p>About 140 pages of the same volume contain a diary kept by Susan M. Cobb
                     Bullock, wife of John Bullock. From January 1, 1869 to January 6, 1871, she
                     writes about daily life on the plantation and farm where the family lived. She
                     mentions visitors, the weather, illnesses, and religious worship and related
                     events. On February 28, 1869, she writes about her birthday and contemplates
                     aging, her husband's death, and the eleven children she bore and her feelings
                     about those who had passed away.</p>
                  <p>Other notes in the volume include about six pages of lists itemizing farm
                     chores performed by enslaved people, referred to by first names, from 1839 to
                     1840, and a shorter list of work performed in 1869 perhaps by former slaves,
                     also with first names. "Sam" and "Orange are among the names listed which recur
                     in letters and other papers in the collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_2959641e55c54a3b2d79e8afde3d8c0f" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Financial Papers</unittitle>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 folders</extent>
                  <physfacet>Approximately 500 items and two volumes.</physfacet>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate normal="1808/1876" type="inclusive">1808-1876 and undated</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_880338e7d35d4b7cdf11e2c4a156cdd6">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Two account books, and loose receipts, bills, promissory notes, estate papers, and
                  other financial records concerning the Bullock family, particularly John Bullock's
                  general store in Granville County (now Vance), and the 19th century farms and
                  small plantations of the Bullocks and other relations. Of particular note are two
                  1836 documents concerning the purchase by John Bullock from the Torrey or Toney
                  family of an African American woman, Kitty, and her three children, Martha Ann,
                  Mordecai, and Sally.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_97f4975b0e44d5029fb77b19340960dc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ledgers</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1808/1819" type="inclusive">1808, 1818-1819</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_f246a6fde20ed37498622957dea4bcd5"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_37dd9b25ababf22c306739526196c7b3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Two bound volumes, missing covers, listing accounts from John Bullock's general
                     merchandise store in rural Granville County (now Vance), North Carolina; the
                     smaller volume is from 1808, while the larger volume dates from 1818-1819. The
                     entries are listed by personal name. Several Bullocks are regular customers.
                     Total approximately 200 pages.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_d22ffe498cbdddfbd54a77020307327b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Financial records</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1818/1825" type="inclusive">1818-1825</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_da2b36de9f5732ed519b0c012415f5c2"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_14c54485c1e8c23a30fba7d45ed9f664" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Financial records</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1825/1829" type="inclusive">1825-1829</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_a4e4af3e2108911d3d107c65fbe152e5"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_0f4560167657dff264595a0cac8d48c1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Financial records</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1830/1835" type="inclusive">1830-1835</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_57e5b05bf08cebd078499eb3ab2a305e"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_7407863188777a116f197428a11d0773" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Financial records</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1835/1847" type="inclusive">1835-1847</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_a371a5b9eefca49fe645f04d4378857a"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_a0f6cc4c15276e810df067fb86345c87" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Financial records</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1850/1876" type="inclusive">1850-1876 and undated</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_6c017531c513f119b1c716cf1ae5ea47"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ed3acf559bf612afef824c9faa8527eb" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Legal Papers</unittitle>
               <unitdate normal="1784/1845" type="inclusive">1784-1845</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_82564c110f54d38e5c09887a94283080">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Series contains legal papers mainly recorded in Granville County, including a
                  handful of indentures and deeds for land, several summons initiated by John
                  Bullock for non-payment, a record relating to William Anderson's estate, an estate
                  trial for Dennis Royster with William Bullock as administrator, as well as a few
                  records pertaining to community disputes.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_fc08497d763b6eaf3f3f3890a7dc1712" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Legal records</unittitle>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_f893f7ac8769195098ff21a6966084f2"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_80d55b6e5f0b30fb94a25caeef1ee531" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Other Papers</unittitle>
               <unitdate normal="1834/1920" type="inclusive">1834-1920</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_8f3a1f072314e2bac0beaac607ef1f2c">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Includes a folder of medical receipts and treatments by local doctors, 1834-1837,
                  chiefly for family members but also mentions enslaved people and servants. Other
                  papers of note in the series include a list of slaves initialed by John Bullock,
                  1857; 19th century commodities price sheets from Virginia; and school grades and
                  comportment reports, with a few antebellum from the University of North Carolina
                  at Chapel Hill for the sons of John Bullock.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_c76ca4dbbb08439a9d21ff3d050ef7a3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Medical receipts and notes</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1834/1837" type="inclusive">1834-1837</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_ebb55ddcb5fa1046a88bfe214e9eea21"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_b0f464bb4a3d5b3255e900bd30a61db3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Various papers</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1829/1899" type="inclusive">1829-1899 and undated</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_e9ee66cec9120a59027d5b4e28d70065"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_302c8ad925e0652793617c46ad7fd9e4">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Folder houses an assortment of small items from the Bullock family papers
                     outside the scope of the other series. Items of special interest: a sheet of
                     paper initialed by John Bullock with several lists naming approximately 40
                     enslaved individuals, 1857; school grade and comportment reports from UNC
                     (1850s); a militia roll, circa 1862, for the Nutbush, NC 37th regiment, with
                     first and last names of 43 men from the area, led by Captain William Wallace
                     White (1825-1911), with Richard Bullock, Jr. appearing as a private; and
                     several published commodities price sheets from Virginia, 1857-1858.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_34eb4e291d3eb182595c484f7fd351b3" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Photographic Materials</unittitle>
               <unitdate normal="1900/1949" type="inclusive">circa 1900-1940s</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_c2aa33a88e2eb7380f2b4313af43b37c">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Acquired in the 1990s as an addition to the Bullock family papers collection, this
                  group of images represents African American and bi-racial descendants of the
                  Bullock family of Granville (Vance) County, NC. The earliest image is a head and
                  shoulders portrait of a toddler-aged child, from around 1900-1910 or earlier.
                  Individuals photographed circa 1930s and 1940s are the donor's great-grandfather
                  and great-grandmother Thomas S. Bullock (born ca. 1869) and Eliza Hendricks
                  Bullock (born ca. 1875); grandfather and grandmother George Bullock and Winnie
                  Russell; and aunts Alice and Sally. Other names are Elnora "Noda" Bullock, the
                  donor's mother, as a child. The portrait of Thomas S. Bullock as a middle-age man
                  was taken by the Flushing Photo Studio in Flushing, N.Y. Sally Bullock's photo at
                  age 16 gives the location of Manson, NC, near the Bullock family's original
                  homeplace. Thomas S. Bullock and Eliza Hendricks Bullock are listed in the 1910
                  census as a mulatto married couple in Nutbush, Vance County, NC. In other censuses
                  and records, they are identified as African Americans ("Negro" or "Black").</p>
               <p>The original photographs were loaned to the library in the 1990s, and staff
                  created these negatives and photographic copies. A set of paper photocopies of
                  some of the prints are labeled with individual's names. </p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_af7c66f210e2b8c8074e8d6f07214b2e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photographs (modern copies)</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">14 photographs</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">1 folder</extent>
                     <physfacet>14 modern black-and-white photographic prints; 5 paper sheets with
                        photocopies of images, with names added.</physfacet>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate normal="1900/1949" type="inclusive">circa 1900, 1930s-1940s</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_923e3740454cb7b2ddfb3d2bb5a2e9dd"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3e263321050ffe8fb5ebd6011c3de8a2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Dates represent original date when the photographs were taken. The copies were
                     made in the 1990s.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_065010159a48c8e19b23dac43b432039" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Negatives (modern)</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">14 items</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">1 folder</extent>
                     <physfacet>14 negatives</physfacet>
                     <dimensions>4x5 inches</dimensions>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container altrender="Document-Legal" id="aspace_4cbf7e2c8f31304c7455afc1ecb664b5"
                     label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
