<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/campbell/">campbell</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Campbell Family Papers, 1731-1969 <num>RL.00186</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;amp;
               Manuscript Library Staff; machine-readable finding aid created by: Stephen Douglas
               Miller</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000846361</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-28 13:37:00
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Campbell Family papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <famname source="ingest">Campbell family</famname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00186</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">20 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1731/1969" type="inclusive">1731-1969</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_54a845a33e3c69328c7ac0a97a02fd7d">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <physdesc id="aspace_b7846abaf198782051efbc7bd4641570">
            <extent>8,334 items</extent>
            <extent>37 volumes</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_2dbc9f481456703eeaeb0bc4e08e1693">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_1db09ef637a86b42e11f0303d94a82b4">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_7dc2ffc7f3f729773e24ef9367f487e4">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in the Campbell Family Papers are unknown. For more information,
            see the section on copyright in the Regulations and Procedures of the David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_1027ef8f6a31695478c2f866d8fd4f1c">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Campbell Family Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_2807cf120d73744b0aeb12b16dcf6b8a">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Campbell Family Papers were acquired by Duke University in the early 1930s to 1973.
            They were assembled as a collection from the papers of family members by Lemuel Russell
            Campbell.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_5121de1fe209d88346fe6a95c06b6e8d">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by: Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library
            Staff</p>
         <p>Encoded by Stephen Douglas Miller</p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_08cd8f1fe16f1393d2771c0d95344366">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The collection was originally called the David Campbell Papers, but was changed to
            reflect the presence of papers originating from other relatives. Members of the Campbell
            family represented in the collection:</p>
         <list type="ordered">

            <item>
               <persname>Campbell, David, </persname>
               <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1779-1859</date>
            </item>
            <item>
               <persname>Campbell, William Bowen, </persname>
               <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1807-1867</date>
            </item>
            <item>
               <persname>Campbell, Arthur, </persname>
               <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1742-1811</date>
            </item>
            <item>
               <persname>Campbell, John, </persname>
               <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1789-186?</date>
            </item>
            <item>
               <persname>Campbell, James, </persname>
               <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1794-1848</date>
            </item>
         </list>
         <p>Family, business, and political correspondence of David Campbell (1779-1859), governor
            of Virginia, 1837-1840, lieutenant colonel in the War of 1812, major general in the
            state militia west of Blue Ridge mountains; and of William Bowen Campbell (1807-1867),
            governor of Tennessee, 1847-1848, and member of U.S. Congress, 1837-1843, 1865-1866; and
            of their families, friends, and political associates.</p>
         <p>David Campbell (1779-1859), a deist and devotee to the reforms of the American
            Revolution, left a set of remarkable papers concerned with many activities, including
            education, politics, wars, religion, household economy, methods of travel, slavery,
            secession, commission business, settlement of the old Southwest, legal practice, and
            general mercantile pursuits. Included also are many letters concerned with the War of
            1812, in which he served as major and lieutenant colonel of infantry, with information
            bearing on quarrels among officers, inefficiency of military organization,
            courts-martial, lack of patriotism, and promotion of officers over their seniors.</p>
         <p>From 1814 until 1837, while David Campbell was political leader of western Virginia, his
            papers reflect his career, throwing light on state politics, state militia, affairs of
            the office of clerk of court, which position he held, many intimate details of the
            Virginia Assembly, in which he served, 1820-1824, and accounts of various journeys made
            to Philadelphia when buying goods for his mercantile establishment in Abingdon.
            Campbell's papers for 1837-1840 contain material on the common schools, the panic of
            1837, establishment of the Virginia Military Institute, Lexington, and the state asylum
            for the deaf, dumb, and blind. After 1840 his papers refer to his activities as school
            commissioner, as trustee of an academy and of Emory and Henry College, Washington
            County, Virginia, as justice of the peace, and as a planter.</p>
         <p>In letters to his wife, his nieces, and his nephews are many references to Thomas Mann
            Randolph, Winfield Scott, the bank and sub-treasury of the Jackson-Van Buren era,
            disapproval of emotion in religion, concern for the plight of the free Negro, and
            interest in historical works and literature. Included also are accounts of various
            Revolutionary battles in which his forebears took part, of the early history of the
            Abingdon vicinity, and of religious denominations.</p>
         <p>Letters, 1785-1811, to David Campbell include those of his uncle, Arthur Campbell
            (1742-1811), famous Indian fighter and Revolutionary patriot, containing treatises on
            democratic government; comments on thought of French philosophers of the eighteenth
            century; reminiscences of the Revolution; and comments on European affairs, especially
            the rise of despotism under Napoleon. Other letters to David Campbell include many from
            William C. Rives during the most active period of Campbell's leadership in Virginia
            politics. Letters to Maria Hamilton (Campbell) Campbell (1783-1859), wife of Governor
            David Campbell, from her father, Judge David Campbell (1753-1832), contain information
            on the early settlement of eastern Tennessee, government and politics of the young
            state, and information on Archibald Roane, his brother-in-law and an early governor of
            Tennessee.</p>
         <p>Letters of John Campbell (1789-186?), member of the executive council of the governor of
            Virginia, member of the state constitutional convention of Alabama, 1819, treasurer of
            the United States, and brother of Governor David Campbell, contain information on
            student life at Princeton College, Princeton, New Jersey, prominent men and events in
            Richmond, 1810-1817 and 1819-1829, War of 1812, John Taylor of Caroline, Virginia
            penitentiary, Spencer Roane, states' rights, Lafayette's visit, Jacksonian campaign of
            1824-1828, Virginia constitutional convention of 1829, Richmond Theatre fire of 1811,
            Andrew Jackson as president, Peggy O'Neale affair, storage of specie in 1837, rise of
            the Whig party, Washington gossip, and Washington bureaucracy. In the letters of Arthur
            Campbell (1791-1868), brother of Governor David Campbell and government clerk in
            Washington, 1831-1851, are accounts of mercantile pursuits in Tennessee; Andrew Jackson;
            Thomas Ritchie; and Washington gossip.</p>
         <p>Letters of James Campbell (1794-1848), lawyer and member of Tennessee legislature,
            contain accounts of his college life and studies at Greenville, Tennessee, law practice
            in Tennessee, settlement of Alabama, Tennessee legislation, literary and historical
            works, the theater in Nashville, and dramatic literature of his day.</p>
         <p>Letters and papers of Governor William Bowen Campbell, nephew of Governor David
            Campbell, contain accounts of his legal training in the law school of Henry St. George
            Tucker at Winchester, Virginia; law practice in Tennessee; services as circuit judge;
            activities in Creek and Seminole wars, 1836; small-scale farming operations; mercantile
            establishment in Carthage, Tennessee; firm of Perkins, Campbell, and Company, commission
            merchants in New Orleans; banking business as president of the Bank of Middle Tennessee
            at Lebanon; Mexican War; activities of the Whig party in Tennessee; career as governor;
            plans to prevent secession; bitter local fighting of the Civil War; and his career as a
            Unionist during and after the war, including his disappointment in methods of
            Reconstruction by Congress while he was a member of that body in 1865-1866.</p>
         <p>Of the many letters by women, those of Virginia Tabitha Jane (Campbell) Shelton, niece
            and adopted daughter of Governor David Campbell, contain valuable information on social
            events in Richmond while her uncle was governor; household economy; dress; slavery;
            methods of travel; literary works; conditions of Union University, Murfreesboro,
            Tennessee, Brownsville Female Academy, Brownsville, Tennessee, and West Tennessee
            College, Jacksonville, Tennessee, where her husband, William Shelton, taught; political
            campaigns; slavery; and a variety of items important in the social history of the
            period. Included in the collection also are the letters of Adine Turner, remarkable for
            their literary excellence and sparkling wit. Numerous letters from relatives in Arkansas
            reveal much information connected with the early history of the state. Letters of the
            McClung family of East Tennessee contain information on the settlement, growth, and
            Civil War in that area.</p>
         <p>Also included are papers for several related families, including the Owens, Montgomerys,
            Kelleys, and Newnans. Papers, 1811-1831, concern the estate of Hugh Montgomery, and a
            Moravian tract on that land. Letters in the 1830s include several from Daniel Newnan,
            U.S. congressman from Georgia, dealing with Andrew Jackson, Sam Houston, and political
            corruption. Letters of the Owen family, originally of North Carolina, deal with Daniel
            Grant, a Methodist minister of Georgia, 17881796, his opposition to the Baptists, and
            the disturbance of his conscience by the question of owning slaves; the Great Revival of
            1800 as described by Thomas Owen; and medical education in Philadelphia of John Owen,
            1810-1812, and of his sons, Benjamin Rush Owen (1813-1849) and John Owen (1825-1889).
            Papers of David C. Kelley include letters concerning his education in medical school at
            the University of Nashville, 1850s, and his service as missionary in China, along with
            his wife, Amanda (Harris) Kelley, 1855; several writings by him, including "A New
            Philosophical Discovery"; legal papers; and family correspondence with his second wife,
            Mary Owen (Campbell) Kelley, 1870s and 1880s, and his son, David C. Kelley, Jr., 1890s
            and early twentieth century.</p>
         <p>Genealogical material includes two notebook tablets containing copies of North Carolina
            and Tennessee wills, deeds, marriage records, and other documents pertaining to the
            Wherry, Bowen, Montgomery, Newnan, Campbell, and Kelley families. There are religious
            writings, poetry, leaflets, booklets, and clippings. Volumes are chiefly account books
            of Governor William B. Campbell. Also included are a daily journal kept by David
            Campbell while governor of Virginia, a volume containing copies of his wife's letters to
            him, 1812-1825, a short diary kept by William B. Campbell during the Mexican War, a
            diary of John D. Owen, and a photograph album containing pictures of members of the
            Campbell, Kelley, Pilcher, Owen, and Lambuth families.</p>
         <p>Among the correspondents are Joseph Anderson, William S. Archer, Alexander Barry, Thomas
            Barrow, John Bell, William Blount, Willie Blount, O. H. Browning, William G. Brownlow,
            B. F. Butler, Joseph C. Cabell, A. Campbell, David Campbell, William B. Campbell,
            William P. A. Campbell, Newton Cannon, Mathew Carey, George Christian, Henry Clay,
            Thomas Claiborne, I. A. Coles, Edmund Cooper, J. J. Crittenden, Claude Crozet, Jefferson
            Davis, L. C. Draper, J. H. Eaton, Benjamin Estill, Emerson Etheridge, M. Fillmore, S. M.
            Fite, William H. Foote, E. H. Foster, Joseph Gales, Horatio Gates, M. P. Gentry, William
            A. Graham, Felix Grundy, A. Hayne, G. F. Holmes, George W. Hopkins, Andrew Jackson, Cave
            Johnson, Charles C. Johnston, William B. Lewis, L. McLane, Bishop James Madison, A. J.
            Marchbanks, P. Mayo, R. J. Meigs, William Munford, P. N. Nicholas, A. O. P. Nicholson,
            Thomas Parker, John M. Patton, Balie Peyton, Timothy Pickering, Franklin Pierce, J. R.
            Poinsett, James Knox Polk, William C. Preston, J. A. Quitman, J. G. M. Ramsey, T. J.
            Randolph, T. M. Randolph, William C. Rives, Thomas Ritchie, A. Roane, Wyndham Robertson,
            Theodore Roosevelt, Edmund Ruffin, Benjamin Rush, John Rutherfoord, Winfield Scott,
            Alexander Smith, William B. Sprague, A. Stevenson, Jordan Stokes, W. B. Stokes, A. H. H.
            Stuart, Johnston Taylor, Zachary Taylor, Waddy Thompson, H. St. G. Tucker, Martin Van
            Buren, J. W. C. Watson, Daniel Webster, Gideon Welles, H. L. White, J. S. Yerger, and F.
            K. Zollicoffer.</p>
         <p>From <bibref>
               <title type="simple" render="italic">Guide to the Cataloged Collection in the
                  Manuscript Department of the William R. Perkins Library, Duke University,</title>
               by Richard C. Davis and Linda Angle Miller, <imprint>(Duke University,
                  1980)</imprint>.</bibref>
         </p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina -- Genealogy</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Education -- Virginia</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- 19th century</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Virginia -- History -- 19th century</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Governors -- Tennessee</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Virginia -- Washington County -- Abingdon</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Lawyers -- Correspondence</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Family life -- Virginia</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Governors -- Virginia</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Tennessee -- History -- 19th century</geogname>
         <persname source="ingest">Campbell, William Bowen, 1807-1867</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Campbell, John, 1789-186?.</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Campbell, James, 1794-1848</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Campbell, David, 1779-1859</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Campbell, Arthur, 1742-1811</persname>
         <famname source="ingest">Campbell family</famname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref13_4ab" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_3wq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1774-1811</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_dc69b3f97bad2a0c4ccedbd64d8993d2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_smk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1812-1813</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_39ed30e434f9d06f28dd050fd06eb1cd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_wq8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1814-1818</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3a8041762154e331a94b67b7d1ceef45" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_9rf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1819-1823</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_51efae03b10320f03428c39fe7ffd27c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_zsb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1824-1826</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4f33f1d1d53609f8a1d817b564edde77" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_2pj" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1827-1829</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a001b276d948d1c7f99397d0f7401d53" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_jfi" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1830-1831</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_80902e382be9689273bc2e9e9d5201b7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_r0k" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1832-1833</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a51d12bdbccc1982efa756e4c585b135" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_voo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1834-1835</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fe3f362d200b3f13bd6a40e024978ec1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_82k" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1836</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_197cdd46a5224390e4297d345e1a4e2e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">10</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_yp2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1837, Jan.-June</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_7922a037a4d1c1537c2e7f6994a30c96" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_6bv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1837, July-Dec.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c09718c6d44ca203dd29cfe3e7852c66" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_y67" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1838, Jan.-Apr.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d775faea686f0a0c845f1827e5106874" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_pmj" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1838, May-Dec.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_70c9674c09990accb683f61316964e4c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_xs1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1839</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_536cfeaed5b55e189fc10e9d19738fc4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">15</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_5nc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1840, Jan.-June</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_eab821db6f2e7a84225b38316cf5e048" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_v5e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1840, July-Dec.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_eb3619f3a0af2e731c8ed9914e9e29b1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">17</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_583" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1841</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5d4e85bd24fb7ca0bc7e0c221e31a6a4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">18</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_2vq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1842</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5d87d45675515681421d890b47de370f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">19</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref33_myl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1843-1844</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d50ff1bccb64e77e680c848e66eb2351" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">20</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref34_c4o" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1845, Jan.-1846, July</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9cd879736823b89eab5f899f03fe170d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">21</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_0b4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1846, Aug.-Dec.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2a3cdc658a2e7be05475a8e7a353df99" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">22</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref36_5yq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1847</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_616b0656ed2e6a3fbcc0f581a041e30e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">23</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref37_pga" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1848-1849</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d1f14c69aa5d9def3c41c96c754ca859" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">24</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref38_614" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1850-1851</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9194d747d24bcc926806f584bf4223ed" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">25</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref39_4xk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1852</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_334e8e226314cf0aee16ead216fc8a38" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">26</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref40_r8p" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1853</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4552cbb320e3df3f5d6b5c33a210fa24" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">27</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref41_sy7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1854</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b4dc5abf340a56cc844e5e849cff484f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">28</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref42_ndo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1855</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9afbca5f8603b5efd5dcb73f216d2266" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">29</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_ep6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1856-1857</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_995e3a4b388e8f13149b80f6d0808d1d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">30</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref44_g7q" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1858-1859</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5f3374b021a9266f532ff72f6ed50392" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">31</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref45_yfs" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1860-1864</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_806877cba3e14ec7ad197c074ade9dd6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref46_yeq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1864-1866</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_7619622d69e671bc6b75e5ff82d7d4a6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_v30" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1867-1938</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3e0ff16c7ca8b49806467d2737bae759" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">34</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref48_kse" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_faddb2d00c1bfc1ffa3605379fb43145" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">35</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref49_9kx" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref50_u07" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Legal papers</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_cdb3f41ed7c493016d1460a0cbf665fa" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">36</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref51_7yx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Financial papers, 1777-1849</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ed6292ac6135ffae8fc2dc02f3e924a3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">37</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref52_x7m" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Financial papers, 1850s</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ef1622c5524d06cd8bb9c9ab33bfc4b9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">38</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref53_erw" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Financial papers, 1860s and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_017baa1751ad317bcc8ff3ab13459626" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">39</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref54_6dw" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Writings</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0a3c2953313d876c5991419d42105600" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">40</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref55_hv8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Writings</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_90d5326c07854cb0250f2f460da9e9ae" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">41</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref56_ccr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Genealogical material</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_969758594119756ec1222998c1865e03" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">42</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref57_zzc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellany</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8e8c67c02d7276b8b5363ce4a1413348" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">43</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref58_7r7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed material</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5014212e3cd0ffd31c6dbe3958a25cff" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">44</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref59_4ct" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Clippings</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_690f683fb1111f793cf36f3bd363e30e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">44</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref60_60k" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Pictures</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3362d4c34c7407f54d7e09b021741458" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">45</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref61_1up" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volumes (mainly diaries)</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1574272f3d3aeb258e59de27d8602881" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">46</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref62_fc2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volumes (mainly business and account books)</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_dfc65ab6b42d2a5bf83e4e8886aa1bcf" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">47</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref63_jax" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Oversize Material</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref64_62j" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Clippings and miscellaneous</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_da4e7df900c39ca8be6c1100fe5cd2b5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">Sec. A OV4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref65_707" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Financial papers</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d4d08274eb2eb842065bd4d745e68c86" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">Sec. A OV4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref66_31b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Legal papers</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d73a3e6f5d003ece35b5492755300ae6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">Sec. A OV4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref67_cyd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_70d15752d1321bb1bd035f33ca91c9ac" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">Sec. A OV4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref68_tv9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Family chart, 1910</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5e38bcce7e344d065793d9f759b215cd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">SS:53</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
