<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/chalonerjohn/">chalonerjohn</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the John Armstrong Chaloner papers, 1862-1935
          <num>RL.00208</num></titleproper>
        <author>Processed by Paul Sommerfeld</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>2017</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000851094</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-05-03 14:19:23
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2014</date>
        <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported to
          Archivists Toolkit</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>John Armstrong Chaloner papers</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="ingest">Chaloner, John Armstrong, 1862-1935</persname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="source">
        <corpname role="rps" source="ingest">History of Medicine Collections (Duke
          University)</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.00208</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1876/1933" type="inclusive">1876-1933</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_281530522423f7871c1f376149cd40ee">John Armstrong Chaloner was a celebrity
        and writer known for coining the catchphrase “Who’s looney now?” in the aftermath of
        psychiatric experiments and own legal troubles regarding his sanity. Great-grandson of John
        Jacob Astor; from Cobham (Albemarle County), Virginia. Collection includes business and
        personal correspondence, legal papers, writings and drafts by Chaloner, printed materials
        primarily composed of newspaper clippings, and some personal financial documents and
        photographs. The letters, almost half of the collection, are concerned with Chaloner’s
        attempts to have himself declared sane after a four-year involuntary internment in
        Bloomingdale Asylum at White Plains, New York.</abstract>
      <physdesc id="aspace_e896b0235433c408713caa3e30d8424c"><extent>Approx. 6,500
        Items</extent></physdesc>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_a650d054792c77baa51727242ecbc716">Material in English </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_1754e4a8d409ac0ac0f933850b25c6c1">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
        research use.</p>
      <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_d5272b24f7a2c1bc5197ac74130c6ecb">
      <head>Copyright Notice</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_ca536946dde83f4450f939b2b7e88c65">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], John Armstrong Chaloner Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_b571d931b91f8910a6aca32a1e94e3a3">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The John Armstrong Chaloner Papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library from 1936-1954.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo id="aspace_44217466e50b7e06795d5bc9bc13dff5">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Paul Sommerfeld, April 2017</p>
      <p>Accession(s) described in this finding aid: 36-828 and later accessions.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_ab867e889d35077a094d584a0746057b">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>The John Armstrong Chaloner papers have been arranged into five series: Correspondence,
        Legal Papers, Writings/Drafts, Printed Materials, and Personal Materials. Correspondence,
        almost half the collection, comprises business and personal correspondence. Most the content
        consists of Chaloner’s communications and consultations with various attorneys in New York,
        North Carolina, and Virginia that address his multiple legal battles. Legal Papers consists
        of legal briefs, appeals, court transcripts, depositions, memos, and notes from Chaloner’s
        various legal petitions and trails. Writings/Drafts comprises manuscript drafts, notes, and
        some published versions of Chaloner’s assorted publications. Printed Materials includes an
        assortment of magazine articles, advertisements, invitations, flyers, and newspaper
        clippings. Personal Materials includes some personal photographs and an assortment of
        financial documents such as bills, receipts, cancelled checks, and ledger sheets.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_3ed9e73b3db88c2ba4421b24c5b23044">
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p><archref><unittitle label="Collection">United States Supreme and N.Y. Circuit Court
            Chaloner trial records [three electronic resources]</unittitle><repository
            label="Repository">Duke University Libraries</repository>
        </archref><archref><unittitle label="Collection">John Armstrong Chaloner Papers [147
            items]</unittitle><repository label="Repository">Albert and Shirley Small Special
            Collections Library, University of Virginia</repository>
        </archref></p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <bioghist id="aspace_50913a1ec111e7b0e22ba5702522f981">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>John Armstrong Chaloner (1862-1935) was a celebrity and writer known for coining the
        catchphrase “Who’s looney now?” in the aftermath of psychiatric experiments and own legal
        troubles regarding his sanity. Known in his youth as Archie Chanler, Chaloner was the
        great-grandson of John Jacob Astor. When Chaloner’s family learned he believed he possessed
        a new sense that he called the “X-Faculty,” they had him committed in March 1897 to a
        psychiatric hospital in New York. In June 1899, a court declared Chaloner insane and ruled
        he be permanently institutionalized. Chaloner escaped in November 1900 and entered a private
        clinic, where doctors declared him competent and able to function in society. He spent the
        next two decades crafting legal strategies to challenge his New York verdict and lunacy laws
        in general. His case became the cause célèbre for many leading psychologists. Continually at
        odds with his family, in 1908 Chaloner legally changed his name from Chanler to what he
        believed to be its original spelling. Chaloner reconciled with his family in 1919, when they
        no longer opposed his petition for a New York court to certify him legally sane, but kept
        his changed surname. </p>
      <p>Throughout his legal battles, Chaloner published almost two dozen books and articles on his
        experiments with psychotherapy and his stay in the insane asylum. Books like The Lunacy Law
        of the World (1906) attacked psychiatric medicine, which proved controversial within the
        field. Chaloner had also married the novelist Amélie Rives in 1888, but the couple divorced
        in 1895. After his escape from the asylum, Chaloner lived near her Albemarle County home for
        most of his remaining life on his own estate, the Merry Mills. Chaloner died of cancer in
        1935. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Insanity (Law) -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Mentally ill -- Commitment and detention -- United States</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
      <subject source="lcsh">Motion picture industry -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Trials (Malpractice) -- New York (State) -- New York</subject>
      <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Jastrow, Joseph, 1863-1944</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Rives, Amélie, 1863-1945</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Overman, Lee S. (Lee Slater), 1854-1930</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Kitchin, Claude, 1869-1923</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Gordon, Armistead C. (Armistead Churchill), 1855-1931</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Duranty, Walter, 1884-1957</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Choate, Joseph Hodges, 1832-1917</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Chaloner, John Armstrong, 1862-1935</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Byrd, Richard Evelyn, 1888-1957</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Bruce, Philip Alexander, 1863-1945</persname>
      <corpname role="rps" source="ingest">History of Medicine Collections (Duke
        University)</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_58b2046736beee5447987e9d8b7eb3a3" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitid>1</unitid>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1876-1932 and undated</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_c19e70d4feb9e3475611e61cde90da65">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Almost half of the collection, Correspondence comprises both business and personal
            letters. Most of the content consists of Chaloner’s communications with various
            attorneys in New York, North Carolina, Virginia, and West Virginia that address his
            multiple legal battles. The letters discuss his efforts to regain possession of his
            estate, verdicts from psychologists concerning his mental condition, the circulation of
            his sonnets on European politics prior to 1914, and congratulations on his receiving a
            favorable verdict from the U. S. Supreme Court regarding his sanity. Also includes
            content on the fostering of motion pictures for rural areas. The series contains one
            nineteenth-century typed transcript of a letter from 1782 regarding the Revolutionary
            War in Virginia. </p>
          <p>Correspondents include: J. W. Bickett, Philip Alexander Bruce, Richard Evelyn Byrd, J.
            H. Choate, Dr. John Staige Davis, Richard, Donaho, W. A. Dunn, Walter Duranty, John W.
            Fishburne, Armistead C. Gordon, James Lindsay Gordon, M. M. Habbiston, Charles Hartnett,
            Thomas N. Hill, Herbert W. Jackson, Joseph Jastrow, Claude Kitchin, J. P. Morris, Lee
            Slate Overman, W.L. Phelps, William D. Reed, John D. Rhodes, J. M. Stoddard, Morris
            Streusand, F. H. Treacy, Frederick A. Ware, J. E. White, Micajah Woods, the governors of
            South Carolina and Georgia, and with the Washington Post. </p>
          <p>Locations for much of the correspondence remain on the eastern coast of the United
            States: New York, New York; White Plains, NY; Concord, North Carolina; Halifax County,
            NC; Raleigh, NC; the Western State Hospital in Roanoke Rapids, NC; Pennsylvania Hospital
            for the Insane in Philadelphia, PA; Albemarle County, Virginia; Lynchburg, VA; and
            Staunton, VA. </p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_3bfa34d41c0f2d4e87651becdbd23498" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1876-1904</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="aspace_936456aee1441e8b5a87dfde40534ef8">15 folders</physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_77e73b25ce0da8dc1a0bc4dbba694a16" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_e4806b3342b391c5ef34b95732ac9a4a">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Personal correspondence with a variety of individuals. Also includes Chaloner's
              correspondence with attorneys in Virgina, New York, and North Carolina</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_fccfa37249eb50b6e612e5e121110b63" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1905-1916</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="aspace_9cc24176afa9b9e97efd8a4e66894a2a">14 folders</physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_a18078e1a1aa223f1401585e5123ccad" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_b89d3d6c57ed09e8c80f7b75e9b3699d">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Includes 1906 July 17 letter to William Randolph Hearst from Chaloner</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_95ca50d6e670064a52d45b67c8f81001" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1917-1932 and undated</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="aspace_4ada56f88f36035ba416a37e3d8b7dfb">16 folders</physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_8ccadd23528cee934fe1736dbcf4aa88" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_5dc29e312e5d5028c09ce94f13d0fae5">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Personal correspondence with a variety of individuals. Also includes Chaloner's
              correspondence with a variety of attorneys, mostly in Virgina and North Carolina</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_33c937baaa7d8b2ebcf7b5077751b981" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bound volume of correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d7f6dab6ce6dccecd590aa792475c451" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">9</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_44dea1ea52a3cf72f03b7c8ab4bb46c3">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Consists of nineteenth century tissue paper carbon copies; includes alphabatized
              index of correspondents with page numbers for their letters</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_09e3d8f8c25a3b54387e540d57b6b247" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Legal Papers</unittitle>
          <unitid>2</unitid>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1891-1925 and undated</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_0a792bd7fec2f172f2acf871bc5aefdf">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Legal Papers consists of legal briefs, appeals, court transcripts, depositions, memos,
            and notes from Chaloner’s various legal petitions and trails. Included are the cases
            Thomas T. Sherman v. John Armstrong Chaloner, Chaloner v. Sherman, Chaloner v. New York
            Evening Post, Chaloner v. United Industrial Company, and Heil J. Evans v. Omer B.
            Johnson et. al., Ferguson v. Crawford, Chaloner v. Society of the New York Hospital,
            Miller v. Chaloner, and William Dike Reed v. Chaloner. </p>
          <p>Documents within the series come from multiple courts and legal appeals, such as the
            Southern District Court of New York, the New York Supreme Court, Virginia Western
            District Court, West Virginia Supreme Court of Appeals, U. S. Circuit Court of Appeals
            (2nd Circuit), and the U. S. Supreme Court. </p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_1e03a4143aed2e1e0628fa81b18fc2b2" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Legal Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1891-1919 and undated</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="aspace_182073716ca78341d0192e7e6a8916ec">13 folders</physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_7ea75a6ac64eaf5e2d867c284c695634" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_7fcda26000c2b0d18dcde4f7f988a3a9">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Legal briefs, appeals, court transcripts, opening statement drafts, memos, notes,
              correspondence; includes the cases Thomas T. Sherman v. John Armstrong Chaloner,
              Chaloner v. Sherman, Chaloner v. New York Evening Post, Chaloner v. United Industrial
              Company, Heil J. Evans v. Omer B. Johnson et. al.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_824c963a5718a4b3b35ded1832148bdb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Legal Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1912-1925 and undated</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="aspace_9befd4e648602a7942aa0b23f392781d">8 folders</physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_14003a9eabfe557eed9f681cc70ba70c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_e3ee6a56e126afff8419c889a8176848">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Legal briefs, petitions, court transcripts, depositions, orders for Writ of
              Protection, notes, correspondence; includes the cases Chaloner v. Sherman, Ferguson v.
              Crawford, Chaloner v. Society of the New York Hospital, Miller v. Chaloner, William
              Dike Reed v. Chaloner, Chaloner v. New York Evening Post</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_3dd39a942646c162b79acb41830197df" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>California Assembly Bill on Mental Illness and Commitment</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1923</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_6f94880518200e231361432662f8927f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_bd49a2c1f78f12a348a172abb2647bba" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>U. S. Supreme Court Transcript, Chaloner v. The Washington Post</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1922</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_1e8d18848f04fcfe7543af04d9fc6dd7" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_a31ee45280446e52957c32a3e0dcc3a0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>U. S. Supreme Court briefs, Chaloner v. W. Gilmer Dunn</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1921</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_7362e0f789a34260f76f645f0f23b193" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_5fe702e2a82c463d72bee4003cc19090" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>U. S. Supreme Court excerpt of brief, Chaloner v. Thomas T.
              Sherman</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1897</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_8d8d46cbf927900fa64aa815c2f28b30" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_1b9233b4f43c468976aeb38bb23cfeda">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>From The Society of the New York Hospital</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_74af1035e375c31bb29be6ed3b5c498d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Art scholarships, Chaloner Paris Prize</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1891-1903</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c8503cebc02b3f62005dc6047d3c1d47" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_d977eb51fa77623cadd9fddf423e12a9">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Press releases, notes, accounting logs</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_10e707b1b40d1944a7d373f40849f211" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Writings/Drafts</unittitle>
          <unitid>3</unitid>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1903-1933 and undated</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_f86d7cc47779dbba24f7239b7400858a">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Writings/Drafts comprises manuscript drafts, notes, and some published versions of
            Chaloner’s assorted publications. Included are treatises on the lunacy laws of various
            states, Chaloner’s experiments in psychology, a variety of sonnets, and drafts of two
            plays: Robbery Under Law, and Saul, A Tragedy in Three Acts.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_fbe749d4f1d10aa9ad0024b3de4f978b" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Assorted manuscript treatises on lunacy law by John Armstrong
              Chaloner</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1903-1904 and undated</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="aspace_8178cb003505e2297cee5e24cca1f1da">3 folders</physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_0ba66679d5169155931dbcb871aa2dc7" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_b35ac3be7e2d508cf5dc0607398a07e0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"The Lunacy Law of the World: Being That of Each of the Forty-Eight States
              and Territories of the United States, with an Examination Thereof and Leading Cases
              Thereon; Together with That of the Six Great Powers of Europe—Great Britain, France,
              Italy, Germany, Austria-Hungary, and Russia"</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1906</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_ea5eaac70bfe048592f48bff3ceebe8a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_1b5a6f1a2e22ec3cdbf66a927619d3c5">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Manuscript drafts and notes</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_bba0d79ed31491574b14d033d03fde99" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"National Need of Lunacy Law Reform"</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1921</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_620ad671f2e0bad89cb72272f1fa8081" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_d52f713e5c4b6210b58a6441f54735cf">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Published lecture</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_a5b613023c85f25353671a694190cedd" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Assorted manuscript drafts and notes</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1905</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_496130c372f3a5f479a7d7266e0f5731" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_32fd5ba0599da7a26c07ab7b32fa5156" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Assorted lecture notes and sonnet drafts</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1910-1933 and undated</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="aspace_0e5ac155aa489430cde39d2cca0ad498">7 folders</physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_308001d7f1677697daf82c731caab43b" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_794b2c3839380acea4328723b0ebe03b">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Includes Saul: A Tragedy in Three Acts, "The X-Faculty, or, the Pythagorean Triangle
              of Psychology," "New Force in Regrowing Tooth," and various sonnets. Also includes
              1910 United States census data and Chaloner Essay Contest and History Prize
              manuscripts</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_1e8d86d56cf0deb74667bfcb690e5b08" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Assorted sonnet drafts, "In Memoriam: Shakespeare-Wordsworth-Lord
              Byron"</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1915</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_64e972669729badd22230eeefd10a153" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_1d42e486c68773b58c5f58e0e748cada">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Includes World War I news bulletin manuscript drafts</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_d5b5fd7b0b185262bdf5c8e3c065e42c" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"A Brief for the Defense of the Unequivocal Divinity"</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1923-1924</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_4649e3807c0fd853c4133e06a22d8f5c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_b0a6482df2967be59d3f9da17bdc1318">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Published lecture</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_9036f3c4298fbd8a42f24f1a052d1c72" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Hell: Per a Spirit-Message Therefrom (Alleged): a Study in
              Graphic-Automatism," and Chaloner's sonnets and their newspaper reivews,</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1912-1913</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c0ac6c9c67a943e0678f6755341677e7" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_5b8a0b01cf5b01ee2bc983aaeb67f603">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Drafts, notes, press materials; also includes indenture with Roanoke Rapids, NC</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_94ae2159e86d5da98bf5b1609f7af94d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Pieces of Eight: A Sequence of War Sonnets," "The Hazard of Die," "The Swan
              Song of 'Who's Looney Now'?"</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1914</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_203b522bbdd604b309c3638158d5887b" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_88963cd0b67991b5dde8a84308d9a18d">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Manuscript drafts, notes, press releases</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_f4d9ef2e83471c53f812995b46a791a0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Robbery Under Law Act I, assorted sonnet and lecture note drafts</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1922-1925</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e1ba3495567a054d047c194176fbcc47" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_9fbd5cdadcdce19410afed7eeb0e7d45" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Robbery Under Law Acts II-III, Cooper Union 'Rex' Lectures</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3ef84cfd67a7e29e689ef2f045b15fc9" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_f53ba518cbcbef03c20712218ad2ce9a">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Manuscript drafts and notes</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_9f080da99fa811132b96d73c5c1cae49" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Robbery Under Law, reviews of Chaloner's various writings</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1916-1917</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_5b0a584d9423a9f5deadfb268a83bd77" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_8d6e540d3397c4dfd5bef21d58ca2f20">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Includes assorted notes and drafts, newspaper bulletins from World War I, and a list
              of lawyer fees</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_21cba472789e8297a2802646cf939be1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Robbery Under Law revisions</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1920-1921</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3a59878b5fe174c0bf0003ade75326a9" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">7</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_95d4acdd1d4b91e42f14eebf1042ea76">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Includes interspersed assorted lecture notes and drafts</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_1eb126917e438259da42af8fdc0bb849" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Robbery Under Law reviews</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1920</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_1c58b189af96e3f166aab1a08a7b4379" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">7</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_7a4540b3d8e5e79e048e3b9c237f6d98" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"The Strength of Sin is the Law"</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1917</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_5564fb1c9c828be0fa24b4fcd827e4bf" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">7</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_f1fb29cf10b3b2eb00cbfbe4fb34a4dc">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Published lecture</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ac6d0baea3a4ea382ad1cd0088ba8541" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"The X-Faculty, or, the Pythagorean Triangle of Psychology"</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1907-1909</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c6c62f582133b89a62d03844581f41a9" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">7</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_f9f91deb2fbed42778f979a0c88e2d30">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Drafts, ledger accounting sheets; also includes drafts of sonnets from Scorpio
              sonnets by Chaloner</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_c0d220c7385c760181f4c308cddba663" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Printed Materials</unittitle>
          <unitid>4</unitid>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1888-1933 and undated</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_6a7384d73ba9ee6753e78e0ab13f4ed7">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Printed Materials includes an assortment of magazine articles, advertisements,
            invitations, flyers, invitations, and newspaper clippings. The newspaper clippings are
            largely confined to the career of Chaloner’s divorced wife, the novelist Amélie Rives,
            as well as comments caused by the popular phrase Chaloner coined, “Who’s looney
            now?.”</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_e7d859edd968c07eed10641eafc272dc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Assorted printed materials and publications</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1901-1931 and undated</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="aspace_542bf4f63de23bdaa5bda35bd1315e23">2 folders</physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_b8e81e3d6c20c818cbb5071b6beff935" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">7</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_33b28fbfed36dfbf833babad0455660a">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Magazine advertisements, articles, newsletters, invitations, flyers, Virginia House
              of Delegates pamphlets</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_f1c9acc3e48efd582dda99c478013a89" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chaloner Paris Prize Foundation pamphlets</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1919-1923</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_0b4524e258bdd18e0a3efe0279799cce" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">7</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_33bb660acb1995170ff1f0fedb7657b9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Introduction to Third Court Theatre Lecture"</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_09d632114ac4e63d77572bb53815151d" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">7</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_b49cf494fceeb950bfd2a87cdf58f9f3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Assorted newspaper clippings</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1888-1933</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="aspace_b2239337f6eddbde7cbc4bcdd1b2641b">7 folders</physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_84a5a3795a1a92c83751bf150bc6ee7a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">7</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_fc787ffd443a90db8f66d07366ad1610">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Includes clippings from the Chicago Examiner, Chicago Tribune, New York City Globe,
              New York City Journal, New York City Revue, New York City World, New York Law Journal,
              Philadelphia Record, Richmond Times-Dispatch, Washington Post, Washington Times</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_85733209699aad40191ef20f5360407a" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Assorted newspaper clippings</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1888-1933</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="aspace_56e8a2a7367a587848d5939ba1cec2a5">2 folders</physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_ac6b4b2b5a476bc2c7274bd9b191f1ee" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_bec3920ac63cf9b5c0ea087bf59cd7f2">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Includes clippings from the Chicago Examiner, Chicago Tribune, New York City Globe,
              New York City Journal, New York City Revue, New York City World, New York Law Journal,
              Philadelphia Record, Richmond Times-Dispatch, Washington Post, Washington Times</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_3c82b5ddd2430f3310f3dcb1af7c9661" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Personal Materials</unittitle>
          <unitid>5</unitid>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1902-1932 and undated</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_5525d6be22b75513038c9290ff243075">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Personal Materials includes an assortment of postcards, photographs, and financial
            documents. Postcards and photographs include snapshots, formal portraits, and buildings
            in Roanoke Rapids, NC. Financial documents include bills, receipts, cancelled checks,
            and ledger sheets. The ledger sheets include the finances for the Merry Mills,
            Chaloner’s estate in Albemarle, VA.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_7c93e807e0bb3bfdd9df759406151639" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Assorted financial records</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1904-1929</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="aspace_100e5ad8f25c93305524b783608c4cc2">4 folders</physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_007f2669c292a1d28669515118f2bf9e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_dc8b7f72fa4e920b228963499f46cbdb">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Bills, receipts, cancelled checks, ledger sheets and budgets from The Merry Mills
              estate; also includes diary fragments interspersed</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_68ba599157feb630759851589e1879ef" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Photographs and postcards</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1902-1932 and undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_257486d20e1190fa18840527cc00fa9c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_3e48f7f0415187ae7ad28f6d6d4e79c5">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Personal and family snapshots, formal portraits, buildings in Roanoke Rapids, NC,
              photograph of letter</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
