<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="https://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/cookjustin/">cookjustin</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Justin Cook Photographs, 2005-2016
          <num>RL.11357</num></titleproper>
        <author>Paul Somerfield, Paula Jeannet</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>January 2017</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">007708985</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-06-10 15:35:29
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Justin Cook photographs</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname source="naf">Cook, Justin</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.11357</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent>
        <physfacet>40 prints</physfacet>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="2005/2016" type="inclusive">2005-2016</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_9c389cfecd88e7cfc8f120c7671aeb5d">Collection comprises 40 color inkjet
        photographs taken from 2005 to 2016 in Durham, North Carolina by photographer Justin Cook.
        The images examine the intertwined effects of violence, gangs, homicide, incarceration,
        poverty and urban renewal in Durham. Their subjects include African American families and
        their experiences of death, loss and grieving; felons' struggles post-prison; police
        officers and religious leaders; and gatherings of both predominantly Caucasian and African
        American communities. There are also several views of the city of Durham that highlight its
        varied and changing architecture. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at
        Duke University.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_907ba353fa81369abb3abe46c5a57c36">Materials in English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_c0af7e19a86667819320749aa43a5a6a">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research. Images may only be used for educational, non-commercial
        purposes; any other use requires the photographer's permission.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
        research use.</p>
      <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_ca49ceb962ae30ab36fbbbf7ddf1a85d">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>The Justin Cook photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2016.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <arrangement id="aspace_fc49e166d1ad8b3a2d34c59e2ccfd049">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Prints are arranged and numbered in narrative order by the photographer.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <bioghist id="aspace_23a0a40b61ae97ee1c0094518ff1c818">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Justin Cook is a photographer based in North Carolina whose images document justice issues,
        and marginalization and memory in America. His work has been featured in The Bitter
        Southerner, VICE, The New York Times, PDN, on WUNC, and CNN. He works for editorial and
        commercial clients worldwide, including The New York Times, Bronto Software, National Public
        Radio, ESPN, The National Audubon Society, Education Week and The Wall Street Journal.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <prefercite id="aspace_0ff1d58dab7868ab99e68e7bc254cf98">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Justin Cook photographs, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_264072668eb45f3c481df98b622d1451">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Paul Somerfield, January 2017.</p>
      <p>Encoded by Paula Jeannet and Paul Somerfield, January 2017.</p>
      <p>Accession(s) represented in this finding aid: 2016-0308.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_0ff555f3b5f08294fe787fe4ab930739">
      <head>Related Materials</head>
      <p><archref><unittitle label="Collection"><extref xlink:type="simple"
              xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/grossmanwill/">Will
              Grossman photographs, 1969-1979 and undated (images of Durham)</extref>
          </unittitle><repository label="Repository">Rubenstein Library, Duke
            University</repository>
        </archref></p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_1833da85feed62095fa307f6f46e8f1d">
      <head>Content Description</head>
      <p>Collection comprises 40 color inkjet photographs taken from 2005 to 2016 in Durham, North
        Carolina by photographer Justin Cook. The images are a decade-long photographic look at the
        intertwined effects of violence, gangs, homicide, incarceration, poverty and urban renewal
        in Durham. In Cook's own words, "the intimate personal narratives reveal two Durhams and two
        Americas... While young professionals flock to one Durham and developers remake it in their
        image, another Durham, scarred by segregation, fights for the right to exist, and struggles
        to keep its young people alive." Cook's photographs have as their subjects African American
        families and their experiences of death, loss and grieving; felons' struggles post-prison;
        police officers and religious leaders; and gatherings of both predominantly Caucasian and
        African American communities. There are also several views of the city of Durham that
        highlight its varied and changing architecture. </p>
      <p>The signed and numbered prints are arranged in a narrative order created by the
        photographer and are accompanied by original captions. The first 37 are from the <title
          render="italic">Made in Durham</title> zine; three extra images have been included by the
        photographer at the end of the collection. The prints are all 13x19 inches in size, and were
        printed on Epson matte photo paper. </p>
      <p>Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <userestrict id="aspace_33174b84126c87c756169e129b225115">
      <head>Copyright Notice</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">African American families -- North Carolina</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Ex-convicts -- Employment</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Poverty -- North Carolina</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Urban renewal -- Social aspects</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Urban violence -- Social aspects</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Durham (N.C.) -- Pictorial works</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Durham (N.C.) -- Social conditions</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Durham (N.C.) -- Race relations</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Durham (N.C.) -- Religious life</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina -- Race relations</geogname>
      <genreform source="aat">Color photographs</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Inkjet prints</genreform>
      <corpname source="naf">Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_29b0f10ca0452fab392b3bfd3fa62286" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Made in Durham</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="2005/2016" type="inclusive">2005-2016</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_164496746220a6ae61d08f90a299aa3e" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Fireworks burst over the Durham Bulls Athletic Park, 2014</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_b94afca89c0908007bf89f9d9c78f86c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_e54188dcba6e7c84ebc8a73e7eb935be"
              parent="aspace_b94afca89c0908007bf89f9d9c78f86c" type="folder">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_d28b5a2892515e6bb99825f14d1b8e5c"
              parent="aspace_e54188dcba6e7c84ebc8a73e7eb935be" type="image">001</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_ebde77630c045238d687505ea15a7ceb">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Fireworks burst over the Durham Bulls Athletic Park in revitalized downtown Durham,
              N.C. on Independence Day, July 4, 2014. Durham's downtown withered with its tobacco
              industry, but has been revived by investment, hi-tech entrepreneurs, restaurants and a
              performing arts center. That prosperity has not reached everyone, however, and Durham
              remains economically and socially segregated as it transitions.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_d7e6ebc9aa4f9fa962a1f7e185e85114" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A mural of Durham's historic African-American Hayti Community,
              undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_d600b9a5f94eb33d5dc52d8efa5da5e8" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_e387696d2fd864ede1cba6c12200ccff"
              parent="aspace_d600b9a5f94eb33d5dc52d8efa5da5e8" type="folder">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_a1c0ba70d28fa086a951f3a9a686d195"
              parent="aspace_e387696d2fd864ede1cba6c12200ccff" type="image">002</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_a3e2ae92f6d90725520c18929d2297b1">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>A mural of Durham's historic African-American Hayti Community at the Heritage Square
              shopping center is disintegrating. Older residents say Hayti was ruined in the 1960s
              and 1970s by urban renewal projects including the Durham Freeway, which cut off
              thriving black businesses from downtown. Others suggest that Hayti was already
              declining through unemployment and people leaving the neighborhood and that its demise
              was inevitable.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_9530bb14457fe455dd521499490017db" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Kalin Swinney pauses by the casket of his first cousin, 9-year-old Jaeden
              Sharpe, at Beechwood Cemetery, 2014</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_f39e7ffcbe59668ea6fbfdb3183ae457" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_4e9bd2a3db0280fd4c95116480aca821"
              parent="aspace_f39e7ffcbe59668ea6fbfdb3183ae457" type="folder">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_2a8163d1e03dd244175cfed5c33a5ff8"
              parent="aspace_4e9bd2a3db0280fd4c95116480aca821" type="image">003</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_897ad44c2e855fb6ea756ce08fc9cde0">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Kalin Swinney pauses by the casket of his first cousin, 9-year-old Jaeden Sharpe, at
              Beechwood Cemetery. Jaeden was shot in the head and his mother, in the face, as they
              sat in her car near their home on Jan. 4, 2014. He died Jan. 9. His murder was the
              first of 2014 in Durham. Nationally, the leading cause of death for black males ages
              15 to 34 is homicide, according to the Center for Disease Control and Prevention. From
              2009 to 2012, Durham's homicide rate for black males ages 15 to 34 was about eight
              times the national rate. Seventy three percent of gun-homicide victims ages 15 to 34
              were black; 3 percent were white. Eighty-three percent of gun-involved aggravated
              assault victims were black; 8 percent were white, according to an April 2015 U.S.
              Department of Justice report.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_5652e31f677784529d899e12bdcb2f3b" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Joslin Simms, [...] weeps at the corner of Broad and Leon streets where her
              son, Rayburn, 30, was shot to death on May 21, 2005, 2015</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_ab357870cf70e916a764721f1784250a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_b38b7772a6472537b5b8d238091cca61"
              parent="aspace_ab357870cf70e916a764721f1784250a" type="folder">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_a337619f6532fef653430e3efcc01322"
              parent="aspace_b38b7772a6472537b5b8d238091cca61" type="image">004</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_afb024ac4ee6cd2262b07027997cbae0">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>"Since Ray been murdered, I have nightmares. I dream of him in the morgue and when
              they are cutting his body I wake up because I can feel the knife cutting me," says
              Joslin Simms, who weeps at the corner of Broad and Leon streets where her son,
              Rayburn, 30, was shot to death on May 21, 2005. The case remains unsolved. Ray left
              behind four children and a devastated mother. A decade later, Joslin limps along
              maimed by grief and depression. She calls it a "walking death."</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_518aa6d2270a15f19496e50d7e11034c" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Joslin at her son's grave in Beechwood Cemetery, in 2007</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_70660f88331fc453f23a7f5793fc26ff" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_4a19fb388641b04598512933aa6e61f2"
              parent="aspace_70660f88331fc453f23a7f5793fc26ff" type="folder">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_d6cc25f0c61717517b7b38127d6920da"
              parent="aspace_4a19fb388641b04598512933aa6e61f2" type="image">005</container>
          </did>
          <separatedmaterial id="aspace_4f983c73c917d6b9b49805cbb0c49b6e">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>"I just want to go dig up his body so I can touch his face one more time," says
              Joslin at her son's grave in Beechwood Cemetery, in 2007. Her imagination leaves her
              restless. She sees Ray's face on the young men walking down her street; "Ray! Ray!"
              she calls out to them, but when she blinks, their features morph, and suddenly they
              are not him.</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_5fe054097adfbc913e17ab8875ebce89" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Gang graffiti near the intersection of Vale and Clay streets in
              2005</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_dd6ef3aa96153a568d0a3ea9cea1ea91" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_1a6f60df8d7775e448d27bd5b261713b"
              parent="aspace_dd6ef3aa96153a568d0a3ea9cea1ea91" type="folder">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_7818a59e86654671ce7d7f46868707dd"
              parent="aspace_1a6f60df8d7775e448d27bd5b261713b" type="image">006</container>
          </did>
          <separatedmaterial id="aspace_75e930036b4a68f04a084a4465ad839e">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Gang graffiti near the intersection of Vale and Clay streets in 2005. East Durham's
              Census Tract 10.01 is 67 percent African-American, has a 45 percent poverty rate, a 19
              percent unemployment rate, and a per capita annual income of $10,126 according to U.S.
              Census American Community Survey 2013 five-year estimates. Nationally, two-thirds of
              people in jails report annual incomes below $12,000 prior to arrest. DATA SOURCE:
              RACHEL L. MCCLEAN AND MICHAEL D. THOMPSON, REPAYING DEBTS (2007).</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_1ad7376519e56c73309119be4833b0b8" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>On house arrest for failing to pay his restitution, Rashard Johnson is afraid
              to set off his monitoring anklet, so he keeps one foot in the house while he smokes a
              cigarette..., 2012</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_bc10ad38e3488d83fd759da84f43dc6e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_0532de81f5fe84192b1efaeede072054"
              parent="aspace_bc10ad38e3488d83fd759da84f43dc6e" type="folder">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_3f6904b20dbf309eb69f45ecd08e54c1"
              parent="aspace_0532de81f5fe84192b1efaeede072054" type="image">007</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_2105d251d3f33eae27d930d075fbbe4f">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>On house arrest for failing to pay his restitution, Rashard Johnson is afraid to set
              off his monitoring anklet, so he keeps one foot in the house while he smokes a
              cigarette in 2012. Rashard never knew his dad, and his mother did the best she could
              to make ends meet. He ran away from home, and at 16 he was arrested and charged as an
              adult for breaking into houses and possession of stolen goods. By 18, he was convicted
              of many nonviolent felonies. In 2012, when this image was taken, he had escaped gang
              life. He wanted to start over, and use his past to help other young black men. But
              Rashard's felonies follow him wherever he goes. These convictions make it difficult
              for ex-offenders to find a job, a place to live, to get an education and live a stable
              life. How will Rashard become more than his past if he is perpetually punished for his
              mistakes? North Carolina and New York are the only states that still prosecute 16-year
              olds as adults in felony cases. Durham recently passed an initiative banning the check
              box on employment applications that ask whether the applicant has been convicted of a
              crime or been incarcerated.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_87ddb93a81ee814f18d19c8e613b1a54" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Young men who identify as Crips gather in a circle and spill liquor to mourn
              Maurice Streeter, who was shot and killed in April 2013, undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_f50475dab43681775bc96ada64dc2e34" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_05669dfed860a30f84002c25b4d2763e"
              parent="aspace_f50475dab43681775bc96ada64dc2e34" type="folder">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_f94162dbdbd82069e25936ebfa328f1f"
              parent="aspace_05669dfed860a30f84002c25b4d2763e" type="image">008</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_2b95368708226d3bd6f89f26df48be1b">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Young men who identify as Crips gather in a circle and spill liquor to mourn Maurice
              Streeter, who was shot and killed in April 2013. Gangs offer young people a sense of
              purpose and family in neighborhoods torn apart by poverty and incarceration. The drug
              markets they often enforce are a substitute for a mainstream economy, from which they
              are often excluded.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_6727216338b96eefe809f308c7ba31b5" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Gloria Streeter's funeral, August 2014</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_17b348585203f8de5b9856569e71b3d0" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_3bf65b82e74735bdaf184687aa0888ef"
              parent="aspace_17b348585203f8de5b9856569e71b3d0" type="folder">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_f05efdc40a9fc689c4eaec5dc23c631f"
              parent="aspace_3bf65b82e74735bdaf184687aa0888ef" type="image">009</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_0658dded4a9c3cbd8ca3fec0333629ea">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Gloria Streeter's funeral, August 2014. Gloria died after complications from a
              stroke. Her son, Maurice, was killed in April 2013. Her family says she never got over
              her son's death, and a broken heart contributed to her demise.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_04b9cbbbaf8af90751790276b15dd44a" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Mothers of murder victims and memorials to the slain in Durham,
              undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_68ee876df3a5f32aafa8c887a3d51400" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_555eee45738e9cf86ab7e35fc73439f8"
              parent="aspace_68ee876df3a5f32aafa8c887a3d51400" type="folder">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_a0ae969ee6cb6eb61819cbe3ad7484e5"
              parent="aspace_555eee45738e9cf86ab7e35fc73439f8" type="image">010</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_a716636afef34df816c4b430be10d91d">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Mothers of murder victims and memorials to the slain in Durham. FROM TOP LEFT TO
              RIGHT: Nyron Robinson, 17, who died after allegedly crashing a stolen car in 2011;
              Joslin Simms, mother of Ray Simms, 30, shot and killed in May 2005; Zacchaeus Kejuan
              Ormond, 26, shot and killed in August 2012; a mural for JeJuan Jonteil Taylor Jr., 19,
              shot to death in April 2013; Tauarus Hamlett, 28, and James Webb, 24, shot and killed
              in August 2005; Effie Steele, president of The Religious Coalition for a Nonviolent
              Durham and mother of Ebony Robinson 21, shot and killed along with her unborn son,
              Elijah, in 2007; Dennis Lamb, 23, shot to death in August 2012; Keisha Holloway,
              mother of Jaeden Sharpe, 9, shot and killed in January 2014; Lensy Arnett Gill, III,
              23, shot and killed in January 2015; Carrie Watkins, whose daughter Carrie Denise
              Watkins was shot and killed in 2008; Breon McCallum, 18, shot and killed in August
              2014; Bonnie Turner, mother of Jeremy Turner, 19, shot and killed in May 2011; Thomas
              George Docher Jr., 29, shot and killed in June 2015; Frederick Edgerton, 52, shot to
              death in May 2015; Delonta Hart, 16, shot to death in January 2015; Bonita Scarlett,
              mother of Nigel Scarlett, who was shot and killed in December 2011; Kaaylon Pamplin,
              17, shot and killed in October 2012; Jonathan Tyrick Moore, 19, shot and killed in
              November 2013; Anthony Tramaine Glenn, 37, shot and killed in June 2015; Mohammed
              Arfan Sundal, 51, shot and killed in December 2012; and Gloria Streeter, mother of
              Maurice Streeter, shot and killed in April 2013.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_341f452d4c8517cca3e44b1965a1010a" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Crosses from a memorial to homicide victims stacked inside The Shepherd's
              House, United Methodist Church in East Durham in 2013</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_ab3fbf0aa707a4972ba0a9ff947303c9" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_866dd3460abdae72bdad1c7eb65d4004"
              parent="aspace_ab3fbf0aa707a4972ba0a9ff947303c9" type="folder">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_e1d212c001fed64b1b5038e3cbee90c6"
              parent="aspace_866dd3460abdae72bdad1c7eb65d4004" type="image">011</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_7de5f14c2d5aa762d1c1470ace2e9e76">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Crosses from a memorial to homicide victims stacked inside The Shepherd's House,
              United Methodist Church in East Durham in 2013. Shepherd's House is dedicated to
              nonviolence and reconciliation.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_24bd8ba912169f7c21f5c33c6714c16c" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Rayburn Antonio Demarcus Simms is featured among 51 other unsolved Durham
              homicides in a deck of playing cards designed to generate leads in cold murder cases,
              undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_bca993e6d7806fa2e06bea592cf4aee0" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_7b1bcef9ca33d66a7736315dc57df1e4"
              parent="aspace_bca993e6d7806fa2e06bea592cf4aee0" type="folder">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_cc45f1581379d645f8ab9511a5fcbfa7"
              parent="aspace_7b1bcef9ca33d66a7736315dc57df1e4" type="image">012</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_609bcc0afe1586caae0c1ab77a615eb2">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Rayburn Antonio Demarcus Simms is featured among 51 other unsolved Durham homicides
              in a deck of playing cards designed to generate leads in cold murder cases. According
              to Durham Police, there are more than 150 unsolved homicides in Durham stretching back
              to the 1990s. Distrust of the police and fear of retaliation for snitching discourages
              many African-American witnesses from coming forward, and prevents murders from being
              solved.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_2d4730c43979af387097b0d3a9bf88c5" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>The remains of Fayette Place public housing project on Fayetteville Street in
              2011</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_7f93ec5496e4baba1e2dda4e4e6c433e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_a52d6c0ac02c5344053ee5743f4290fa"
              parent="aspace_7f93ec5496e4baba1e2dda4e4e6c433e" type="folder">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_def84fe34bdfe34f7a930ac9e6931796"
              parent="aspace_a52d6c0ac02c5344053ee5743f4290fa" type="image">013</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_0400df52d66d66ae937de6b6d2006064">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The remains of Fayette Place public housing project on Fayetteville Street in 2011.
              The 20-acre property, which used to be home to low-income families, has been vacant
              since 2007. The property was purchased by a developer that planned to turn it into
              affordable housing for N.C. Central University students. But by 2015, nothing has been
              done with the property where 200 apartments once stood. There is an acute affordable
              housing shortage in Durham County, and fewer low-income, working-class families can
              find a home. There are 8,358 total subsidized units in the county, but only 111
              available according to Durham County Open Data from February, 2015.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_2be6a2049f8c627baf4b0a35d08543cb" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>After a drug raid in 2005, a member of the Durham Police Department Selective
              Enforcement Team escorts a child to the bathroom</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_a9dcb9b7f796e0d1a6f1b10ef666c878" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_97ff4d07dc1be4ce32a704b05e5d50ad"
              parent="aspace_a9dcb9b7f796e0d1a6f1b10ef666c878" type="folder">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_3ef83224fe600c519e883fdbd2d69693"
              parent="aspace_97ff4d07dc1be4ce32a704b05e5d50ad" type="image">014</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_d9e16e533623cd265589e455363d37d6">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>After a drug raid in 2005, a member of the Durham Police Department Selective
              Enforcement Team escorts a child to the bathroom. His mother was temporarily detained
              during the search of the home and couldn't tend to him. Through raids, officers hope
              to recover illegal or stolen guns, and disrupt drug trafficking and gang activity.
              Some residents welcome the raids; others complain that they terrorize the
              neighborhood, and that police efforts should focus on solving murders and other
              violent crimes. Many SET officers have children, and none of them like it when kids
              are caught in the middle of drug raids.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_c31d7ae3b2fa7ceccf7e86165e00e8d2" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Rashard Johnson at the Durham County Detention Center after being arrested
              for cutting off his house arrest ankle monitor, violating his probation, and going on
              the run for two months, undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_2b07ad230e0e53e50634c5e2ea4ef505" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_d4d3cedd1809ac1889b7abb862977ea1"
              parent="aspace_2b07ad230e0e53e50634c5e2ea4ef505" type="folder">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_2a97b673577fba4a63c375c292a102c1"
              parent="aspace_d4d3cedd1809ac1889b7abb862977ea1" type="image">015</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_57f2f9d2952345f225fc50ab3ffc559b">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Rashard Johnson at the Durham County Detention Center after being arrested for
              cutting off his house arrest ankle monitor, violating his probation, and going on the
              run for two months. Without a GED or a job, Rashard couldn't repay his restitution and
              succumbed to frustration in 2012.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_c206af568bed91de5c51c0f110e0df0c" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A squirt gun war breaks out before a foot race outside of Fullsteam Brewery
              at the edge of the gentrifying Cleveland-Holloway and Old Five Points neighborhoods in
              Northeast Central Durham, undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_2b3b9146a6320a0d55ed9b6c5520faf3" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_38f84ec88ce64e6737de62995053c6ef"
              parent="aspace_2b3b9146a6320a0d55ed9b6c5520faf3" type="folder">4</container>
            <container id="aspace_5108467cfb745fdaff2931d070f9ebd2"
              parent="aspace_38f84ec88ce64e6737de62995053c6ef" type="image">016</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_dfb2f69a2aac4da82a4f0ce0d1e8c088">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>A squirt gun war breaks out before a foot race outside of Fullsteam Brewery at the
              edge of the gentrifying Cleveland-Holloway and Old Five Points neighborhoods in
              Northeast Central Durham. After a first wave of reinvestment by the City and
              developers, an area once riddled with vacant and abandoned homes, businesses, and lots
              now buzzes with energy again as a hub for creatives and foodies. The neighborhood is
              rapidly changing, but many wonder, 'Into what, and for whom?'</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_97fa0c046925f058140e6a0d082e23a7" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Blood stains remain hours after a bystander was killed by a stray bullet in
              East Durham, undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_fd2c3ac8b740ac4cf4a27a264fe9bd22" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_400ad381a9dd56700b289488943f756d"
              parent="aspace_fd2c3ac8b740ac4cf4a27a264fe9bd22" type="folder">4</container>
            <container id="aspace_9f8edabb52f1d251d3ba8bc56342879f"
              parent="aspace_400ad381a9dd56700b289488943f756d" type="image">017</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_b9007f188033ffee9d3090450d7d4e69" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Congregants of Mount Gilead Baptist Church, led by Pastor Sanders Tate (far
              right), pray for peace at an East Durham intersection at the beginning of the 2013
              school year</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_2762ec2bbc80b2135ebbd67cdae2c8f7" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_23d6a6cb497b4a99451c5aa42cfc61f1"
              parent="aspace_2762ec2bbc80b2135ebbd67cdae2c8f7" type="folder">4</container>
            <container id="aspace_060aa7a7908dfea57b7e26477efa7e73"
              parent="aspace_23d6a6cb497b4a99451c5aa42cfc61f1" type="image">018</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_e25e5732c5accc64d435e4c327ab2684" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Joslin Simms recovers at Duke University Medical Center after a stroke,
              undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_8c22f2bd6f347e2861909c854443fcfa" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_9546c7e69f5f6763b5321aa57a69f4a5"
              parent="aspace_8c22f2bd6f347e2861909c854443fcfa" type="folder">4</container>
            <container id="aspace_3b5df627c7fdc46deddc0d5d4a7c0ac0"
              parent="aspace_9546c7e69f5f6763b5321aa57a69f4a5" type="image">019</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_a13a46a99712c4bf964596f41fe44be7">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Joslin Simms recovers at Duke University Medical Center after a stroke. The stress of
              her grief weighs on her constantly. A 2012 study published in the <title
                render="italic">Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp; Psychiatry</title> found
              "strokes were more common among those with stressful lives and high-strung
              personalities, even after controlling for risk factors like smoking and diabetes."</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_3300b82593b71afa0e058470c40d0c32" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Demolition and construction continues in Durham's Southside neighborhood in
              2013</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_df160aa0a06666e188c54c6694b02d1c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_a6f4ba60de95fbcee872ea9181941e81"
              parent="aspace_df160aa0a06666e188c54c6694b02d1c" type="folder">4</container>
            <container id="aspace_f7628d50285131387c978eb33e6808a2"
              parent="aspace_a6f4ba60de95fbcee872ea9181941e81" type="image">020</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_a24278a02d05de7b0695e6c049192190">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Demolition and construction continues in Durham's Southside neighborhood in 2013.
              Nonprofits have partnered with the City of Durham to reclaim land in the neighborhood
              for a redevelopment project. The goal is to build nicer and more affordable housing,
              and to revitalize the area. Some residents are excited about a fresh start for the
              neighborhood, were homes start at $160,000 and income-based subsidies are offered by
              the city. But other Southside residents don't think the price is affordable and feel
              wary of the effects of gentrification and urban infill in their proud, historically
              black neighborhood. They say past urban renewal projects in Durham, including the
              construction of the Durham Freeway, dislocated a once centralized and vibrant black
              community. Many residents dub these projects "Urban Removal." Southside's census tract
              13.01 is 77 percent African-American; 45 percent of its total population lives in
              poverty and 26 percent are unemployed. The annual median household income is $18,125
              according to 2013 American Community Survey five-year estimates.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_543d08e62fdcc3aca58257ebe340592c" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Rashard Johnson waits to interview at a Durham job fair that helps felons,
              the recently incarcerated and others with a criminal record to find employment,
              undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_832ef2cb137f024bbdf47c83ecdb54a0" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_73c358dd1bac802e57c44488ece0b461"
              parent="aspace_832ef2cb137f024bbdf47c83ecdb54a0" type="folder">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_e3fb169e293281cd03e7d63423bcbe89"
              parent="aspace_73c358dd1bac802e57c44488ece0b461" type="image">021</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_8da96603c413800f2fe02f2f5d1efa91">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Rashard Johnson waits to interview at a Durham job fair that helps felons, the
              recently incarcerated and others with a criminal record to find employment. Rashard
              served nine months in prison and a judge waived his restitution upon his release. He
              landed a job as a door-to-door salesman for a cable and internet company, but quit the
              job after a few months because he couldn't make sales, which were based on commission.
              Being a felon is at once boring and agonizing. Rashard felt like he had no purpose,
              and he spent his days worrying and waiting. Studies estimate that one-third of young
              black men in the U.S. are out of work. The jobless rate for black male high school
              dropouts, including the incarcerated, is 65 percent. DATA SOURCE: BRUCE WESTERN,
              PUNISHMENT AND INEQUALITY IN AMERICA (2006).</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_e0ad5e3e6330daa84ea0a84fcaaceadf" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Rashard Johnson kisses his girlfriend Cheyenne after being apart for several
              weeks in 2012</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_63440c047e64532427a3b44136788a91" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_fdac9d3e4f4686a89b7b0035dbbaedf0"
              parent="aspace_63440c047e64532427a3b44136788a91" type="folder">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_78a9e10ebf66627e866d477c6163613c"
              parent="aspace_fdac9d3e4f4686a89b7b0035dbbaedf0" type="image">022</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_7ccef1e3a3a17446c7d2e7eb89744de0">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Rashard Johnson kisses his girlfriend Cheyenne after being apart for several weeks in
              2012. They eventually break up because of the instability caused by Rashard's criminal
              record.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_5bd4f47b2309ec952252765521eb2e54" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Revelers gather at the Marry Durham celebration in the revitalized Central
              Park District in 2012</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_650d89a315bda358c560ba980732d1eb" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_eb8e7bb60b65a3ca6f46d90ca5132774"
              parent="aspace_650d89a315bda358c560ba980732d1eb" type="folder">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_d51944a80af28aee26f740c70aa6e760"
              parent="aspace_eb8e7bb60b65a3ca6f46d90ca5132774" type="image">023</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_883742832a59fff221713f0931000072">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Revelers gather at the Marry Durham celebration in the revitalized Central Park
              District in 2012. Durhamites pledged their love and commitment to the city during a
              mock marriage ceremony and parade.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_df26066d4054fe3a2e54776047d8f4fb" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Young men revel along Fayetteville Street during Hillside High School's
              homecoming parade</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e21cb3e0c3ffa74a20ff565e7ea9c60c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_91b8ca1cff01fdb12e50cda2705a4061"
              parent="aspace_e21cb3e0c3ffa74a20ff565e7ea9c60c" type="folder">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_59183de6abdf5087a58e50983e241d65"
              parent="aspace_91b8ca1cff01fdb12e50cda2705a4061" type="image">024</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_7d94e98cbcac54701592751a0afc38db">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Young men revel along Fayetteville Street during Hillside High School's homecoming
              parade. Hillside has a predominantly African-American student population and serves
              many low-income communities in East and South Durham. According to Durham Public
              Schools data, Hillside once had a graduation rate as low as 52 percent in 2009, but it
              rose to 89 percent in 2014.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_41c5bd34e04f30e5e73b3f934ca98254" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>The 64th annual Watts-Hillandale Neighborhood Independence Day Parade at Oval
              Park in west Durham, 2013</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_d71aad7eb4294ed6d1f526b4dc229883" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_702ab85e96fee2a0433e828364c8f85c"
              parent="aspace_d71aad7eb4294ed6d1f526b4dc229883" type="folder">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_3654a0366e173c5250cf54df520e6661"
              parent="aspace_702ab85e96fee2a0433e828364c8f85c" type="image">025</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_00cf8f135d942954d45251a80727e9e7">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The 64th annual Watts-Hillandale Neighborhood Independence Day Parade at Oval Park in
              west Durham. Watts-Hillandale's census tract 4.01 is 82 percent white. Only 8 percent
              of people live in poverty and 94 percent graduated high school; only 4 percent are
              unemployed and the per capita income is $35,016 according to U.S. Census American
              Community Survey 2013 five-year estimates.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_d47e6e2c878210e6c5284c517c29644e" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A man who calls himself "Lil' Salt" flexes in triumph after climbing the
              corner store dressed as Spider-Man during Halloween festivities in Durham's Southside
              neighborhood, undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_173fc9e8e51cee4066e4f114899c4917" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_4754f51b9a6c08161d3aff1faf7ff3ba"
              parent="aspace_173fc9e8e51cee4066e4f114899c4917" type="folder">6</container>
            <container id="aspace_6d24274f81ed3d36fe3b9cacbd588bcc"
              parent="aspace_4754f51b9a6c08161d3aff1faf7ff3ba" type="image">026</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_4264c7ae60a013ecc9fb22b13d155ba6">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>A man who calls himself "Lil' Salt" flexes in triumph after climbing the corner store
              dressed as Spider-Man during Halloween festivities in Durham's Southside neighborhood.
              The Southside has endured despite violence in the past decade, but is changing rapidly
              under the City of Durham's redevelopment plans.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_a6368fbab80159b1e3dd4980575d1eef" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Durham Police officer R. Carson dances with members of North Carolina Central
              University's step dance team during National Night Out near McDougald Terrace, a
              low-income public housing project where shootings have been frequent,
              undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_1df21c81ab2eddc0aef0e6a57c3ed302" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_b1f85e2a9c3160e66b880780fd092d0e"
              parent="aspace_1df21c81ab2eddc0aef0e6a57c3ed302" type="folder">6</container>
            <container id="aspace_540bf3ebcc564fa0f1f5ecc6ff277745"
              parent="aspace_b1f85e2a9c3160e66b880780fd092d0e" type="image">027</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_8838a465739b3954370713f7c012810e">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Durham Police officer R. Carson dances with members of North Carolina Central
              University's step dance team during National Night Out near McDougald Terrace, a
              low-income public housing project where shootings have been frequent. National Night
              Out events strengthen relationships between neighborhoods, civic groups, and police in
              an effort to fight crime and increase community spirit. Only about 42 percent of
              Durham Police officers live in Durham, according to a 2014 city report. The late
              Harvard University criminal justice scholar William Stuntz saw a cure to violent crime
              through a return to neighborhood-friendly policing over modern proactive, militaristic
              methods. Encouraging officers to live in or near the neighborhoods they patrol builds
              trust, discourages crime, and makes witnesses feel safer to talk when violence occurs.
              The results are more effective jury trials, fewer plea deals, more respect for the
              police, and more democratic justice in communities that struggle with poverty and
              violence.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_5f1fa0030936a503ca05228005956604" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Ray's brother Billy Simms remembers his slain brother as friends and family
              celebrate Ray's birthday in 2012</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_f9aca7c7d46f57021938a8e76b1e3a88" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_747a6430164b763d96b5cc0aa7256bf1"
              parent="aspace_f9aca7c7d46f57021938a8e76b1e3a88" type="folder">6</container>
            <container id="aspace_34f2bcd4e4fe0ab40bbcfdbe6590e90a"
              parent="aspace_747a6430164b763d96b5cc0aa7256bf1" type="image">028</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_c7d6b6ef8d8b9a898ed21f53fc4e1baf">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Ray's brother Billy Simms remembers his slain brother as friends and family celebrate
              Ray's birthday in 2012, seven years after his murder. Billy said he used to sell drugs
              and live the street life, but gave it all up when Ray was killed. Now he works in a
              mechanic shop. "I used to make $1,000 a week, but I was always afraid. Now I barely
              make a dime, but I got a lot more joy," he says.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_4b7199d21b7065530705fb2a7947d0de" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Z'Dayvia Holloway, 7, dressed as Snow White, posed for a portrait at the
              Southside Community Center on Halloween in Durham in 2014</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_dc428250944334147ebd0ad09c8bed16" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_994bd8acb7ccc47aa84945213b11dbdb"
              parent="aspace_dc428250944334147ebd0ad09c8bed16" type="folder">6</container>
            <container id="aspace_22cd8536faf67d10ee5ffb241a36860f"
              parent="aspace_994bd8acb7ccc47aa84945213b11dbdb" type="image">029</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_04e494aae6a3a4cb7f5dd4ed8597a0b0" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Rashard Johnson's crucifix after a job fair for felons, undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_d283d3fe71d6e12e278963ffa73b4b69" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_3ff60dd0f7546dba08cb41bad7416c1a"
              parent="aspace_d283d3fe71d6e12e278963ffa73b4b69" type="folder">6</container>
            <container id="aspace_fca320e8f835997d3d0cc800aada1e2b"
              parent="aspace_3ff60dd0f7546dba08cb41bad7416c1a" type="image">030</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_40ac29a7c9374295ebebeca35c4c4c57">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Rashard Johnson's crucifix after a job fair for felons. In his lowest moments,
              Rashard finds refuge in his faith.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_d1bbd43a8a921e119ecc1291540638aa" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Community is formed from grief as mothers laugh and weep when they remember
              their murdered sons and daughters during a meeting of the Circle of Hope and Healing,
              undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_8fe71a71ec247ea8bab7c30fb87363f6" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_66d870ed771e68c3b046022c11efbbe5"
              parent="aspace_8fe71a71ec247ea8bab7c30fb87363f6" type="folder">7</container>
            <container id="aspace_8f533dfbeb55e4fae563a93b0fbc32f4"
              parent="aspace_66d870ed771e68c3b046022c11efbbe5" type="image">031</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_1927648685a2ca0ef6ada715fd827a22">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Community is formed from grief as mothers laugh and weep when they remember their
              murdered sons and daughters during a meeting of the Circle of Hope and Healing. The
              meetings are held for grieving parents by The Religious Coalition for a Nonviolent
              Durham in the basement of The Shepherd's House United Methodist Church in East
              Durham.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_2fdaf0dd8adf84d9cd6803f204250542" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A community vigil for Jeremy Turner, who was shot to death on May 17, 2011,
              when he was 19 years old, 2013</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_5ec221f4541a7ebfb7f3d5943fd924cc" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_024cc87bd7938494bf75fbfcd6538408"
              parent="aspace_5ec221f4541a7ebfb7f3d5943fd924cc" type="folder">7</container>
            <container id="aspace_a146e7e66b4a8ebec9daae95736a6349"
              parent="aspace_024cc87bd7938494bf75fbfcd6538408" type="image">032</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_8650ce02c81ba4d56a8b5d5c8e2782cb">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>A community vigil for Jeremy Turner, who was shot to death on May 17, 2011, when he
              was 19 years old. About 100 friends and family gathered on July 17, 2013, at the
              family home on Gerard Street to celebrate what would have been Jeremy's 22nd birthday.
              The Religious Coalition for a Nonviolent Durham holds vigils at the site of homicides
              in Durham as a call for peace, community unity, and healing.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_6357736687ff0aa8d5a8472ec27a0419" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Shae Simms gave birth to a son, Bryson DeMarcus China, named after her
              murdered father Rayburn Antonio DeMarcus Simms, at Duke Regional Hospital in Durham in
              July 2014</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_e20deaa8dee608dd506d34639a1ac23b" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_20a0e9f907da416d62ee53e8013187c3"
              parent="aspace_e20deaa8dee608dd506d34639a1ac23b" type="folder">7</container>
            <container id="aspace_7f82d84a0393c29a2087fcac459a7f9e"
              parent="aspace_20a0e9f907da416d62ee53e8013187c3" type="image">033</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_3d3ae7ac262289de82569eac52cbbead" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Raven Simms, Ray's daughter, shows off her prom dress to her grandmother,
              Joslin, and her mother, Sheila, in 2013</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_d52a906a8f07f8820133efcf7ab663e7" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_3a656e3e3a3b5a2f079e47d9ef3e07dc"
              parent="aspace_d52a906a8f07f8820133efcf7ab663e7" type="folder">7</container>
            <container id="aspace_a2ec7b467dfdf2021b02518114e7a929"
              parent="aspace_3a656e3e3a3b5a2f079e47d9ef3e07dc" type="image">034</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_95627a67c2c763ba08b009e3625a74d6">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Raven Simms, Ray's daughter, shows off her prom dress to her grandmother, Joslin, and
              her mother, Sheila, in 2013. Raven and her siblings miss Ray the most on holidays,
              birthdays, proms, graduations, and other milestones. She says her father came to her
              in a dream a week before her senior prom. He held her tightly, whispered to her that
              he loved her and that everything was going to be all right. Then he vanished back to
              his grave.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ba43442e33c02b0b989cb436150236cf" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Joslin Simms poses with politicians and gun-control advocates after speaking
              at a Mayors Against Illegal Guns rally in Chapel Hill in 2014</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_020ea9dc10ca869aac050549bf9cf26d" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_188784e8f4e620274b7279ef0405ef87"
              parent="aspace_020ea9dc10ca869aac050549bf9cf26d" type="folder">7</container>
            <container id="aspace_c35a20dcf8df43d5df980c91faccdfbb"
              parent="aspace_188784e8f4e620274b7279ef0405ef87" type="image">035</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_0139caa61a6b9af19c53a7cff0952ec8">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Joslin Simms poses with politicians and gun-control advocates after speaking at a
              Mayors Against Illegal Guns rally in Chapel Hill in 2014. Increasingly isolated by
              depression and grief, Joslin found companionship and community in organizations like
              Moms Demand Action for Gun Sense. She and other mothers who have lost their children
              to violence don't want them to have died in vain, so they have organized with the hope
              of influencing national and local gun, education and anti-poverty policies.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_0bd63e41023b1af26a6d85bdbe2d850f" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>In 2015, Rashard helps demolish and renovate an old restaurant into a new
              coffee shop in Durham</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_775cf27e8db2a3f2dd5c325d48e5a747" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_16ba9404229070c078972521854ae443"
              parent="aspace_775cf27e8db2a3f2dd5c325d48e5a747" type="folder">8</container>
            <container id="aspace_404430cbbbf12906e63ef6ca613bd585"
              parent="aspace_16ba9404229070c078972521854ae443" type="image">036</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_869f3660df1e514392162e9b6cde551e">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>In 2015, Rashard helps demolish and renovate an old restaurant into a new coffee shop
              in Durham. He began to piece his life back together as he worked on a construction
              crew with New Beginnings, a faith-based nonprofit that helps the recently incarcerated
              find work and stability. Most people with felony records are limited to construction
              and manual labor.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_f223c4f38c7f0b92fd4c637abd23b490" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A summer storm rolls in over Angier Avenue and Driver Street in East Durham
              at sunset, undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_11330f400e4f023bb9b18d811ed3f8c4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_d824499a6abefc2f6dfaa4d06b3951c0"
              parent="aspace_11330f400e4f023bb9b18d811ed3f8c4" type="folder">8</container>
            <container id="aspace_5154e34b55785d9fe74008eb6bf26fd3"
              parent="aspace_d824499a6abefc2f6dfaa4d06b3951c0" type="image">037</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_14c9c3a16f71ac970eb7ebdc296ab37b" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Joslin in the sunflowers along the Neuse River Trail in Raleigh, N.C.,
              undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_8311c17df82e5358cb638e7e0d9480c4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_5bf48271f8dc9ae5942c5e0707203eed"
              parent="aspace_8311c17df82e5358cb638e7e0d9480c4" type="folder">8</container>
            <container id="aspace_80dadcf0b8ebca245174022d5383e27e"
              parent="aspace_5bf48271f8dc9ae5942c5e0707203eed" type="image">038</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_82a3e53a0fbc69562102390ab63b9080" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reverend Michael Page baptizes Janayah Wallace, 6 at Antioch Baptist Church
              in October 2013</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_af60e90cc3198718c8cfda02dab71551" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_cb08cc7e66604b439d96cb7ea3bc8781"
              parent="aspace_af60e90cc3198718c8cfda02dab71551" type="folder">8</container>
            <container id="aspace_35545ab9ee4b0bc34e505db23fb1e898"
              parent="aspace_cb08cc7e66604b439d96cb7ea3bc8781" type="image">039</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_d3160b41f5e5e392aa1f3afaed6ccd18" level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Rashard Johnson spoke on a panel about incarceration at Howard University in
              Washington, D.C. in April 2015</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_7f76fc35e9cc5a8ca5c53f248396a770" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_9fb0ba94e979d9f86f20e0a6dfaa1a32"
              parent="aspace_7f76fc35e9cc5a8ca5c53f248396a770" type="folder">8</container>
            <container id="aspace_c8844419c9753e4f74ea8af8974157b2"
              parent="aspace_9fb0ba94e979d9f86f20e0a6dfaa1a32" type="image">040</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
