<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/craigheadmeinrad/"
         >craigheadmeinrad</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Meinrad Craighead Papers, 1901-2007 <num>RL.00265</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Meghan Lyon; machine-readable finding aid created by: Meghan
               Lyon</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">004289377</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-28 14:57:00
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Meinrad Craighead papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Craighead, Meinrad</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00265</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1901/2007" type="inclusive">1901-2007</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_242c4dd54935ef60b8aac488cc98da87">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_bfc000a7e6ecd1fdada0d79e1cddd5f1">Award-winning artist and writer
            whose works focus on humankind's relationship with God. She has lived and worked around
            the world, but eventually settled in New Mexico in the 1980s. Accession (2010-0020)
            includes letters; photographs; exhibition catalogs and publicity; public response to her
            poems and books; research and notes on mythologies, art, and nature; and other personal
            materials from her life. The materials largely date from the 1960s through the 1980s,
            covering her scholarship in Europe, her time in England as a nun in Stanbrook Abbey, and
            the years following her return to New Mexico. Includes Craighead's prayer books and
            psalters, some dating from the early 1900s, as well as some copies of her own
            publications and artwork. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's
            History and Culture.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_1c71043388fb20e9050e7ffe6d2cca40">
            <extent>2500 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_8dca6d758a9fc8bb7008e0c47348e2c8">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_578e7f25620dd5da35286d776beeb328">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_9098a01334c35c4955e0508de5c56a0b">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_ab80624d3815a0e1a4583a6667896c02">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Meinrad Craighead Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_cde57e81e7c7deeb8c99afbbaba6900a">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Meinrad Craighead Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a gift in 2010.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_ec0638585d911c2c7f20c954e38c5185">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Meghan Lyon, February 2010</p>
         <p>Encoded by Meghan Lyon, February 2010</p>
         <p>Materials may not have been ordered and described beyond their original condition.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_74611828a4c02b3bb6aaf36bb7df4ce4">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Meinrad Craighead was born in Little Rock, Arkansas, as Charlene Craighead in 1936. She
            was raised in Chicago, where she attended Catholic schools throughout her childhood.
            Craighead graduated with a M.F.A. from the University of Wisconsin in 1960, after which
            she moved to New Mexico to teach and paint. She also began exhibiting her work, which
            was heavily influenced by nature and Native American imagery.</p>
         <p>In 1962, Craighead moved to Florence, Italy; she remained in Europe for the next 21
            years. She taught at several schools in Florence before winning a Fulbright in 1965. She
            spent her Fulbright year in Spain, where she studied medieval Catalan art. While staying
            at Montserrat, a monastery in Barcelona, Craighead felt called to monastic life. She
            entered Stanbrook Abbey, a nunnery in England, in 1966, and took the name of Meinrad.
            She remained a nun until 1980.</p>
         <p>During her time in the abbey, Craighead continued to create, paint, and write. Her first
            book, <title type="simple" render="italic">The Sign of the Tree</title>, was published
            in 1979. After leaving the abbey, she received support from the Arts Council of Great
            Britain to continue her art and writing. In 1983, Craighead returned to the United
            States, and she settled in Albuquerque on the Rio Grande. She remained active in the
            Catholic church, and continued her research and writings about mythology and Native
            American spirituality. In more recent years, Craighead has conducted workshops on the
            Feminine Divine, as well as continuing to publish a compilation of her work in 2003.</p>
         <p>Craighead's publications include <title type="simple" render="italic">The Sign of the
               Tree</title> (1979), <title type="simple" render="italic">The Mother's Songs</title>
            (1986), <title type="simple" render="italic">The Litany of the Great River</title>
            (1991), <title type="simple" render="italic">Sacred Marriage: The Wisdom of the Song of
               Songs</title> (co-authored with Nicholas Ayo, 1997), and <title type="simple"
               render="italic">Crow Mother and the Dog God: A Retrospective</title> (2003). </p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_1ea985b4f7aa2cc04750a3bf2dec16ea">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The Meinrad Craighead Papers includes a variety of materials, largely dating from
            Craighead's adult life from the 1960s to the 1980s. The collection is divided into the
            following series: Personal Papers, Writings, Research, Artwork, Photographs, and
            Books.</p>
         <p>Craighead's <emph render="bold">Personal Papers Series</emph> is a mixture of items,
            ranging from personal correspondence to official correspondence relating to her U.S.
            passport. Several folders have information on Craighead's recent activities, including
            presentation notes, her travel for speaking or workshop engagements, and materials from
            her retreats and public programming in the 1990s-2000s. This series also includes
            several versions of Craighead's resume, documenting her activities prior to the
            mid-1980s.</p>
         <p>The <emph render="bold">Writings Series</emph> consists largely of feedback, book
            reveiws, and correspondence following the publishing of three of Craighead's books:
               <title type="simple" render="italic">The Sign of the Tree</title> (1979), <title
               type="simple" render="italic">The Mother's Songs</title> (1986), and the <title
               type="simple" render="italic">Litany of the Great River</title> (1991). Drafts from
            the latter reveal that the book was initially referred to as the <title type="simple"
               render="doublequote">Litany of the Rio Grande.</title> The Writings Series also
            includes loose drafts, poems, and other undated materials.</p>
         <p>The <emph render="bold">Research Series</emph> includes Craighead's handwritten notes
            and drafts from her research into the mythology and mysticism of different world
            cultures, including ancient Egypt, Rome, and Native Americans. Another interest of
            Craighead was the role of nature, including different animals, in the symbolism and
            spirituality of various religions and groups. These files are loosely sorted by
            subject.</p>
         <p>Samples of Craighead's prints and paintings can be found in the <emph render="bold"
               >Artwork Series</emph>, which also includes exhibition catalogs, printings and
            publications of her work (including several copies of <title type="simple"
               render="italic">Catholic Worker</title> newspapers, which used her illustrations in
            the 1970s), as well as a small amount of artwork and poetry by others that Craighead
            collected. The prints in this series are not original works of art, but instead are
            photocopies or photographs of her work. They include copies of her inkprints, paintings,
            and glass etchings.</p>
         <p>The <emph render="bold">Photographs Series</emph> includes the majority of the
            collection's photographs, which are both color and black-and-white prints, as well as
            negatives. Craighead appears to have taken several rolls of film of altars, outdoor
            landscapes, foliage, rock formations, and animals that she then used in creating her
            artwork. Other photographs from this series are portraits of Craighead, by both friends
            and professional photographers, as well as a small amount of photographs of Stanbrook
            Abbey in England. A final photograph worth mentioning is one of Craighead and three nuns
            at Pope Pius VI's coronation in Rome in 1963.</p>
         <p>The final series, the <emph render="bold">Printed Materials Series</emph>, includes
            Craighead's personal books, copies of her published books, and books that include her
            artwork as illustrations. Craighead's personal books consist of prayer books, early
            editions of Christian texts, and a book about the Stanbrook Abbey Press. Craighead's
            illustrations can be found in three editions of Catholic missals from 1975 and 1982.
            Finally, this series includes autographed copies of Craighead's own publications, <title
               type="simple" render="italic">The Mother's Birds</title>, <title type="simple"
               render="italic">The Sign of the Tree</title>, and <title type="simple"
               render="doublequote">Christian Symbols,</title> a compilation of loose prints.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_88b34e67f6375dbd8534eaec6d737dce">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>The Meinrad Craighead Project, a documentary film about Craighead's life and work, was
            funded by the <emph render="bold">Resource Center for Women and Ministry in the
               South</emph>. The Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture (part of Duke
            University Special Collections) also houses this organization's records.</p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women in the Catholic Church</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Spiritual Life -- Art</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Art and mythology</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Idols and images</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Art and religion -- 20th century</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Albuquerque (N.M.) -- Women artists</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Women artists -- England</geogname>
         <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
         <corpname source="ingest">Catholic Church</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Craighead, Meinrad</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Craighead, Meinrad</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Stanbrook Abbey</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref13_aud" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Personal papers, 1970s-2007</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_554137a57f7c2e618cba39b72b78fd54">
                  <extent>1 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_ddd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Personal correspondence, 1970s-1980s</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_240f7fd571c1bb0298372b982f18c2d9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_0kc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Personal papers, including resumes, 1980s</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e0d3b39492b5f0da0e8655560abb2b95" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_to2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Retreats, public programs, 1990s-2000s</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b4a4be07da588f5dcbd979226fd0a53f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_avz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Presentation notes, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_808ed1fa9f5a61a32d9a2c9ed7a50908" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_pdw" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Travel-Paris, Prague, and others, 2006-2007 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4866bc30096c3e5892401b532044e2fe" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref20_0uq" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Writings, 1986-1994 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_477084ec3d73758dff927b483cc14ad0">
                  <extent>1 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_lxw" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Writings, poems, drafts, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9a12c76b25e56568c11e92414f8209e3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_9lx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">The Sign of the Tree</title> (1979)</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref24_uu2" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Correspondence and reviews</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_aae36cf8c468deeb1e079b22479df37c" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_vpa" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">The Mother's Songs</title> (1986)</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref26_slh" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Letters and correspondence, 1986</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_e26d9fa122e0f8a6781303c00cbb8732" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref27_1nc" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Book reviews, 1986</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_eff1a9952a0d63b815f6e0c6aeb6d51d" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref28_aaw" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Reviews and articles, 1986-1990</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_c597f4188a692b0ca489b6cbfa364a52" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_1f4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">The Litany of the Great River</title> (1991)</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref30_r44" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Rio Grande-drafts, writings, notes, undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_3327f35719dc7a392822848691afc29a" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref31_005" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Letters, 1991</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_10656d7d9cd9feddf5bcbb59a8732b1b" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref32_pkw" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Book reviews and articles, 1991</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_f823bba4e90dc4e51c4b4dadf6988eec" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref33_33b" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Research, undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_e60cb5adca782d12a0bb74b70b9f2766">
                  <extent>1 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_gad" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Notes and research</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e7a27946fe72c5db3c1e05d604806cb6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref36_0e3" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>General</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_e6f66651a6c2087c37765a2e8576ea72" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref37_3d7" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Egypt</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_4ec2e6117157b5e9c5caa05a345f9cf6" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref38_ncj" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>North American Indians</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_82ed548e35f7dbf4dec97e9576d737f8" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref39_h9r" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Ancient and medieval cultures</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_303bad6d529f158fe37ee849919efc94" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref40_0dn" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Birds</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_ce6e0ca5c61b623a49c3ddb7c3a7aaa2" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref41_eew" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Animals</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_cc609ddabe26b75a57f21aaf39cd8d7a" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref42_z6f" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Symbolism</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_c17c66fe844f08215b2de3256a008f0f" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref43_s5q" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Artwork, 1963-1980s and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_a0ccffd62e159d7c6797a324962449c9">
                  <extent>1 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref45_3yt" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Craighead's exhibition catalogs, 1963-1980</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_af3ce191f9ad22f51d164ce486ccc3f8" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref46_u5k" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Publications (of Craighead's art, writings, biographies, etc.),
                     1970s-1980s</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_32647362948a66080fd9b79a676dc917" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_43y" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">Catholic Worker</title>, with Craighead's prints,
                     1969-1980</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4aa0869b626d28448e389b675ec30b6d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref48_xnm" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Art shows, events, exhibitions (Craighead's and others)</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a7ed49085e9e4224ede115bb4c3f3dd2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref49_d4e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Artwork and poetry collected by Craighead</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_91a96f3c49769b361636b55947d0b3a3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref50_nsv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Georgia O'Keefe clippings</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_25d85ee68084e5c94c6b362161c028af" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref51_8io" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Craighead's prints and copies of prints (2 folders)</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_75053a3f3d6fb0d250b4f0bd0e9c1a48" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref52_w49" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Oxford Baptist Church glass doors</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ba926a84831100189266a3a82ba359b5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref53_fi6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Glass etchings projects</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_54ad4bb1588398835e8abc4029387df6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref54_fyb" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Photographs, 1963-2000s and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_25d5a678352ea4cd737a0cc9c473774a">
                  <extent>1 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref56_ss3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Craighead in Rome, 1963, and Stanbrook Abbey photographs,
                     undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6430ddbbb0d023e0ab001842df562553" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref57_dm9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Portraits and other photographs of Meinrad Craighead</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fc19a9ebfb620168866146582e6c6908" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref58_1ka" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Molly Eaves photographs of Meinrad Craighead, 1997 June</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_621a0447ff73dd6f255ad2cbc28f724a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref59_wz7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Jill Fineberg portraits of Meinrad Craighead for <title render="italic"
                        >Common Boundary</title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ef2c93f4452ae698ece6cbbcf61a8ea9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref60_cvk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Artwork, nature, inspirations, etc. (2 folders)</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_7ff9e8cf99d0967a53de98fb89a67435" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref61_nn2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Paintings since <title render="italic">The Litany of the Great
                        River</title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_881b55d1e4fdb23d708e07d6d166c683" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref62_n4t" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Travel to Paris</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a59552ec8d902f7bb4910e1b11eeae44" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref63_aoq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Unlabelled photographs</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ca9b1ab1aefee73e77ea06ec368c417b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref64_o0z" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Printed materials, 1901-1979 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_56b89672581e6d218fecb618c9fdaa86">
                  <extent>2 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref66_pm8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Personal prayer books, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_47c008e61061cddbfa5a19f6870d8b28" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref67_5dz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Publications with Craighead's illustrations</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_998099cbe04545e410266ed87e54f7d7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref68_gbj" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">The Sunday Missal</title>, 1975 and 1982
                        editions</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_d6ba977efc90f51e9e7a4a26e8f16a9a" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref69_ksi" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">The Weekday Missal</title>, 1975</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_bcacf2fe20eafdbe3a78428df9d5de02" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref70_oos" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">The Malvern Country</title> by Bertram C.A. Windle,
                     1901</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b450de6ec61732819eeab74d8b2eac6c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref71_hku" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">The Cloud of Unknowing</title>, 1924</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_74ff20c867fce99219cefca47953ac15" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref72_s0i" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">The Book of the Lover and the Beloved</title>,
                     undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_cb2cf9b3b5d416122ac8fcf582b1805b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref73_48l" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">Stanbrook Abbey Press</title>, 1970</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_617059e7946b46ae6fbeae0e1bde516f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref74_271" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Craighead's own publications</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref75_7q1" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">Song of Songs</title> greeting cards</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_c1e692e9c2a90a9b11207c038c87a3ee" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref76_hfx" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="doublequote">Christian Symbols,</title> 1975</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_1e9235ea0e68cd1d2c7916edc8a2eaf8" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref77_6jg" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">The Mother's Birds</title>, 1976</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_cb505981f80b27eacd5d04fbf0e4462e" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref78_zhu" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">Sign of the Tree</title>, 1979</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_0a94359448993b27d17bc072a1565355" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
