<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="https://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/currency/">currency</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Duke University Currency Collection, 1746-1982
          <num>RL.00276</num></titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: William Erwin ; machine-readable finding aid created by: Stephen
          Douglas Miller</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>1983</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">001826867</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-07-01 16:00:52
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2014</date>
        <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported to
          Archivists Toolkit</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>The Duke University Currency collection</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <corpname source="ingest">Duke University</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.00276</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1746/1982" type="inclusive">1746-1982</unitdate>
      <physloc id="aspace_c97d9126883b4e7973de5a08b9d0844d">For current information on the location
        of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
      <physdesc id="aspace_9d406aff86cd1b730ac7d1278f4cdaf1"
        label="General Physical Description note"><extent>4,896 Items</extent></physdesc>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_d8338db33db1cb53fe84727ada6a2ce8">English.</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_ea21a38dd18a8f9461e6267de5d4c4d0">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Please contact Research Services Staff to inquire about restrictions on access to this
        collection.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
        research use.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_a3f715575c6b8e147bb43ac0f8c78c46">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information consult the section on copyright in the Regulations and Procedures of
        the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_751df778e45496b3af879b19a2c3e0a7">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], The Currency Collection, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_d815ba0d4cf2fc1885d485084c2a9ae4">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>Collected by Duke University through gifts and purchases.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo id="aspace_9a6a21dbc7c74926907311c34ced84a4">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Guide by: William Erwin </p>
      <p>Completed August, 1983</p>
      <p>Encoded by Stephen Douglas Miller</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_5c807d674511e8bdbde0c29a5801006b">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>The Currency Collection contains 4896 pieces, 1746-1982, of which all except a small number
        of coins and tokens are paper currency. Most of this money is domestic, but there are a
        limited number of foreign items, some of them quite old and interesting. Approximately
        two-thirds of the collection dates from the Civil War and one-fourth from the antebellum
        period.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_f9ce65a50456250bdca39a7951cb1ad4">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>A variety of elements are involved in the arrangement of the currency within the above
        categories. The first criterion of arrangement is geographical for the colonial,
        Revolutionary, Southern states, and foreign currency, and for the currency issued by banks
        and other corporate bodies, businesses, etc.: by states, provinces, countries, etc. The
        Confederate currency is arranged first by denominations: 50¢, $1, $10, etc. Part of the
        collection is deacidified and part is not, so some categories are divided into two sets on
        this basis.</p>
      <p>Itemized lists have been compiled of all pieces of the currency, and the contents of these
        lists, which are not the same for all categories, are noted in the descriptions of the major
        categories. There are two sets of lists, one of which is kept with the collection and the
        other with the department's security copies of collection inventories. The lists in the
        security set are all filed together. Within the Currency Collection, the lists are divided,
        each folder of currency containing the list itemizing its contents.</p>
      <p>The Information Folder filed in the first box includes a variety of material: information
        about the provenance of parts of the collection; reference sources; a copy of D. C. Wismer's
          <title render="doublequote">Descriptive List of Obsolete Paper Money: Part I - Embracing
          the Circulating Notes Issued by State Banks, Private Banks, Bankers and
          Corporations</title> for North Carolina published in <title render="italic">The
          Numismatist</title> during June-August, 1931; articles about early North Carolina
        currency; a poem about Confederate currency; an earlier description of the collection
        removed from the card catalog, etc.</p>
      <p>The list in the Information Folder entitled <title render="doublequote">American
          Confederate State Bills Comprising over Eight Hundred Confederate State Bills, Confederate
          State Bank Notes, Confederate State Currency Notes, Private Scrip, Etc.</title> (25 pp.)
        is dated August, 1949. It lists the joint collections of the late Judge Van Wart of New
        Orleans and of W. George Head of Wimbledon, Eng., formerly of Shelby, N.C. This list was
        apparently compiled by a dealer whose name is not on it. This list provides the provenance
        for a sizeable part of the Currency Collection. </p>
      <p>The part of the collection entitled <title render="doublequote">Currency Issued by Banks
          and Other Corporate Bodies,</title> including both antebellum and Civil War issues and
        currency from the South and also from other states, came primarily from the Van Wart and
        Head collections. They also provided the sources of a sizeable part of the North Carolina
        State Currency issued during the Civil War.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918 -- Economic aspects</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Money -- Germany</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Money -- France</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Paper money -- Confederate States of America</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Economic conditions</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Paper money -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Money -- United States -- History</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Coinage</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Bonds -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Bonds -- Confederate States of America</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Money -- Confederate States of America</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Coinage -- United States</subject>
      <corpname source="ingest">Confederate States of America -- Economic conditions</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref13_zxr" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Colonial Currency</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_2bc364d78b3f18655854732a06920af4">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>An excellent catalog of American paper currency from its inception in 1686 to 1789 is
            Eric P. Newman's <bibref><title type="simple" render="italic">The Early Paper Money of
                America</title><imprint>(Racine, Wisc., 1967)</imprint>
            </bibref>. Newman noted the distinctiveness of this money: <emph render="doublequote"
              >The early paper money of America has the unique distinction of being the first paper
              money issued by any government in the Western World. No country, state, or colony in
              Europe had made a prior issue of publicly sponsored paper money.</emph>
          </p>
          <p>This collection includes 27 examples of colonial paper currency from: </p>
          <list type="ordered">
            <item><geogname>Delaware </geogname>(3), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1746-1759;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Georgia </geogname>(1), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
              >1774;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Maryland </geogname>(4), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1767-1770;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>North Carolina </geogname>(13), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1754-1771;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Pennsylvania </geogname>(6), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1769-1775.</date></item>
          </list>
          <p>The Delaware bills are notable for having been printed by Benjamin Franklin. An undated
            bill for 5 shillings from North Carolina is colonial, for the state issued currency in
            dollars beginning in 1775. This bill is not listed in Newman. It is signed by Thomas
            Polk (d. 1793), one of the founders of Charlotte and a leading colonial and
            Revolutionary figure in Mecklenburg County and the state. Signatories of the North
            Carolina bills include Richard Caswell (1729-1789), first state governor and a member of
            the Continental Congress (currency of 1768 and 1771).</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref18_5a6" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Revolutionary Currency</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_25d0a72df6d0974d5f3f3c6e93c05117">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>There are 67 pieces of Revolutionary paper currency and one copper plate for printing a
            bill. They include the Continental Currency issued by the Continental Congress and also
            the Revolutionary War state issues. There is currency from:</p>
          <list type="ordered">
            <item><corpname>The Continental Congress </corpname>(10), <date calendar="gregorian"
                era="ce">1776-1779;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Georgia </geogname>(18), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1776-1778;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>North Carolina </geogname>(23), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1776-1780;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>South Carolina </geogname>(14), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1775-1779;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Virginia </geogname>(2), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1777-1780.</date></item>
          </list>
          <p>From North Carolina there is a copper plate used for the printing of one of the $2 1/2
            bills of the issue of April 2, 1776 (the bill with a vignette of a Liberty Cap over an
            altar). The other side of the same copper plate was used to print $5 bills of the same
            issue (version with vignette of a raven). Signatories include five members of the
            Continental Congress: William Sharpe and John Williams from N.C. and William Few,
            William Gibbons, and Edward Telfair from Georgia. Telfair signed the Articles of
            Confederation, and Few signed the Constitution.</p>
          <p>This currency is arranged by colonies/states. Lists itemize each bill. The lists
            record: name of colony/state; denomination; serial letter; date; and occasional
            comments.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref23_1yu" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Currency Issued by Banks and Other Corporate Bodies, Businesses,
            Etc.</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_33afaba16b03982f4f85ea610b0e7e08">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>The Continental Congress issued a great quantity of paper currency in order to finance
            the Revolution. The depreciation of this money and its economic effects produced a
            distrust of any national paper currency. For that reason the 1789 Constitution forbade
            the states to issue paper money. The Constitution was deliberately silent on the federal
            government's right to do so. However, there was no ban against their issuance by private
            organizations and local governments. This loophole was utilized to provide paper
            currency which was both convenient and necessary for economic life. Over 30,000
            varieties of notes were issued by 1,600 different banks in 34 different states between
            1790 and 1865. These figures do not include the issues of local governments and private
            businesses that were not banks. The history of this money ended substantially during the
            Civil War. The Confederate government and the various states of the Confederacy issued
            paper currency-during the war. The U.S. Congress authorized a national paper currency in
            1861, and it is the only paper currency to survive the Civil War as a significant
            economic factor. Some currency and scrip continued to be issued at various times by
            businesses and local governments, but it was economically and quantitatively
            insignificant. It should be remembered, of course, that the federal government issued
            gold and silver coinage during this period.</p>
          <p>The paper currency in this collection issued by banks and other public and private
            organizations and businesses numbers 1225 items dating between 1815 and 1906. Most of
            the money dates from 1815 into the 1860's. Every decade during this period is
            represented, but currency is most abundant during the 1850's and 1860's. After the Civil
            War there are occasional bills. See also the Raphael P. Thian Papers for a sizeable
            collection of this type of currency (Vols. 768 &amp; 770).</p>
          <p>This currency is divided into two sections, those bills deacidified and those bills not
            yet deacidified. There are 625 bills, 1815-1906, in the set not deacidified.
            Twenty-eight states and the District of Columbia are represented. They are: </p>
          <list type="ordered">
            <item><geogname>Alabama </geogname>(4 bills), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1855-1871;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Arkansas </geogname>(2), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1861-1869;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Connecticut </geogname>(4), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1825-1862;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Delaware </geogname>(1), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1861;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>District of Columbia </geogname>(16), <date calendar="gregorian"
                era="ce">1844-1862;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Florida </geogname>(3), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1835-1859;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Georgia </geogname>(192), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1816-1862;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Indiana </geogname>(1), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
              >1857;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Kentucky </geogname>(7), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1837 &amp;
                undated;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Louisiana </geogname>(3), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1852-1861;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Maine </geogname>(4), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1854-1862;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Maryland </geogname>(8), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1841-1862;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Massachusetts </geogname>(31), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1863-1873;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Michigan </geogname>(12), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1835-1869;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Mississippi </geogname>(41), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1837-1861;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Missouri </geogname>(2), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1862;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>New Hampshire </geogname>(2), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1837-1862;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>New Jersey </geogname>(26), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1827-1862;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>New York </geogname>(38), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1816-1862;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>North Carolina </geogname>(91), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1837-1874;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Ohio </geogname>(4), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1839-1862;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Pennsylvania </geogname>(31), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1816-1865;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>South Carolina </geogname>(54), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1826-1873;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Tennessee </geogname>(17), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1837-1862;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Texas </geogname>(7), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1862-1864;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Utah </geogname>(4), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1898-1906;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Vermont </geogname>(6), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1815-1863;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Virginia </geogname>(38), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1854-1862;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>West Virginia </geogname>(4), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1852-1860.</date></item>
          </list>
          <p>Six states are represented in the deacidified set that contains 599 bills, 1861-1867.
            They are:</p>
          <list type="ordered">
            <item><geogname>Alabama </geogname>(5), 1862-1864;</item>
            <item><geogname>Florida </geogname>(1), 1861;</item>
            <item><geogname>Georgia </geogname>(479), 1861-1864;</item>
            <item><geogname>Louisiana </geogname>(77), 1861-1867;</item>
            <item><geogname>Mississippi </geogname>(36), 1861-1863;</item>
            <item><geogname>Texas </geogname>(1), 1862.</item>
          </list>
          <p>This currency is arranged by states. Lists itemize each note. The lists record: name of
            the state; place of origin within the state; issuing body; denomination; serial letter
            or number; date; note number; and occasional comments.</p>
          <p>Banks were the principal issuers of paper currency. From the samples in this collection
            it appears that railroads and local governments (cities, towns, counties, etc.) were
            notable sources of paper money, but not in the same magnitude as the banks. A great
            variety of private organizations and businesses issued money including the following
            types and examples represented in this collection: savings and loan; insurance;
            building; a lyceum; mining; manufacturing; a rice mill; a cotton mill; an apothecary;
            mercantile stores; a furniture warehouse; a hotel; a bakery; associations of planters
            and mechanics; bridges; steamship companies; a tow-boat company; canals; turnpikes,
            etc.</p>
          <p>Many bills are fine examples of engraving and printing. Counterfeiting was a problem.
              <emph render="doublequote">The private banks retaliated against the counterfeiters and
              made the process of manufacture more and more complex by using fancier paper, more
              complicated designs, more watermarks, secret printing marks, indentures, marbling,
              laminated papers, polychrome printing, 'mice' and/or fiber inclusions, composite
              plates, elaborately engraved ornaments, and portraits engraved by the finest artists
              of the period. All these countermeasures helped to create some exceptionally beautiful
              notes, some surpassing in many respects our present-day currency with its more limited
              designs and subject matter</emph> (Gene Hessler, <title type="simple" render="italic"
              >The Comprehensive Catalog of U.S. Paper Money,</title> pp. 11-12).</p>
          <p>Vignettes used as decorative and protective illustrations on bills were commonplace.
            They depicted a great variety of scenes as well as portraits of men and women. Some
            vignettes contain idealized scenes, mythological figures, etc. Many vignettes, however,
            are useful historical representations because either they were intended as realistic
            depictions or because the generalized views of scenes and activities record past
            objects, places, technology, workers, equipment, agriculture, manufacturing, animals,
            buildings, ships, trains, bridges, etc. Some examples in this collection are: a turnpike
            booth and gate and a view of Stoddartsville, Pa., from Wilkes-Barre Turnpike Co., 1816;
            gathering naval stores, Timber Cutter's Bank, Savannah, 1861; interior of a tobacco
            factory, screw presses, and blacks at work, Bank of Yanceyville, N.C., 1856;
            agricultural and dock scenes; Natural Bridge, Virginia Military Institute, and
            Washington College on Bank of Rockbridge bill, 1859; Mount Hecla Steam Cotton Mills,
            Greensboro, N.C., 1837; etc.</p>
          <p>The portraits of men and women in the vignettes included not only notable and
            historical persons but also local citizenry, in most cases probably people connected
            with the bank. Women of all ages appear. An especially illustrative example is a
            five-dollar bill of the South Western Bank of Virginia at Wytheville in 1857 which
            contains the portraits of two men, the bank's president and cashier, and of two women,
            Florence Nightingale and a relation, probably the wife, of the bank's president. This
            bill is not in the collection, but it may be seen in Charles J. Affleck's <title
              type="simple" render="italic">The Obsolete Paper Money of Virginia,</title> Vol. II,
            p. 253. The portraits of women on the currency in this collection represent all ages
            except infancy.</p>
          <p>This paper currency sometimes circulated at par, but most often at a discount in places
            distant from the point of issue. Counterfeiting was a serious problem. It was also
            necessary and difficult to keep up with which banks had failed. <emph
              render="doublequote">The situation was so alarming and prevalent that for the years
              from 1826 to 1866 numerous periodicals called 'Bank Note Reporters' and 'Counterfeit
              Detectors' were published, most of them today comparatively scarce. Of the 153 titles
              of such periodicals noted in W. H. Dillistin's <title type="simple" render="italic"
                >Bank Note Reporters and Counterfeit Detectors,</title> 1949, the American
              Antiquarian Society has 28, more than any library listed</emph> (Clarence S. Brigham,
              <title type="simple" render="italic">Fifty Years of Collecting Americana of the
              Library of The American Antiquarian Society</title> 1908-1958, p. 139). Perkins
            Library has several examples of these publications. For example, Bicknell's <title
              type="simple" render="italic">Counterfeit Detector and Bank Note List,</title> Vol.
            XV, No. 5, Whole No. 186 (Philadelphia, March 2, 1846), listed three closed banks in
            North Carolina and the bills of other banks circulating in Philadelphia at discounts of
            1 1/2% and 2%. The American Antiquarian Society has an extensive collection of paper
            currency.</p>
          <p>There is no single, comprehensive bibliography of this currency as there is for
            colonial and Revolutionary currency. The closest thing to it is a series of articles
            published over a period of time in <title type="simple" render="italic">The
              Numismatist,</title> a journal unavailable in this library. These articles were D. C.
            Wismer's <title type="simple" render="doublequote">Descriptive List of Obsolete Paper
              Money, Part I - Embracing the Circulating Notes Issued by State Banks, Private Banks,
              Bankers and Corporations.</title> These articles were illustrated and contained
            descriptions of each variety of bill issued by an institution. The Information Folder of
            this collection contains a photocopy of the North Carolina section published in <title
              type="simple" render="italic">The Numismatist</title> during June-August, 1931. A more
            extensive list of the currency of twenty-one North Carolina banks is J. Roy Pennell,
            Jr.'s <title type="simple" render="italic">Obsolete Bank Notes of North Carolina</title>
            (Anderson, S.C., undated) of which a photocopy is filed in the Information Folder.
            Bibliographies are available for some states. An excellent example is Charles J.
            Affleck's <title type="simple" render="italic">The Obsolete Paper Money of
              Virginia.</title>
          </p>
          <p>See also the tokens in this collection which were also issued by private businesses as
            currency.</p>
          <p>1 item added, 8-18-83. A dollar bill issued on Feb. 2, 1852, at New York City by the
            Hungarian Fund. It was one of the American issues of Lajos Kossuth, President of the
            first Hungarian Republic (1848-1849), in his attempt to raise funds for a return from
            exile. This note is considered to be currency; see Colin Narbeth, et al., <title
              type="simple" render="italic">Collecting Paper Money and Bonds</title> (New York,
            1979), p. 53.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref30_dqd" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Confederate and Southern States Currency</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_e2fa0ee70046635fb01086ca278d0b57">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>The collection of Confederate and Southern states currency is very extensive,
            consisting of 3329 pieces. Of this total 2601 bills were issued by the national
            government, and 727 bills were issues of state governments. See also the Raphael P.
            Thian Papers for a large collection of Confederate and Southern States currency.</p>
          <p>The standard catalog for this money is Grover C. Criswell, Jr.'s, <title type="simple"
              render="italic">Confederate and Southern States Currency.</title> It is the basis for
            the identification and listing of the bills in this collection. A copy of this catalog
            is available in the Rubenstein Library. The latest edition available for use in
            describing this collection was the 1964 edition. The Confederate currency in this
            collection is divided into three categories: </p>
          <list type="ordered">
            <item>Confederate Currency (Deacidified), 638 items;</item>
            <item>Confederate Currency (Not Deacidified), 47 items;</item>
            <item>Confederate Currency (Ball Family Division), 1930 items all of which have been
              deacidified.</item>
          </list>
          <p>The Ball Family Division was the gift of Mr. Douglas B. Ball and his father, Mr. George
            W. Ball, former U.S. ambassador to the United Nations, among whose family possessions
            this money was found. Mr. Douglas Ball, whose knowledge of Confederate currency is
            extensive, knew of the large collection at Duke and chose to augment it with the Balls'
            sizeable collection. Gifts from the Balls also made possible the deacidification work
            that has been done. Douglas Ball is author of the <emph render="doublequote"
              >Foreword</emph> to the 1972 republication of Raphael P. Thian's <title type="simple"
              render="italic">Register of the Confederate Debt,</title> a basic source for checking
            the authenticity of Confederate paper currency.</p>
          <p>Douglas Ball had cataloged the Ball Collection in detail, its basic arrangement based
            upon Criswell. Ball's lists of the currency are filed with it. Ball sometimes deviated
            from or elaborated upon the listings in Criswell. For example, there are $20 bills, Type
            58, Criswell No. 418/1 which Ball has further subdivided into undated, redrawn letters,
            and maroon letters. His lists also record his evaluations of the variety, rarity,
            condition and value of the bills. Mr. Ball's extensive cataloging and listing made it
            especially appropriate to maintain the Ball Collection as a separate division of the
            Currency Collection. Not all of Ball's lists itemize each bill, citing the number of
            each note. In these cases, additional lists have been made itemizing each bill and
            recording its number whenever legible. Thus, some groups of bills have two lists. The
            checkmarks beside the note numbers on the Ball lists were made by staff of the
            Rubenstein Library, the marks indicating that those bills are part of the Duke
            collection. Ball did not always list notes in strict numerical order. For example, among
            the $20 notes, Type 18, he mixed Criswell numbers as well as note numbers. His lists
            should always be used with this characteristic in mind.</p>
          <p>The Confederate Currency (Deacidified and Not Deacidified) consists of the library's
            collection that originated from sources other than the Ball family. The Confederate
            Currency (Not Deacidified) consists of more recent acquisitions and other bills that
            were not included in the deacidification project and that have to be kept separate from
            the treated items. The arrangement of the Ball Family Division of Confederate Currency
            and of the Confederate Currency is the same. The notes are arranged first by
            denominations: $1, $5, $20, $50, etc. Each denomination is subdivided by Type numbers as
            listed in Criswell's catalog. Types are bills of different designs. Types are subdivided
            according to denominations, dates, internal design differences, overprints, etc., each
            subdivision having been assigned a Criswell number. Thus, Types are subdivided by
            Criswell numbers, although not always in exact numerical order. The lists record the
            Type number, Criswell number, denomination, serial letter, note number, condition and
            value (Ball's lists), and occasional comments.</p>
          <p>The numerical count of the denominations of notes in the Ball Family Division is: </p>
          <list type="ordered">
            <item>$1 (6);</item>
            <item>$2 (15);</item>
            <item>$5 (569);</item>
            <item>$10 (662);</item>
            <item>$20 (514);</item>
            <item>$50 (106);</item>
            <item>$100 (53);</item>
            <item>$500 (4);</item>
            <item>$1000 (1).</item>
          </list>
          <p>The count for the Confederate Currency (Deacidified) is:</p>
          <list type="ordered">
            <item>50¢ (20);</item>
            <item>$1 (24);</item>
            <item>$2 (94);</item>
            <item>$5 (116);</item>
            <item>$10 (190);</item>
            <item>$20 (85);</item>
            <item>$50 (45);</item>
            <item>$100 (58);</item>
            <item>$500 (6).</item>
          </list>
          <p>Duplicates are numerous, but, of course, no two bills have the same note numbers which,
            although occasionally printed in early currency, are usually handwritten. The count of
            the Confederate Currency (Not Deacidified) is:</p>
          <list type="ordered">
            <item>50¢ (2);</item>
            <item>$1 (9);</item>
            <item>$5 (5);</item>
            <item>$10 (10);</item>
            <item>$20 (8);</item>
            <item>$50 (3);</item>
            <item>$100 (2);</item>
            <item>$500 (2);</item>
            <item>(a total of 41 pieces.)</item>
          </list>
          <p>The Southern States Currency is divided into two categories in order to keep separate
            the deacidified and non-deacidified notes. The non-deacidified notes (549) are from the
            following states:</p>
          <list type="ordered">
            <item><geogname>Alabama </geogname>(2);</item>
            <item><geogname>Georgia </geogname>(2);</item>
            <item><geogname>Louisiana </geogname>(2);</item>
            <item><geogname>North Carolina </geogname>(518);</item>
            <item><geogname>Missouri </geogname>(8);</item>
            <item><geogname>Texas </geogname>(1);</item>
            <item><geogname>Virginia </geogname>(16).</item>
          </list>
          <p>The deacidified notes (166) are from:</p>
          <list type="ordered">
            <item><geogname>Alabama </geogname>(34);</item>
            <item><geogname>Arkansas </geogname>(1);</item>
            <item><geogname>Georgia </geogname>(91);</item>
            <item><geogname>Louisiana </geogname>(5);</item>
            <item><geogname>Mississippi </geogname>(28);</item>
            <item><geogname>North Carolina </geogname>(6);</item>
            <item><geogname>Virginia </geogname>(1)</item>
          </list>
          <p>The engraving, printing, and decorative vignettes on the currency issued by the
            Confederate and Southern state governments are worthy of note, but these bills in
            general are not as colorful, varied, and beautiful as those issued during and before the
            Civil War by the private banks and other businesses. Illustrative vignettes are still
            common. They include portraits of men and women, public buildings, planters and slaves
            in the fields, Indians, railroads, steamships and sailing ships, mythological scenes,
            historical scenes, war scenes, agricultural scenes, places, etc. A notable vignette is a
            view of the port of Wilmington, N.C., that appears on a $5 bill from N.C. and also on a
            $100 bill from Mississippi, in the latter case not labeled on the bill.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref45_wc4" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>United States Currency</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_525ddd090aa0b2173ceb2ca76f6e1c06">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>Congress authorized a national paper currency in 1861 which has continued in use since
            that time. A useful catalog of all issues is Gene Hessler's <title type="simple"
              render="italic">The Comprehensive Catalog of U.S. Paper Money</title> (Chicago,
            1974).</p>
          <p>This collection includes 13 pieces of U.S. fractional currency. As the Civil War
            developed, the intrinsic value of coins exceeded their face value, and coins disappeared
            from circulation to such a degree that commerce was hampered. Congress, therefore,
            authorized the issuance of fractional paper currency that appeared in five issues during
            1862-1876 in denominations of 3, 5, 10, 15, 25, and 50 cents. The twelve pieces in this
            collection are from all five issues and all denominations except fifteen cents. There
            are also five silver certificates from, 1896, 1899, and 1935.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref47_kiy" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Foreign Currency</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_56127bda203f6002f2378b981bf3aa6a">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>There are 162 pieces of paper currency, 1771-1982, from 19 countries in Europe, Asia,
            Latin America, and North America. The countries are:</p>
          <list type="ordered">
            <item><geogname>Austria </geogname>(10 bills), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1920-1944;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>France </geogname>(19), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1792-1944;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Belgium </geogname>(1), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
              >1916;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Czechoslovakia </geogname>(1);</item>
            <item><geogname>Germany </geogname>(50), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1914-1944;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Russia </geogname>(7), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1918-1919
                &amp; undated;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>China </geogname>(11), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1940-1944;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Japan </geogname>(7), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1771 and
                modern;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Japan </geogname>in Occupied Areas of <geogname>Philippines,
                </geogname><geogname>Dutch East Indies, </geogname>and British colonies (35), <date
                calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1940's;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Cuba </geogname>(14), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1872-1897;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Colombia </geogname>(1), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1953;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Peru </geogname>(1), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
              >1956;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Ecuador </geogname>(1), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
              >1958;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Chile </geogname>(2), modern;</item>
            <item><geogname>Argentina </geogname>(3), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1869 &amp;
                undated;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Brazil </geogname>(4), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1891 &amp;
                undated;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Mexico </geogname>(3), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
              >1914;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Haiti </geogname>(1), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
              >1827;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Costa Rica </geogname>(1), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1982;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Canada </geogname>(2), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1859-1861.</date></item>
          </list>
          <p>Many of the Austrian and German bills are from the severe inflationary period of the
            early 1920's, and many were issued by towns and cities. Two Austrian and three German
            bills are occupation notes issued by the Allied military authorities in 1944. Five bills
            from Imperial Russia include one of 1918 from the Siberian Temporary Government. Two
            early bills from the Soviet Union in 1919 have the slogan <emph render="doublequote"
              >Workers of the World, Unite</emph> printed on them in various languages. French
            currency includes four assignats, 1792-1793, from the Revolution and several bills from
            World War I.</p>
          <p>From Asia there are bills issued by banks in China during World War II. Japanese
            currency includes three bills of 1771 from Bungo, Kyushu. They are called bookmarks,
              <emph render="doublequote">hansatsu,</emph> which were a long, narrow form of paper
            money issued in feudal Japan. They were printed on both sides by the woodblock method in
            black ink. Bookmarks were not produced by the central authority, the shogunate, but
            rather by local authorities. Thirty-five bills were issued by the Japanese government
            for use in the occupied Philippines, Dutch East Indies, and British colonies during
            World War II. The bills for the British colonies have the letters <emph
              render="doublequote">OC</emph> printed on them which apparently signify use in
            Oceania. These bills are known as occupation notes and JIMs, short for Japanese invasion
            money.</p>
          <p>From Latin America there are Cuban bills dating from just before the Spanish-American
            War as well as earlier. There are three bills of 1914 from the state of Chihuahua during
            the Mexican Revolution. Two Argentine bills were issued in 1869 by the Province of
            Buenos Ayres. There is an 1827 bill from Haiti. Brazilian currency includes items from
            1891.</p>
          <p>The two Canadian bills of 1859 and 1861 were issued by private banks.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref52_ihr" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Coins: U.S. &amp; Foreign</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_e5253eba0d1de8732352034e06525e2d">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>An assortment of 63 coins, 1875-1971, are from:</p>
          <list type="ordered">
            <item><geogname>U.S. </geogname>(9), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1875-1964;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Great Britain </geogname>(5), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1971;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Canada </geogname>(3), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1926-1944;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Switzerland </geogname>(1), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1913;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Tunisia </geogname>(1), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
              >1941;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Japan </geogname>(1), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
              >1966;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Peru </geogname>(2), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1946-1959;</date></item>
            <item><geogname>Brazil </geogname>(41), <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"
                >1938-1960.</date></item>
          </list>
          <p>The U.S. coins include 50¢ commemoratives for the World's Columbian Exposition in
            Chicago, 1893, the Lexington-Concord Sesquicentennial in 1925, and the Pilgrim
            Tercentenary in 1920. The British coins are from the first issue of decimal coinage in
            1971.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref57_auu" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Tokens: U.S. &amp; Foreign</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_15493072690356009091d3669c030a12">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>The shortage of money during the Civil War resulted in the issuance of low-value
            metallic tokens as well as paper currency. First issued in late 1862, over 11,000 kinds
            of Civil War tokens, including die and metal varieties, were issued between late 1862
            and mid-1864. They were struck largely in copper, bronze, and brass. Merchants of every
            conceivable type issued tokens. This practice continued until Congress forbade private
            individuals to issue money, including tokens, in April, 1864. Since the North had the
            metal and the machinery to produce coins, and the South lacked them, the issuance of
            Civil War tokens was almost entirely a Northern phenomenon. There are two categories of
            Civil War tokens: patriotic tokens parading nationalistic types and slogans; and endless
            varieties of commercial advertising tokens called <emph render="doublequote">Civil War
              store cards</emph> or simply <emph render="doublequote">store cards.</emph> A concise
            history of these tokens is in <title type="simple" render="italic">The Macmillan
              Encyclopedic Dictionary of Numismatics.</title> An extensive catalog of Civil War
            advertising tokens is: George and Melvin Fuld, <title type="simple" render="italic">U.S.
              Civil War Store Cards</title> (Lawrence, Mass., 2nd ea. 1975). A catalog of the
            patriotics is George and Melvin Fuld's <title type="simple" render="italic">Patriotic
              Civil War Tokens; Descriptive and Price Catalogue the Die Varieties of Patriotic Type
              Tokens Used as a Substitute For Money During the American Civil War</title> (Racine,
            Wisc., 1965).</p>
          <p>This collection includes two advertising tokens from businesses in Troy, N.Y., and New
            York City. There are three patriotic tokens. Their reverse designs are illustrated in
            George Hetrich and Julius Guttag's <title type="simple" render="italic">Civil War Tokens
              and Tradesmen's Store Cards</title> (Stow, Mass., 3rd ea. 1968).</p>
          <p>There is one British commercial coin. It is a heavy, one penny copper token issued in
            1812 by the Union Copper Company in Birmingham, England. This token is described in
            Robert Charles Bell's <title type="simple" render="italic">Copper Commercial Coins
              1811-1819</title> (Newcastle upon Tyne, 1964), pp. 88-89. Another piece, a probable
            token, has on one side a British sailing ship and on the other side the words <emph
              render="doublequote">Ships Colonies &amp; Commerce.</emph>
          </p>
          <p>An unidentified probable token is from a <emph render="doublequote">Hotel
              Piscopu,</emph> place and date unknown. </p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref59_9vq" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Northern States Currency</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_333eefd4b889720f17e63bf3891f0d03">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>There is one bill, a nine pence bill issued by the state of Rhode Island in 1786.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
