<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/dalton/">dalton</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection, 1695-1955 and undated
                  <num>RL.00284</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Compiled by: Kimberly Sims; machine-readable finding aid created by: Kimberly
               Sims</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2008</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">001662928</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-09-28 09:42:10
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton collection</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Dalton, Harry L.</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00284</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">80.5 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1695/1955" type="inclusive">1695-1955 and undated</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_90225ad24af9816300600d0703565533">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_9d85ab4de3bfc268fa51d2b4e6e4b62e">Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton
            collected art, rare books, and manuscripts, and made many contributions to art museums
            and libraries, most notably the Duke University Library, the Mint Museum, and the
            library of the University of North Carolina at Charlotte. The Dalton Collection is
            comprised of sub-collections acquired by Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_9a65dcd29d262b7c1f1f03deb7ec7a5c">
            <extent>approx. 11,160 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_17308f314c629897a5fea9e6efcffdf5">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_f496339d49fcbe5266c97a1eaa5c7f1d">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_f9d6577a14be0d42083e4dd744ad92d4">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_02284268c5dec4ae13aa99e9b13156b8">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection, David M. Rubenstein
            Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_1c6dc566239aeb51e31d3522fba628c7">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare
            Book &amp; Manuscript Library as a series of gifts in 1977, 1978, 1980, 1982, and
            1991.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_b407c1c293282a500b5fd862b82cfa95">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Compiled by Kimberly Sims, April 2008</p>
         <p>Encoded by Kimberly Sims, April 2008</p>
         <p>Updated by Kimberly Sims, October 2011</p>
         <p>Accessions were merged into one collection, described in this finding aid. </p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_39806193e31c429e29c0d227ff61b23e">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Harry Lee Dalton was born in Winston, North Carolina on June 13, 1895. A graduate of
            Trinity College (now Duke University), he served in the U.S. Army Air Corps during World
            War I. Dalton had a successful career in banking and finance and served as an officer
            and investor in numerous companies, including American Viscose Corporation, American
            Credit Corporation and Wachovia Bank. His other business interests included investments
            in oil extraction ventures, mainly through the Ancora Corporation. </p>
         <p> Dalton and his wife, Mary Keesler, collected art, rare books, and manuscripts, and made
            many contributions to art museums and libraries, most notably the Duke University
            Library, the Mint Museum, and the library of the University of North Carolina at
            Charlotte. Dalton died in Charlotte on July 26, 1990. </p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_4b1f5b042c2f45c8da696aaa865be3ef">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The Dalton Collection is comprised of sub-collections acquired by Harry L. and Mary K.
            Dalton. Included are family papers, correspondence, diaries, account books, photographs,
            engravings, land grants, and military papers. The material largely encompasses the Civil
            War, Southern [U.S.] history, business and politics. The material ranges in date from
            1695-1955.</p>
         <p>Each sub-collection is listed in alphabetical order below. Most include their
            descriptions from the catalog record as well as a link to the record which will serve to
            state the physical location of the sub-collections. For the small number of
            sub-collections not yet fully cataloged, a brief description will follow as well as
            which Dalton Collection box the material resides in. </p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_ab487b0a15d3e37220e43b67f2257238">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>
            <archref>
               <unittitle label="Collection">Harry L. Dalton Papers, 1776-1990</unittitle>
               <repository label="Repository">Special Collections, J. Murrey Atkins Library,
                  UNC-Charlotte</repository>
            </archref>
         </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <persname source="ingest">Dalton, Harry L.</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref13_zq9" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>A-B</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_epe" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000842384"
                           >Adams Family papers, 1828</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_916fb928dd0a3d4e6acd1c4eab56b8ae">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Land grant signed by John Quincy Adams for William Mason of Huntsville, AL in
                     1828.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_gvd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE003950049"
                           >Andrassy, Count Julius papers, 1832-circa 1873</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4ae7ff2314959b8cf3ac2bbc696f73af">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>One 1832 letter written in Hungarian, possibly from Andrassy's father, Karoli,
                     as well as a couple of newspaper articles that deal with the acceptance by
                     Count Andrassy of the post of Prime Minister of Hungary, written in English in
                     the 1870s. Items are located in Box 1 of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton
                     Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_a8f" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001751725"
                           >Arnett Family papers, 1861-1865</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_756882f1a5c42afc20cce5511ab29067">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Two Civil War diaries chiefly concerning camp life. Contributors to diaries
                     are: B. A. Arnett, a private in the Buck Head Guards of the Fairfield District,
                     S.C., his brother R. C., and his sister Sue. Entries include accounts and debts
                     contracted during the war by the Arnett brothers.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_rh8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001662926"
                           >Austin, Benjamin W. papers, 1798-1895</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d74585a1eece623032ada744b3ebe0cf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>This is the autograph and signed letter collection of Benjamin W. Austin. Many
                     of the letters and autographs were obtained through Mr. Austin’s written
                     request, but older items appear to have come from the autograph collection of
                     Henry Sheldon of Salisbury, Vermont. Although many items are older, most of Mr.
                     Austin’s active collecting was done in the 1880s and 1890s. The group includes
                     items from Congressmen, Civil War heroes, literary figures, and educators. Of
                     special note in the collection is a 1798 message from William Henry Harrison at
                     Fort Washington. Many of the items are accompanied by biographical clippings
                     and several are attached to photographs. Of particular interest are the vintage
                     photographs of Commander Gilbert C. Wittse, naval engineer William H. Shock,
                     and statesman and educator J. L. M. Curry.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_e1z" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002494262"
                           >Balloch, William papers, 1856-1866</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5e9c72cb2ac5035031101dd908c17a5d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Account book (1832-1851) lists transactions with local people (including
                     relatives). Entries document the sale of farm products; the letting of fields,
                     vehicles, and animals; and transactions with a boarder. Occasionally Ballock
                     was paid in labor and in trade. Form 1844-1851 Balloch used part of the book as
                     a memorandum book, recording household and personal purchases. Cash book
                     (1856-1866) lists objects and services bought by Balloch and names the
                     supplier. Purchases include books and newspapers, toys, and a violin as well as
                     household supplies. Entries also document loans made, funds handled for the
                     town of Claremont, N.H., and drugs purchased.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_y0p" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000897849"
                           >Baylor, Mary papers, 1861</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_44198f46f820dc37de9a8cb457e45a4c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Three letters from E. R. Brown of North Mountain, Va., to Mary Baylor,
                     concerning her slave, William, who is imprisoned in the Hagerstown (Md.) jail.
                     Brown offers Miss Baylor his assistance in crossing Confederate lines to
                     retrieve William before he is sold. The final letter is an angry reply to an
                     "impertinent" message from Miss Baylor and contains a cartoon vignette of
                     slaves fleeing to Fort Monroe, Va., while a Southern master dressed in a white
                     suit and with a whip attempts to stop them.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_ovh" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001732993"
                           >Beatty, Reading K. papers, 1898-1906</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_00fb182cb99d05afb64a0a96e0163d9f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Chiefly personal letters written from the Philippines by John Beatty, soldier
                     in Company A, First Tennessee Infantry, to his brother Reading K. Beatty.
                     Topics include: Manila; the Spanish-American War; Philippines culture; John's
                     business ventures in the Philippines; and references to Maryville College in
                     Tennessee. Also includes a few financial papers and printed public documents
                     such as executive orders.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_61y" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002505330"
                           >Beauregard, Doctor [Chevalier?] papers, 1808-1822</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3c5d1492c9bf14aed887cdaa89a29bad">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Sales slips and bills of Beauregard in Philadelphia, buying medicinal goods and
                     settling acounts (1817-1819); three letters from "Good Rest" (1822), one from
                     his overseer, Richard Newman, one from his manager, John Cotter, and a letter
                     from young Dr. Beauregard to his father in Augusta, Ga. An undated list of the
                     goods and slaves of his plantation in included in the collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_t4d" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000845240"
                           >Beauregard, [Pierre] Gustave Toutant papers, 1860-1870s</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_90079bb7a862e13205399c82176ee575">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Papers are an estimate signed by Beauregard of the funds necessary for the
                     operations of Fort Jackson, La., during the fiscal year ending June 30, 1861
                     and a report of "Sherman's March" written on 1870s stationery of the New
                     Orleans and Carrollton Railroad Company, giving mileage and dates.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_s6c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002180171"
                           >Bingham, Lemuel papers, 1815-1816, 1832</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1b045de1604f931db51602cabb47196c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lemuel Bingham's ledger is divided into two parts: an auctioneer's sales book
                     for a Fayetteville, N.C. auctioneers' firm listing sales of groceries and
                     sundries from January 1815 -January 1816 and a subscription book, 1832, for the
                     CATAWBA JOURNAL (Charlotte, N.C.).</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref34_3mb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref
                           xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/bradleyf/"
                           >Bradley Family papers, 1774-1882</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d4a99e7ee76dedc6aa9232506e9959ca">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Stephen Row Bradley and his son William Czar Bradley were lawyers who, as
                     residents of Westminster, Vermont, served in the U.S. Senate and House of
                     Representatives respectively. Later Stephen moved to Walpole, New Hampshire.
                     Many prominent New Englanders corresponded with them about Federalist,
                     Republican, and Democratic politics, patronage, and legal and personal matters.
                     Stephen's son-in-law, Samuel Griswold Goodrich ("Peter Parley") was his most
                     frequent correspondent. Other subjects of the correspondence include the
                     Vermont militia, relations between the U.S. and Tripoli, attitudes toward the
                     War of 1812, surveying of the northeastern boundary between the U.S. and
                     Canada, General Lafayette's visit to Thomas Jefferson in 1824, John Quincy
                     Adams, Henry Clay, and Andrew Jackson.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref36_qci" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000846347"
                           >Bragg, Braxton papers, 1847-1876</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4cbd26c07ba9ef1ebc10a03b53ff14b9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Predominently letters concerning military affairs. The four items collected by
                     the Daltons were combined with other Bragg materials in 1980.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref38_2y9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002245413"
                           >Brown, Jacob Jennings papers, 1814-1825</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1674dfe1e258ab46dbc2b625997cf9f3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection consists of two undated engravings of Brown, a letter, and a
                     memorandum bound in pink ribbon. The letter is addressed to the Secretary of
                     the Navy and was written in Brown's capacity as Commander. The full title of
                     the memorandum booklet is "Memoranda of occurences and some important facts
                     attending the Campaign on the Niagara." Brown narrates the events of the
                     campaign. There are verified copies of major communications during the
                     campaign, including messages from J.C. Calhoun, James Monroe, General Ripley,
                     and others. Of special interest is a sort of appendix consisting of "An
                     Estimate of the British Regular Troops in Upper Canada, July 1, 1814. With a
                     view of their distribution." It is a detailed look at early nineteenth century
                     military conflicts.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref40_32a" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000887917"
                           >Buchanan, James papers, 1841-1859</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4a85d276a9bb43ac4cd2605bfef06187">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>One letter dated 1841, land grants signed by Buchanan; and an 1856 pamplet
                     entitled, <title type="simple" render="italic">The Agitation of Slavery. Who
                        Commenced! and Who Can End It!! Buchanan and Fillmore Compared from the
                        Record. </title>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref42_cmv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002494265"
                           >Burns, Robert, undated</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_97c12470b20a2caed0f6fe63b067ca8a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Letter from Burns to an unnamed friend in Edinburgh thanking him for the gift
                     of a set of the writings of Edmund Spenser. Burns closed the letter with a
                     stanza of poetry. Transcription of the letter is included.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref44_20t" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002582807"
                           >Butler, Benjamin Franklin papers, 1864-1893</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a3267014c39db79009938d8ee834c164">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Primarily letters, most to O. D. Barrett regarding financial matters. Also
                     included are references to organized labor, the eight-hour law, and Butler's
                     attitude toward African Americans.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref46_a56" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002247865"
                           >Butler, Matthew Calbraith papers, 1851-1920</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_793fc6ff3ab0200c31f101ea159fb78a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection is primarily composed of Butler's personal and political
                     correspondence. A few letters relate to his cousins in Louisiana. He sends
                     detailed accounts of the war to his wife, Maria, daughter of S.C. Governor
                     Pickens. Butler vividly describes battles, troop movements, and camp life.
                     After the war, some correspondence deals with his Senate office, including his
                     involvement in the Spanish evacuation of Cuba. Other papers concern his son's
                     murder and legal matters. There are poems, genealogical materials, a 32-page
                     memoir of Reconstruction in S.C. by Butler's daughter, plus an essay by
                     her.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref48_o00" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>C-D</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref49_ap0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001112758"
                           >Cist, Lewis Jacob papers, 1726-1896, undated</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_33dda8b14622f0892c5e94608c9e9ddf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>283 autographed letters collected by Cist, largely of military officers as well
                     as writers and scientists.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref51_yra" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Civil War, Miscellany papers, 1860-1865</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7ac8c3d844645f1c0cf7ad2ba0f700d5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Thirty-eight items that relate to the Civil War. Mainly correspondence, the
                     material represents both the Union and the Confederacy. Of note is an 1862
                     petition signed by 74 citizens of De Soto and Marshall Counties in Mississippi
                     in an effort to have a negro named Isaac returned to De Soto County from the
                     protection of General Sherman. Isaac was accused of the rape and murder of a
                     local woman, Ellen Vines. The items are located in Box 2 of the Harry L. and
                     Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref53_uq0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001751774"
                           >Clawson, Jacob H. papers, 1820-1862</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bff31b31b02b77bed5805fa8218781b2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection consists mostly of correspondence concerning business dealings among
                     Clawson's family members in Berkeley County, W. Va. Although most of the items
                     in this collection concern the collection of old debts, several letters from
                     Thomas Dunn outline the hardships of frontier medical life. A few letters are
                     addressed to "Dr." Jacob H. Clawson at the Ebenezer Academy near Rock Hill, S.
                     C.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref55_x0e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001751775"
                           >Cleburne, Patrick Ronayne papers, 1864</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_79c6ae78b21316b7d839de0c1f7a6c34">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>This collection centers on a copy of a speech given by General Cleburne to the
                     regimental commanders and general officers of the Army of the Tennessee on
                     January 2, 1864. The copy was requested from Cleburne by General W. H. T.
                     Walker to be forwarded to Jefferson Davis. Walker considered the address
                     inflammatory and likely to result in "ruin" and "disgrace." The document
                     itself, signed by Cleburne, is his famous suggestion that the Confederacy, by
                     that time in dire circumstances, should free the slaves and muster them into
                     the Army. Cleburne outlined the main reasons this would be beneficial: 1) the
                     wind would be knocked out of Yankee moral zeal, 2) foreign countries would be
                     morally free to give substantial aid to the South, 3) the actual size of the
                     Army would be greatly augmented, and 4) the black population of the South would
                     no longer constitute a threat as spies for the enemy.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref57_sab" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000890414"
                           >Crawford, Samuel Wylie papers, 1861-1863</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9afc0703c8e221defef697b60869aeb8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Report to Lt. Col. F. T. Locke of the operations of the 3rd Division in the
                     battles near Gettysburg [1863], a letter from John Titcomb Sprague, 1861,
                     commenting on Fort Sumter and its commander, Robert Anderson; orders from
                     Crawford, 1870, as commander of the United States troops in Alabama instructing
                     officers on the policing of the polls during the coming election; and a letter
                     from the sheriff of Montgomery, 1870, concerning the threat of a riot.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref59_dlx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002199801"
                           >Davis, James M. papers, 1864</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a9fd5173effbba4628365342d079dd6f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Two letters written by Davis to his wife in Camden, South Carolina, during the
                     Civil War. He wrote the week of May 7-10, 1864, of his efforts to rejoin his
                     command.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref61_yza" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000849840"
                           >Davis, Jefferson papers, 1841-1938</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3dfa42eaa10ccd4ff49a2ba17768b907">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Four items collected by the Daltons were combined with other Davis
                     materials.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref63_4ru" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002199805"
                           >Deblois, Thomas A. papers, 1833</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_dc479a096d8ee193d50fb2c3f6992b98">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Letter from Nathan Hale, editor of the Boston Daily Advertiser, to Deblois
                     writing in support of Daniel Webster as a possible presidential candidate. Hale
                     makes reference to Andrew Jackson and asks Dublois to pass an article about
                     Webster on to Major Jack Downing (pseudonym for Seba Smith) for possible
                     publication in the Portland Courier.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref65_qq6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002199806"
                           >De la Rame´, Louise papers, circa 1893</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7f279074015162181ddb8aef719a4013">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>This signed manuscript is a translation of Louis-Adrien Levat's "La Disparition
                     des Oiseaux" (La Nouvelle Revue, Vol. 80, Jan.-Feb. 1893, pp. 598-602). De la
                     Rame´ was a translator of French who went by the pseudonym Ouida.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref67_lhl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000851748"
                           >De Saussure Family papers, 1788-1916</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2b3e7a02bb7d4aa71fcc8456dde9d556">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Correspondence and papers of Henry William De Saussure and of grandson Wilmot
                     Gibbes De Saussure, South Carolina legislator and Confederate Army officer.
                     Subjects include the establishment of South Carolina College (later the
                     University of South Carolina), the Mexican War, conditions in the Confederacy,
                     political phases of Reconstruction, an interview between Carl Schurz and Henry
                     A. De Saussure, effect of the contested election of 1877, and the Charleston
                     earthquake of August 31, 1886. Also included are documents concerning real
                     estate transfers, and genealogical records of the Bacot, Burden, De Saussure,
                     Gourdin, Hamilton, Mood, Pringle, and Swinton families. Among the
                     correspondents and persons mentioned are P.G.T. Beauregard, Henry Alexander De
                     Saussure, John M. De Saussure, Adam T. Millican, Benjamin Silliman, and Henry
                     D.A. Ward. The 5 items collected by the Daltons were merged into this
                     collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref69_p5u" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">District of Columbia, Miscellany papers, 1815-1928</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_021b102c3b8eb0cd0ebe7f738ad4e598">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>These 22 items are largely correspondence written in Washington, DC or sent to
                     Washington, DC. Examples include a 1928 letter from Herbert Hoover to John
                     Mullowney of Nashville, TN, a 1901 letter from Senator Orville H. Platt to
                     Julius Brown, Esq., an 1884 letter from Secretary of the Interior, Henry M.
                     Teller to U. S. Representative Richard Warner, an 1881 letter from Supreme
                     Court Justice John Marshall Harlan, an 1879 letter from then-U. S.
                     Representative James A. Garfield to Joseph Carter of Missouri, an 1877 letter
                     from Z. Chandler, Chairman of the National Republican Committee to George
                     Carter of New Orleans, an 1863 and an 1866 letter from U. S. Representative
                     Schuyler Colfax, and an 1865 letter written by Confederate veteran, George C.
                     Watkins of Little Rock to Washington lawyer James Carlisle, regarding Watkins'
                     legal post-war woes. This folder is in Box 3 of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton
                     Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref71_p2w" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002683930"
                           >Dugas Family papers, 1763-1848</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0e8ef1c6ffcc143799ef9397b07320a6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Papers in this collection include letters, as well as financial and legal
                     documents. The oldest item is a French marriage contract drawn in 1763, in the
                     name of Louis Renee Adrien Dugas. Most of the material in the collection,
                     however, pertains to Leon Frederick E. Dugas, who traveled extensively as a
                     cotton merchant and general factor. Letters to Dugas discuss business and
                     prices, as well as numerous lawsuits and disputes with importers. Several
                     letters to Dugas from his brother-in-law and partner Paul Ronignol, are in
                     French. A letterpress volume from 1845 records much of Dugas's correspondence
                     from that year. Many of these letters are in French, and virtually all deal
                     with matters of finance, cotton sales, or estate settlements. Of interest are
                     documents representing Dugas's attempts to gain control of the Habersham Iron
                     Works; papers relating to the sale of slaves to the family; and an inventory
                     showing that in 1827, the Dugas family purchased most of the land, goods, and
                     slaves of <title type="simple" render="doublequote">Good-Rest,</title> the
                     Edgefield, S.C. home of Dr. Beauregard.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref73_yy4" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>E-G</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref74_ltb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002560941"
                           >Ellet, William papers, 1761</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_783d0ca863f4af631544b289b88f9ba4">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Book of arithmetic problems and rules.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref76_076" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002273871"
                           >Espy, James Pollard papers, 1844</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d310529523cde58b683ce7c6bd89098b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection centers on the rain theories of Espy. Included is the text of an
                     address on artificial rain-making. There are also two documents from the
                     citizens of Coudersport, Pennsylvania, who tried Espy's theories on a small
                     scale and believed them to be effective.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref78_e7i" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002356522"
                           >Faunce, S.E. papers, 1861-1865</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d13f1ccf52cffd1dcba88c9e507766ca">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection consists of a highly readable account of a Union soldier's
                     experiences in the Civil War. It is in the form of a 48-page, typewritten
                     memoir. There is no substantial clue to the identity of the author, but an
                     attached business card is that of an "S.E. Faunce." The memoir describes events
                     surrounding the 13th Mass. Volunteer Infantry, including the author's
                     witnessing of the battle of Hampton Roads between the MONITOR and the MERRIMAC.
                     Some relationship probably exists between the author of this memoir and Daniel
                     W. Faunce, also of Plymouth.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref80_qvq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002356524"
                           >Feaster Family papers, 1755-1860</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e37cbe10914d8e71b7b0eafa994adfde">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection contains mainly legal items, such as deeds and land grants. The
                     evolution of a tract of land in S.C., 1755, may be traced to the Civil War.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref82_4yq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002388154"
                           >Fludd, Eliza papers, 1865-1868</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_002c4b9327480f352485a7eb4cdf8644">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection contains letters from Fludd mostly written to her friend, Mrs.
                     Jolliffe. Fludd was the sister-in-law of a brother of George A. Trenholm,
                     Secretary of the Treasury of the Confederate States of America. In clear
                     handwriting, Fludd reveals herself to be deeply religious, well-educated, and a
                     witness to the political and social events of the time; her context is
                     Calvinist doctrine. She witnessed the battle and surrender of Fort Sumter and
                     her belongings were destroyed or stolen when Sherman's army passed through
                     Charleston. The letters describe her experiences and trials during the end of
                     the Civil War. She gives an account of her radical change in lifestyle from
                     living with abundance to starvation during Reconstruction, and also of the
                     attitudes of the South to the North.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref84_v1u" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002388021"
                           >Frost, Arthur Burdett papers, 1913-1914</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d9b4383a9815090d394b77e90943df44">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection consists of two letters. One is from Katherine Hinton Wootten,
                     librarian of the Carnegie Library in Atlanta, to Frost thanking him for his
                     letter and drawing of Brer Rabbit. His reply from Switzerland gives news of his
                     illness.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref86_6c5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002254457"
                           >Gaffney Family papers, 1862-1866</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bb40d67516df7c6a29c378536e2f271c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Letters to the Gaffney family of Columbia, S.C., from friends and relatives. A
                     letter (1862) written by P. Lemmons of the 12th South Carolina infantry
                     (Gregg's Brigade) while he was at Camp Arsenal Green in Charleston, S.C.,
                     describes the stealing of a steamship, THE PLANTER, by a party of African
                     Americans. Several letters were written by William W. Gaffney to his parents
                     during the Civil War: one (1862 May 20) from Camp Jackson in Spottsylvania,
                     Va., These describe the events of battles in Virginia and Pennsylvania. Two
                     items deal with financial matters at Furman University.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref88_wkh" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref
                           xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/galesand/"
                           >Gales &amp; Seaton records, 1811-1868</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a6b9eef550883eb6c236c796c4ef7606">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection contains the business papers of Joseph Gales, Jr., and William W.
                     Seaton, editors of the National Intelligencer. Correspondence pertains to
                     subscriptions, advertising, announcements and letters to the editors. Some
                     prominent names appear in the subscription correspondence. Of particular
                     interest are fifty-six transcripts of Congressional speeches, resolutions, and
                     motions. These were presented for publication and are marked for editing. Among
                     the authors of the manuscripts are Henry Clay, James K. Polk, Martin Van Buren,
                     and Daniel Webster. Many are signed. Part of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton
                     Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref90_7ty" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE003952462"
                           >Gaston, William papers, 1814, 1817</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_dc47c4b81038bf0718834b8ec8e71721">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Two letters written by Gaston [of New Bern, NC] to an unknown person. These
                     letters are located in Box 4 of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref92_6ve" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Georgia, Miscellany papers, 1806-1865</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_961624999b41ede23ae23d174aa03dfa">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Twelve items, miscellaneous in relation to one another, but all relate to
                     Georgia. Items include a pledge of allegiance to the Union, signed by Andrew
                     Young in 1865 and an 1806 pardon for Jedediah Seymore signed by Secretary of
                     State Horatio Marbury. These items are located in Box 4 of the Harry L. and
                     Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref94_bz6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002508717"
                           >Greenaway, Kate papers, 1895-1901</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3e7e823e72e67247d0fd100ea83752d8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Contains two letters written to a friend she addresses as Lady Maria. In the
                     first letter she is trying to arrange a time for Lady Maria to visit her, and
                     refers to Mr. Ponsonby, presumably Lady Maria's husband. In the second letter
                     she thanks Lady Maria for flowers she has sent from Ireland; says she has
                     influenza; and reports a coming art exhibit that would feature paintings by Sir
                     John Everett Millais.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref96_xzt" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002586486"
                           >Great Britain, Miscellany papers, 1804-1939</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_117f06ad54c8851c6f641665bad18685">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Primarily correspondence of various government departments and individuals.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref98_qjd" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>H-K</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref99_qp4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE003952514"
                           >Hill, Daniel Harvey papers, 1923</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_cdf8a18379c6803781d97fda60573601">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Two letters to Hill from the Adjutant General of the State of North Carolina
                     regarding the service of North Carolinians in World War I. They are located in
                     Box 4 of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref101_lor" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002565755"
                           >Huddleston, Eliza A. papers, 1861-1864</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c6a6c7dd60c8faea5a279bb5cc0ff441">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Consists of Civil War correspondence between R. R. Huddleston, 6th Regiment of
                     the S.C. Volunteers, and his wife, Eliza A. (Chandler) Huddleston. The first
                     two letters, headed "York District, S.C.," are love letters written before the
                     couple married in 1861. Soon after this, R. R. left for the war. His letters
                     during the period 1862-1864 are from various places in Va., and contain
                     occasional comments on battles and camp life. In one letter (Sept. 12, 1863)
                     Huddleston recounts to his wife the story of having to watch as two fellow
                     South Carolinians were shot for desertion.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref103_jd2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002779194"
                           >Iredell, James papers, 1831-1842</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_724503de9893b869e7eb3a14fc468a97">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Three letters by Iredell addressed to John Branch, Secretary of the Navy; Gales
                     and Seaton; and Willie P. Magnum and William A. Graham. The letter to branch
                     recommends James H. Popelston for a midshipman's warrant. The letter to Gales
                     and Seaton pertains to a subscription to the NATIONAL INTELLIGENCER. To Magnum
                     and Graham, Iredell writes in support of James H. Brazier for appointment as
                     midshipman, and requests that they forward his letter to Secretary of the Navy,
                     Abel P. Upshur. On the same page, Magnum and Graham write a note of transmittal
                     to Upshur, stating that they concur heartily with Iredell's recommendation.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref105_g07" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000862797"
                           >Jackson, Andrew papers, 1820-1836</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_50b759fdb2e255a9aafd2245ef127c1e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Papers chiefly concern military and Indian affairs, including a fight with the
                     British at Mobile, Ala., 1814; raids of the Creek and Seminole Indians;
                     relations between the U. S. government and the Indians in Alabama; the use of
                     U. S. troops to remove intruders from Cherokee lands; affairs of the military
                     department of the South when Jackson was in command, 1816; construction of a
                     military road from Nashville to New Orleans, 1816; and the Seminole War,
                     1835-1842. Several letters discuss politics during and after Jackson's
                     presidency, including his relationships with John Rhea and John C. Calhoun.
                     There is also material about military actions in Florida and Georgia during the
                     War of 1812 and on government relations with the Creek Indians.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref107_00f" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002588767"
                           >Jesup, Thomas Sidney papers, 1787-1860</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a715f6035c8ff3d99841656d331b2167">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>This collection consists military and other papers of Gen. Thomas Sidney Jesup
                     relating mainly to the War of 1812, The Seminole War, and the Mexican War. It
                     contains correspondence between Jesup and Major Willson, Hugh McCall, William
                     Linnard, James Brown, L. P. Heintzelman, William Schley, and William Ballard
                     Preston, among others. Topics are mostly related to military matters and
                     relations with the Creeks and Seminoles. A detailed memoir by Jesup entitled
                     "Memoir of the Campaigne on the Niagara" complements a similar item in the
                     Jacob Jennings Brown Papers. Combined, the two memoirs yield a stunning
                     overview of the Niagara Campaign, and also point to interesting areas of
                     disagreement. Also included in the collection are two items from Washington,
                     D.C., dated 1831. One represents the sale of 21 slaves to Jesup, while the
                     other is the official District of Columbia authorization for such a sale, which
                     is on Department of State Letterhead, and is signed by Secretary of State
                     Edward Livingston. Additionally, the collection contains an 1813 article of
                     agreement between Jesup and Brintnel Robins of Penn., who contracted to supply
                     65 boats for the U.S. troops. The boats were intended for the expedition that
                     later led to the Battle of the Chippewa.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref109_wml" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000862813"
                           >Johnson, Andrew papers, 1865</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0bc4f296df61372f3192d1997d5c4a65">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>This folder contains a draft of a petition to Johnson, 1865, requesting
                     favorable action on the application for pardon submitted by James H. Wilson of
                     Charlotte.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref111_yde" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002586367"
                           >Johnson, Thomas papers, 1776-1779</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_10e5511d85a16990d2480e1a22de0f44">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>The collection consists of 24 items addressed to the Maryland Council of Safety
                     (of which Johnson was a member) and to Thomas Johnson in his capacity as
                     Governor of Maryland (1777-1779). Most of the letters and documents concern
                     Revolutionary War matters, such as the raising of the militia, the difficulties
                     in getting men to accept military commissions, loyalty vouchers for ships
                     leaving Annapolis, and financial aspects such as checks for the payment of
                     debts for supplies. Many names prominent in Maryland history are mentioned.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref113_rnr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002474145"
                           >Jones, Iredell papers, 1842-1906</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2c63e3a3ec4c3129052660d2c8457225">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection contains Jones's correspondence and focuses on the Civil War. Some
                     letters are from Jones to his parents, written while a student at S.C. College
                     and a member of a volunteer group concerned with abolition. In all of the
                     letters he wrote with a terse style, relating news and events. He includes
                     detailed accounts of the military activities surrounding Charleston and Fort
                     Sumter, such as iron-clad battles, bombardment of Sumter and hand to hand
                     combat. Letters of family members, including his brother Cadwallader (Waddy)
                     Jones, also give vivid pictures of the military and social aspects of the war
                     in a broad area of the South. There is an account of the June 1862 twelve-day
                     forced march to Fredericksburg. Other correspondence reflects Jones's courtship
                     and marriage to Ellen Adams. He may have been a member of the Ku Klux Klan and
                     letters tell of his arrest and imprisonment in 1871. Other items include legal
                     papers, miscellany such as an unidentified photograph, and papers concerning
                     the United Confederate Veterans, including data on many veterans.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref115_j8t" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002683903"
                           >Kee, C. T. papers, 1866-1878</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6c92d2a5bc9280f208b7a2b7c57e4bb9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection consists of one volume, which appears to be a records of
                     compensation for agricultural labor. Most of the volume consists of lists of
                     staples, foodstuffs, and cash given to laborers on a per diem basis from 1866
                     to 1878. The last few pages of the book contain written receipts from wages
                     paid by C. T. Kee. All recipients have signed with an "X." This, and a
                     reference to several laborers as "Freedmen" indicate that Kee's laborers were
                     African American. If so, then this volume, covering the 10 years after the
                     Civil War, is valuable documentation of the ways in which African Americans
                     were co-opted into semi-slavery in many parts of the South.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref117_2pz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002683909"
                           >Kelly, Henry Kuhl papers, 1933</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7733cfd91d5f32db4780e44b32015099">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection consists of three short notes from Dr. Harry Atwood Kelly to his son
                     Henry Kuhl Kelly. Dr. Kelly, a devout Christian, writes of his travels and
                     cautions his son on the importance of a pious life and the temptations of
                     alcohol.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref119_dju" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002235673"
                           >Kendall, Amos papers, 1840-1849</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_64f2b67fa6a2824bc54704fe53c972a8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Letter (1840 May 20) from James W. Jeffreys, postmaster at Red House, Caswell
                     County, N.C., to Kendall. The author congratulated Kendall on becoming editor
                     of the Extra Globe and listed his qualifications for the position. Letter (1844
                     Oct. 7) from Andrew Jackson to Kendall. In his letter, Jackson told Kendall how
                     he planned to try to overawe the "nulifiers" of S.C. with a force of around
                     150,000 volunteers from a number of states. If this did not work, he planned to
                     punish the leaders only and not "their humble followers." Jackson reminisced
                     about fighting the Creek Red Sticks in the Battle of Talladega and referred to
                     the mutiny and disorder in his camp at Ten Islands. He also revealed that in
                     his 1829 inaugural address, his friends persuaded him to strike a paragraph
                     opposing the Bank of the United States as being unconstitutional. In closing,
                     Jackson spoke of his shortness of breath when he attempted to walk unassisted.
                     Letter from Sears Cook Walker (1849 Aug. 11) soliciting aid in connecting
                     Southern Telegraph Company lines with the Charleston Observatory.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref121_b2m" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002683912"
                           >Kentucky, Miscellany papers, 1795-1865</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_83cf8a30fe388f2976b4f18ae64f7616">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection of miscellaneous items from Kentucky, including a 1795 Commonwealth
                     of Ky. land grant of 9,728 acres in Nelson Co. to Joseph Lewis, among other
                     deed transferrals. Additional items include a letter of recommendation from
                     George Bibb; a letter dated 3 August 1816, from R. Whiting in New York to James
                     Prentiss in Lexington, Ky., concerning the failure of acceptance of bank drafts
                     on the Mechanics Bank and other banks in Philadelphia and New York; and various
                     business letters.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref123_u0e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE003952439"
                           >Kincaid, M. Virginia papers, 1875-1888</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_967c7aadbfbef6626a199ab1c504c834">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>This collection contains correspondence written to Virginia "Jennie" Kincaid of
                     Collettsville, NC. The folder is located in Box 4 of the Harry L. and Mary K.
                     Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref125_zc2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002588754"
                           >Knox family papers, 1837-1884</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1e958b474ac2a53bb700abf8a181c3c8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>The first item in this collection is a letter from Rome written in 1837 to John
                     Knox of Leesville, S.C. The signature is missing from this item, which relates
                     to the sights and art of Rome. The second item is a letter (1866) addressed to
                     James Knox from Robert H. Miller of Lawrence, Kan. Miller discusses in detail
                     his feelings about the recent Civil War. Most of the letter is devoted to a
                     detailed and stirring account of Quantrill’s 1863 raid on Lawrence, Kan., and
                     the extraordinary events that happened at Miller’s own house. The next three
                     items pertain to W. D. Knox, the son [?] of James Knox. One item is a personal
                     letter of family news written in 1872. Also from that year is a Davidson report
                     card for W. D. Knox’s son, John. The final item (1884) is W. D. Knox’s
                     appointment certificate as school commissioner for Chester County, S.C.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref127_fp2" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>L</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref128_n2t" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001826859"
                           >Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert du Motier, Marquis de
                           papers, 1825-1830</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_74faf818b2fd24cbfbabfbbf7973c775">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Letter of Lafayette, 1825, written on board the "Natchez" on the Mississippi
                     River, introducing Prince Achille Murat, son of the King of Naples, and a group
                     of Murat's Neapolitan friends; letter from Lafayette in Halifax, N.C.,
                     responding to an invitation to visit Tarboro, N.C.; letter from Lafayette to
                     unidentified friend, written from LaGrange, France, 1830, concerning funds for
                     a statue of Thomas Jefferson to be commissioned in Europe on behalf of the
                     University of Virginia (Lafayette favored the appointment of his friend
                     Pierre-Jean David for this commission).</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref130_s42" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE003952864"
                           >Langley family papers, 1855-1887</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_28fd2cbc19cd03e08e4e84c2fae8b1ee">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>This collection consists mainly of Civil War letters written by T. C. Langley
                     (Company J, 12th Regiment, South Carolina Volunteers), to his family near
                     Lancaster Courthouse, South Carolina. Many of the letters are addressed to his
                     father, William C. Langley, and many South Carolina names are mentioned.
                     Although T. C. Langley wrote regularly from 1861-1865, these letters have
                     little military or political content and pertain mainly to personal matters.
                     Langley's main concerns were his brother John (serving with him, and frequently
                     ill) and the state of agricultural matters back home. The regiment to which
                     Langley belonged traveled widely but little is revealed about camplife,
                     battles, or war perspectives, other than occasional lists of casualties. Of
                     interest at one point in the correspondence is the writer's anger that a
                     Lancaster neighbor had tried to buy first T. C.'s father and then his little
                     brother as substitutes in the army (1862). Miscellany for the collection is
                     mainly pre-war legal material from Lancaster District, including small court
                     suits and the settlement of a James Langley's estate. This folder is located in
                     Box 5 of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref132_l8o" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002878433"
                           >Lane, Samuel papers, 1817</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d9d5ce2a8257014d187b04ac6c22536d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>One letter in which Lane informs Congress the new Representative and Senate
                     Chambers will be ready by the autumn of 1818. Dated 1817, the letter includes
                     reports from James Hoban, who was put in charge of rebuilding the White House
                     after it was destroyed in the War of 1812. Hoban gives a detailed account of
                     materials, costs and interior finishing and reveals that the Oval Office was
                     originally called the "Elliptical Saloon."</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref134_1xl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/lee/"
                           >Lee, Robert Edward papers, 1749-1975</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6cbf190f17d8790f462dbcbe91c3a70e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>The Daltons gifted 27 items which help make up the Lee papers.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref136_zto" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001767415"
                           >Lee, Thomas Sim papers, 1779-1782</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_18ba76bd5d2852c867e3055988421b0a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Correspondence directed to Governor Thomas Sim Lee of Maryland during the
                     Revolutionary War. Included are two letters from Army provisioners, and various
                     military letters concerning resignations and deserters. One letter from the
                     General Council grants a man and wife the right to return to Great Britain
                     despite the war; another, from Richard Barnes, solicits aid and describes
                     British harassment of boats and citizens at the mouth of the Potomac.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref138_hhi" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001767417"
                           >Leech, Abraham Paul, 1796-1955(bulk 1840-1930)</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f8087e0be713ef8a56e22bc491136870">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Correspondence, legal and financial papers, photographs, printed material,
                     writings, clippings, and volumes relating chiefly to the Leech family, but also
                     to relations in the Dewey, Warner, and Duryea families. Correspondence topics
                     include: nineteenth-century American politics; reform movements; lectures and
                     lyceums in New York; late nineteenth-century courtship; and school activities
                     at the Stone School and Williams College. One series of letters from 1841 refer
                     to the American poet Walt Whitman. Another series of letters from the Dewey
                     family, beginning in the 1840s, originate from Ohio. Also included in this
                     collection are papers concerning the Jamaica Lyceum, of which Abraham Paul
                     Leech was secretary pro tem in the 1840s.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref140_3hr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000863105"
                           >Legaré, Hugh Swinton papers, 1837-1843</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7676f6d59454a80ad7863e84d307f46a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Miscellaneous correspondence concerning Legaré's legal practice, politics, and
                     the purchase of books for his library. Letter to Legaré (1837) from jurist
                     Frederick Grimke in Delaware, Ohio, while Legaré was in the U.S. Congress,
                     relating to the organization of the court system in the Ohio area and Legaré's
                     planned visit to the "western U. S." Also contains a letter, 1838, from Joel
                     Poinsett, secretary of war of the United States, pertaining to a treaty with
                     the Sioux Indians, and a letter from the sculptor, John Stevens Cogdell,
                     concerning his career.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref142_cfa" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001767357"
                           >Leventhorpe, Collette papers, 1862-1931</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_797f91f47ebdafa06dee096bccffe980">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Records of Confederate Army's 11th Regiment of N.C., formerly 1st Infantry
                     Regiment, also known as the "Bethel Regiment." Includes orders issued by
                     Leventhorpe as commander of the regiment, and orders issued to Leventhorpe;
                     final accounts of members who died in service and inventories of their personal
                     effects; certificates of disability and discharge; and proceedings of
                     courts-martial. Final accounts of deceased members include a physical
                     description of individual, and often his former occupation. Also includes a
                     1931 clipping with a photograph of Leventhorpe.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref144_5sp" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000863868"
                           >Lincoln, Abraham papers, 1861-1938</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4175add82d6228af0c0b4897646767b5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Chiefly facsimiles of Lincoln letters; clippings; and other miscellany
                     concerning Lincoln and his assassination.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref146_6zo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001767367"
                           >Lockyer, Edmund papers, 1811-1814</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_13ec898a3b8e05dd07085a14c10db479">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Handbills and one letter related to British sale of goods captured from sailing
                     ships during War of 1812. Handbills are for sales in Plymouth, England: one
                     (1811) advertises the auction of the cargo of the brig "Fox," and includes
                     detailed auction sheet; another advertises 1812 auction of the cargo of
                     American schooner "Arrow", whose cargo included items such as silk, brandy,
                     champagne, almonds, dress goods, and toys. Each handbill names William Lockyer
                     as broker, and Edmund Lockyer as customs-house agent. A letter (1814) from
                     George Tobin, captain of the H.M.S. "Andromache" asks Edmund Lockyer for
                     payment of bounty on captured ship.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref148_3qe" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001112753"
                           >Long, Benjamin papers, 1854-1856</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_595f6bc373c8ef95f4eb175a07e00876">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>The Daltons gifted 4 items in 1980 which were cataloged under James R. W.
                     Sellwood's name. The items are correspondence from James Sellwood and his
                     brother, John, to Benjamin Long of Mendon, Ill., chiefly concerning the
                     Sellwoods' mission in and around Grahamville, Beaufort Co., S.C. The letters,
                     including a copy of a report to the mission's trustees, describes Sellwood's
                     living conditions and salary, the religious condition and lives of the
                     inhabitants in and around Grahamville, sermon topics, and local customs.
                     Sellwood also mentions the existing local prejudice against the Episcopal
                     Church and that the Baptists attracted possible communicants away from
                     Anglicanism.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref150_hna" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002235674"
                           >Lucas Family papers, 1813-1867 and undated</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_415ff634be10bc423856ba70e71b0c53">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Correspondence, legal papers, and financial papers of the Lucas family of
                     Raleigh, N.C. Early letters (1813-1816) were written by Alexander Lucas to his
                     wife Mary while he visited Pennsylvania and Washington, D.C. Legal papers
                     pertain to a lawsuit involving William Lucas, Henderson Lucas, and Margaret
                     Lucas and concerning the estate and Revolutionary War military bounty of their
                     grandfather, Thomas Lucas. A letter written to William Lucas from N. Davidson
                     (1857) on an advertising sheet contains descriptions of inventions of 1857,
                     including a counterfeit preventing machine for the printing of banknotes, a
                     windmill, a pump, and a letter-copying press. Also included in the collection
                     are letters (1861-1862) from Henderson Lucas of the 34th Regiment of N.C.
                     Troops, Company G, to his sister Margaret. Lucas wrote from Camp Fisher near
                     High Point, N.C., from Camp Davis near Wilmington, and from Hamilton's
                     Crossing. Clippings include one describing Henderson Lucas' heroism at the
                     battle of Gettysburg. Collection also includes a small account book (1821) in
                     which Mary Lucas made a few brief entries.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref152_acw" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>M-O</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref153_l1d" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Maryland, Miscellany papers, 1775-1860</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_39378e7f51e98cdbc92771dd6ba83483">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection of miscellaneous items from Maryland. Includes correspondence and an
                     indenture. This folder is located in Box 6 of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton
                     Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref155_kcv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002241554"
                           >Mason, George papers, undated</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f3a87af927a6ded85519161f435b3890">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection consists of a photostat of pages six and seven of a letter from
                     Mason to an unidentified relative. Mason tells him to proceed to execute a
                     warrant and entry for a grant of land, and he will make an assignment of the
                     entry to him. The land matter involves others, including Messrs. Steptoe and
                     Gosnell. Mason writes that he has delivered to his son a hogshead of tobacco
                     recently received from one of the addressee's tenants, and mentions a snuff
                     mill with which his son Thomson was "concerned" for two years.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref157_ckm" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000868351"
                           >Mayer, Brantz papers, 1845-1890</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f8a3f6eadaf8de84cd034aef8df6b942">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Papers including several letters concerning Bennet Allen, an 18th century
                     Anglican clergymen, pertaining to a riot in Allen's parish and to property he
                     left in America at the time of the Revolution; and correspondence and papers
                     concerning Mayer's interest in Maryland history and archival sources and in the
                     Maryland Historical Society.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref159_6lr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE005999071"
                           >McIntosh, Alexander papers, 1860-1865</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c665f79612d437a7b1699e4df60d54d4">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Chiefly letters to McIntosh from his wife and other relatives. Several are
                     written to him in early 1865 while he was stationed with Company K, 4th
                     Regiment, Senior Reserves in Salisbury, NC, and they primary concern his family
                     and other personal news. Another letter, dated February 4, 1865, is to
                     McIntosh's wife from her brother, R. Gerrard Sifford, while he was being held
                     as a prisoner of war at Point Lookout, MD. McIntosh and his family lived in
                     Martindale, Mecklenburg County, NC. This folder is located in Box 6 of the
                     Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref161_rpv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002241567"
                           >Medical College of Georgia records, 1833-1859</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_31570dd5cca08e7b064dc0580c04b849">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection contains three items. The first is the bill (1833), creating the
                     Medical College from the old Institute. It is signed by Governor Lumpkin and
                     endows the college with funds, land, and trustees. The second item is an 1858
                     graduation statement, listing graduates and discussing briefly the fact that
                     enrollment is down due to the local economy. A third letter (1859), is from F.
                     Campbell at the college, informing an unknown addressee that he has been
                     appointed to the Board of Trustees.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref163_bq0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002241568"
                           >Megahey Family papers, 1861-1877</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_89495d309431c19dc6f0fdef5e3a2736">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection contains three letters from T.C. Megahey to his family in Charlotte,
                     N.C. He recounts events of a trip to Petersburg, Va., and writes of camp life.
                     For one letter, the stationery is from the U.S. Sanitary Commission. The final
                     item is an April Fool's rhyme sent to Miss Mary Megahey.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref165_mbc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Miscellany papers, 1695-1919</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9fe2f9b5270062c56f27c24359a9e418">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>These are miscellaneous items gifted by Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton. Included
                     are deeds and correspondence, including a letter from Jonathan Trumbull, an
                     1865 oath of allegiance signed by James Stump, a ticket to the trial of Tilton
                     vs. Beecher in 1874, and a rough draft of a letter [1877] to Lucy Hayes. This
                     folder is located in Box 6 of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref167_gr6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE003953502"
                           >Montgomery, Josiah papers, 1862-1869</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bdc9272900a68e2d52533d0043a41793">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Largely correspondence written by Montgomery to his mother. This folder is
                     located in Box 6 of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref169_bxd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002251866"
                           >Morrow, John W. papers, 1836-1894</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0066a08db1e7aaa529266e0828f7079b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection consists of Morrow's business papers that cover a wide variety of
                     legal and financial matters. Morrow appears to have specialized in the
                     settlement and disposition of estates. Of note is the correspondence and legal
                     materials of J.E. Hennigan of Texas. Morrow administered the estate of
                     Hennigan's father and the papers reflect the facts of the estate but also
                     family squabbles. The 1888 Articles of Incorporation for the Pineville Cotton
                     mill, as well as two diaries, and an account book are also included.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref171_ek9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000748142"
                           >Murdoch, Susan Butterworth papers, 1894-1912 and undated</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fa32f445554484049d90316ea931c302">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Diary, 1894-1900 (ca. 320 p.), kept by Susan B. Murdoch, and four miscellaneous
                     items. The diary, written primarily from Maineville, Ohio, describes daily
                     routines of a homemaker and wife as well as family concerns. There are
                     additional entries for Benjamin Butterworth (1837-1898) ; the 2d Ohio Volunteer
                     Infantry Regiment; floods; elections and women voting; and medical home
                     remedies. An undated essay by Murdoch's husband describes pioneer life in
                     Ohio.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref173_9na" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000868037"
                           >Nadenbousch, John Quincy Adams papers, 1861-1871</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8b1e582e84adbb99a3ef49f3bf448cb8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Included in this collection are Civil War papers relating to Nadenbousch's
                     service as Provost-Marshall of Martinsburg, [West] Virginia and as a Captain in
                     the "Stonewall" Brigade. Although several items of family correspondence
                     appear, most letters concern military affairs.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref175_jl2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">New York, Miscellany papers, 1765-1924</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2992c500a6563ae9be448087ade5e732">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Miscellaneous items related to New York, largely correspondence. This folder is
                     located in Box 6 of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref177_cpn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">North Carolina, Miscellany papers, 1806-1878</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d0a834b0ea15b454f2b29d4bff91cfd1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>This collection contains miscellaneous items related to North Carolina. Largely
                     correspondence, included is a speech on women, written by North Carolina's
                     first governor, Richard Caswell. This folder is located in Box 6 of the Harry
                     L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref179_bis" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001021269"
                           >Norton, Mary papers, 1852-1895</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f1d5150b2022f065584905bf5446029f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Chiefly letters from Clara Barton, founder and president of the American Red
                     Cross, to Norton who was an intimate friend. Letters contain references to
                     mutual friends and family and document the administration and operation of the
                     Red Cross. Letters written during the Civil War include instructions for
                     sending relief supplies and detailed observations which illustrate Barton's
                     life in the trenches with the soldiers. Later letters concern Barton's travels,
                     speaking engagements, and charity work; her life in Dansville, N.Y., as she
                     contemplated the future of the Red Cross; and her work as the superintendent of
                     the Reformatory Prison for Women in Southfarmington, Mass. A letter from Barton
                     to her cousin Jerry details her breakdown in London, her views on the Stanley
                     and Livingston affair, and her activities in France during the Franco-Prussian
                     War. Other items include pamphlets on women's schools and charity organizations
                     and a letter to Norton from P.T. Barnum discussing Horace Greeley.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref181_i2n" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002269720"
                           >Otis, Harrison Gray papers, 1803</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6196b626e3c795f87365bdc4bacb993c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Letter is written to Otis from Alexander Hamilton, and discusses a civil suit
                     related to trade between a New Jersey company and Para, Brazil. Hamilton
                     mentions evidence from Portugal.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref183_qvj" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>P-R</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref184_jny" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001751784"
                           >Paca, William papers, 1782-1783</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e3824284801018bdd8c04391c38d7722">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection consists of four letters addressed to Paca. Most are requests from
                     various persons, e.g., a British prisoner asking for his freedom and permission
                     to settle in Annapolis with his family, a Maryland Representative writing on
                     behalf of a woman seeking restitution for personal losses to the British, and a
                     Baltimore man seeking an official pass to visit New York City on business.
                     Another letter inventories the losses in the 1783 fire at the Annapolis
                     armory.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref186_dsj" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001751785"
                           >Palliser, Hugh papers, 1770s[?]</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ae676f38e6e4a42e2e7b1454fc2eb55d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>A note on the cover of a missing letter. The note refers to the enclosed letter
                     on the 14th from Palliser, who has given intelligence information to the
                     British regarding a vessel that is to be purchased or detained for His
                     Majesty's use.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref188_3yr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002569225"
                           >Payne, John Howard papers, undated</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_178ef2c8d4296a8cf8ad8644028f2c7e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Facsimile of Payne's "Home, Sweet Home." Located in Box 7 of the Harry L. and
                     Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref190_r0e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Pennsylvania, Miscellany papers, 1796-1915</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a85ca45289a20b7ee501b9b7b81a7bac">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Miscellaneous correspondence written in Pennsylvania. Items are located in Box
                     7 of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref192_70l" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001767386"
                           >Perry, Oliver Hazard papers, 1808-1813</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3e79b84097611fe3bb0a8e93554fe8dc">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Three letters, two engravings of Perry, and an announcement of a public dinner
                     given by the citizens of Washington, D.C. in honor of Perry's victory on Lake
                     Erie in 1813. The letters, two of which are facsimiles, are written by Perry to
                     Robert Smith, Secretary of the Navy, and General William Henry Harrison, and
                     chiefly concern his military victory on Lake Erie, the delivery of prisoners
                     following that event, and a recommendation that a William Prant Smith be given
                     a midshipman's warrant.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref194_453" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001751791"
                           >Phillips, John papers, 1743-1798</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8035fd58a1742ed53be6e9236ab77df2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection consists of oversized parchment deeds and indentures pertaining to
                     land in what was called the "Northern Liberties" of Philadelphia in the 18th
                     century. Included is a map [ca. 1778?] of land owned by William Coates, a
                     Revolutionary officer and Justice of the Peace for the township of North
                     Liberties. Of particular interest is the plot of land on Coates Street
                     designated as the property of Benjamin Franklin. This is the plot mentioned in
                     Franklin's last will and testament as "my pasture-ground which I have in
                     Hickory Lane, with the buildings thereon..." The remainder of the collection
                     consists of land indentures made by several different parties.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref196_bei" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002586491"
                           >Pickens, Andrew papers, 1801-1827</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_89e0fa44d9f194a2b9a29b0248b9816a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Includes correspondence; a memorandum of agreement between Pickens and David
                     Files regarding a loan from Pickens to Files; financial papers relating to the
                     operation of Pickens' plantation in Alabama; a mortgage bond; and an
                     Agricultural Memorandum Book (1822-1826) which discusses the clearing of land
                     for planting cotton and corn, describes the seeds he used, and includes several
                     pages of accounts. Pickens also comments on his visits to Cahaba, Alabama, and
                     the flood which occurred while it was the state capitol.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref198_we0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000868115"
                           >Pickens, Francis Wilkinson papers, 1806-1868, undated</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7d1e229a36224fffb7bf89fe9a8b03bd">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Twenty-three items of correspondence in this collection mainly concern
                     political matters after 1832, when Pickens became openly active in the
                     nullification controversy. Several letters from 1833 deal with Colonel Pickens'
                     efforts to promote the state oath of allegiance and to raise and provision a
                     contingent of his Edgefield constituents. Of particular interest is a letter
                     detailing the types and amounts of military supplies available to various local
                     volunteer groups. The finest items in the collection are three lengthy letters
                     from James Hammond to Pickens in 1839-1840. Some correspondence is personal.
                     Also included are some legal documents and miscellany items. The collection is
                     housed in Box 7 of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref200_ict" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE003955129"
                           >Picture Collection, after 1860</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0a2e0728346ad6a95652fc5034a6f4d3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>The major portion of this collection of pictures consists of 53 cartes de
                     viste, dating from the 1860s. Most of them are pictures of Civil War generals.
                     Many of these cartes bear a U.S. postage stamp, indicating that they were
                     produced before or during the period Sept. 1, 1864-Aug. 1, 1866, when all such
                     photographs transported in the U. S. mail were subject to this form of
                     government tax in order to raise additional wartime revenue. Only five of them
                     have not been identified. Also included in this collection are 30 engravings,
                     most of them of prominent American statesmen. Included in the collection are
                     engravings of Kit Carson, Samuel P. Chase, Horatio Gates, and members of
                     Abraham Lincoln's cabinet. Two non-person pictures include an undated print of
                     the Charlotte Female Institute and an 1863 print of Camp Vermont, Virginia
                     during the Civil War. As of April 2008, these items are located on 6th
                     16:B.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref202_0px" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002458598"
                           >Pillow, Gideon Johnson papers, 1861</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7cd6961f3ca4cb0702278c5cd4f0ffd9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection contains largely routine items pertaining to Gen. Pillow. They
                     concern army supplies and skirmishes around, Charleston, Mo.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref204_wal" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Poetry, Miscellany papers, 1848-1865</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f5899affbe99f8fa474d96cddd617af3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Miscellaneous poems, most of the creators are unidentified. These items are
                     housed in Box 7 of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref206_8yk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000872365"
                           >Polk, James K. papers, 1840-1845</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b46571b5cbb931899ac32f64dd04725b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Includes a written statement from the Sherriff of Bradley County, Tennessee in
                     addition to two unrelated letters. These items are housed in Box 7 of the Harry
                     L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref208_42l" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001776958"
                           >G. P. Putnam's Sons records, 1886-1908</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f6c394ad2556013bc851e3cf1d08b3bf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Correspondence illustrating the publication and investment relationship of
                     Theodore Roosevelt with the G. P. Putnam’s Sons publishing house. Among the
                     items are four notes from Roosevelt to George Haven Putnam, discussing business
                     affairs and Roosevelt’s reasons for breaking off business with the company. Two
                     other notes discuss Roosevelt’s North Dakota cattle ranches. Other
                     correspondence comes from Douglas Robinson, a New York real estate man and
                     partner with Roosevelt in an investment venture with the Putnam firm. Robinson
                     questions the timing and amount of his returns.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref210_pgp" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE003953848"
                           >Revolutionary War autographs, 1776-1784</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_557864dfe0b0f068c7f71e83efaa266d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Individual autographs of Revoluntionary War soldiers. These items are located
                     in Box 7 of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref212_sai" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001826863"
                           >Roosevelt, Theodore papers, 1916, undated</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3886f62b785f55815231136ff1bd63e6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Includes a note written by Roosevelt to Judge M. W. Morrow and a thank-you note
                     to a Dr. Mullowney. These items are located in Box 7 of the Harry L. and Mary
                     K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref214_cbf" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>S</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref215_fma" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001826809"
                           >Saye, James Hodge papers, 1790-1896</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_cee0fd7af06764d03b1fbe0001580658">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Chiefly correspondence of the Saye family. Early letters trace James Saye's
                     progress through the Columbia Theological Seminary in Decatur, Ga. Other
                     correspondence details his pastorships in Henry County, Ga., in Unionville and
                     Fairforest, S.C., then in Chester County, S.C. Several letters are from fellow
                     ministers, and discuss Presbyterian Church matters and national politics. Later
                     correspondence is chiefly between the six Saye daughters and their mother,
                     Rebecca Saye (McJunkins), and concern domestic issues and Reconstruction in the
                     South. A letter by Rebecca details the genealogies of the Saye and McJunkins
                     families. One letter (1883) addressed to James Saye from a professor at
                     Davidson College recounts college affairs. Other documents include legal
                     papers, including one Freedmen's Bureau document of 1866 which indentures an
                     orphaned African-American boy to Rev. Saye for fourteen years.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref217_o90" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001826813"
                           >Schriver, Edmund papers, 1834-1853</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_784ffec486be26104ddaf625315a54dc">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Correspondence to Edmund Schriver from two West Point fellow graduates, Robert
                     Selden Garnett and William Wallace Smith Bliss. Topics deal in great detail
                     with army life in general, including politics, scandals, and events; the
                     Cherokee War; the war with Mexixo, including the battles of Palo Alto, Resaca
                     de la Palma, Monterey, and Buena Vista; Bliss' role as chief-of-staff to
                     General Zachary Taylor, and, later, as private secretary to President Taylor in
                     Washington; and the reaction to Taylor's election in 1848.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref219_8rm" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001826866"
                           >Scott, Winfield papers, 1822</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0c3d830007aa5413a7ab758eef79b5a6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>This collection contains 2 items: an 1822 letter from Scott to John Floyd in
                     Washington and Floyd's response to Scott. The letters discuss military
                     publications. These items are located in Box 8 of the Harry L. and Mary K.
                     Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref221_xz5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">South Carolina, Miscellany papers, 1787-1934</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0cb63ce01cf58362252bf71567d4b341">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>This collection includes miscellaneous items related to South Carolina.
                     Correspondence makes up the bulk of the collection and correspondents include
                     Strom Thurmond and Arthur P. Hayne. Also included are financial documents such
                     as receipts and printed material such as pamphlets for The Crosby Military
                     Institute in Feasterville, S.C. and reports regarding S.C. government. The
                     material is housed in Box 8 of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref223_6yx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000879187"
                           >Sherman, William T. papers, 1863-1869</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_89002c0d6eac0d9b68361f6f48903e6e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Included in this collection are correspondence and orders written by Sherman as
                     well as his address to the 1869 graduating class of the United States Military
                     Academy at West Point. These items are located in Box 8 of the Harry L. and
                     Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref225_tc3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001826832"
                           >Sims, Joseph Starke papers, 1819-1903 and undated</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3f210dc9f9bdfe897787c62359bf837d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Correspondence, financial records, legal documents, clippings, account books,
                     commissions, addresses and speeches, and a diploma. Correspondence concerns
                     chiefly cotton growing, trade and prices; slaves who worked in cotton fields;
                     financial matters; Washington, D.C. politics, with references to Henry Clay and
                     John Calhoun; state and national politics; descriptions of newly settled areas
                     of Mississippi and California; and a cholera outbreak in Charleston (1832).
                     Civil War letters detail problems at Fort Sumter (1861), and often refer to
                     economic difficulties and shortages in South Carolina. Other Civil War letters
                     are also written from Manassas, Alabama, and Mississippi. One letter from
                     Mississippi details the desperation of women left alone and unable to flee
                     before the advancing Union Army. Post-war letters reveal the problems of
                     Reconstruction in South Carolina. Many of the letters are to Sims' wife Jane
                     Emily Sims (Farnandis). Includes an autobiographical letter from J. K.
                     Paulding, author and statesman, and an essay by the same, entitled "The history
                     of Uncle Sam and his boys." Some of Sims' addresses and one of the legal
                     documents concern Nullification, which Sims' strongly supported. Other
                     documents include an obituary for Franklin H. Elmore, plantation and general
                     account books, and some material on Sims' student days at South Carolina
                     College (ca. 1817-1819), which includes a letter to his brother in 1819 "in
                     defence of General Jackson," and his "treatment of the Indians."</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref227_5e8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001826833"
                           >Sims, William papers, 1770-1860</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_afc5b0eb6e616806b7d1355e62e7f0f3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Correspondence, financial papers, and legal documents, concerning William Sims'
                     extensive plantation holdings in South Carolina. Includes two account books.
                     Correspondence is primarily related to business matters, including cotton trade
                     and prices; the price and availability of slaves; and the beginnings of a
                     textile industry on the plantation. Local and state politicians in South
                     Carolina are often mentioned, as is the general economic plight of the Southern
                     planter in the period (ca. 1819-1830), and currency problems in the state (ca.
                     1826-1830). One personal letter effusively describes newly settled land in
                     Mississippi and the quality of the cotton grown there. Detailed financial
                     papers form the bulk of the collection, and concern the cotton trade (including
                     weights, bale numbers, shipping, prices, and sales), and household and
                     plantation expenses. Legal papers are confined to deeds, documents of land
                     litigation, military commissions, and documents relating to slaves, such as
                     indentures and lists of slaves on the plantation. Also includes genealogical
                     information on the Sims family.Cotton grower in Union County, South
                     Carolina.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref229_pde" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002254456"
                           >Samuel Slater &amp; Sons records, 1839</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_13c5d1f2c83058082cec8e2b272d17bf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Letters and financial papers from shops and individuals who bought cloth from
                     and sold cloth to Samuel Slater and Sons. Many of the merchants discussed
                     problems in cash availability, as the letters were written during one of the
                     peaks of the 1839 banking crisis.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref231_g08" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001534679"
                           >Sloan, Edwin R. papers, 1861-1863</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_aa41a329682567543167dc93afffe18e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Civil War letters from Edwin R. Sloan, a private in Company F, 1st Regiment,
                     N.C. Cavalry, chiefly to his wife Sarah in N.C. Letters span Sloan's military
                     career from 1861 to ten days before his death in September, 1863. Some of
                     Sloan's letters are written from Camp Marsh; Camp W. S. Ash; Washington Co.,
                     Md.; Culpepper, Va.; Hanover Junction, Va.; Upperville, Va.; and Raccoon Ford,
                     Va. Letters contain accounts of camp life, deprivations, and rumors and
                     predictions about the war. The author expressed strong Southern sentiments. One
                     letter written in 1861 provides an account of Confederate soldiers fraternizing
                     with the United States soldiers under a flag of truce and being entertained and
                     fed by them. Sloan also described scouting expeditions along the Potomac; Union
                     soldiers burying Confederate dead at Upperville; his sorrow on the death of
                     General Jackson; and his attempt to buy a furlough to come home. In August and
                     September of 1863, Sloan reported of rumors that North Carolina would return to
                     the Union. He expressed his desire for peace, but not at the expense of
                     returning to the Union.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref233_8tc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001826842"
                           >Smith, Samuel Francis papers, 1831-1936</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1a4b7c17a74f4242bb6c3b66b6fb7390">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Signed holograph copy of four verses of "America," written by Samuel Francis
                     Smith, and a pamphlet published by American Autograph Shop, containing a
                     facsimile of the first and last verses of "America"; a copy of the entire hymn
                     as printed for the celebration by the Boston Sabbath School Union of
                     Independence Day in 1931; printed copies of two other hymns; a copy of an
                     address to the children by the Rev. Wisner; and a facsimile of notes made by a
                     Dr. Jenks during the celebration.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref235_13o" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001845550"
                           >Stephens, William papers, 1780-1811</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2142b8f61799e86b133f331265852c68">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Letters pertaining to Stephens' business and legal affairs, as well as a letter
                     in which he complains to Governor Richard Howley about the lack of a jail in
                     Augusta and the consequent lawlessness in the county. One letter to Abraham
                     Mims in Newport, R.I., was written from the Stephens family vacation home in
                     Providence.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref237_7ug" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002044924"
                           >Sternes, A. L. papers, 1861-1862</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_847ea863cbe5d8accd757c23e742c42e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Two letters from Sternes to his wife, expressing affection and concern, and a
                     third letter from Lieutenant L. A. Potts informing Mrs. Sterned of her
                     husband's death on August 2, 1862.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref239_ipm" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002372622"
                           >Stuart, J.E.B. papers, 1861-1863</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_aa5dab97f9a37c407b34706bf492c618">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>This addition to the Jeb Stuart Papers includes the following: General Order
                     no. 14 issued under Stuart's order and signed by Heros von Bourke; an
                     announcement of the death of Captain Redmond Burke at Shepherdstown, Va.;
                     letters to Major Martin concerning cavalry operations in Va.; and a number of
                     letters to Stuart's wife, Flora, in Wytheville(?), Va. One group of letters to
                     her is from Harper's Ferry and concerns men and arms for an upcoming battle.
                     Others discuss the Union troops' advance, Stuart's advancement in the C.S.A.,
                     his concern for his wife's well-being, and efforts to arrange for her a visit
                     to his camp. One holograph message from Stuart states that General Jackson
                     wishes to see Rufus Barringer.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref241_155" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000875791"
                           >Sumner, Charles papers, 1862-1868</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9f2a8717b9ab557e7c741a2495de33ab">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>This collection includes four letters to Sumner, including one from W. H.
                     Seward and one from Edwin Stanton. These items are housed in Box 8 of the Harry
                     L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref243_e19" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>T-Z</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref244_mno" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002044936"
                           >Tappan, Mason Weare papers, 1857-1865</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bd517050c8e0fbae10d98a063cacf29a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Letters to Mason W. Tappan primarily concerning Republican politics.
                     Correspondents include Schuyler Colfax, N.H. senator John Parker Hale, and Amos
                     Tuck. Also includes letters on legal matters from U.S. Attorney General Caleb
                     Cushing.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref246_wug" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001996468"
                           >Tucker-Coalter Family papers, 1794-1821</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_51087fac9ec2ce62a48e10a8602ffb4d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection of letters chiefly written by John Randolph, known as "Randolph of
                     Roanoke," to various family members, including his half-sister Frances Bland
                     Tucker Coalter, John Coalter, and Henry St. George Tucker. Other correspondents
                     include St. George Tucker, Edmund Randolph, and William Wirt, Attorney General
                     of the U.S. Topics cover family matters, Washington and Virginia politics,
                     legal matters, illnesses, and child-rearing. Another letter mentions
                     "automata," mechanical men Randolph observed while a law student in
                     Philadelphia.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref248_prm" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001112507"
                           >Tyler, Erastus Barnard, 1856-1863</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_cafb43c350d5c867408aedb7aece60c2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Primarily letters written during the Civil War by Tyler to his parents from
                     camps in the Kanawha Valley of Virginia as well as posts near Washington, Va.,
                     and Culpepper, Va; and the field at the Battle of Gettysburg. These letters
                     reflect Tylers's service under General Rosecrans as well as the movements and
                     engagements of his forces. One letter was written from Fort Randall, Nebraska
                     Territory in 1858.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref250_2fp" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002067265"
                           >Tyler Family papers, 1834-1881</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ba97b034a48550bee11d9f75763a7640">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Papers pertaining to President John Tyler and his family. Petition, 1834, from
                     prominent residents of King and Queen County, Va., asking Tyler to endorse
                     their candidate for the U.S. Senate; letter of recommendation (1841) from Burke
                     Washington concerning a naval candidate, Alexander Jones; letter from John
                     Tyler, Jr. (?) in reply to H. C. Corbin; letter written by Julia (Gardiner)
                     Tyler (1881) in reply to an autograph collector.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref252_9c3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE003877925"
                           >U. S. Dept. of the Navy records, 1802-1877</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8d02c999b92097c4120bdf9fc7820fd5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>This collection of correspondence, directed to the Secretaries of the U. S.
                     Navy, consists largely of recommendations for young men desiring appointments
                     to the Naval Academy and other Naval positions. Other contents include
                     incidental messages on Navy finance, notes and letters on legislation affecting
                     the Navy, reports on Naval operations in Gibraltar and elsewhere, on sailors'
                     conduct and on provisioning.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref254_tgw" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002257991"
                           >U. S. War Department records, 1814-1865</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_770c786d7996407c042a2cc4c1d94cee">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>A detailed list of a cavalry troop; a letter from Tenn. governor Willie Blount
                     to Capt. James Cowan of the U.S. Rangers, concerning the Creek Wars in Tenn.; a
                     letter from Mass. governor Caleb Strong to Adj. Gen. John Brooks referring to
                     appointments to the War Dept.; four letters of recommendation, two of these
                     directed to Joel R. Poinsett, then Secretary of War; a property document (1865)
                     from the Freedmen's Bureau; and a grant of military bounty lands to a Mrs.
                     Sarah Woolley.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref256_dsg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002582823"
                           >Van Buren, Martin papers, 1837-1840</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b57d118679b517e09ac1be9a8d0c47d5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>This collection includes a letter (1840) to Van Buren from his daughter-in-law,
                     Angelica as well as a land grant from 1837 to Benjamin Crumpacker of La Porte
                     County, Indiana.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref258_ci4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002205148"
                           >Van Ness, William Peter papers, 1805</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f611751cfbc1f1f8b07873d6b976da16">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Van Ness was the second in Aaron Burr's duel with Alexander Hamilton and was
                     indicted as an accessory to Hamilton's murder. He fled to New York and later
                     became judge of the U.S. Circuit Court for a New York district. The letter is
                     from Burr from Chilicothe. Here, Burr asks Van Ness to meet him in Berkeley
                     Springs and instructs him to contact certain people in New York and
                     Philadelphia.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref260_o3q" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002205153"
                           >Vinson, Fred M. papers, 1944-1946</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_accbff155042c12f2ce6b69b4dca3053">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Included are four short pieces of correspondence addressed to Harry L. Dalton
                     from 1844-1946. A large folder of clippings and miscellany includes articles on
                     Vinson and the Treasury, a long statement delivered to the House Ways and Means
                     Committee (Oct 1, 1945), as well as clippings and the Life magazine cover story
                     on Vinson's swearing in as Chief Justice (1946).</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref262_hmk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Virginia, Miscellany papers, 1761-1864</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c547b83121be6f9b89c5b9dceeda8f7d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Miscellaneous items related to the Commonwealth of Virginia. Collection
                     includes mainly land grants and correspondence. This material is located in Box
                     9 of the Harry L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref264_0j3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001530414"
                           >Voigt, Edward papers, 1839-1874(bulk 1839-1845)</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_67f8232f4316331efe9969f594239392">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Predominantly correspondence between Edward Voight and Caroline Voigt of Warren
                     Farm, Chester County, Pa., during their courtship and early years of marriage.
                     A majority of the letters are from Edward's hand. The correspondence between
                     the couple concerns Edward's work as a bookkeeper, and later his mercantile
                     business in Philadelphia; religious devotion and piety; social engagements; the
                     couple's courtship and wedding plans; and travel, particularly by rail between
                     Chester County and Philadelphia. These letters provide a perspective on gender
                     roles and relations during the mid-nineteenth century insofar as they reflect
                     the propriety and etiquette expected of the young couple, as well as Edward's
                     expectations concerning Caroline's religious devotion and her independence on
                     this matter.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref266_6qt" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000884148"
                           >Washington, George papers, 1775-1939</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a7ee0113956c63ef31b7d999d47ad306">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Facsimilies of Washington correspondence and several engravings of both
                     Washington and his wife Martha. These items are located in Box 9 of the Harry
                     L. and Mary K. Dalton Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref268_nh7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002199783"
                           >White, R. L. C. papers, 1852-1861</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_78f2f134df199d5af8ebac89f4226423">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection is composed of autographs solicited and collected by R.L.C. White of
                     Lebanon, Tennessee. Most of the signatures are from government figures in
                     Washington. A note is also included, dated March 10, 1860, written from
                     Washington, DC by Charles Francis Adams in response to a request for an
                     autograph.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref270_pbl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002199785"
                           >Whiteside, Thomas papers, 1821-1864</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_783eb7bde7bd3bfe4871629bd4feabf0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Gentleman's pocket book, bound in suede with flap. Scanty accounts fill only a
                     small portion of the book. "Thos. Whiteside--His book" is written on the front,
                     and the name is mentioned several times inside. Book appears to have originally
                     been owned by Jesse Broomfield whose initials appear above Whiteside's on the
                     cover and the earliest entries bear his name. Broomfield was one of the
                     original sponsors of the Ebenezer Academy (1834) near Rock Hill, SC.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref272_gwv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000877883"
                           >Wilkes Family papers, 1816-1877</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_04ba80e327545f11f3243b415f6b4548">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Correspondence of members of the Wilkes family, consisting primarily of letters
                     to Charles Wilkes (1798-1877), naval admiral, and of many letters that he
                     wrote. Letters from prominent scientists such as James Renwick, Asa Gray, James
                     D. Dana, and Jean L. R. Agassiz also appear in the papers, as does
                     correspondence of naval officers, Congressmen, diplomats, and cabinet
                     secretaries, especially Secretaries of the Navy. Included among the numerous
                     subjects mentioned in the papers is the exploring expedition that Wilkes
                     commanded to the Antarctic continent, islands of the Pacific Ocean, and the
                     American Northwest coast from 1838-1842. There is a lot of family
                     correspondence from various members of the Wilkes family which include two
                     wives of Charles Wilkes. Other types of material in the collection are legal
                     papers, financial records, printed material, writings, account books, a science
                     notebook written by Wilkes' son Edmund in 1847, and a volume entitled, "Notes
                     Relative to the Fijii [sic] Islands," written by Charles Wilkes. These items
                     make up part of the Charles Wilkes Papers.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref274_0sl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002199792"
                           >Willard, Henry A. papers, 1834-1890</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5a9e128ce222fd53c0362de140fe4714">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Most of the collection deals with Willard's ownership of the famous Willard
                     Hotel. Extensive correspondence documents the comings and goings of clients at
                     the hotel, as well as repair and financial matters there. Legal and financial
                     papers are concerned with the hotel, as well as with Willard's other interests
                     as founder of the National Safe Deposit, Savings and Trust, Co., as a member of
                     the D.C. Board of Public Works, and as chairman of the Board of Trustees for
                     the District of Columbia Reform School in the 1870s and 1880s. Willard received
                     appointments signed by the President every three years. Thus, the signatures of
                     Grant, Hayes and Cleveland appear here. A few personal items are included, such
                     as an icy exchange between Henry and his brother Joseph C. Willard. Of interest
                     is a long document to the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia which
                     details the feud between the two brothers.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref276_kvo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001530449"
                           >Williams, William Augustus papers, 1825-1867 and undated</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ed01777d55f0381b48fa1fe3061ea9bd">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Collection consists of correspondence, notebooks, and miscellaneous papers of
                     Colonel William Augustus Williams of Wilmington and Charlotte, N.C.
                     Correspondence includes letters from Henderson C. Lucas, Williams's nephew, who
                     was wounded at Gettysburg while serving in the 11th Regiment of the N.C.
                     Infantry; and letters related to Williams's efforts to bring the wounded Lucas
                     to Charlotte. Other correspondence is primarily of a financial nature. A letter
                     from William Henry Heyward describes the effects of reconstruction on South
                     Carolina Coastal planters. A letter from Rev. Aldert Smedes mentions the
                     financial hardships suffered by St. Mary's School in Raleigh, N.C. and is
                     written on stationery describing the school's tuition and curriculum. Notebook
                     dated 1827 contains exercises in penmanship and renderings of famous poems,
                     while one dated 1825 is an arithmetic practice book. Also included are papers
                     related to the Raleigh City Guards.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref278_6rq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000885573"
                           >Wirt, William papers, 1810-1854</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_066c9466d2deafe0befaf6a3bb778ca3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Papers of William Wirt and of Elizabeth Washington (Gamble) Wirt, including
                     letters concerning William's law practice; a letter relating an anecdote
                     concerning William Wirt, Henry Clay, and a General Parker; fragmentary letter,
                     1833, from Wirt to a law student at the University of North Carolina, Chapel
                     Hill, discussing education; and a fragment of Wirt's draft of his biography of
                     Patrick Henry. Correspondence of Elizabeth Washington (Gamble) Wirt, wife of
                     William, and two sons, Dabney Carr and William C., concerns the purchase and
                     sale of land, a debt incurred by Wirt for land he planned to develop in
                     Florida, the widow's financial affairs, the erection of a monument to her
                     husband, and other family matters.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref280_xkg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">
                        <extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE000885579"
                           >Woodruff, Isabella papers, 1768-1865</extref>
                     </emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fb98e9e358ab7c11f941d3b114cdf495">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>This collection contains correspondence, primarily containing observations of a
                     social and political nature regarding the period in South Carolina before,
                     during and immediately following the Civil War. Much of the subject matter
                     deals with viewpoints of the women. Correspondants include: her mother, Mrs.
                     Louisa Roberts; her brother, Samuel C. Roberts; and her best friend, Countess
                     Aniela N. Pinkind, as well as Charles F. A. Holst, her future husband.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
