<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/deonchevalier/">deonchevalier</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Chevalier d'Eon papers, 1778-1779
          <num>RL.11592</num></titleproper>
        <author>Alice L. Poffinberger</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>January 2018</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">008176322</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-07-25 16:42:50
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>July 2018</date>
        <item>revised biohist based on new information</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="fre">French</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Chevalier d'Eon papers</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname role="com" source="lcnaf">Eon de Beaumont, Charles Geneviève Louis Auguste André
          Timothée d' , 1728-1810</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.11592</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.0 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">8 items</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1778/1779" type="inclusive">1778-1779</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_d1edb7b047f5767b86fd5b4d698bea7b">Charles Geneviève Louis Auguste André
        Timothée d'Eon de Beaumont, known as Chevalier d'Eon, was a French diplomat, spy, freemason
        and soldier who fought in the Seven Years' War. Collection comprises a dossier of seven
        items (approximately 75 pages) compiled by Chevalier d'Eon articulating his wish to forsake
        his female persona in order to fight in the American Revolutionary War.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_e724c5dca74670c79cb8404a353ea746">Materials in French</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="aspace_a9c3bceb3b6ee7b779fa023d02d4fe83">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Charles Geneviève Louis Auguste André Timothée d'Eon de Beaumont, known as Chevalier
        d'Eon, was a French diplomat, spy, freemason and soldier who fought in the Seven Years' War.
        In 1756, he joined the secret network of spies called the Secret du Roi employed by King
        Louis XV. D'Éon appeared publicly as a man and pursued masculine occupations for 49 years.
        Then, according to an agreement concluded in 1776 with Louis XV, the Chevalier was required
        to live as a woman in exchange for a life annuity. D'Eon explained that he had been born
        female but raised as a male by a father desperate for a son. In August 1777 d'Eon returned
        to France. Upon presenting himself at Versailles in military uniform, he was promptly
        ordered to resume female dress. The chevalier's requests to be allowed to don his uniform
        and to serve in the American Revolutionary War were turned down, and he was refused
        permission to return to London in 1778 to look after his financial interests after the death
        of Lord Ferrers. D'Éon settled on his family estates at Tonnerre. After a few months
        imprisonment at Dijon in 1779 for wearing his uniform in public, he again took up residence
        at Versailles before being finally allowed to return to England in November 1785. His unpaid
        landlord in Brewer Street was threatening to sell his library and collections. The Chevalier
        d'Eon died in England in 1810; and it was discovered that he was really a man.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_a92984f973b982bae877b8d4cff4751d">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_8256c225222bb4b3995bd375c23ea2b8">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_2c6010238aa7038f2e3f0a1ed728c1c1">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Chevalier d'Eon papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2017.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_fe8b3c0996043b8e24c847654c95d0f8">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Chevalier d'Eon papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_98f8b02f3d2a2ee1f209e44160ae243e">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Alice Poffinberger, January, 2018</p>
      <p>Accessions described in this collection guide: 2017-0209</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_950367b2104ed629ad7b6d0718588afe">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>Collection comprises a dossier of seven items (approximately 75 pages) compiled by
        Chevalier d'Eon articulating his wish to forsake his female persona in order to fight in the
        American Revolutionary War. The seven items are wrapped in a blue paste-paper wrapper. The
        first item is a collection of 35 commissions and supporting documents from diplomats,
        military officers and French, Russian or English ministers, testifying to Eon's qualities
        and his activity in the secret services for 20 years, including the peace mission to the
        court of Russia (1755-1756); a mission to Vienna carrying the campaign plan of the Russian
        army and revelation of a secret Russian-Prussian correspondence, along with another mission
        to Russia (1757); commission as secretary of the French embassy at the court of Russia,
        after having contributed to the success of four treaties (1757-1759); commission as
        aide-de-camp of maréchal de Broglie in Germany (1760-1762); secretary of the French Embassy
        in Great Britain, for the conclusion of peace (1762); resident, then Minister
        Plenipotentiary in London (1763); refusal of proposals to communicate particulars and papers
        relative to the peace to the opponents of the court of St. James (1764-1765); followed by a
        Franco-British plan for the Mexican and Peruvian uprisings against Spain (1766-1768) for the
        Spanish ambassador in London; against the accusations of venality and corruption by the
        Court of France by the Princess of Wales and the English ministers (1769-1770); secret
        correspondence with Louis XV, the Prince de Conti, the Comte de Broglie, all ending in a
        promise of a life annuity from Louis XV.</p>
      <p>The second item is a brief Memoire by d'Eon, dated 20 May 1778, for the Count of Vergennes,
        Minister for Foreign Affairs, in order to obtain payment of his pension, with a copy of 5
        supporting documents. The third item is a memorandum describing the Chevalier's affairs in
        England, as of August 1778, including rents due on a house in Brewer Street/Golden Square,
        which is scheduled to be demolished. There are further details of d'Eon's state of affairs
        in France, where the Chevalier blames his feminine state and sedentariness as cause of a
        very painful rheumatism. D'Eon accordingly begs the King and his ministers to allow him to
        don men's clothes and fight.</p>
      <p>Items four through seven are signed letters. One to M. de Miromesnil, Garde des Sceaux,
        Versailles 12 February 1779, with a copy of his petition to the King's special adviser, the
        Comte de Maurepas, of the 8th of February, asking support for the Chevalier's request to
        serve as a volunteer in the Comte d'Orvilliers' fleet. The other two letters are written to
        the Comtesse de Maurepas, Versailles 12 February 1779, with a copy of the Chevalier's
        petition to the comte, 8 February, requesting the comte's protection.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Diplomats -- France</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Transgender people -- France -- 18th Century -- Early works to
        1800</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Gender nonconformity -- History -- 18th Century -- Early works to
        1800</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Female impersonators -- France -- Early works to 1800</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Gender identity -- France -- History -- 18th Century</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">France -- Politics and government -- 1774-1793</geogname>
      <persname source="lcnaf">Eon de Beaumont, Charles Geneviève Louis Auguste André Timothée d'
        , 1728-1810</persname>
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Lisa Unger Baskin Collection (David M. Rubenstein Rare
        Book &amp; Manuscript Library)</corpname>
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and
        Culture</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_4a04c10583009a123983b20d8b17737c" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Chevalier d'Eon papers</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_2573b5a7a92e194b335acaa5cbd8a202" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
