<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/dimitry/">dimitry</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the John Bull Smith Dimitry Papers, 1848-1922, 1943 bulk
               1857-1922) <num>RL.00311</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Library staff; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Michael Fitzgerald</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000853469</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-28 15:21:56
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>John Bull Smith Dimitry papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Dimitry, John Bull Smith, 1835-1901</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00311</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1848/1922" type="inclusive">1848-1922, 1943 (bulk 1857-1922)</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_84d880a22da4ab426091b5570da8d521">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_4a0a955ed2126cf918c549486facaa5c">The Dimitry, Hardeman, Stuart, and
            Mayes families were white Southerners involved in education, government, business, and
            the military during the time just before and after the Civil War. The collection
            includes correspondence that documents the lives of family members in the South from the
            1850s to the 1890s. In addition to local family matters, there are accounts of
            Confederate army service and views on politics and government. Extensive writings on
            religious and mathematical topics as well as poetry are also to be found. Family members
            who are featured in the collection include Colonel Oscar J. E. Stuart, Sarah Hardeman
            Stuart, Oscar, James, and Edward Stuart, Ann Lewis Hardeman, William and Mary Hardeman,
            John Bull Smith Dimitry, Adelaide Stuart Dimitry, Bettie Stuart Mayes, Fanny Harris
            Mayes, Robert Burns Mayes, Robert Burns Mayes, Jr., and Robert Burns Mayes
            III.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_ca7c3d12dc66fc90eb675503b25a56e3">
            <extent>580 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_26bde2aa90272c30222ae9b159047b22">Material in English , French
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_ad50bbd5be3c7f8cce592f086adadf13">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_e23e018c50fd36bcd64a4420d59476b2">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_137eae16ae40c07b996b71817996fbf4">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], John Bull Smith Dimitry Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_c4fa0caa9d2a8e510de4c7a97774f8c5">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The John Bull Smith Dimitry Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library as a gift in .</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_29abf7fc7371982caeea9f722efa048b">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library staff, Michael Fitzgerald</p>
         <p>Encoded by Michael Fitzgerald</p>
         <p>Completed March 2007</p>
         <p>Accessions were merged into one collection, described in this finding aid.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_95c50381ed2ee3431da1562c4c31fb36">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>John Bull Smith Dimitry (1835-1901) was the son of Alexander and Mary P. (Mills) Dimitry
            of New Orleans and was born in Washington, D.C. He was educated at Georgetown College,
            and (1859-1861) served as secretary to his father who was then U.S. Minister to Costa
            Rica and Nicaragua. He served in a New Orleans regiment during the Civil War and was
            later wounded at Shiloh. Thereafter he served as chief clerk in the Confederate Post
            Office Department, where his association with John Henninger Reagan began. Dimitry
            stayed with the retreating Confederate government as far as Washington, Georgia, in
            1865, and then returned to Louisiana. Dimitry had some contact with the family of
            Colonel Oscar J. E. Stuart and in 1871 married Stuart's daughter Adelaide. </p>
         <p>Colonel Stuart (born 1810) and Sarah Hardeman (born 1816) were married in 1837 and moved
            to central Mississippi. Their first son, James Hardeman Stuart, was born in 1838 and a
            second, Oscar Ewing Stuart, was born in 1841. Adelaide Lewis Stuart was born in 1843 and
            Annie Elizabeth Stuart (usually called <emph render="doublequote">Bettie</emph> or <emph
               render="doublequote">Patti</emph>) was born in 1845. The third son, Edward, was born
            in 1847 and a daughter, Sarah Jane was born in 1849. Sarah Hardeman Stuart died shortly
            thereafter, leaving the six children to be brought up largely by their aunt, Ann Lewis
            Hardeman, with the assistance of other family members, particularly her brother William
            Hardeman and his wife Mary. Colonel Stuart took little part in the raising of his
            children. May of 1853 saw the death of the youngest child, Sarah Jane.</p>
         <p>James H. Stuart attended the University of Mississippi and was graduated in 1858 with
            the highest honors in his class. Oscar also began his studies at the University, but ill
            health necessitated his leaving in early 1861. He planned to study medicine but this was
            interrupted by the outbreak of the Civil War. From 1859 to 1861 the two daughters
            attended Saint Mary's Hall at Burlington, New Jersey.</p>
         <p>At the beginning of the Civil War both James and Oscar enlisted in the 18th Regiment
            Mississippi Volunteers, known as the <emph render="doublequote">Burt Rifles.</emph> In
            the summer of 1861, Oscar was made a sergeant-major of the Burt Rifles and James was
            detached from this regiment and made a member of the Signal Corps stationed in
            Centreville, Virginia. James's term of enlistment was to have expired early in 1862 and
            he tried to raise a company so that he could get a commission. This effort failed, but
            in June of that year he was commissioned a captain in the signal corps and was attached
            to the staff of his distant cousin, General J. E. B. Stuart. In the meantime, Colonel
            Oscar J. E. Stuart had tried to organize a company of older men to be known as the <emph
               render="doublequote">Silver Greys,</emph> but, failing this, had enlisted. Oscar
            re-enlisted and in the winter of 1862 was promoted to the rank of first lieutenant. He
            also served as adjutant.</p>
         <p>James was killed August 30, 1862, at the battle of Manassas Junction and Oscar in May
            1863 in the surrender of Marye's Heights. This left only Edward Stuart, the youngest of
            the brothers, who had enlisted in the summer of 1862, in the Confederate Army. He was
            incapacitated by a severe case of scurvy from about the time of Oscar's death until
            1864, and was cared for, as was Oscar at an earlier period, in the household of Dr. W.
            A. Horsley, a distant relative of the Stuarts. He was also in Pratt Hospital near
            Lynchburg, Virginia, and was captured and imprisoned at Point Lookout in Maryland,
            toward the end of the war. </p>
         <p>After the death of William Hardeman in 1863, the Hardeman and Stuart families moved to
            Haynesville, Alabama and in 1864, Adelaide Stuart worked in a branch of the Ladies
            Treasury Department in Columbia, South Carolina. During this time, Colonel Oscar J. E.
            Stuart attempted to obtain a patent for his new and improved plowshare from the
            Confederate States Patent Office. </p>
         <p>After the Civil War, the family dispersed in efforts to exist under the economic and
            political hardships of the Reconstruction period. Colonel Oscar J. E. Stuart moved from
            Summit, Mississippi and spent much of 1870-1871 in Burksville, Kentucky, with his niece,
            Mrs. Mary Cheek, whose husband had died in 1868. Before her marriage, Adelaide Stuart
            worked as a schoolteacher and for a time Ann Hardeman and Bettie Stuart lived together
            in Franklin City, Mississippi. Mary Hardeman restored La Vega, her Mississippi
            plantation, and Ann Hardeman lived there until her death in 1868. Edward followed the
            carpentry trade in Louisiana and, in later years, Texas. In 1867 Bettie married Judge
            Robert Burns Mayes (born 1820), whose first wife had died, leaving several children.
            Their first child, Robert Burns Mayes, Jr. was born in 1868 and their second, Adelaide
            Eleanor Mayes, was born in 1870. Stuart Hardeman Bowman Mayes was born in 1873. Their
            fourth and fifth children were daughters: Fanny Harris Mayes (1877-1896) and Annie
            Elizabeth Mayes (1879-1975). </p>
         <p>In the years following the Civil War, John Dimitry and his wife Adelaide traveled to
            South America where he taught languages in a university - Colegio Caldas, Colombia -
            from 1874-1876. He later also taught at Montgomery College, Virginia (1895). He engaged
            extensively in journalism and contributed to various papers. His <title type="simple"
               render="italic">Lessons in the History of Louisiana, from its Earliest Settlement to
               the Close of the Civil War, to Which are Appended Lessons in its Geography and
               Products</title> was published in 1877. Dimitry was also widely known for his
            epitaphs on Confederate heroes. He planned to write a series of biographies of
            outstanding Confederates but it would seem that he never progressed further in this work
            than the writing of epitaphs. Dimitry died on September 7, 1901. In 1911, Adelaide
            Stuart Dimitry, who was historian of the Stonewall Jackson Chapter of New Orleans,
            published <title type="simple" render="italic">War-Time Sketches: Historical and
               Otherwise</title>. </p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_0ba96faf0e6fce8feaa9bae41b76400a">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The John Bull Smith Dimitry Papers, 1848-1922, 1943 (bulk 1857-1922), consists of
            writings by various members of the Dimitry, Hardeman, Stuart, and Mayes families, who
            were related by marriage. Correspondence includes detailed discussions related to the
            Confederacy, Civil War, and Reconstruction from the point of view of white Southerners
            living in the Mississippi, Virginia, and Kentucky areas. This correspondence provides
            considerable information on family affairs, including business and legal matters and the
            role of women. There are also letters describing life in South America in the 1870s.
            Poetry, religious, and mathematical writings relate primarily to the Mayes family.</p>
         <p>This collection appears to have incorporated an earlier Mayes-Hardeman-Stuart Collection
            and there are many mimeographed copies of originals held by the Mississippi Deparment of
            Archives and History. These seem related to <title type="simple" render="italic">Aunt
               Ann's Boys</title>, an unfinished project by Robert Burns Mayes, Jr. which compiled
            correspondence between James, Oscar, and Edward Stuart and their aunt, Ann Lewis
            Hardeman.</p>
         <p>Details of these families are found in O'Brien, Michael (ed.). <title type="simple"
               render="italic">An Evening When Alone: Four Journals of Single Women in the South,
               1827-67</title>, Southern Texts Society/University Press of Virginia, 1993, which
            publishes the 1850-1867 journals of Ann Lewis Hardeman.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_90b3be2a6704b4a50440a335d2ad92e7">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>
            <archref>
               <unittitle label="Collection">Documenting the American South. </unittitle>
               <repository label="Repository">University Library, The University of North Carolina
                  at Chapel Hill.</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle label="Collection">Adrien Emmanuel Rouquette Papers</unittitle>
               <repository label="Repository">Tulane Manuscripts Department, Tulane
                  University.</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle label="Collection">Dimitry Collection</unittitle>
               <repository label="Repository">B. S. Ricks Memorial Library.</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle label="Collection">William Henry McRaven Papers</unittitle>
               <repository label="Repository">Tennessee State Library and Archives.</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle label="Collection">Archives</unittitle>
               <repository label="Repository">Mississippi Historical Society.</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle label="Collection">Mayes-Dimitry-Stuart Family Papers</unittitle>
               <repository label="Repository">Mississippi Department of Archives and
                  History</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle label="Collection">Oscar J. E. Stuart Papers</unittitle>
               <repository label="Repository">Mississippi Department of Archives and
                  History</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle label="Collection">University Archives</unittitle>
               <repository label="Repository">University of Notre Dame</repository>
            </archref>
         </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Confederate States of America -- Social conditions</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Confederate States of America. Army -- Military life</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Virginia -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Confederate States of America. Army. Mississippi Infantry Regiment,
            18th</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Soldiers -- Confederate States of America --
            Correspondence</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877) -- Mississippi</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">University of Mississippi -- Students</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Confederate States of America. Army -- Supplies and stores</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 --
            Campaigns</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 --
            Hospitals</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">South America -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <persname source="ingest">Mayes, R. B., Jr., b. 1868</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Mayes, R. B. III, d. 1922</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Mayes, Fanny Harris, 1877-1896</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Mayes, Elizabeth Stuart, b. 1845</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Hardeman, Ann Lewis, 1803-1868</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Dimitry, John Bull Smith, 1835-1901</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Dimitry, John Bull Smith, 1835-1901</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Dimitry, Adelaide Stuart, b. 1843</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Stuart, James, 1838-1862</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Stuart, Oscar Ewing, 1841-1863</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Stuart, Oscar J. E., 1810-1885</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Mayes, Robert Burns, 1820-1884</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Reagan, John H. (John Henninger), 1818-1905</persname>
         <famname source="ingest">Stuart family</famname>
         <persname source="ingest">Stuart, Edward, 1847-1881</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref13_qzr" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence/Papers, 1848-1897</unittitle>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_6f5640ddc815fed7944d9abb96bbd2d4">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Includes material from several disparate sources placed in chronological sequence.
                  There are many mimeographed copies of originals held by Mississippi Department of
                  Archives and History as well as some mimeographed copies complete with originals.
                  Participants include members of the Stuart and Hardeman families. Topics include
                  family life; James H. Stuart's time as a student at the University of Mississippi;
                  and James, Oscar, and Edward Stuart's participation in Civil War battles in
                  Virginia and Mississippi. In June of 1861 James and Oscar wrote of the lukewarm
                  sentiments of many Virginians around Lynchburg. There are also allusions in these
                  letters to the cost of uniforms and equipment, the scarcity of ammunition and
                  other supplies, anticipated military action at Manassas, and the beauty of the
                  Virginia countryside. There may be found also in the letters of the war period
                  information on military action at Manassas, Bethel Church, Drainsville, Leesburg,
                  Fredericksburg, and Marye's Heights; and references to desertions, morale,
                  censorship, theatrical productions given by the troops, and camp life in general.
                  The deaths of James, and then Oscar Stuart receive prominent attention.</p>
               <p> Correspondence regarding business and personal interests of Colonel Oscar J. E.
                  Stuart and materials related to Robert Burns Mayes and his legal and insurance
                  careers are present. In addition to letters to Colonel Stuart from his three
                  children and his niece, Mary S. Cheek, there are a number of letters from more
                  distant members of the Stuart family. Letters to Adelaide Stuart Dimitry from her
                  siblings are also included.</p>
               <p>Several long letters document the time spent in South America by John and Adelaide
                  Dimitry. These letters, written to the family in Mississippi, trace with great
                  detail the Dimitrys' life in Colombia. There are descriptions of the ocean voyage,
                  Jamaica, Barranquilla and Bogota (the two towns in which they lived), the
                  landscape of Colombia in general, a trip through the Andes, the climate, the
                  political and economic state of the country, educational facilities, and the
                  social life, customs, and temperament of the natives.</p>
               <p>Correspondents from outside of the family include John Henninger Reagan, among
                  others. Documents include the 1865 certificate of release of prisoner of war for
                  Edward Stuart, a short diary by James H. Stuart documenting his time in the Signal
                  Corps, a portion of the 1855 book <title type="simple" render="italic">The
                     Catholic History of North America</title> by Thomas D'Arcy McGee, and a
                  handmade 1865 calendar.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_9rc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1848-1867</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_c86e30a8ba9c423836e61c235e3aa612">
                     <extent>3 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_0eeaba3b10f2c7bec9e0cbe9c2ed2ef1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_pxp" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1868-1887</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_5105ef0b9118ff0c9201c1da71158204">
                     <extent>3 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_1276bcac3cb29e10789d6922e512fb0e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_kha" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_28cb8504b582addff582a61f0842f288">
                     <extent>5 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_d21aa1be201f885fd9801e1d84186418" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref22_sge" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Writings, undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_a0bddd32628fd66616402594fd61425f">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>The Religious Writings concern Robert Burns Mayes's book <title type="simple"
                     render="italic">The Tecnobaptist</title> (published 1857) and related topics
                  including his essays on aeiparthenia, anti-Romanism, and church music.</p>
               <p>Mathematical Writings relate to Robert Burns Mayes's 1878-1880 study of the
                  ancient Greek geometric problem of trisecting an angle (a mathematical
                  impossibility) and include correspondence with Professor J. W. Nicholson as well
                  as Mayes's essay <title type="simple" render="doublequote">The Mathematical
                     Pariah</title>.</p>
               <p>Poetry consists of writings by Robert Burns Mayes III and Fanny Harris Mayes.
                     <title type="simple" render="italic">In All Generations</title>, subtitled
                     <emph render="doublequote">Poems of the Past, the Passing, and the
                     Coming,</emph> is a 458-page typescript collection of poems on religious and
                  historical themes. Many of the poems relate to the Civil War and to Mayes, Stuart,
                  and Dimitry family history and there are some long passages of biographical
                  narrative. It is dedicated to <emph render="doublequote">my eight soldier-uncles
                     [...] who have ended the march, and are resting on the bivouac.</emph> It seems
                  that this work was intended for publication as it was edited and annotated at some
                  point after the author's death in 1922. Brief excerpts from works by other poets
                  are interspersed. </p>
               <p>
                  <title type="simple" render="doublequote">Ivy Locke</title> is a 36-page poem
                  written circa 1895 by Fanny Harris Mayes at age 18.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_k9q" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Religious Writings by Robert Burns Mayes</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_aadb0a5d13b51c037835ae489ea96f4d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref25_xfk" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">Tecnobaptist</title> materials</unittitle>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_19e0052fa946921681ff14d483f483c9">
                        <extent>4 folders</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_111c97f62c57400c28974eab037570f2" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref27_f12" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Essays and notes</unittitle>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_f0f15ab3033c02d161a77e33309d0083">
                        <extent>3 folders</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_935e67b96d44e7f92791d6e21a1458c2" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref29_jgv" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Aeiparthenia</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_6911043f9cf1efe42bfaf80362d69207" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">4</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_ics" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Mathematical Writings by Robert Burns Mayes, 1878-1880</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_a777fb8e88e6e09001b9e53f96ab5323">
                     <extent>3 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_4994dc8517a721783eb409cd431d84dc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_hd7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Poetry</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref33_d7y" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">In All Generations</title> by Robert Burns Mayes III,
                        circa 1922</unittitle>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_18964ead6e9b41ab8f5885a1deef0ddf">
                        <extent>2 folders</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_db394aa10d26da5056f19671230abad8" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">4</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref35_zl4" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="doublequote">Ivy Locke</title> by Fanny Harris Mayes, circa
                        1895</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_ff4fa8d96fa9c5266553a4e92c167df0" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">4</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
