<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="https://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/dorseywhitney/">dorseywhitney</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Dorsey &amp; Whitney records, 1997-2008 and undated, bulk
          2004-2008 <num>RL.00320</num></titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: Yektan Turkyilmaz; machine-readable finding aid created by: Yektan
          Turkyilmaz</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>2009</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">004207683</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-07-17 11:53:45
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2014</date>
        <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported to
          Archivists Toolkit</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Dorsey &amp; Whitney records</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname source="ingest">Dorsey &amp; Whitney (Minneapolis, Minn.)</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.00320</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7.8 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">12 boxes</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1997/2008" type="inclusive">1997-2008 and undated</unitdate>
      <unitdate normal="2004/2008" type="bulk">2004-2008</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_4e419a2f99350e13a3a56748a5a481a0">Dorsey &amp; Whitney LLP is a
        Minneapolis-based business law firm whose lawyers took on the pro bono cases of Bahraini
        detainees at the Guantánamo Bay detention center. The Dorsey &amp; Whitney Records span the
        years 1997-2008, with the majority of the materials created between 2004 and 2008. The
        records consist largely of legal papers, news clippings, writings and correspondence
        regarding the cases of six Bahraini detainees: Jumah Al-Dossari, Abdullah Al-Nuaimi, Isa
        Al-Murbati, Salah Al-Balooshi, Adel Hajji and Salman bin Ibrahim Al-Khalifa, kept under
        extra-judicial detention by the U.S. military at Camp Delta, Guantánamo Bay Naval Base,
        Cuba. A team of three lawyers, Mark S. Sullivan, Joshua Colangelo-Bryan and Christopher G.
        Karagheuzoff took on the cases of Bahraini detainees pro bono in 2004. The records in this
        collection document the lawyers' legal motions, public campaigns and diplomatic negotiations
        for writ of habeas corpus and the release and repatriation of the Bahraini detainees. Many
        of these documents are also present in electronic form. The records are arranged in four
        series: Case Files, Correspondence, Publicity, and Digital Files. Acquired as part of the
        Human Rights Archive.</abstract>
      <physdesc id="aspace_b6ddf4b09c810626e07fac46a37ea215"><extent>Approximately 4,875
          Items</extent></physdesc>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_f3c1ccf7ef16ba51468f7b63143e7c69">Material in English and Arabic
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_4dc138f22b7c82a73824705eb5fbbe4b">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>Original electronic files and audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these
        materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research
        Services before coming to use this collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
        research use.</p>
      <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_5e0f736835ed4597f9121c37cedd5dc8">
      <head>Copyright Notice</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_1c87b40beb6ef929d57a2c136a9d6c4c">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Dorsey &amp; Whitney Records, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_3bf9fa447bb4d8ded12c2285987d417d">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Dorsey &amp; Whitney Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo id="aspace_1a1ea2458d3f85c97a9846fb97fac216">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Yektan Turkyilmaz, October 2009</p>
      <p>Encoded by Yektan Turkyilmaz, October 2009</p>
      <p>Accession(s) described in this finding aid: 2009-0181</p>
    </processinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_aa1e0023e470c9884ccb4519e5012df4">
      <head>Biographical Note</head>
      <p>Dorsey and Whitney LLP is a business law firm which was founded in 1912 in Minneapolis, MN,
        where its headquarters are still located, to provide legal counseling to the First Bank of
        Minneapolis. A team of three lawyers, Mark S. Sullivan, Joshua Colangelo-Bryan and
        Christopher G. Karagheuzoff, from the New York Office of the firm took on the cases of
        Bahraini Guantánamo detainees <emph render="italic">pro bono</emph> in 2004. These lawyers
        represented the Bahraini detainees until the release and repatriation of all of them by
        2008. Sullivan, Colangelo-Bryan and Karagheuzoff did not only follow the legal cases of
        their Bahraini detainees but also got involved in public activities in order to raise
        awareness about the human rights situation and abuses at the military detention center in
        Guantánamo Naval Base. They also initiated negotiations with Bahraini diplomats and
        officials regarding the release and repatriation of their clients. The team of Dorsey &amp;
        Whitney lawyers also paid a visit to Bahrain to meet with the relatives of their
        clients.</p>
      <p>Jumah Al-Dossari is a joint citizen of Bahrain and Saudi Arabia detained in December 2001
        in Pakistan, kept under arrest by the U.S. military in Kandahar, Afghanistan, and
        transferred to Camp Delta military detention center in January 2002 and eventually released
        without facing any charges in 2007. He suffered severe psychological and physical abuse both
        in Kandahar and Guantánamo. Al-Dossari attempted suicide thirteen times and went on hunger
        strikes at least twice while under extra-judicial detention at Guantánamo. His case became
        an emblematic example of the abuse and torture at Guantánamo naval base and detrimental
        consequences of long term solitary confinement. Al-Dossari was represented by the Dorsey
        &amp; Whitney LLP lawyer Joshua Colangelo-Bryan and he was repatriated to Saudi Arabia in
        2007.</p>
      <p>Joshua Colangelo-Bryan is a Senior Attorney at the New York office of Dorsey &amp; Whitney
        LLP. He gained his law degree in 1999 from the University of Washington School Of Law. Prior
        to working for Dorsey, Joshua served with the United Nations Mission in Kosovo, where he
        participated in the prosecution of criminal cases involving war crimes and terrorism. He
        also has participated in post-conflict humanitarian aid work in the Balkans. He practices in
        the areas of complex civil litigation, employment law, and securities fraud. He also
        represents individuals and entities before federal and state agencies. He devotes a
        substantial portion of his practice to <title type="simple" render="italic">pro bono</title>
        cases, including the representation of Guantánamo Bay detainees.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_e2a9a164b4f88fc8cd1f1cbc46d946cd">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>The Dorsey &amp; Whitney Records span the years 1997-2008, with the majority of the
        materials created between 2004 and 2008. The records consist largely of legal papers, news
        clippings, writings and correspondence regarding the cases of six Bahraini detainees: Jumah
        Al-Dossari, Abdullah Al-Nuaimi, Isa Al-Murbati, Salah Al-Balooshi, Adel Hajji and Salman bin
        Ibrahim Al-Khalifa, kept under extra-judicial detention by the U.S. military at Camp Delta,
        Guantánamo Bay Naval Base, Cuba. </p>
      <p>A team of three lawyers, Mark S. Sullivan, Joshua Colangelo-Bryan and Christopher G.
        Karagheuzoff took on the cases of Bahraini detainees <emph render="italic">pro bono</emph>
        in 2004. The records in this collection document the lawyers' legal motions, public
        campaigns and diplomatic negotiations for writ of habeas corpus and the release and
        repatriation of the Bahraini detainees, as well the surrounding issues of the Bush
        administration's responses to terrorism, the civil rights of prisoners of war, and the use
        of interrogation and torture at U.S. installations. Many of these documents are also present
        in the form of electronic files.</p>
      <p>The records are divided into four series: Case Files, Correspondence, Publicity, and
        Digital Files. The Case Files Series (nine boxes of the thirteen in the collection)
        comprises petitions, filings, documents relating to the Combatant Status Review Tribunal
        (CRST), and a wide variety of legal records regarding the six Bahrainis' and other
        concurrent Guantánamo detainee cases. The Correspondence Series includes exchanges between
        client detainees, Department of Justice officials, Bahraini diplomats and officials, U.S.
        senators and congressmen, law scholars, and colleagues of the Dorsey &amp; Whitney team
        representing the Guantánamo detainees. The letters and writings in this series cover issues
        and problems related to the legal status of Guantánamo detainees, human rights violations at
        Camp Delta, and diplomatic efforts for the release and repatriation of the Bahraini
        detainees. The high-profile case of Jumah Al-Dossari, detained in 2001 and eventually
        released without facing any charges in 2007, is covered in depth in this series, becoming an
        emblematic example of the abuse and torture at Guantánamo Naval Base and detrimental
        consequences of long term solitary confinement. Also covered in depth in the Correspondence
        Series is the Graham-Levin-Kyl Amendment approved by the Senate on November, 15 2005, which
        prohibits all habeas corpus claims by Guantánamo detainees and allows military tribunals to
        rely on evidence gathered by the use of torture. The Publicity Series brings together news
        articles regarding Bahraini Guantánamo detainees, commentaries addressing the legal process
        and human rights issues, and interviews with Dorsey &amp; Whitney lawyers about the
        conditions at the military base and the legal and living situation of the detainees. The
        clippings in the collection were published by major news press and online media outlets
        worldwide, and include seven folders which hold many Arabic language news clippings. Many of
        the legal team's documents are also present in the form of electronic documents which are
        organized into folders described in the Digital Files Series. Also present is a
        twelve-minute unclassified audio recording on CD-R of the CRST hearing for Al-Murbati, and
        printed images of the families of the detainees. Original electronic files and recordings
        are closed to access but use copies may be requested; please contact Research Services.</p>
      <p>The Dorsey &amp; Whitney Records are composed of materials predominantly in the English
        language. There is also a considerable amount of Arabic language items in all three series.
        These chiefly consist of affidavits, letters by detainees and their relatives, and news
        clippings. Most of the Arabic language materials have English translations, with the
        exception of the news clippings. </p>
      <p>Acquired as part of the Human Rights Archive at Duke University.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_5a8519f5ace5ac9d24dd0037cafb1b70">
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p><archref><unittitle label="Collection">Baher Azmy Papers, 1986-2007 and undated [Lawyer
            representing a Guantánamo detainee] </unittitle><repository label="Repository">David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University</repository>
        </archref></p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Aliens -- Government policy -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Combatants and noncombatants (International law)</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Detention of persons -- Cuba -- Guantánamo Bay Naval Base</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Human Rights -- Government policy -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Prisoners of war -- Abuse of -- Cuba</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Prisoners of war -- Civil rights -- Cuba -- Guantaánamo Bay Naval
        Base</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Prisoners of war -- Government policy -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Prisoners of war -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Cuba -- Guantaánamo Bay
        Naval Base</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Terrorism investigation -- Moral and ethical aspects</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Torture -- United States -- Psychological aspects</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Torture -- Government policy -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">War on Terrorism, 2001-2009 -- Law and legislation -- United
        States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">War on Terrorism, 2001-2009 -- Moral and ethical aspects</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp -- Bahraini detainees</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">CD-ROMs</genreform>
      <corpname source="ingest">Human Rights Archive (Duke University)</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Dorsey &amp; Whitney (Minneapolis, Minn.)</corpname>
      <persname source="ingest">Al-Dossari, Jumah, 1973-</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref13_6u8" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Case Files</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1997/2008" type="inclusive">1997-2008 and undated</unitdate>
          <physdesc id="aspace_b442645941a0517483c7b79d279b1578"><extent>8 boxes</extent></physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_c05b1acb2caad8bb51d98241c070b93c">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>Comprises petitions, filings, documents relating to the Combatant Status Review
            Tribunal (CRST), and a wide variety of legal records regarding the six Bahrainis' and
            Guantánamo detainees' cases such as Al-Odah and Boumediene. The series documents legal
            efforts of their lawyers for writ of habeas corpus, writ of certiorari, amelioration of
            living condition at Camp Delta, and finally for the release and repatriation of their
            clients. The series also contain documents regarding the government's efforts to
            preclude attempts to attain any rights for the detainees kept extra-judicially as enemy
            combatants by the U.S. military at Camp Delta. The series contains extensive material
            related to the workings and procedures of and trials by the Combatant Status Review
            Tribunal (CSRT), which was established by the U.S. government on July 7, 2004. Also
            comprehensively covered in this series are the legal records and other documents
            concerning the Detainee Treatment Act of 2005 and Military Commission Act of 2006. The
            Bahraini detainees Al-Dossari and Al-Murbati cases are especially well-documented. The
            series is composed predominantly of materials in English language, but also contains
            many Arabic documents some of which are also translated into English. Other items
            include a twelve-minute unclassified audio recording on CD-R of CRST hearing for
            Al-Murbati (Box 4) and photographic images of the families of the detainees.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="aspace_981657e026fc4d6cd358a9576937590b">
          <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
          <p>[Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require
            production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research Services before
            coming to use this collection.]</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref15_uxe" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Case file folders</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_1082870b5dadfbe9c8b7e1cbfe3b06c8" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1-8</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref18_2cn" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="2004/2007" type="inclusive">2004-2007</unitdate>
          <physdesc id="aspace_2943a4fa29b63f298f8fa4a1a38fa7d3"><extent>1 box</extent></physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_8da98bb4594f6a5fd365c1f4fca9d25d">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>The Correspondence Series includes writings between the attorneys and client detainees,
            Department of Justice officials, Bahraini diplomats and officials, U.S. senators and
            congressmen, law scholars, and colleagues of the Dorsey &amp; Whitney team representing
            the Guantanamo detainees. The writings cover issues and problems related to the legal
            status of Guantánamo detainees, human rights violations at Camp Delta and diplomatic
            efforts for the release and repatriation of the Bahraini detainees. The high-profile
            case of Jumah Al-Dossari is covered in depth in this series; his case became an
            emblematic example of the abuse and torture at Guantánamo naval base and detrimental
            consequences of long term solitary confinement. Also covered extensively is the
            Graham-Levin-Kyl Amendment approved by the Senate on November 15, 2005, which prohibits
            all habeas corpus claims by Guantánamo detainees and allows the military tribunals to
            rely on evidence gathered by the use of torture. The series mostly consists of letters,
            but there are also photocopies of photographic images from the visit of the lawyers to
            detainee relatives in Bahrain and court-related material attached to letters. The
            written material is largely in English; all letters written in Arabic have English
            translations but court-related Arabic materials are not translated.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref20_ly4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>To/From detainees, Bahraini officials, and Department of Justice, 2006 Mar.
              4-2007 Jun. 14</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_c655af02e9e0c141ea93e621ef31cb7e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">9</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref21_6yb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>To/from detainees, Bahraini officials, U.S. politicians, lawyers, and
              Department of Justice, 2005 Jun. 2-2007 Aug. 15</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_7e1077277eab09f36c083bb340560cce" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">9</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref22_lx9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>To/from detainees, Bahraini officials, lawyers, and Department of Justice,
              2004 Jul 9-2005 Sep., 1</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_c5df465776898499800de89dc6fc2d9a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">9</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref23_7p6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>To/from detainees, Bahraini officials, Department of Justice, and law
              colleagues, 2005 Sep. 22 - 2005 Dec. 7</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_91e823f9abf19ef87152a2613ed079d4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">9</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref24_jsa" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>To/from Al-Dossari, Department of Justice, Bahraini officials, and law
              colleagues, re: Al-Dossari, 2005 Dec. 22 - 2006 Mar. 1</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_8f9fd77f85e3a60741f0172137f07c94" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">9</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref25_c2z" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>To/from U.S. politicians, law scholars, and Department of Justice, re:
              Graham-Levin-Kyl Amendment, 2005 Dec. 9 - 20</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_0ec175d15ff1a4296012f3cb4766e5ed" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">9</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref27_99u" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Publicity</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="2004/2008" type="inclusive">2004-2008</unitdate>
          <physdesc id="aspace_da69c7067157cb9709ca45eec75c7a2e"><extent>3 boxes</extent></physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_ba107a4fe2e4a93436dde96d1098b138">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>Consists of news clippings - chiefly photocopies or printouts - compiled by the Dorsey
            á Whitney lawyers to document their clients' cases. This series brings together news
            articles regarding Bahraini Guantánamo detainees, commentaries addressing the legal
            process and human rights issues, and interviews with Dorsey á Whitney lawyers about the
            conditions at the military base and the legal and living situation of the detainees. The
            clippings in the collection were published by major news press and online media outlets
            worldwide, including <title type="simple" render="italic">The New York Times</title>,
              <title type="simple" render="italic">The Washington Post</title>, <title type="simple"
              render="italic">Newsweek</title>, <title type="simple" render="italic">Time
              Magazine</title>, <title type="simple" render="italic">The International Herald
              Tribune</title>, <title type="simple" render="italic">Gulf Daily News</title>, <title
              type="simple" render="italic">The Independent</title>, <title type="simple"
              render="italic">The Guardian</title>, <title type="simple" render="italic"
            >BBC</title>, <title type="simple" render="italic">Khaleej Times Online</title>,
            gulfnews.com, <title type="simple" render="italic">Arab News</title> and <title
              type="simple" render="italic">Aljazeera,</title> and many others. The clippings are
            chiefly in English; however there are seven folders which hold many Arabic language news
            clippings.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref29_5r3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Publicity files, 2004-2008</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_6be09bd25f515718dd5c7f7b58331f08" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">10-12</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref31_pha" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Digital Files</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="2004/2006" type="inclusive">2004-2006</unitdate>
          <physdesc id="aspace_5bfd6694243f44387595ac0331a53b81"><extent>349
            files</extent></physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_d3e4ad462df63d50f61015aeb77d5691">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>Consists of electronic files, chiefly PDF and MS Word document formats, arranged into
            the following folders: ARB Material; Bundestag Inquiry; Catalogue of Documents; Client
            Notes and Declass Summaries; Correspondence; DC Admissions; Diplomacy; Kurnaz Visit and
            Access Info; Petitions; Press; and Protective Order and New Access Procedures.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <accessrestrict id="aspace_bcc457304780a5f5820485177a44d067">
          <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
          <p>Electronic files have been transferred to a library server and can only be accessed in
            the Rubenstein reading room. Please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use
            this collection.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
