<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/downeysamuel/">downeysamuel</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Samuel Smith Downey Papers, 1762-1965 <num>RL.00323</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Library Staff; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Meghan Lyon</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000853484</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-28 15:50:25
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Samuel Smith Downey papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Downey, Samuel Smith, d. 1851</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00323</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">20 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1762/1965" type="inclusive">1762-1965</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_ced79f0e4d90cdba54aae4f5c192172e">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_4fd0b44413a80400c6ed4f7c50c1d880">Irish immigrant and planter, of
            Granville Co., N.C. The early portion of this collection is made up of the papers of
            Ephraim Macquillen, a merchant of Richmond, Va., containing letters, bills, and receipts
            from business firms in New York, Philadelphia, and Boston to which he sold flour and
            tobacco and from which he bought supplies. The papers of Samuel S. Downey, which also
            contain the papers of James Webb Alexander, John Granville Smith, Thomas Downey, James
            Downey, and son-in-law Isaac H. Davis, concern S. S. Downey's administration of the
            estate of John G. Smith and the many suits involving the estate; management of
            plantations in Mississippi and North Carolina including correspondence and legal papers
            dealing with hiring slaves to build a railroad from Natchez to Jackson, Miss., in the
            1830s; letters from factors in Richmond, Va., concerning Downey's tobacco; and the Civil
            War letters of Downey's sons, for the most part describing the effects of the war on
            civilians.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_78ac0fb77c6805c1301683fc4a6e98dc">
            <extent>3279 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_85b6687958de18ea4d1e773c0d53da34">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_ac5b00f8b945563855e61ee7d8251f91">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_c22b51c1fa22114f3f2ab37fbc7c83db">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_a3e9ea081c850179032769fb369e7058">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Samuel Smith Downey Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_513122dd0932397027bd1c983ed57d92">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Samuel Smith Downey Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a gift in 1949. Additional materials were added on June 26, 1964;
            transferred from the W.H. Gregory papers, August 1964; and transferred from the Jonathan
            K. Smith papers in June 1971.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_bdaef3fe498b54de1522007809e5b5ff">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library Staff, 1989</p>
         <p>Encoded by Meghan Lyon, July 2011</p>
         <p>Materials may not have been ordered and described beyond their original condition.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_a56ad4015d7ee447463e6d2b43b8126b">
         <head>Biographical and Historical Note</head>
         <p>Samuel Smith Downey was the son of James and Elizabeth (Smith) Downey. His grandfather,
            Samuel Smith, migrated from Essex County, Virginia, in the early 1760s to occupy a grant
            of land from the Earl of Granville County, N.C. James Downey, father of Samuel S., was
            born in Essex County, Va. S.S. Downey owned plantations in Mississippi and Granville
            County, N.C. He hired out slaves for the building of a Mississippi railroad, and also
            sold tobacco throughout the mid-Atlantic. Downey served as deputy sheriff in 1812,
            became justice of the peace, and was postmaster of Abram's Plains from 1841 until at
            least 1847. He died in 1851. </p>
         <p>Samuel Smith Downey married Jane Harrison in 1812. She died in 1827, at the age of 36,
            after bearing him three children: John Alexander (A.B., University of North Carolina,
            1836 and M.D. from University of Pennsylvania Medical School, 1839); James Webb (A.B.,
            University of North Carolina, 1843), and Jane E.S (in school in Chapel Hill in
            1843).</p>
         <p>In 1829, Downey married his second wife, Sarah (Sally) Pomfret Smith, his first cousin
            and the daughter of Alexander Smith. Their only child was Anne (1830-1914). Ann attended
            Salem Female Academy. </p>
         <p>In 1845, John was in the Wisconsin Territory. By 1862 he had moved to Hardeman County,
            Tenn., but he also owned property in Floyd County, Ga. which was supervised by Lewis D.
            Burwell. In February 1863, John Downey became disillusioned and wrote from Homer,
            Claiborne Parish, Louisiana, to Burwell depicting the trials of Federal rule in
            Tennessee, his flight to Texas, and the sale there of his slaves who had not deserted to
            the Federals. In 1884 he was still in Galveston, Texas, supporting Cleveland in the
            presidential race.</p>
         <p>Ann Downey married Isaac H. Davis, a tobacco and cotton farmer who sold his crops
            through commission merchants in Petersburg and Norfolk and through Cooper, Blackwell,
            and Co., and Reams's warehouse in Durham, N.C. </p>
         <p>Jane Downey's history is harder to trace. There is no mention of her in the division of
            property following Samuel Smith Downey's death. </p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_b15e67b1cf2e30d1eee8919c6d6f0f9d">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Although predominately the papers of Samuel Smith Downey, this collection also contains
            materials from Ephraim Macquillen, a Richmond, Va. merchant, and Isaac H. Davis, the
            son-in-law of S.S. Downey.</p>
         <p>The Macquillen manuscripts are mainly letters, bills, and receipts from business firms
            in New York, Philadelphia, and Boston to which he sold his tobacco and flour and from
            which he bought supplies. Many of the letters contain reports of the state of the market
            for flour, tobacco, and other commodities, and of the condition of Macquillen's flour
            and tobacco upon their arrival in those cities. Papers concern the loss of the <title
               type="simple" render="italic">Fox</title>, attempts to collect insurance on its lost
            cargo, and the bankruptcy of Thomas Hooper. </p>
         <p>Ephraim Macquillen's wife and children came over from Ireland in 1801. News reached New
            York on the evening of November 20, 1801, that the preliminaries of peace were signed on
            October 1 in London between England and France. Samuel Hicks in 1803 wrote that war
            would be resumed between England and France and that every preparation possible was
            being made in London for it. The collection also contains a copy of a letter from Thomas
            Jefferson, with his views on Christianity.</p>
         <p>The portion of the collection that is principally S.S. Downey's correspondence also
            includes papers of James Webb Alexander, John Granville Smith, and Thomas and James
            Downey. S.S. Downey was John G. Smith's favorite nephew and executor. John G.,
            unmarried, left considerable property over which there was lengthy litigation, and a
            great many of the Downey manuscripts deal with suits by Smith's heirs.</p>
         <p>Samuel Smith Downey, who had moved to Mississippi, returned to Granville County, N.C.,
            but he continued to hold his plantation in Mississippi. He owned a large amount of
            slaves, 27 of whom he hired out to work on the construction of a railroad from Natchez
            to Jackson. These slaves, along with those of three other Granville County men -- Dr.
            John R. Hicks and Joseph Amis (d. Aug. 3, 1840), brothers-in-law of Downey, as well as
            Flemming Beasley -- were under the supervision of Dr. Joseph Hicks, the brother of John
            Hicks and the agent of Downey.</p>
         <p>The letters of Joseph Hicks to Downey and John R. Hicks contain accounts of illness and
            a few deaths among the slaves. After a contract between Downey and Welman and Mills
            expired, Hicks worked the slaves for a short time near Jackson, then for a little while
            with Judge Jack of Pa. in partnership with Major Arnold. The slaves worked on the
            Natchez to Jackson railroad. Hicks and Arnold became deeply indebted to Downey for the
            hire of his slaves; and after the death of Hicks, Downey instituted suits against the
            executors of Hicks and against Arnold.</p>
         <p>Overseers were in charge of Downey's Mississippi plantation until his son James went out
            to take it over. Both Downey and his two sons made a number of trips to Mississippi to
            look after affairs before James settled there. Letters to Downey from his overseers and
            his lawyer, A. Burwell of Vicksburg, report on conditions on his plantation. While
            Downey was in Mississippi in the spring of 1837, he wrote from Jackson that his slaves
            were not paying expenses. Since the legislature of Mississippi had passed a law
            prohibiting the bring of slaves into the state for hire or sale, he did not know what to
            do with his. Also in May 1837, Joseph Hicks wrote that he had received orders to
            discontinue work on the railroad in Hinds Co., Mississippi, and that the people of that
            county had deposed their sheriff.</p>
         <p>Letters in 1837 and 1838 reveal some effects of the depression: one by Samuel Smith
            Downey from Mississippi in 1837 comments on the scarcity of money there and about the
            advisability of re-chartering the U.S. Bank. The next year, William Ford referred in one
            of his letters to the plight of commercial men in Richmond, and Joseph Hicks listed in
            one of his letters several types of Mississippi bank notes that were no good. The bank
            of the Natchez R.R. Company became insolvent, and S.S. Downey instituted a suit against
            it to collect the money due him.</p>
         <p>S.S. Downey sent his tobacco produced in Granville County by wagon to merchants in
            Petersburg, where it was re-shipped to William Ford in Richmond. Letters from Ford and
            factors in Petersburg relate to the marketing of Downey's tobacco and to goods which
            they purchased for him. In 1848, Downey correspondence with merchants in Charleston,
            S.C., about selling manufactured tobacco in that city.</p>
         <p>The collection also contains land deeds and other legal papers of Granville County;
            deeds for slaves purchased; a brief diary from a boat trip made by John G. Smith in 1827
            from Nashville to New Orleans and back; papers concerned with the estate of Alexander
            Smith; will of John G. Smith of Granville County and papers concerning the selling of
            the estate; will of James Downey; contract between S.S. Downey and Robert D. Wade of
            Hinds County, Mississippi, providing that the latter would take charge of Downey's
            plantation and slaves; letters relative to the Southern Temperance Convention to be held
            in Fayetteville, N.C., in November 1835; the N.C. Mutual Insurance Company; contract for
            hiring the slaves of Downey to work on the Natchez to Jackson railroad; and numerous
            other broadsides and legal papers.</p>
         <p>Some other projects treated in the manuscript collection are: A project for clearing the
            Roanoke River; incorrigibility of slaves; Methodists and Episcopalians in Jackson
            County, Tennessee; a camp meeting in Kentucky; religious matters at Union Theological
            Seminary, Va.; runaway slaves; purchase of slaves for gold mining in Granville County;
            victory of the Whigs in that county; depredations of Confederates.</p>
         <p>There are 2 bound volumes: A ledger of John G. Smith of Granville County, 1798-1803,
            which includes a daybook of Ann A. Davis, 1887-1901; and a ledger of S.S. Downey,
            1828-1874. </p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Executors and administrators -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Merchants -- Virginia -- Richmond</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Plantations -- Mississippi</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Plantations -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Railroads -- Mississippi</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Slavery -- Mississippi</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Confederate States of America -- Social conditions</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Tobacco -- Marketing</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
         <persname source="ingest">Downey, Samuel Smith</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Downey, Thomas</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Macquillen, Ephraim</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Smith, John Granville -- Estate</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Alexander, James Webb</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Davis, Isaac H.</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Downey, James</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Downey, Samuel Smith, d. 1851</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_iyi" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Manuscripts, 1762-1899 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_a73277419dd45615649b163b4f395ead">
                  <extent>16 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_0e426f288f9605e51602a92579cef326">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Collection's letters and papers are grouped in the early boxes and have been
                  arranged chronologically. Bills and receipts are also grouped and arranged
                  chronologically. Additional formats are listed at the end of the description.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_mx2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Unaccessioned, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b7ecab7f0653a7721985eb33fd7c44ad" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_sne" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters and papers, 1762-1802</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_d10f1ca623cb4fd1790397fcc4cfb858">
                     <extent>3 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_cb975bbeda5df017403aa106e98db8f7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_nkp" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters and papers, 1802-1823</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_dbe00b0e94592c6d0975c1a6337c52b9">
                     <extent>5 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_c2fc8da20a0b3c1b712ace7909999371" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_y4e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters and papers, 1824-1829</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_2d6f3ad9c8f730d8230942e85e2f0289">
                     <extent>3 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_0627590b7d798ba786e8c70d3b5f3e86" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_pau" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters and papers, 1830-1836</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_49811575dc4626bf8f6b45d4fe1e3634">
                     <extent>7 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_e613d446a01aa675ba1a7932569b6a4d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_726" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters and papers, 1837-1839</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_3e287e1612794e839fea7c4698d7d46d">
                     <extent>3 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_826139bc1d3921dcd900ac7592c8c259" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_8kc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters and papers, 1840-1847</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_f3413910065724d2d3a13f8e64323496">
                     <extent>8 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_9bc07fb6981717216935188db9ef3a04" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_tqk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters and papers, 1848-1858</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_b6aa32e464be2ccab4a1fc0daf4aa1ef">
                     <extent>3 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_483647053da3c67a9565a1510ba9ac41" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_h0h" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters and papers, 1860-1889, 1892-1912</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_8903a78aa2a05cc4a850c492e024bbcf">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_27a99fc7821b6aefa297a43564234d9e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_5k9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters and papers, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0986bd3b188a84a9fa9c6d5c09fa8a13" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_b4m" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Silhouettes, framed</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_128edf4b9acf815d9b604635f4b2e194" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref33_oxq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bills and receipts, 1774-1809</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_ece38dc2eea309ca4e17fe0ed0dfa89c">
                     <extent>2 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_17332714d4681e295ee2585dddc3d21a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">10</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_ix7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bills and receipts, 1810-1829</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_97b82d4b90e3d068ecadfab32eb837df">
                     <extent>3 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_3e0f2deb71bcfe922b3d7d6a7172c2d5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref37_ggp" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bills and receipts, 1830-1839</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_1746b536ddb8e0f4b1e090c2b6493d7c">
                     <extent>2 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_4df4ea1a8480dbc30f98e435cfb81081" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref39_fbz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bills and receipts, 1840-1865</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_d1adc4e7c1bc23f315559f1c197b8308">
                     <extent>5 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_37fcac17032c84de3901f3ac7e619050" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref41_k6x" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bills and receipts, 1866-1882</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_607572c02397f2a93e25a4ec06676785">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_51c8d9f12ab4569aee2816ebc77ec93c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_hwc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bills and receipts, 1883-1899, and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_a46c628a083e111434cba91dc6b0287e">
                     <extent>3 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_a2638b0f0b3c8a49c8caec71990c9216" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">15</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref45_g03" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed materials</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1c7dc61b55792ac20a9017fb92dcf0d7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref46_f8m" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Record of slave births and deaths</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c4c21565a98929bd60ab7b7d24fe3203" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_n41" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>18th century Psalm book</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2a4c827f943e78c75f350dba0d506b2e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref48_hmu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Broadside, 1831</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_eeea0e740d866d04b6ea732c04e6ae86" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref49_31a" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Scrapbook-ledger, 1840</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e1874475f016b6dedf55911456a79c46" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref51_zh3" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Bound manuscripts, 1798-1874</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_d9419f23a9adb0da80a94a2bd2b9e402">
                  <extent>2 volumes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref53_nty" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ledger, 1798-1803</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_46a7d79462e442d8c118b8ec52346b6f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M: 2376</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref54_t0e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ledger, 1828-1874</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3adeabbe2f7b9a9f3a9d8100d1db864f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">F: 921</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
