<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/eltinge/">eltinge</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Eltinge-Lord Family Papers (Peter Eltinge Papers), 1856-1871
                  <num>RL.00361</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;amp;
               Manuscript Library Staff; machine-readable finding aid created by: Stephen Douglas
               Miller</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000853494</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-28 16:30:09
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Eltinge-Lord Family papers (Peter Eltinge papers)</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Eltinge, Peter, ca. 1842-1877</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00361</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 Linear Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">14 boxes</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1856/1871" type="inclusive">1856-1871</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_5f37a9c53a00cf55b6149c2db7985809">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <physdesc id="aspace_4437b5f6d9767a8c4d77a5966668eaaa">
            <extent>2,245 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_df5d2de63ae5ec2add6641d9d6b695d3">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_19697b1e8ad3c52693245280c1ad9f54">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_cdd53b8d3368b9fb67918d14488309d2">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The status of the copyright interests in the Eltinge-Lord Family Papers is unknown. For
            more information, consult the section on copyright in the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_199d7856e6ae1521fbe5c0b04fba7ba2">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Eltinge-Lord Family Papers (Peter Eltinge Papers), David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_d8ef37063d1cccd3d1018f387cd13e49">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Eltinge-Lord Family Papers were acquired by Duke University in 1976.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_67ba3e08efa83f52ae4ae050e68c38af">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by: Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library
            Staff</p>
         <p>Completed ca. 1976</p>
         <p>Encoded by Stephen Douglas Miller</p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_9d641f420b71412d010dc543df63f891">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The Eltinge-Lord Family collection consists of the papers of two men related by marriage
            who served as Union officers in the Civil War. It has been organized into two divisions
            respectively centered on Peter Eltinge (ca. 1842-1877) of New Paltz, New York, and
            George P. Lord (ca. 1842-1866) of Camden, Delaware. Lord's marriage to Peter's sister,
            Mary Eltinge, formed the link between the two. Peter, a store clerk before the war,
            entered the 156th New Yolk Volunteer Infantry in August, 1862, and rose to the rank of
            captain. Most of his papers consist of correspondence with his father, Edmund Eltinge,
            an officer of the Huguenot National Bank in New Paltz, and the other members of his
            family. George obtained a naval commission in 1861, served with the Mississippi
            Squadron, and eventually became a lieutenant commander. The bulk of his papers consist
            of the official records of two of his commands, the U.S.S. <emph render="italic"
               >Chillicothe</emph> and the U.S.S. <emph render="italic">Ozark</emph> . For a brief
            time in 1864, the two brothers-in-law served in the same theater and met while taking
            part in Banks' Red River campaign of that year. After the war Eltinge and Lord were
            partners in a grocery business in Memphis, Tennessee, until Lord's death in August,
            1866. Peter Eltinge returned to New Paltz, where he worked in his father's bank and in
            insurance until his own death at the age of 35.</p>
         <p>Filed in the first box of the Lord Division are a printed catalog of the contents of the
            various official naval records, a typewritten supplement of added material of similar
            nature, and copies of sketches of ships' histories as given in the U.S. Navy's <title
               type="simple" render="italic">Dictionary of American Fighting Ships.</title> Filed in
            the first box of the Eltinge Division are copies of biographical sketches of individuals
            mentioned in both divisions. Other supplementary material filed at the beginning of the
            Eltinge collection includes a list of members of the 156th New York Volunteers and the
            service records of its officers as given in <title type="simple" render="italic">New
               York and the War of the Rebellion</title> 1861-1865, Vol. 5. Researchers may also
            wish to consult Will Plank's <title type="simple" render="italic">Banners and
               Bugles,</title> a popular history of the participation of Ulster County, New York, in
            the Civil War.</p>
         <p>Researchers using the printed and typewritten guides to the Lord Division should be
            warned that those aids do not definitively describe the current order of those papers.
            Some material previously considered <emph render="doublequote">undated</emph> has been
            re-filed in appropriate places in the collection by date. Other peculiarities in both
            divisions include the filing of such items as general orders, printed materials, etc.,
            in among correspondence and other categories. In such cases the material remains where
            originally filed and, in the instance of the Lord Division, as listed in the guides
            provided.</p>
         <p>The most important part of the Eltinge Division is Peter's correspondence (1856-1871),
            which, although it includes one letter from 1856, does not begin with any continuity
            until 1859, or after he had already lived in New York City for a year. Another gap
            occurs between April, 1861, and September, 1862, for which there are no letters. The
            correspondence also becomes very thin after Peter closed his business in Memphis. Nine
            letters which appear after that date consist of exchanges with the War Department and
            Treasury concerned with clearing up minor discrepancies in accounts connected with
            military service. Other materials in the collection include typescripts of Peter's
            correspondence (1859-1871), a xerographic copy of a scrapbook, legal papers (1864-1865,
            undated), newspaper clippings (1863-1864), a picture of Eltinge in his officer's
            uniform, and a collection of miscellany (1865-1866). Researchers should be aware that
            the typescripts of the Eltinge correspondence reproduce only a portion of the letters
            for the years indicated and not always very accurately at that.</p>
         <p>Most of the historically significant Eltinge material is contained in Eltinge's
            correspondence, particularly that dealing with the Civil War. Eltinge obtained a second
            lieutenant's commission in the fall of 1862 in the 156th New York Volunteer Infantry, a
            regiment recruited from Richmond County (Staten Island) and Ulster County, New York. The
            regiment saw service in several theaters and participated in General N. P. Banks' probe
            at and later seige of Port Hudson in 1863 and the Red River campaigns of 1863 and 1864
            in the Department of the Gulf, as part of the 19th Corps relief force sent to defend
            Washington against Early, in Sheridan's Shenandoah Valley campain , as paw of
            Schofield's army which moved westward from the North Carolina coast to meet Sherman at
            Goldsboro, and on occupation duty in Lexington, Georgia, after the war in 1865. Peter
            Eltinge saw comparatively little action for all that campaigning, as either his regiment
            was held in reserve, his company detailed as a headquarters guard, or he himself in the
            hospital or in New York on a stint of recruiting duty which allowed him to convalesce.
            Peter was present, however, for practically all of Sheridan's campaign in the Shenandoah
            Valley, during which his regiment suffered heavy casualties.</p>
         <p>The composition of the Lord Division provides very different material than that of Peter
            Eltinge. That portion of George Lord's personal correspondence reposited at Duke
            (1862-1867) consists of only one folder of letters, while xerographic copies of other
            personal letters (1862-1868) are only slightly more numerous. By far the largest part of
            the division consists of the official records of the U. S. naval vessels <emph
               render="italic">Chillicothe</emph> (1863-1867, undated) <emph render="italic"
               >Ozark</emph> (1864-1865), and Osage (1863, undated), and other naval records. Those
            records pertaining to the <emph render="italic">Chillicothe</emph> are both plentiful
            and comprehensive, taking in official correspondence (1863-1867, undated), the reports
            of the chief responsible commissioned and noncommissioned officers (1863-1865), orders
            (1862-1865 , undated), commercial papers (1864-1865, undated), and a miscellany
            collected by or pertaining to the <emph render="italic">Chillicothe</emph> (1863-1865 ,
            undated). Other portions of the division include oaths of allegiance (1864-1865),
            printed material (1863-1865), a logbook of orders (1864), a collection of miscellany
            (1864-1865 , undated), captured Confederate papers (1862-1865), clippings (1861-1862,
            undated), and photographs of naval officers, ironclads, and gunboats (ca. 1861-1865,
            undated).</p>
         <p>The papers of the Lord Division are marked by a number of gaps and omissions. The
            personal correspondence and the copies of personal correspondence contain relatively few
            items for the years 1862 and 1863. Although Lord wrote only sparingly to Peter Eltinge
            and his own family in Delaware, he apparently undertook an extensive correspondence with
            his fiancé and later bride (See Eltinge Division, letters, Edmund to Peter Eltinge, Jan.
            9, 1864, and Lord Division, personal letters, copies, Mary to Edmund Eltinge, May 2, 19,
            1864), while Mary presumably wrote with equal frequency. Practically none of these
            letters are represented in the collection, although the absence of Mary's early letters
            to George can be explained by their probable destruction in the sinking of the <emph
               render="italic">Covington</emph>, one of George's ships, in the spring of 1864.</p>
         <p>The records of the <emph render="italic">Chillicothe</emph>, although by far the most
            numerous of the several ships' records in the collection, are not fully complete. There
            are several large and obvious gaps - occasionally months long - in the morning reports
            and other sections of the several sets of officers' reports. It should also be noted
            that the earliest examples of the <emph render="italic">Chillicothe's</emph> official
            correspondence do not involve Lord, but rather his predecessor, Lt. Joseph P. Couthony.
            Most of the various specialized sections of the ship's records are devoted to narrow
            subjects.</p>
         <p>George Lord had been a cadet at the Naval Academy for a short time in the 1850s. He
            obtained a commission as a master's mate at Cincinnati in 1861, and participated in the
            Belmont, Ft. Henry, New Madrid (Island No. 10), and Red River campaigns and served
            afterwards on the lower Mississippi River. Lord's official correspondence as commander
            of the <emph render="italic">Chillicothe</emph> late in the war chiefly pertains to the
            regulation of trade on the river. Some of the naval records also cover George's service
            as commander of the <emph render="doublequote">Ironclad Fleet in Ordinary</emph> in the
            late part of 1865, while some personal letters (copies) deal with his brief career as a
            grocer in Memphis.</p>
         <p>A general review of the information contained in the Eltinge and Lord Divisions follows.
            Please see appropriate cards in the subject catalog for a complete list of dates and
            references for topics mentioned.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_a68e100a32ce3dae9a3eb34160b17dde">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>Peter Eltinge's correspondence yields particularly good material on the battles in which
            he actively participated. Those actions included three sharp fights - Winchester,
            Fisher's Hill, and Cedar Creek (letters, Sept. 22, Nov. 11, 1864) during Sheridan's
            Shenandoah Valley Campaign. Other, though less significant actions in which Peter saw a
            moderate amount of fighting were Banks' Red River Expedition of April-May, 1863
            (letters, Apr.-May, 1863), and a large skirmish at Mansura, La. (letter of May 18-21,
            1864), during Banks' Red River Expedition of 1864. Eltinge also wrote about the fighting
            of the Port Hudson campaign (letters of Mar. 6-July 23, 1863) the Red River Expedition
            of 1864 (letters of Mar. 19-June 7, 1864) including the battles of Pleasant Hill and
            Sabine Cross Roads, and Sherman's Campaign in the Carolinas (letters of Mar. 11-Apr. 20,
            1865), although his company served as a headquarters guard for most of the Port Hudson
            campaign, his regiment was held in reserve for most of the important battles of the Red
            River campaign of 1864, and his division was used primarily in a supporting role in the
            Carolinas in 1865. His letters about the Red River campaign in 1864 do, however, contain
            considerable detail about the sinking of George Lord's vessel and his subsequent escape
            (various and scattered earlier letters also contain some personal information on
            Lord-not obtainable in the Lord Division itself). Eltinge serves solely as a commentator
            for other actions in which he played no part at all. These include the Yazoo expedition
            (letters of January 5, 11, 1865), Banks' probe toward Port Hudson (letters of March,
            1863), Sherman's March to the Sea (letter of November 24, 1864), and the reactions to
            and controversy about the Confederate surrenders at Appomattox, Virginia and Durham
            Station, North Carolina (letter of April 14, 20, 1865).</p>
         <p>Other excellent material on specific campaigns and battles can be found in the scrapbook
            and clippings contained in the Eltinge Division, particularly for the battle of Antietam
            (scrapbook, pp. 11, 12) and the Port Hudson campaign (clippings, July 14, 1863 and
            scrapbook, pp. 21-30). Much of the scrapbook consists of clippings taken from the <title
               type="simple" render="italic">New Paltz Times,</title> which reprinted letter of area
            soldiers serving in one or another of the regiments recruited in that region of New
            York. One of the paper's correspondents was Charles J. Ackert, the paper's prewar
            editor, who had volunteered as a private soldier in the 156th New York Volunteers and
            after an early discharge became one of Peter Eltinge's correspondents.</p>
         <p>Apart from the fighting itself, Eltinge wrote home about a wide variety of topics of a
            purely military nature, such as efforts to improvise cavalry in the Department of the
            Gulf and training troops through target practice and drill. More often, Eltinge wrote
            about routine problems, many of which were related to the management of personnel,
            especially as his regiment was chronically short of manpower. Related topics include:
            mobilization, recruiting and enlistment, alcoholism and military personnel , discipline,
            desertion, leaves and furloughs, discharges, and demobilization. Disease and battle
            casualties created a large number of vacancies among the officer ranks and inspired
            maneuvering for promotions among the surviving officers and enlisted men. Peter claimed
            that the colonel of the regiment often chose his own favorites for the vacancies and
            used the board of examination to eliminate unwanted candidates instead of the
            incompetents as the army had intended. From the other end of the personnel replacement
            system, Edmund Eltinge kept his son posted as to the effect conscription had on the male
            population at home and how local governments appropriated bounties to entice enough
            volunteers to meet their quotas.</p>
         <p>The letters also cover some of the most mundane aspects of military service in the Civil
            War, including camp life, the military postal system, guard duty, foraging, food,
            medical and sanitary affairs, supplies and stores, surgeons, and chaplains. Due to
            frequent changes of station, pay became a problem, as the paymasters seldom caught up to
            the regiment in time. Additional information on some of these subjects may also be
            obtained from the scrapbook. Eltinge described some conditions at a few permanent and
            temporary barracks and quarters in the New York City area and at Key West, Florida. The
            clipping file contains a copy of an army newspaper, the <title type="simple"
               render="italic">Port Hudson [La.] Freemen</title> (also referred to in scrapbook),
            edited by Charles J. Ackert.</p>
         <p>Eltinge's letters and the scrapbook refer to the transportation of both men and supplies
            at various stages of the war. Most of the transportation was by water - ocean and river.
            One of the most significant of such references concerns the running aground of the 156th
            N.Y.'s transport, <emph render="italic">M. Sanford</emph>, on a reef near the Florida
            Keys. Peter's letters from Beaufort and Morehead City, North Carolina, during Sherman's
            Carolinas campaign touch on the transportation of supplies as he describes efforts to
            unload Chips in those ports in order to resupply Sherman's approaching forces.</p>
         <p>Primarily because of his relationship with George Lord, Peter Eltinge's papers contain a
            number of references to naval affairs. Those references concerning naval operations on
            the Red and Mississippi rivers, prize money, and ironclads came chiefly from Peter's
            letters, while the clippings and oversize folder contain material on blockading
            operations as well, including the capture of Confederate blockade runners by Union
            gunboats.</p>
         <p>Other topics associated with the military side of the Civil War in the Eltinge Division
            include the confiscation of property in the U.S. Army, fraternization of Southerners
            with Union soldiers in Louisiana, Confederate guerrilla activity in the lower
            Mississippi River Valley, conscription and desertion in the Confederate army, Union
            soldiers exercising their suffrage rights, 120th N.Y. Inf. troops held as prisoners by
            the Confederates, and the exchange of prisoners of war. Union commanders discussed
            include Generals Nathaniel P. Banks, Phillip Sheridan, William T. Sherman, Charles P.
            Stone (of Ball's Bluff, in connection with a visit he made to Banks' headquarters in
            1863), and Albert Lee, the cavalry commander during Banks' Red River Expedition of
            1864.</p>
         <p>Peter Eltinge mentioned a number of Union Army regiments. In addition to his own, the
            156th New York Volunteer Infantry, which was also known as the <emph
               render="doublequote">Mountain Legion</emph> (letters, clippings, scrapbook, oversize
            folder), his papers also make prominent mention of the 20th (scrapbook) and the 120th
            New York Volunteer Infantry (letter), regiments from his home county which served in the
            army of the Potomac. Other regiments mentioned include the 90th New York Volunteer
            Infantry, which served as a garrison at Key West, and the 31st Massachusetts and 176th
            New York Volunteer Infantry, both of which served in the Department of the Gulf. Edmund
            Eltinge wrote to Peter about conditions in the Army of the Potomac as a whole with
            regard to discipline and temperance.</p>
         <p>During the Port Hudson campaign, Peter Eltinge had a chance to observe two black Union
            regiments in action, the 1st and 3d Louisiana Native Guard, the men of which impressed
            him with their bearing and courage. Eltinge wrote favorably of using blacks in military
            service, but he disapproved of northern states attempting to recruit southern blacks to
            meet conscription quotas. Soldiers' letters printed in Eltinge's hometown newspaper and
            preserved in the scrapbook also spoke well of the black soldier. Members of Peter's
            regiment sought commissions in black regiments as a way to obtain higher rank. Eltinge
            himself hired a black, Fulton Cox, as a servant from an army hiring agency near
            Washington, and he kept him in his employ after the war (letters, 1865; legal papers,
            1864; scrapbook).</p>
         <p>The Eltinge Division material contains a fair amount of information on non-military
            aspects of the Civil War as well, many of which deal with economic or racial questions.
            The banking background of the Eltinge family gave Peter a sharp eye for the economic
            landscape in the locales he passed through, and father and son exchanged observations on
            hot the economy of New York and the Union at large affected the investments Peter
            arranged for his father to make with the portion of his salary he sent home. Some of the
            other specific economic topics discussed include banks and banking in New York, economic
            conditions in Louisiana and Arkansas, wages in southern states, and cotton trade and
            smuggling during the war. Peter also took note of how blacks generally fared during the
            Civil War, and how they were perceived by white Union soldiers, and he commented on a
            particularly prosperous black at Key West who appeared to produce most of the fresh
            fruit and vegetables on the island.</p>
         <p>Peter Eltinge also provided more general descriptions of areas he served in and how the
            war altered them. These locales included New Orleans and Baton Rouge, Louisiana;
            Morehead City, Beaufort, and Goldsboro, North Carolina, and Key West, Florida.</p>
         <p>Scattered topics discussed briefly include censorship of newspapers in New Orleans, the
            celebration of Thanksgiving Day with dinner sent from New York to the 156th in the
            field, and reaction to the assassination of Abraham Lincoln and the capture of Jefferson
            Davis. In the division there are also a copy of a Unionist newspaper, the <title
               type="simple" render="italic">New South,</title> published at Port Royal, South
            Carolina, and a letter published in a newspaper and reproduced in the scrapbook which is
            a good example of an amateur attempt at propaganda.</p>
         <p>Prior to the war, Peter Eltinge worked as a clerk in two different firms in New York
            City. After working hours, he found time to participate in a choral group, and he
            attended several church services on Sundays, sampling the preaching Of several different
            ministers in the city, including Henry Ward Beecher and William Milburn, <emph
               render="doublequote">the blind preacher</emph>. Partly at the behest of one of his
            employers, Peter also taught Sunday school in poor neighborhoods of the city. He had
            earlier been active in a temperance education society for young people, <emph
               render="doublequote">The Band of Hope,</emph> when he had lived in New Paltz, and
            after moving to New York - and even after joining the army - he remained vitally
            interested in the temperance movement both back at home and on the state and national
            level. Peter inquired about and commented on the activities of the society in New Paltz,
            read copies of the <title type="simple" render="italic">Prohibitionist,</title> a
            periodical published in Albany, and exchanged notes with his father and family about
            prominent temperance and prohibitionist figures like John B. Gough, Henry Ward Beecher,
            and John Pinchard Jowett, some of whom came to New Paltz to lecture, and others of whom
            Peter heard in New York.</p>
         <p>Peter Eltinge also had a strong prewar interest in politics which he retained throughout
            his military service and after the war. He felt opposed to Democrats of whatever
            persuasion at the state and local level, most notably Fernando Wood, mayor of New York
            City, but he was also bitterly opposed to the abolitionists, as he preferred the
            non-extension, non-interference positions with regard to slavery. He judged himself to
            be ''a conservative Union man," not a Republican as his father was. Peter watched the
            Presidential election campaign and secession crisis of 1860 with an interest relatively
            devoid of partisanship, although he voted for Lincoln. He attended a speech given by
            William H. Seward in New York City, November 2, 1860, in which Seward repeated
            sentiments similar to those of the earlier famous <emph render="doublequote"
               >irrepressible conflict</emph> address. During the war he watched northern friends
            serving as Treasury officials at New Orleans form a campaign committee for Michael
            Decker Hahn, a German émigré who became the Republican wartime governor of Louisiana.
            Edmund Eltinge continued to write to Peter about the shifts in New York State politics,
            especially the election of 1863 and the defeat of the Copperheads. The elder Eltinge
            also reported rumors of Lincoln's cabinet crisis in December, 1862, while Peter sent
            back rumors on the future assignment of the regiment. Among the other prominent
            political events and figures that appear in the Eltinge correspondence are the New York
            City elections of 1859, the presidential election of 1864, the Democratic convention at
            Charleston, South Carolina, in 1860, Abraham Lincoln, George B. McClellan, Horatio
            Seymour, and John C. Fremont.</p>
         <p>The conservative temper of Peter Eltinge's political beliefs resurfaced not long after
            the war, while he was serving on occupation duty in Lexington (Oglethorpe Co.), Georgia.
            He intervened on the side of the planters to quell discontent among newly freed Negro
            agricultural laborers, and he expressed himself opposed to extending the suffrage to
            blacks and was suspicious of the motives of Wendell Phillips for his advocacy of giving
            freedmen the vote. Peter at first thought that the political integration of Georgia
            under Presidential Reconstruction went rather well. During his stay there and in
            subsequent correspondence with people he had met there, he observed the revival of
            politics, the holding of new elections, a state constitutional convention, and even the
            observance of the Fourth of July in 1865. Apart from keeping law and order until civil
            authorities could reassume power, Eltinge's chief duty was the administration of oaths
            of allegiance to the inhabitants, most of whom took the oath readily. As 1865 ended,
            however, Peter felt that Georgia still had not met all qualifications for readmission to
            full statehood, and opinion for which a white Georgian correspondent excoriated him. As
            he had in the Civil War, Peter reported on the economic conditions prevailing in
            Georgia, especially the confusion in prices due to a lack of faith in Federal paper
            currency.</p>
         <p>Peter Eltinge's attitudes had changed only a little by the time he and George Lord went
            to Memphis the next year to establish their grocery business. He noted that there was a
            lot of bitterness in Tennessee over the management of Reconstruction by Congress, and he
            himself thought Congress was acting too harshly, but he reported voting a straight
            Radical ticket that fall. Race relations in Memphis were strained, and a race riot
            involving hundreds broke out May 1, 1866.</p>
         <p>Most of Peter's letters from Memphis dealt with economic matters. Eltinge and Lord were
            two of many northerners trying to make a quick gain in the recovering region. Business
            activity seemed to rise and fall quickly, and Peter complained to his father that the
            banks were too cautious in making loans to businesses. He wrote home often of their
            fortunes and prospects with the grocery, which did most of its business selling
            provisions to large plantations, but Eltinge was eager to invest in a more lucrative
            venture. He first considered wholesaling tobacco in the area before finally deciding to
            buy an interest in a cotton crop. A number of Union officers, including other former
            officers of the 156th New York Volunteers, had established themselves as labor
            contractors to cotton plantation owners in return for a share of the cotton crop. Peter,
            with the help of substantial loans from his father, took a fractional share of a cotton
            crop in Arkansas, but the venture turned out badly, as changing marketing patterns and
            bad weather drove down prices and held down both the quality and yield of the crop Peter
            had invested in. Eltinge had begun thinking of investing in cotton growing during the
            war and had discussed cotton prices in a letter written in Georgia. Once in Memphis, his
            letters became increasingly filled with discussions of cotton prices, growing, ginning,
            trading, and commission merchants in the area of Arkansas, Mississippi, and Tennessee,
            and of agricultural labor, both black and undesignated, in those states. Scattered
            topics dealing with Eltinge's activity in Memphis include descriptions of the city
            itself, and discussions of the tobacco trade in the area and the availability of fire
            insurance.</p>
         <p>Other items, unrelated to business, which came up during Eltinge's residence in Memphis
            include an explanation of barbecue cookery to his relatives, mention of a Fourth of July
            celebration held by Unionists living in town, and an old regimental comrade's report of
            the effect of the 1866 elections in Illinois.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_284f86f59fe4dbfd23c2cee0986d2849">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>Unlike Eltinge, George Lord saw a considerable amount of battle early in the war, only
            to spend most of the rest of the conflict in more sedentary duty. References in
            newspaper clippings to Lord and the ships he served on, the U.S.S. <emph render="italic"
               >Tyler</emph> and the U.S.S. <emph render="italic">Benton</emph>, give some glimpse
            of his involvement in the Belmont, Mo., Ft. Henry, and the New Madrid-Island No. 10
            campaigns. In the last of these, he led the boarding party which captured and saved from
            destruction the <emph render="italic">General Bragg</emph>. After having participated in
            some of the initial probing during the Vicksburg campaign (such as the Yazoo
            expedition), Lord's vessel, the <emph render="doublequote">tin-clad</emph> U.S.S. <emph
               render="italic">Covington</emph>, took part in a small expedition up the White River
            in Arkansas. During the White River expedition, Lord had his ship tow the burning <emph
               render="italic">Des Arc</emph>, a private cargo ship, away from the supply fleet.</p>
         <p>Lord became involved in the Red River campaign of 1864 after the fall in the water level
            of that stream temporarily stranded the ironclads of the Mississippi Squadron at
            Alexandria, Louisiana. The <emph render="italic">Covington</emph> and other light draft
            vessels were then ordered up the Red River in support. The <emph render="italic"
               >Covington</emph>, which along with the U.S.S. <emph render="italic">Signal</emph>,
            was convoying the <emph render="italic">John Warner</emph> when it was ambushed by
            artillery and infantry of the Confederate army. All three vessels were destroyed, and
            Lord's crew had to disperse to avoid capture. Lord himself made it to Alexandria, where
            on May 7 he was assigned as the executive officer of the ironclad U.S.S. <emph
               render="italic">Chillicothe</emph>, of which he became captain later in the month.
            The most graphic account of Lord's experiences on the Red River contained within the
            Lord Division itself may be found in a letter to his father-in-law of May 24, 1864
            (personal letter, copy). An equally graphic account may be found in one of Peter
            Eltinge's letters home, which is filed in the division devoted to his papers. Other
            valuable letters on this episode are those of Lord's wife, who had gone out to visit
            George shortly before he was ordered up the Red River and who waited anxiously for news
            after learning that the <emph render="italic">Covington</emph> had been sunk (personal
            letters, copies, May 9, 17, 19, 1864). Scattered routine letters relating to the loss of
            the <emph render="italic">Covington</emph> may also be found in various sections of the
            division (letters, personal letters, copies, records of the <emph render="italic"
               >Chillicothe</emph>, official correspondence).</p>
         <p>After the Red River campaign of 1864, Lord's ship rarely saw action. Ship's personnel
            occasionally went ashore to augment sorties by the army, such as at Woodville,
            Mississippi, in October, 1864 (records of the <emph render="italic">Chillicothe</emph>;
            official letters), or to carry out small landing actions or patrols. The <emph
               render="italic">Chillicothe</emph>, which suffered from the lack of a long-postponed
            overhaul, was stationed at Ft. Adams, Mississippi, with the primary missions of
            regulating trade, checking the operations of local Confederate regulars and guerrillas
            and preventing the passage of troops and supplies over the Mississippi to the army
            opposing Sherman in Georgia. The printed material among the Lord papers includes an
            announcement of the capture of Ft. Gaines during the combined army-navy campaign at
            Mobile Bay in August, 1864, the only other significant campaign mentioned.</p>
         <p>Lord put in claims for prize money for his role in the salvaging of the <emph
               render="italic">Des Arc</emph> and the capture of the <emph render="italic">General
               Bragg</emph>, claims which continued to generate correspondence even after his death
            (personal letters, copies; records of the <emph render="italic">Chillicothe</emph>,
            official correspondence). Among the more notable participants in that exchange were
            Admiral Charles H. Davis and S. J. W. Tabor, the Fourth Auditor of the Treasury.</p>
         <p>Apart from active operations and prize money, Lord's papers are rich in material on
            various and detailed aspects of American naval life and science in the period of the
            Civil War. This is primarily due to the fairly comprehensive nature of the collection of
            the U.S.S. <emph render="italic">Chillicothe's</emph> records, with additional material
            coming from the miscellaneous papers associated with that same ship, the smaller
            collections from the <emph render="italic">Osage</emph> and <emph render="italic"
               >Ozark</emph>, and Lord's personal correspondence. The distinctly naval topics raised
            include some details of ship life, training requirements for the crew, <emph
               render="doublequote">watch bills</emph> - or lists assigning men to combat stations
            and duties in case of fire -, orders for the pattern of signals to identify transports,
            intelligence reports exchanged with other army and naval units on Confederate army and
            guerrilla activity, precautions to be taken against submarine mines (then known as
            torpedoes), lists of the various firearms available to the ship's crew (and instructions
            on the use of the Sharps rifle), regular reports by the <emph render="italic"
               >Chillicothe's</emph> chief gunner on the condition and supply of munitions and
            ammunition, and a letter from a fellow officer serving on blockade duty on the Atlantic
            coast Complete and partial lists of vessels in the Mississippi Squadron can be found in
            printed materials and among copies of personal letters. While the Lord material
            necessarily deals with gunboats and ironclads on a continuing basis, specific references
            to vessels which can be placed in either category have been so cataloged. Note should
            also be made of Lord's postwar duty of directing the demobilization of the <emph
               render="doublequote">Ironclad Fleet in Ordinary</emph> at Mound City, Illinois.</p>
         <p>The naval material also covers such logistical topics as food, provisioning, ordnance
            and ordnance stores, fuel (primarily coal), and the transportation of supplies and
            stores. Many of these are represented in departmental reports of supplies on hand or in
            correspondence and commercial papers exchanged with naval depots and private
            contractors. Some of the responsible officers who filed related reports include the
            engineer, who kept records on the condition of the power plant (records of the <emph
               render="italic">Chillicothe</emph>, official letters, engineer's monthly returns;
            records of the <emph render="italic">Ozark</emph>), the yeoman, who was responsible for
            filing miscellaneous reports on personnel and supply matters (records of the <emph
               render="italic">Chillicothe</emph>, yeoman's reports), and the carpenter, who was in
            charge of the maintenance of the wooden structure of the ship and insuring that adequate
            repair materials were kept in stock.</p>
         <p>A number of other topics deal with personnel management, including recruiting,
            promotions, leaves and furloughs, pay and allowances, and discharges. The question of
            discharges became a delicate one as the war came to an end and the navy demobilized at a
            somewhat slower pace than the army. The maintenance of discipline and morale became
            difficult at the unpleasant station of Mound City, where desertion grew more frequent.
            The records of several courts-martial can be found among the official letters and
            miscellany of the records of the <emph render="italic">Chillicothe</emph>, and there are
            references to alcoholism and disciplinary problems in other categories of the Lord
            Division, most notably in the <emph render="italic">Chillicothe's</emph> Master at Arms
            reports of the members of crew under punishment. A printed circular promulgated by
            Admiral David Dixon Porter shortly after he assumed command of the Mississippi Squadron
            directly addressed the problem of morale. Two of the topics Porter discussed in that
            circular included naval hospitals and health conditions, both of which he promised to
            improve for the sake of morale and to keep the men fit for duty. Climate and crowded
            conditions made service on the lower Mississippi and at Mound City relatively unhealthy,
            as may be seen in the surgeon's reports (for medical and sanitary affairs) and in Lord's
            own personal letters (copies: for health conditions). <emph render="doublequote"
               >Fever</emph> was the most common complaint, although dysentery was occasionally a
            problem. One of the <emph render="italic">Chillicothe's</emph> officers applied to
            Secretary of the Navy Gideon Welles for permission to resign due to chronic illness, a
            request Lord duly approved and forwarded.</p>
         <p>Among the more important naval figures whose letters recur in the Lord papers are
            Admiral Porter, Admiral Samuel Phillip Lee, Porter's successor in command of the
            Mississippi Squadron, and Lieutenant Commander E. Y. McCauley, one of Lord's immediate
            superiors in the squadron who later became an admiral.</p>
         <p>Riverine operations and the regulation of trade brought Lord and the Mississippi
            Squadron into frequent contact with governmental and military agencies, both friendly
            and hostile, which line officers of the navy seldom had to deal with otherwise. Since
            the army had initially organized the Mississippi Squadron, and the squadron, even after
            its transfer to the navy, obtained still more men from the army when the government
            permitted experienced seamen and rivermen to transfer services, there are some items
            among Lord's papers which reflect on matters of personnel management in the army. The
            navy, particularly during operations such as Banks' Red River expeditions, assumed most
            of the burden of transporting the army's supplies and stores. In one instance, the navy
            transported cotton bales for the construction of field fortifications. A shore party
            manning an artillery battery during an operation near Woodville, Mississippi, in
            October, 1864, ran into some difficulty and ultimately surrendered to Confederate forces
            when the 3d U.S. Colored Cavalry unexpectedly fired on the sailors. Official letters of
            the <emph render="italic">Chillicothe</emph> include a couple of complaints by Southern
            civilians about confiscation of property by the Union army.</p>
         <p>The Mississippi Squadron worked closely with the army to contain regular and irregular
            forces of Confederates, and it worked with the army and the Treasury Department to
            insure that commerce, particularly cotton trade, was conducted in a manner which did not
            unduly aid the Confederate war effort. The official correspondence of the <emph
               render="italic">Chillicothe</emph> reflects the exchange of military intelligence
            between the two services on guerrilla activity. Such reports included one on a team of
            saboteurs operating against the ships and warehouses along the river (printed material).
            The <emph render="italic">Chillicothe</emph> papers contain some copies of captured
            Confederate documents which relate primarily to the Department (or District) of Southern
            Mississippi and Eastern Louisiana, also referred to as the District of Homochitto (after
            a local river) and <emph render="doublequote">Scott's Command,</emph> (after Col. John
            S. Scott, who headed that jurisdiction in 1864). Orders from that headquarters bearing
            the name of C.S.A. General George B. Hodge, one filed among the <emph render="italic"
               >Chillicothe's</emph> official correspondence and another among that ship's orders,
            indicate what the Confederate regulations were on commerce passing through Union lines.
            Two other items, filed separately as <emph render="doublequote">Confederate Papers,
               1862-1863,</emph> included an enlistment contract which promised a furlough to
            members of the 9th South Carolina Volunteers and a letter from a member of the Texas
            Legion at Vicksburg describing bombardments and health conditions while the city was
            under sedge. Two of Lord's personal letters to his in-laws describe how rapidly the flow
            of Confederate deserters into Union lines grew in the last month of the war. A single
            official letter deals with the attempt of a Southerner to send a letter through a Union
            naval officer to a Confederate soldier held as a prisoner in the north.</p>
         <p>Both the navy and the army in the Mississippi Valley found themselves in the role of
            regulator of trade during the last half of the war. The Union government, particularly
            the Treasury Department, changed policies and procedures often and put military
            officials, who sought both to enforce regulations and end the war as quickly as
            possible, in a difficult position with Southern civilians. A clipping from a Memphis
            newspaper noted that Union General N.P. Buford had 40 cotton traders arrested, although
            they had apparently acted in conformity with recently published regulations. Military
            authorities supervised the conduct of cotton sales and the transportation and
            importation of finished goods entering the interior. As changes in regulation occurred,
            the notifications of the changes sometimes arrived accompanied by explanations provided
            by the Treasury Department.</p>
         <p>The <emph render="italic">Chillicothe's</emph> official letters include a long circular
            on the cotton trade with endorsements by Secretary William Fessenden and President
            Lincoln, among others. Other, angry letters from army and navy commanders periodically
            urged stricter suppression of black market trade in cotton. The official letters and
            commercial papers include numerous applications and certificates for permission to buy,
            sell, or transport cotton and finished goods. The logbook of orders in the Lord Division
            actually contains as many entries about the shipment of cotton and supplies as it does
            about the receipt of orders. One series of official letters (and depositions filed with
            the official letters) deals with a British subject, B.H. Clark, who swindled sellers of
            cotton and was brought to trial.</p>
         <p>Lord's remaining time while stationed on the lower Mississippi was also spent taking
            renewals of the oath of allegiance of residents of the South, some of whom affirmed that
            they had never aided the rebel cause, although most takers of the oath admitted having
            supported the Confederate government in some way. Lord noted the enthusiasm with which
            the people in the Mississippi River Valley greeted the generous terms of Lincoln's
            amnesty proclamation of December 8, 1863.</p>
         <p>In contrast to his brother-in-law, George Lord revealed no strong interest in politics
            in his letters. The election of 1864 intrudes into his papers only when a political
            argument among some of his men led to a breach of discipline requiring Lord's attention.
            A correspondent from Illinois in 1865 mentioned that opposition to Negro suffrage had
            affected politics in that state (letters). Lincoln's name rarely appears. Exceptions
            include official and unofficial printed circulars dealing with his assassination.
            Similarly, Jefferson Davis surfaces for serious attention only in orders concerned with
            his capture at the end of the war.</p>
         <p>Lord appeared to be equally as taciturn on the subject of his own feelings about blacks
            as he was on politics. Some of his official correspondence acknowledged the help that
            local <emph render="doublequote">contrabands</emph> had offered in the gathering of
            intelligence. Otherwise, his main concern about <emph render="doublequote"
               >contrabands</emph> was that he followed proper procedures in accepting them into
            Union control and in reporting them to higher headquarters. He demonstrated a somewhat
            greater, if still dispassionate, interest in the operational details of Negro
            agricultural labor in the Union-controlled areas of Mississippi and Arkansas. He noted
            that by 1864 local planters had shifted over to paying blacks a low, fixed monthly wage,
            and that they claimed using the cheap freed labor to be less burdensome that the
            responsibilities of slaveholding. Lord's few other comments on the economics of wartime
            cotton production include a report that some planters had begun to lease their land
            rather than work it themselves (personal letters, copies). Lord's wife, Mary, during her
            stay at Memphis while George was on the Red River expedition, visited and briefly
            described a camp of contrabands named <emph render="doublequote">Prichettsville</emph>
            in a letter to her parents (personal letters, copies).</p>
         <p>George Lord's few letters from Memphis (personal letters, copies) offer a somewhat
            different picture of prospects there than can be found in Peter Eltinge's letters. Lord
            was more cautious than his brother-in-law, whom he thought tended to be too trusting and
            optimistic when entering into business deals. Lord did not join Peter in speculating in
            cotton crops, although he had been more receptive to the proposal to wholesale tobacco.
            He offered a few observations on business trends and opportunities in Memphis, but he
            wanted to refrain from aggressive investment or speculation until the prize money he
            anticipated to receive would give him ready capital.</p>
         <p>Obituaries of George Lord may be found in newspapers filed in the oversize folder in
            Picture Cabinet II. One of the papers, the Republican Memphis Daily Post of August 17,
            1866, also contains articles on the Republican Party convention of 1866 held in
            Philadelphia and on a convention of blacks held in Nashville, Tennessee, where the
            participants primarily discussed ways of providing freedmen with an education.</p>
         <p>Among the most interesting Items in the Lord Division is a collection of photographs.
            Most are of ships of the Mississippi Squadron on which Lord served or which formed part
            of the force which went up the Red River in 1864. Most of the photographs are sepia in
            color and appear as paper prints, although there are a few modern transparencies of
            ships pictured elsewhere in this and other collections. The ships represented include
            the U.S.S. <emph render="italic">Benton</emph>, <emph render="italic">Blackhawk</emph>,
               <emph render="italic">Chillicothe</emph>, <emph render="italic">Covington</emph>,
            Mound City, Neosho, Ouachita, Queen City, and Tyler. There is a picture of a large
            portion of the Mississippi Squadron on the Red River expedition of 1864 and another of
            the C.S.S. Tennessee. One transparency, taken from a lithograph not contained in this
            collection, is of the naval battle of Hampton Roads between the U.S.S. <emph
               render="italic">Monitor</emph> and the <emph render="italic">Merrimac</emph> (C.S.S.
               <emph render="italic">Virginia</emph>). Important naval personages portrayed include
            Rear Admiral David Dixon Porter and Lt. Cmdr. (later Admiral) James Augustus Greer, the
            commander of the <emph render="italic">Benton</emph>. There are also some modern copies
            of a portrait photograph of George Lord in a naval uniform, three 8 x 10 in. prints and
            one 4 x 5 in. negative.</p>
         <p>Among the other senior officers Lord forwarded letters or reports to were Mai, Gen.
            Edward R. S. Canby, Banks' successor as commander of the Department of the Gulf, and
            Brig. Gen. John W. Davidson, then commanding the District of Natchez.</p>
         <p>While Eltinge and Lord were in military service, the Eltinge family kept them informed
            about activities at home. Several of Peter's sisters became involved in various charity
            fairs in the New York City area which were held to raise money for the United States
            Sanitary Commission (Eltinge division, scrapbook, letters). Similar activities were
            instituted in Boston, where another organization sought to raise money for a sailors'
            home (Lord division, printed material).</p>
         <p>Peter's sisters led a fairly active life during the war. At one time or another, he had
            sisters residing in New York City, Camden, Delaware, and Washington, D.C., while Edmund
            Eltinge occasionally stopped in to see his daughters in Washington and New York. As a
            result, Peter received descriptions of war-time Washington, as well as reports of the
            burning of Ford's Theater in December, 1862, an exhibit of the expeditionary clothing
            worn by the arctic explorer Elisha Kent Kane and lectures at the Smithsonian
            Institution, and visits to art exhibitions, including one by landscape artist Francis
            Regis Gignoux, at art galleries in New York City.</p>
         <p>Peter's father occasionally gave him some indication of how the economy back home fared
            during the war - what were the prospects for the crops on the family farm, about Edmund
            Eltinge's own involvement in getting the Wallkill River Valley Railroad - a spur line
            off the Erie Railroad - pushed through the New Paltz area (letters, scrapbook), what
            local wages were, what interest rates were available, and what the price of various
            securities and commodities were like. Other incidental information relative to economic
            conditions in the North may be gleaned from articles which form part of the newspaper
            clippings found in the Lord Division. Information found there includes exchange market
            quotations on precious metals and commodities. Extraneous pieces of correspondence in
            1865-1866 mention the venture of one of Peter's friends, A, H. Gough, in the oil
            industry of Pennsylvania and Ohio.</p>
         <p>Other interesting bits of information sent to rather than from New Paltz include Peter's
            commentary on the notoriety surrounding the celebrated <emph render="doublequote"
               >Diamond Wedding</emph> of Estaban de Oviedo and Frances Bartlett in New York City in
            1859, and Mary Lord's anecdote as to how her hosts in Memphis in 1864 had made a special
            effort to show her one of the few Steinway pianos then in that area,</p>
         <p>Disease recurs as a topic in both divisions, Although the Lord Division contains the
               <emph render="italic">Chillicothe's</emph> surgeon's file, most of the descriptions
            of the illnesses on board that ship were fairly general, Peter Eltinge's wartime letters
            contain more specific references to the incidence of diphtheria, yellow fever, and
            tuberculosis, and the scrapbook in that division mentions instances of the latter two
            diseases, George Lord once wrote to his father-in-law about an outbreak of smallpox in
            Baltimore in February, 1864, and expressed concern about his family in Delaware,
            Although Peter Eltinge noted several waves of cholera as they passed through Memphis in
            1866, and George Lord experienced at least one bout of some sort of fever prior to his
            death, his obituary listed only <emph render="doublequote">congestion of the
               stomach</emph> as the cause. Peter himself died of tuberculosis, as did several other
            members of his family (scrapbook).</p>
         <p>Among the various items to be found in the clippings in the scrapbook in the Eltinge
            Division are articles written by Civil War humorist Artemus Ward (Charles Farrar
            Browne), an account of winemaking and grape cultivation in Nets Jersey, a history and
            genealogy of the Eltinge family and its settlement in New Paltz, a commentary by Charles
            J. Ackert that wartime New Orleans tended to treat the Sabbath as just another day for
            activity and enterprise, and a portrait (wood engraving) of Winfield Scott. Newspapers
            found in the Oversize Folder, in addition to those already mentioned, include copies of
            the <title type="simple" render="italic">New Paltz Times</title> and <title
               type="simple" render="italic">The Southern Ulster Times.</title>
         </p>
         <p>There are a number of scattered items in the Lord Division connected with the Civil War.
            They include an order limiting the correspondence of naval personnel with members of the
            press (records of the Chillocothe, orders), letters announcing the formation of a
            veterans' organization known as the Mississippi Squadron Association (personal letter),
            a piece of stationery bearing the Confederate flag (Confederate papers), and a critical
            evaluation of General Banks by Mary Lord after George had been ordered up the Red River
            (personal letters, copies).</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Chillicothe (Ship)</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 --
            Campaigns</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Southern States -- Race relations</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States. Army -- African American troops</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Ozark (Ship)</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Mississippi River</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Osage (Ship)</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Georgia -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Merchants -- Tennessee -- Memphis</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Cotton -- Marketing</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Naval
            operations</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Freedmen -- Southern States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Red River Expedition, 1864</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Reconstruction</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Soldiers -- United States -- Correspondence</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Southern States -- Economic conditions</geogname>
         <corpname source="ingest">United States. Army. New York Infantry Regiment, 156th
            (1862-1865)</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">United States. Army. Dept. of the Gulf</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">United States. Navy. Mississippi Squadron</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">United States. Navy -- Officers -- Correspondence</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Eltinge, Peter, ca. 1842-1877</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Eltinge, Peter, ca. 1842-1877</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">United States. Army -- Officers -- Correspondence</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Lord, George P., ca. 1842-1866</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref13_vap" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Eltinge Division</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_xsd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1856-1864 August 29</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_cc64037fe409f9866532f8ef29cb504c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_83i" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1864 Sept. 2-1871</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3cd98646c01320b69477a4d4ca6073bb" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_sqi" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence (typescripts), 1856-1871</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_da7ef373a10002736ebcdcd12c3d0b2f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_pi0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence (typescripts), 1864-1865</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_288e9e27fa3f5fe405b49d67922a7881" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_o2p" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence (typescripts), 1865-1871</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_97a18775107219d56704b20433875b75" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_t9k" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Scrapbook (xerographic reproduction)</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_71c7e8b6fb446bc759d125b414f97330" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_5ch" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Legal Papers, 1864-1865 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_922c174f51a40a558794ccc2395b1a4b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_x44" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellany, 1865-1866 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_aaee99cb58d73c3a359c9fd57f1d92ce" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_qlt" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Clippings, 1863-1864</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1aad01a85e7118cb7c064f7ee71af2f5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_t43" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photograph</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f91651992337accb11105e6ed8eb0bf7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref24_y3a" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Lord Division</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_1pn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Personal Letters, 1862-1867 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_73fba536aa946b60e06d511b759721c6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_261" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Personal Letters (copies), 1862-1868 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_35c78e36e956882d02914dc1bad85031" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_j9j" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Records of the U.S.S. <emph render="italic">Chillicothe</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref28_r31" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Official Correspondence, 1863-1864</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_8e5b573baa43e26d94173e18c3cd41d4" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">8</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref29_2ze" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Official Correspondence, 1865-1867 and undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_afa799420644dd50c4a11429942b52ac" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">9</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref30_7vi" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Reports of the Master at Arms, 1863-1865</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_14a9c02b6aa586791dd161cbc01e3404" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">10</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref31_elq" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Yeoman's Reports, 1863-1865</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_9bc76d3b8da3f6d47f5083298ff47a71" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">10</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref32_b7d" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Surgeon's Reports, 1863- 1865</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_61c60e5557b98364035e40f0050b2413" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">11</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref33_65z" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Daily Coal Reports, 1864-1865</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_d14782887c5fddac41e8162efd2645cb" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">12</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref34_kch" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Engineer's Monthly Returns, 1864</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_be1e42324d87ea69c5761d62d704e778" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">12</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref35_sbn" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Gunner's Monthly Reports, 1863-1865</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_3f5666b82af253d0b963ca2d29f33633" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">12</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref36_7xg" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Carpenter's Reports, 1863-1865</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_05a0dab36999f24566a54f74d9c75d0f" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">12</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref37_gjq" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Ordnance Reports, 1863-1865</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_3aef288934b33bf36b909d4f8db727e2" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">12</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref38_tov" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Statements that boxes brought aboard the <emph render="italic"
                           >Chillicothe</emph> contained no spirituous liquors,
                        1863-1865</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_973551234e5dd16b4d65ba6ddfbc3cbc" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">12</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref39_axx" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Orders, 1863-1865 and undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_331f9fb4f1d7ae361e77ada23607415f" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">13</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref40_gvg" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Commercial Papers, 1863-1865 and undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_60fabc0498fed51ef9f0a11e9b87dd5d" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">13</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref41_275" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellany, 1863-1865 and undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_e2ed80512562344c757c9a20dec07a40" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">13</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref42_ivl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Records of the U.S.S. <emph render="italic">Ozark</emph> ,
                     1864-1865</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6bb5fc011b6bce259ff35e7fe2e046e1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_svo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Records of the U.S.S. <emph render="italic">Osage</emph> , 1863 and
                     undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4a4404eb91a879ab2e36dd4e9600eba5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref44_78m" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Oaths of Allegiance, 1864-1865</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_71e723e161818e82606453375b5f45b7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref45_y8b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed Material, 1863-1865</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0678c74ba4ee93d79f85a33f9426c6dd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref46_ss8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume: Logbook of Orders and Cotton Shipments, 1864</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4edbbe0d770ac7fa10ce950bb8e0337e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_ywh" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellany, 1864-1865 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f259935e1f30c4a6eb909132b868bbfd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref48_yie" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Confederate Papers, 1862-1865</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4a3a60cf115d59ba9f774101187fb3a9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref49_3ia" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Clippings, 1861-1862 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d6decf9a11396c09c5d99c3bb83b2d65" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref50_d4m" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Pictures</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fc5ba0106bce06b408b7a5634102e91b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref51_925" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Oversize Materials, 1864-1866</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref52_0hj" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">Memphis Daily Post</title>, 1866 August 17</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_82d4ac5b98594eb306b0d9c08019a08e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-folder">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref53_4ur" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">The New Paltz Times</title>, 1864 June 3</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0ea8fe22d640975c006c97b52ce87451" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-folder">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref54_s21" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">The New Paltz Times</title>, 1866 August 31</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2324c795cac15e9ef2e90785c3b633e3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-folder">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref55_v9y" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">The Southern Illustrated Times</title>, 1865 November
                     24</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e835f63b8cf4821cff09921bac12d995" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-folder">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
