<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="https://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/fairbank/">fairbank</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Fairbank Family Papers, 1837-1971
          <num>RL.00378</num></titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: Denise Dolan and Janie C. Morris; machine-readable finding aid created
          by: Stephen Douglas Miller</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>1991</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">001020702</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-06-10 17:53:04
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2014</date>
        <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported to
          Archivists Toolkit</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Fairbank Family papers</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <famname source="ingest">Fairbank family</famname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.00378</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.8 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1837/1971" type="inclusive">1837-1971</unitdate>
      <physloc id="aspace_a222c59ab057b2a5b195d7b6d062bf69">For current information on the location
        of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
      <physdesc id="aspace_6b90d1b7fa4cb027982c80d10e78530d"
        label="General Physical Description note"><extent>circa 3,600 Items</extent></physdesc>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_51dbeed8983035b976188c9e479da9c3">English.</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_17251e5b6d2004d4358999ecbcdae925">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_cdacdd302bb2703ed0ee0f0bc63b758c">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in the Fairbank Family papers have not been transferred to Duke
        University.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_1d8285a39adf9190ff809e8b2c135bab">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Fairbank Family papers (1837-1974) were donated to the Rubenstein Library in 1983, 1985
        and l986 by members of the Fairbank family.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo id="aspace_7ac86be72f26c9f6657e87d27c498221">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by: Denise Dolan and Janie C. Morris</p>
      <p>Completed June 24, 1991</p>
      <p>Encoded by Stephen Douglas Miller</p>
    </processinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_c7d6477102007688798753ed986cec10">
      <head>Biographical Note</head>
      <p>This collection encompasses three generations of the Fairbanks, a Protestant family that
        had roots in New England and later relocated to Illinois. There was an extensive network of
        family members and associates, bound together by their Christian ideals and way of life.
        Many of the Fairbanks married other missionaries from families such as the Woods, Moultons,
        Humes, Beals and Hardings. A number of Fairbank relatives remained in and around
        Jacksonville, Illinois while others went to Massachusetts for their education or traveled to
        India to carry out years of missionary service.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="aspace_713476567318f9ed93cbca04e17d7929">
      <head>Samuel Bacon Fairbank</head>
      <p>Samuel Bacon Fairbank, the first family member to travel to India, was born on December 14,
        1822 in Stamford, Connecticut. After spending his boyhood years in New England, he was
        educated at Illinois College, where he received a B.A. in 1842, an M.A. in 1845 and a D.D.
        in 1897. He attended Andover Seminary in 1845. On March 26, 1846, he married Abbie Allen,
        and traveled with her to India that same year, under the auspices of the American Board of
        Commissioners for Foreign Missions (A.B.C.F.M.). He lived primarily in the Vadala District,
        carrying out his work as a missionary among the rural Indians who lived in villages
        throughout the region. Samuel married his second wife, Mary Ballantine on July 11, 1856,
        following the death of Abbie Allen in 1852. With Mary he had ten of his fourteen children,
        and remained in India for over 50 years of almost continuous service until his death on May
        31, 1898.</p>
      <p>Many of Samuel's children followed their parents' precedent and also entered into
        missionary service. They include Emily, Katie, Henry, Edward, and Rose. Emily Maria Fairbank
        was born November 24, 1846 in Ahmednagar, India. She married Thomas Snell Smith in 1871. The
        two spent many years working in the Jaffna District of Ceylon, another A.B.C.F.M. mission.
      </p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="aspace_0ab4aeca7c8d86f22a37abca7b268c22">
      <head>Katie Fairbank</head>
      <p>Katie Fairbank was born in Ahmednagar on May 8, 1859. She attended Mount Holyoke Seminary,
        and graduated from Bradford Academy in 1879. She went to India in 1882 and married Dr.
        Robert Hume of the Wai District on September 7, l887. Katie spent many years working in that
        district, and remained after her husband returned to the United States to die. At the age of
        70, she was appointed to serve yet another missionary term. She died on April 14, 1932.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="aspace_b7a3803896fe0063fd5b53d43972faaf">
      <head>Henry Fairbank</head>
      <p>Henry Fairbank was born in Vadala, India on June 30, 1862. At the age of thirteen, he was
        sent to Massachusetts to begin his formal education. He graduated from Amherst College in
        1883 and Yale Divinity School in 1886. He returned that same year to India as a missionary
        and married Ruby Harding on September 16, l886. With her he had three children, Samuel, Alan
        and Ruth, all of whom were educated in the United States and remained there to live and
        work. He remained in India's Vadala District from 1886-1898, then took a furlough in America
        until 1899. Upon his return, he was given charge of a large high school and an industrial
        school in the Ahmednagar District. His first wife died in 1906. In 1908 he married another
        missionary, Mary Etta Moulton, who was often called "Momo." In 1916, Henry was appointed
        principal of the Union Theological Seminary in Ahmednagar, a post he held until his death.
        He was awarded an Honorary D.D. from Yale in 1923. He died on September 19, 1926. Mary died
        on July 28, 1933.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="aspace_a2a7fe7291f6baf38ca5e103de593c86">
      <head>Edward Fairbank</head>
      <p>Edward Fairbank, born June 5, 1867 in Kodaikanal, India and educated at Amherst College and
        Andover Theological Seminary in Massachusetts, spent most of his missionary career stationed
        in the Vadala District. He married Mary Adelaide Caskey, who had attended Mount Holyoke
        College, on June 14, 1893. Edward died on July 9, 1963. Edward and Mary had a son, Robert
        Fairbank. Robert graduated from Amherst College in 1920 and returned to India that same year
        to teach in the Vadala District. He graduated from the Hartford Theological Seminary in
        1926, and returned to Vadala with his wife, Marie Lively, as a full missionary. In 1938, the
        James Friendship Memorial Hospital was opened there under his leadership.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="aspace_630416159af036c44e970e135aa5753d">
      <head>Rose Fairbank</head>
      <p>Rose Fairbank, born August 1, 1874 in Ahmednagar, graduated from Smith College in 1885. She
        was trained as a doctor at Johns Hopkins University and received her medical degree in 1900.
        She served as head of the Union Mission Hospital in India until 1905, when she married Dr.
        Lester Beals. Together they built the Willis F. Pierce Memorial Hospital in Wai, near
        Bombay, which they managed until their retirement in 1941. The Beals then returned to the
        United States and eventually settled in California. Rose died on March 24, 1955, leaving
        behind three children, Albert, Annette, and Charlotte.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="aspace_318f770db05cd0cc5bd2f1318ab2ba2f">
      <head>Other children</head>
      <p>Other children of Samuel Bacon Fairbank who worked in India, but whose letters do not
        appear as frequently in the collection, are Mary Crocker Fairbank and Mary Darling
        Fairbank.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_60bcbbec1fe73fc2cb3649ef46a7808a">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>The Fairbank Family Papers consist almost exclusively of correspondence written between
        members of the Fairbank family and their religious associates. The letters, carried by
        steamer between India, America and other parts of the world, span the years 1837-1971, with
        the bulk occurring between 1905 and 1940. Earlier letters were sent by Samuel Bacon, Katie,
        and Emily Fairbank and Thomas Snell Smith to Samuel's brother and other relatives in the
        United States. </p>
      <p>This collection is useful in providing a comprehensive view of the religious, educational,
        bureaucratic and financial aspects of mission work in an underdeveloped country. Since this
        is documented by letters written by the missionaries themselves, it provides personal
        insights into their daily life and work. The lives of women missionaries in particular are
        well-documented, since many of the correspondents were female. Despite the fact that the
        Fairbanks worked in India during a period of British occupation, involvement of the British
        government in mission activity is rarely noted in the correspondence. </p>
      <p>A number of themes run consistently through all the correspondence. There is a great deal
        of family news, including accounts of trips ranging from ocean voyages to family visits and
        vacations in India and America. Births, deaths, weddings and illnesses are chronicled in
        detail. Letters also include descriptions of church and school activities, work-related
        trips, meetings, conferences, and visits by religious and government officials and
        missionaries from other parts of the world. There is occasional discussion of contemporary
        world events, such as World War I, the Great Depression, and the rise of Gandhi in India.
        Yearly letters from a missionary friend in Foochow, China relate the turbulent events and
        political climate there between 1911-1931 in detail, including the Foochow rebellion of
        1911. Observations and anecdotes about the Indian people, their religion, food and way of
        life; discussion of the political and economical climate in India; and descriptions of the
        physical environment and climate are woven throughout, although they rarely dominate any one
        letter. Many letters were written in a round-robin format and passed through the hands of
        different family members. Most of the correspondence is one-sided, generated in India and
        sent to the United States.</p>
      <p>According to background material found in the Printed material series, the Fairbanks worked
        as agents of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions (A.B.C.F.M.), a
        religious organization that was later known as the United Church Board for World Ministries,
        and had its home offices in Massachusetts. The A.B.C.F.M. established a network of boarding
        schools, trade schools, hospitals and churches at its mission sites. Schools and hospitals
        were divided by gender into male and female units. The mission's major goals were to:
        increase the literacy of the Indian people, educate women, establish good health care
        practices, improve agricultural productivity, develop industry, raise the standard of living
        of the lower classes, and, ultimately, to train Indians to be their own Christian leaders in
        all of these areas. Involvement of Fairbank family members in all of these activities is
        documented in the Correspondence and Beals Family series. The American Marathi Mission,
        where most of the Fairbanks worked, was located in West Central India in an area which
        included Bombay, and eventually covered 80 villages within 500 square miles.</p>
      <p>Most of the letters fall into two generational groupings: those of Samuel Bacon Fairbank
        and those of his children. These are contained in both the Correspondence and Beals Family
        series.</p>
      <p>Samuel's letters, 1837-1898, were sent regularly to America. They include detailed accounts
        of his agricultural and teaching projects in and around Vadala, as well as descriptions of
        the Indian environment. He conducted experiments with agricultural methods and farm
        machinery to increase the productivity of the land and people, who were subject to frequent
        droughts and famine. He started a boarding school in Vadala and a higher school in
        Ahmednagar. He also taught the singing of hymns in Marathi, the dialect of India spoken in
        that region.</p>
      <p>There are quite a few letters from Samuel's daughters, Katie and Emily, and his son-in-law,
        Thomas Snell Smith. They describe their activities as missionaries to friends and relatives
        in America. Katie, who left a teaching career in the United States, taught rug-weaving and
        lace making at a girls' school in Ahmednagar. Later, stationed at Wai, she gave religious
        counsel and led Bible readings for patients in the women's hospital. Emily ran a girls'
        boarding school in Ceylon, while Thomas helped administer the school system throughout the
        district, attending to a variety of religious, financial and educational duties.</p>
      <p>Letters from Samuel's son, Henry Fairbank and Henry's wife, Mary ("Momo"), written from
        Ahmednagar, comprise the majority of correspondence during the period 1905-1926. They
        describe his work while serving as chairman of the Ahmednagar mission and pastor of the
        church, and in various other capacities for famine relief and religious leadership as
        needed. The first portion consists mainly of weekly letters sent to their children while
        attending school in America. Later letters are addressed collectively to other relatives in
        Illinois and Massachusetts. After Henry's death, Mary assumed the role of chief
        correspondent from Ahmednagar. She eventually became the head of the village schools and
        their teachers in the Ahmednagar District, but her letters focus more on family news than on
        meetings and professional activities.</p>
      <p>From about 1926 until 1940, the majority of letters are round-robin notes from Edward
        Fairbank and his wife, Mary, in Vadala to relatives and friends in America. Much of the time
        he was away from home, touring in the villages of his district. He paid frequent visits to
        the Indian and American teachers and pastors who worked in the mission, hearing reports and
        offering consultation and guidance for the administration of churches and schools. He also
        had charge of a language school in Mahableshwar, where Americans were trained in the Marathi
        dialect. Mary was involved in orphan care and famine relief, as well as various religious
        and educational interests. She began a lace-making industry in Vadala for girls. These
        letters are written mostly by Edward. Letters from their son, Robert, who assisted Edward in
        these duties, become frequent in the late 1920s. There is very little correspondence after
        1940.</p>
      <p>The Beals Family series consists of accounts of mission work done by Rose and Lester in the
        hospital at Wai. There are also quite a few printed newsletters sent to patrons in America
        which include accounts of hospital activity and Indian life and culture. Rose had charge of
        health care for women and children at the hospital. </p>
      <p>Scattered throughout the Correspondence series are handwritten letters from other family
        members and friends living in both India and America, mostly containing family news. Letters
        printed for distribution among patrons in America containing descriptions of mission
        activities and the development of new facilities can be found at regular intervals. </p>
      <p>Related manuscript collections in the Rubenstein Library are the papers of E.Loleta Wood
        and the papers of Joseph L. Moulton, both of whom worked in the Ahmednagar District.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Missionaries -- India -- Pictorial works</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women missionaries -- India</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Foochow (China) -- Politics and government</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Missionaries -- India -- Vadala (District)</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Depressions -- 1929</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Missionaries, Medical -- India -- Wai (District)</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Missions -- India -- Agricultural work</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Missions -- India -- Educational work</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">India -- Economic conditions</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Missionaries -- India -- Ahmednagar (District)</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Missionaries -- Sri Lanka</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">India -- Social life and customs</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">India -- Description and travel</geogname>
      <persname source="ingest">Fairbank, Henry, 1862-1926</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Fairbank, Edward, 1867-1963</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Beals, Rose Fairbank, 1874-1955</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Beals, Lester</persname>
      <corpname source="ingest">American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">United Church Board for World Ministries</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Willis F. Pierce Memorial Hospital (India: Wai District)</corpname>
      <persname source="ingest">Smith, Emily Maria Fairbank, b. 1846</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Smith, Thomas Snell</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Gandhi, Mahatma, 1869-1948</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Hume, Katie Fairbank, 1859-1932</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Fairbank, Robert</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Fairbank, Samuel Bacon, 1822-1898</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Fairbank, Mary Caskey</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Fairbank, Mary Etta Moulton, d. 1933</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref16_pm0" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>DIARY SERIES</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref17_wfu" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Henry Fairbanks diary, 1894-1902</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_46420826bec7776d3427e9597d3dab64" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref18_g04" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>CORRESPONDENCE SERIES</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref19_3ou" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Transcripts and lists of letters, 1871-1897</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_c587148717690644354c313e270db483" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref20_xzy" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1837, Sept.-1883</unittitle>
            <physdesc id="aspace_c7e461d71aad17d23dc5c08512aa262d"
              label="General Physical Description note"><extent>5 folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_a4a995a72dee19496e691fca603fa023" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref22_dpr" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1884-1906, Apr.</unittitle>
            <physdesc id="aspace_777c304c85f25ee3fc052ba7aa3314b5"
              label="General Physical Description note"><extent>6 folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_2d4c6f6d66392f6fa31c882f3560564d" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref24_xev" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1906, May-1909</unittitle>
            <physdesc id="aspace_daa2ef1c5ec9ab6f8ec3e9a5dc9ec67b"
              label="General Physical Description note"><extent>6 folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_0fb8ad4734e7454b199402d8ceb025c8" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref26_ech" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1910-1911</unittitle>
            <physdesc id="aspace_203454afe12de8fe6f08ad703f7c2ea3"
              label="General Physical Description note"><extent>5 folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_c261e70bf0e437666c9299c130dbc034" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref28_mgh" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1912-1914, June</unittitle>
            <physdesc id="aspace_aff0dc2f0a61fd9103cb4a5d8610fc45"
              label="General Physical Description note"><extent>5 folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_ba104e7baa86078a3d727b6fba4c113c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref30_rnh" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1914, July-1920, June</unittitle>
            <physdesc id="aspace_07b8befea0e5608a2a3123ff74bd4a86"
              label="General Physical Description note"><extent>5 folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_fb176271cca52a477cd3583da4555bfc" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref32_cbd" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1920, July-1922, Oct.</unittitle>
            <physdesc id="aspace_9e2b6a3c83155d5a20f17f80ba977a5b"
              label="General Physical Description note"><extent>6 folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_5ec163973a9695b812e3a2d70774f206" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">7</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref34_1bn" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1922, Nov.-1925, Aug.</unittitle>
            <physdesc id="aspace_f0f5cfddd87697131edf05a409aea2c2"
              label="General Physical Description note"><extent>4 folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_7a46015fa7926da51f92c9eb721e70e7" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref36_48i" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1925, Sept.-1930, Feb.</unittitle>
            <physdesc id="aspace_154c0d2a15b9ea7d566244a1c5fa196c"
              label="General Physical Description note"><extent>5 folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_126929b980b7cbac511b973751c6d6eb" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">9</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref38_zm0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1930, Mar.-1945</unittitle>
            <physdesc id="aspace_5120cecb1e61ff58007557c6d819011c"
              label="General Physical Description note"><extent>6 folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_4d084908c696e2d6bc09528de50bcfd2" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">10</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref40_k9a" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1951-1971, undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_6c81f2a06dd97ab649fc3de41d3b59ff" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref41_f8e" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>MISCELLANEOUS SERIES</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref42_0bq" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1852-1954, undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_4d795439c481042c4aacdd86e27334b8" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref43_p3g" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Genealogy--Journal, 1835-1930, undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_a22de164764453c2e62f548191802425" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref44_u6k" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Photographs:</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref45_eg1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1867-1918, undated (numbered)</unittitle>
              <physdesc id="aspace_939b748252d81e422db21007413f1885"
                label="General Physical Description note"><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_ef445d289468577e9820a2fada212a23" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref47_nvz" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1899-1940, undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_96f80b30271964baea42092ccbdd8321" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref48_gbo" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>PRINTED MATERIAL SERIES</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref49_c3w" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings, 1916-1968</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_7dd4a0516e17395d38583a7743ab4d78" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref50_km7" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Missionary work:</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref51_8yz" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>India, 1898-1977, undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_1e762fba3dd06805f81bbd65c416241d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref52_bz5" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>General, 1921-1924, undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_dc18b16d15064eeacd86dca41ba75d9b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref53_19j" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Programs and announcements, 1879-1971, undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_e8cf42d04b9ff8cce2d3ebf30d51b320" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref54_abw" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>BEALS FAMILY SERIES</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref55_8ex" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, 1920-1936</unittitle>
            <physdesc id="aspace_8c2e940e95716adc7c57237c5834a404"
              label="General Physical Description note"><extent>6 folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_3a44e69a1a2e5676e4c2880f7a891065" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">12</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref57_er1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous, 1884-1986, undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_825a23c744c4113c90121019daf708b8" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">12</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref58_0gm" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>OVERSIZE MATERIAL</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref59_bj5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous Series, 1937-1939, undated</unittitle>
            <physdesc id="aspace_8f655a09302f406969d58bdc87845b05"
              label="General Physical Description note"><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_a9de2d997e4323d7834f32305e97aeab" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">Sec. A OV8</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref61_sjm" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Printed material Series, undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_b994b53b93748743ec5f8f9b9a2a243a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">Sec. A OV8</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
