<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
         url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/fernekesfrank/">fernekesfrank</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Frank A. Fernekes photographs and postcards, 1915-1948 and
               undated <num>RL.00388</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Levi Crews; machine-readable finding aid created by: Paula
               Jeannet</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2014</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003909273</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-11-01 16:20:36
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Frank A. Fernekes photographs and postcards</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Fernekes, Frank A.</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00388</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.4 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1915/1948" type="inclusive">1915-1948 and undated</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_4363c9d47f6cfee747ee6a3c64c8d282">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_b6931da2c2b8c3be23a2b95ede03ec03">Frank Fernekes (1872-1953) was a
            commercial photographer with an interest in circus and Wild West themes; he was born and
            resided in New York until sometime before 1927, then moved permanently to Hollywood,
            California and was active through the 1940s. Collection contains photographs and
            postcards chiefly dating from the 1910s through the 1930s, with a few from the 1940s.
            All of the photographs are black-and-white and were taken by photographer Frank
            Fernekes. They feature a set of views of El Paso, Texas, in 1915, which include several
            images of African Americans and inhabitants probably of Mexican descent; a large set of
            images of California circus performers, actors and performers in Western-themed
            costumes, and Native Americans in costumes and traditional dress; and a large souvenir
            photograph with Fernekes taken at McLoed's Happy Hollow amusement park in Arkansas,
            circa 1923. The collection also includes a set of color souvenir postcards with early
            20th century Western-themed illustrations of cowboys and cowgirls, and a few
            black-and-white postcards relating to Buffalo Bill Cody, a Yuma Indian band from
            Arizona, and other Western themes.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_9217a38a81afbae2ae44a63d984faf2d">
            <extent>Approx. 100 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_4e86e91f12e4cd41e682ca2be9173cfd">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_a53cb1df8f997c42ad402d22a3b3a0df">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_44f7170b676b9103f4c51654cd67a1c8">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_be0255eb20cd7140c80bed8b646a7804">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Frank A. Fernekes photographs and postcards, David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_4487a990bd3f6cbe3c314272cd7c1fd6">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Frank A. Fernekes photographs and postcards collection was received by the David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1976.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_a19ccaf3160dcdfb3674fd82ea75d62b">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Levi Crews, February 2014</p>
         <p>Encoded by Paula Jeannet, February 2014</p>
         <p>Accession(s) described in this finding aid: 4-30-76</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_2c193823cd89a14c8e9c2e8bf131d3ab">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Frank A. Fernekes (1898-1965) was a photographer based in Hollywood, California, and was
            active during the 1920s-1940s. He was born in New York City, and lived or stayed for a
            time at an address there before 1927. His primary subject seems to have been circus and
            rodeo performers in California; judging by several photographs in this collection, he
            also probably had close contact with movie personnel from Western film studios in
            Hollywood.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_7a1f0b09788828faf38c7ddbcd46f985">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Collection contains photographs and postcards, chiefly dating from the 1910s through the
            1930s, with a few from the 1940s, all assembled or taken by photographer Frank Fernekes.
            The first folder consists of 15 small contact prints taken in El Paso, Texas in 1915,
            probably by Fernekes, including views of the city from a higher vantage point, close-ups
            of buildings and streets, railroad tracks and bridges, and close-up views of what appear
            to be families and individuals of Mexican descent and their houses. One street scene
            includes many African American men congregating in front of a building. The snapshots
            measure about 3x5 inches, and were printed sometime in the 1970s from the original
            nitrate negatives, which were then discarded from the collection.</p>
         <p>A second folder in this group contains 40 snapshots, chiefly taken in Hollywood and Los
            Angeles, California from 1925-1948. The earliest images were taken in New York City. The
            only dated image is labeled 1925, and is captioned "Chief Manabozho," who was a Native
            American actor on Broadway and in Wild West shows. This image is hand-colored and
            includes Fernekes's NYC address on the back, which is struck out and amended with the
            year 1927 and his California address. The two undated images show Chief Wanabozho again,
            and Frank Fernekes shaking hands with a person in Native American costume in front of
            the Coney Island Luna Fun House, which often held Wild West-themed shows.</p>
         <p>The largest set of snapshots in the second folder are of parades in Venice, Los Angeles,
            and Hollywood, California, chiefly in the 1930s, focusing on individuals in Western or
            Native American costume; staff and performers at the Cole Bro. and Clyde Beatty Circus,
            and the Barnes Circus, sometimes featuring Frank Fernekes posing alongside
            (19302-1940s); and Native Americans in popular culture-inspired costumes and in
            traditional dress, posting in groups and individually. Named individuals include Hubert
            Honanie, a well-known Kachina artist in Pasadena, in Native American costume; Joe and
            Oscar Cody, who were Native American extras early in their film careers (shooting bows
            and arrows in civilian clothing), circa 1938; Montie Montana (Owen Harlan Mickel, a
            rodeo star who resided in California, 1948; "Miss Bluebird," a young Native American in
            costume, taken at the "All-Indian Picnic in Sycamore Grove Park, Los Angeles," 1942, and
            the Woody Hanley Cowboy Band, 1946. Many of the Native Americans and other individuals
            may be actors - there was a studio lot adjacent to Sycamore Grove Park. The photographs
            in this group typically measure 3 1/2 x 5 7/8 inches, and many are captioned, often
            including the stamped address of Frank Fernekes's photography studio in Hollywood,
            California. </p>
         <p>The second group consists of 11 souvenir postcards, part of a fold-out set probably
            dating from the 1920s featuring color reproductions of images dating from 1908. Images
            depict cowboys, cowgirls, and scenes from the "Wild West" as rendered in American
            popular culture at the turn of the 20th century. There is a lone color postcard of "The
            only one-tribe Indian band in the West," which is a group shot of a Yuma brass band from
            about 1930 published by Harry Hertz. There is also an empty souvenir envelope that once
            contained souvenir postcards from the Buffalo Bill Wild West show, undated; a
            black-and-white Burlington Route postcard with an image of the Buffalo Bill Museum in
            Cody, Wyoming, undated; and a black-and-white postcard with "The Fall of the Bronco
            Buster, Walton's Views, Roswell N.M., Pecos Valley Drug Co.," from the 1920s.</p>
         <p>The collection is rounded out by a large decorative cardstock mount, printed sometime
            between 1908 and 1923, featuring on one side an image of McLeod from Happy Hollow, a
            well-known photographer who founded this popular amusement park in Hot Springs,
            Arkansas; the image is accompanied by a publicity verse. The single 6.75x9.25 inch
            black-and-white photographic print that was apparently once mounted on the other side of
            this card frame shows a group of men and women, some astride donkeys, posting for the
            camera. The man on the far right is Frank Fernekes, dating the image closer to 1923.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Photographers -- Hollywood (Los Angeles, Calif.)</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">California -- Pictorial works</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Parades -- California</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Photographers -- California -- 20th century</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Postcards</genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">Indians of North America -- California</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Indians of North America -- Pictorial works</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Cowgirls in art</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Indians in popular culture</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Circus performers -- United States -- Pictorial works</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Cowboys in popular culture</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Hollywood (Los Angeles, Calif.) -- Pictorial works</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Hollywood (Los Angeles, Calif.) -- History</geogname>
         <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs</genreform>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Los Angeles (Calif.) -- Pictorial works</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Los Angeles (Calif.) -- History</geogname>
         <genreform source="aat">Contact prints</genreform>
         <geogname source="lcsh">El Paso (Tex.) -- Pictorial works</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">El Paso (Tex.) -- History</geogname>
         <persname source="ingest">Fernekes, Frank</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_xpc" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Frank A. Fernekes photographs and postcards, 1915-1948 and
                  undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_4d06c716a536efc4cfc280efd91fed6e">
                  <extent>1 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_1wn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photographs of El Paso, Texas, 1915</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_120b827341f2d1db224ce7c5f32be948">
                     <extent>15 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_427b39e46108c3b2be440d313815f020" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_8qy" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photographs of circus staff, performers, and Native Americans, New York
                     City and California, 1936-1948</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_a51f3ee3eb4401de772cf61a88b0df5b">
                     <extent>40 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_b04f092871e251cb4ac86e4f76c25d87" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_hdl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>McLeod's Happy Hollow souvenir photograph and card mount, Hot Springs,
                     Arkansas, circa 1923</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_81e626b7373ac072ea5959a085827117">
                     <extent>2 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_fbe6e3c572773211e341082913c992f5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0ef476226760e6600f18573acbebc75c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Frank Fernekes appears on the far right.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_zz8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Western-themed postcards, 1920s-1930s</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_d959e245c7671786b2f7bb8c111fb5ff">
                     <extent>2 folders; 14 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_4be550351d7cd5840e05fa741ebeb01e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
