<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/firor/">firor</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the John William Firor Papers, 1860-1986 <num>RL.00395</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Sharon Knapp</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000813443</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-28 16:54:56
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>John William Firor papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Firor, John William, 1887-1956.</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00395</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1860/1986" type="inclusive">1860-1986</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_b6019622c4644b3cae4bce64303cade3">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <physdesc id="aspace_ab73233c5fcc5ecbb474df4958673425">
            <extent>circa 1,530 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_bb3966db07a816a2f6303346a757b337">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_d538bb9edf390c27e16bcbc25f9efe93">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research. Accession 2012-0161 (boxes 5-6) may require further
            processing before use.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_493ee16b0ae6a500d3b523bcbfe0b160">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in the papers of John William Firor have been transferred to
            Duke University. For further information, see the section on copyright in the
            Regulations and Procedures of the Rubenstein Library</p>
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_b764db934f277f8b2c6b0e4cf935cad3">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The papers of John William Firor (1887-1956), professor at the University of Georgia and
            author, were a gift to the Rubenstein Library in 1986.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_37df647a8de56bca5d008d947c54b4ea">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Sharon Knapp</p>
         <p>Completed May 20, 1988</p>
         <p>Encoded by Stephen D. Miller</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_7fe0f2e96036f3060b6c4bcc493de823">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <chronlist>
            <head>Chronology</head>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1887, Sept. 23</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Born, Frederick County, Md.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1908</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>B.S. in horticulture, Maryland Agricultural College (now the University of
                     Maryland), College Park, Md..</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1908,1910</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Commandant and instructor, Bethel Military Academy, Warrenton, Va.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1910-1912</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Assistant Horticulturist at the West Virginia Experiment Station,
                     Morgantown, W. Va.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1912</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Professor, Georgia State College of Agriculture (later incorporated into
                     the University of Georgia), Athens.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1912-1917</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Extension Horticulturist, Georgia State College.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1914-1917</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Co-editor, <title type="simple" render="italic">Southern Fruit
                        Grower.</title>
                  </event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1917-1919</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>U. S. Army Field Artillery Officer, serving primarily in France.</event>
                  <event>Taught horticulture in the College of Agriculture, A.E.F. University,
                     Beaune, France.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1918</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Graduate, U. S. School of Artillery Fire.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1920, June 15</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Married Mary Valentine Moss.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1920-1922</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Manager, Planters Products Company, Ga.</event>
                  <event>Horticulturist and marketing agent, Atlanta, Birmingham and Atlantic
                     Railway Company.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1923-1925</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>County Agricultural Agent, Clarke County, Ga.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1926-1927</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>State Agent in Marketing for Georgia.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1928-1951</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Organized and headed the Department of Agricultural Economics and Rural
                     Sociology, University of Georgia.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1931</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>M.S. in agriculture, University of Georgia.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1942-1944</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Education officer and director of Troop School, U.S. Army Air Force, Lowry
                     Field, Colo.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1944-1945</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Member, Governor's Agricultural &amp;amp; Industrial Development Board,
                     Ga.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1947-1948</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Member, City Council, Athens, Ga.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1951</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Retired from University of Georgia faculty.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1956, May 28</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Died.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
         </chronlist>
         <p>Wrote bulletins, government reports, addresses, and many articles for <title
               type="simple" render="italic"> Southern Ruralist, Southern Agriculturist, The Georgia
               Democrat, Country Gentleman, and The Progressive Farmer.</title>
         </p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_134a03f9dbfb88caababb6392eea4f3b">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The papers of John William Firor span the years 1860-1985, but the bulk of the papers
            falls between 1900 and the 1950s. Included are correspondence, articles, a diary,
            postcards, printed material, clippings, notes, and pictures. This collection primarily
            consists of his personal and family correspondence, although there are papers relating
            to his work as a university professor, author, and farmer.</p>
         <p>Firor began his career as a horticulturist prior to World War I and eventually broadened
            his interests to the field of southern agricultural economics, teaching at the
            University of Georgia. A major focus for his work was problems relating to Georgia
            agricultural crops, including especially pecans and peaches, but also watermelons,
            tomatoes, Irish potatoes, and apples. Particular interests in this field included
            fertilizer tests, diseases, expansion and economics of the farming industry, the impact
            of the boll weevil, distribution of farm price information, and general farm problems.
            In addition, he was known for developing the idea of carlot marketing of poultry and
            livestock.</p>
         <p>The single diary in the papers covers chiefly the latter part of Firor's career as a
            professor in the College of Agriculture at the University of Georgia, 1949-1952, with
            only intermittent entries for 1941-1948. He wrote about veterans, his farm, and his
            economic, agricultural, and political philosophy. Entries also discuss various farming
            topics, such as cost and prices, crops, planting, cattle, sales, and the effects of
            temperature and rainfall on crops.</p>
         <p>The Correspondence Series comprises over one-half of the collection. Pre-World War I
            correspondence consists primarily of incoming letters. Family correspondents include
            Firor's mother, Anna Catherine Wisotskey Firor, and his brothers Guy W., George, and
            David F. Some of the letters concern J. William Firor's job searches. In his World War I
            letters from France, he reflected on the U.S. Army, the Armistice, the French people,
            and AEF (American Expeditionary Forces) University (1919). He wrote to his fiancee Mary
            Valentine Moss, a student at Simmons College in Boston, and to Guy and his wife Helen.
            Firor and Mary corresponded from 1915 until their marriage in 1920. In France Firor met
            Viscountess Therese de Montford, and their correspondence extends into 1953. After the
            war, his letters express concern about the arrival of the boll weevil in Georgia. He
            referred to varieties of pecan trees, fruit trees, spraying, and some letters pertain to
            his job searches. Few letters exist for the 1930s.</p>
         <p>Correspondence in the 1940s and 1950s includes a few World War II letters that Firor
            wrote from Lowry Field, Colorado and letters from Yvonne Ragon, a friend in France.
            Other war and post-war letters pertain to Firor's return to the University of Georgia
            and changes in the College of Agriculture and in courses in rural sociology. In letters
            between Mary and J. William Firor, and their daughter Anne Byrd Firor Scott, professor
            of history at Duke University, Dr. Scott wrote of her career and family life. In 1951
            Firor wrote to former students in agricultural economics and associates in response to
            the volume of letters presented upon his retirement from the University of Georgia. Most
            of the post-1951 correspondence is between Firor and his daughter Anne Scott. Prominent
            individuals represented in the Correspondence Series include Reuben “Shorty” Brigham
            (late 1940s), Harmon Caldwell (late 1940s), Paul Wilber Chapman (1940s), William Mauzy
            Kemper (ca. 1908-1914), and Anne Firor Scott (1949-1961).</p>
         <p>The Writings and Speeches Series includes clippings of Firor's articles from such
            publications as <title type="simple" render="italic"> The Country Gentleman, The Georgia
               Democrat, The Progressive Farmer, Southern Ruralist,</title> and <title type="simple"
               render="italic"> The Southern Agriculturalist.</title> Included is a rough draft of
            his <title type="simple" render="doublequote"> Farm Plan for the Future,</title> 1952.
            Firor wrote on a variety of southern agricultural topics, such as economics, prices,
            mortgages, the marketing of crops, sharecroppers, surpluses, farm ownership and
            management, father and son farming, planting, conservation, and farm people. The
            writings reflect a particular concern for problems relating to the cultivation of the
            pecan, sweet potato, peach, watermelon, and cotton crops. He also wrote about politics
            and veterans as farmers.</p>
         <p>The Subject Files Series includes biographical and genealogical files on the Moss and
            Firor families as well as a folder for Anne Firor Scott. There are folders for Thurmont,
            Md., Firor's boyhood home, and for <title type="simple" render="italic"> Country
               Gentleman,</title> to which Firor frequently contributed articles. In the Printed
            Material Series is a booklet, <title type="simple" render="italic"> In Memoriam: Rufus
               Lafayette Moss</title> (1913). In addition, there are clippings about Paul W. Chapman
            in the Miscellaneous Series.</p>
         <p>Addition (2012-0161) (450 items, 0.6 lin. ft.) contains family correspondence (1942-53),
            photographs, photocopies of letters from John William Firor and some transcriptions of
            these created by by Anne Firor Scott, material about Mary Valentine Moss, legal
            documents, genealogical material, and material produced by Anne Firor Scott while
            writing a biograpy of John William Firor. This addition may require further processing
            before use.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">France</geogname>
         <genreform source="aat">Postcards</genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">Agriculture -- Economic aspects</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Georgia</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Diaries</genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- 1913-1921</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Horticulture</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Courtship</subject>
         <persname source="ingest">Scott, Anne Firor, 1921-</persname>
         <famname source="ingest">Moss family</famname>
         <corpname source="ingest">University of Georgia -- College of Agriculture (Athens,
            Ga.)</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">AEF University. College of Agriculture (Beaune,
            France)</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Brigham, Reuben</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Caldwell, Harmon</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Chapman, Paul Wilber, 1891-1953</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Firor, John William, 1887-1956.</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Firor, John William, 1887-1956.</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Kemper, William Mauzy, 1881-</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_sx1" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Diaries Series, 1941-1952</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_c5f1deb0d5133604a70bfffd74bdb644">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Diary of Firor, including handwritten and typed entries.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref13_h3h" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1941-1952</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b2103bd649a9ce73d39741e69eaf9895" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref15_knv" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence Series, 1902-1974 and undated</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_83ff641b97dd406126dd5485c9525c85">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Chiefly of a personal and family nature, although there are some professional
                  letters. Correspondence is to and from Firor, typed and handwritten, with a
                  handful of postcards, <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian" type="inclusive">
                     ca. 1919. </unitdate> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_n73" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1902-1919, Sept.</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_fa546194361da0014d4d6645bf9829be">
                     <extent>5 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_042d5e190da063a173a39f5781895dc4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_qdy" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1919-1951</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_b3e374f46b5e00a34cd686696ec50d4f">
                     <extent>5 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_6b87e9b9c73ba28ae31cd11bab807210" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_hk3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1952-1974 &amp; undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_b4bd7a5fdda742f94b5eb63c577705df">
                     <extent>3 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_90d8bc88314f7bbed8d0b02b1c75cc5f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref23_m5b" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Writings and Speeches Series, 1921-1952 and undated</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_1e5f6d694969017b7742e5c888865e78">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Primarily articles by Firor, arranged chronologically. Includes clippings,
                  typescripts, radio address scripts, and some notes taken by Firor.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_rvy" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Magazine articles by John William Firor, 1924-1937</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b6fd3509559e44009b3fca42404a12de" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_4dk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">The Progressive Farmer</title> articles by John William
                     Firor, 1924-1947</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_dbad5cdba682a2942ab7ce85f867ba69" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_kkq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous articles, 1921-1952</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9c68dde61c5272b095f7d18caff9feb9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_3wq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous articles, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_576a78a4c9684f4248d004c582082e90" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref29_5nc" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Subject Files Series, 1878-1985 and undated</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_aad73f67c7f1d7c8c66d0d8397136974">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Small file, arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_1r8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Biographical Information, 1911-1951</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_71fcf8da69b9860b481864c8f647fda9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_emc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">Country Gentleman,</title> 1942-1945</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d10d99b393d7b373fd4ea49bde6ae1ff" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_2lo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Firor &amp; Moss Genealogy, 1878, 1983-1985 &amp; undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5cb848c8cd0a1f5cb3d43e630233b228" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref33_f77" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Thurmont, Maryland, 1951-1954</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4252f3901e35aa7a2b14386d8d9272d0" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref34_8sb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Scott, Anne Byrd (Firor), 1940-1946</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_cad1b77f814e7189006073487fc4fdba" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref36_or2" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Printed Material Series, 1868-1920 and undated</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_c254eb8f840b0ab6295e7c36f938af9d">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Small file of calling cards, pamphlet, program, and French wedding invitations.
                  Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref37_i4j" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1868-1920 &amp; undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_379615f17eaa6b3e3a09f5d98b6fe91f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref39_opr" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Miscellaneous Series, 1913-1972 and undated</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_07b638f7820681015acd3009d9a503b7">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Small file of clippings, pictures, address and membership lists, estate appraisal,
                  and general material. Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref40_bht" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1913-1972 &amp; undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b624c62591eaa2f095dc9ce580f65234" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref42_1wr" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Oversize Materials, 1951</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_hw5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">Catoctin Enterprise, </title> 1951</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d8188a079f32ee2bed2009d0e42ce691" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-folder">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref44_lyb" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Accession 2012-0161</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_7fc7ceedd3819e766d7110486f23458b">
                  <extent>2 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_1af7d8ecfda326a438bab05e2822da68">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Addition (2012-0161) (450 items, 0.6 lin. ft.) contains family correspondence
                  (1942-53), photographs, photocopies of letters from John William Firor and some
                  transcriptions of these created by by Anne Firor Scott, material about Mary
                  Valentine Moss, legal documents, genealogical material, and material produced by
                  Anne Firor Scott while writing a biograpy of John William Firor. This addition may
                  require further processing before use.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <accessrestrict id="aspace_4786597a9a24c4e1745dbac0b3098a36">
               <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
               <p>This accession may require further processing before use.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref46_x16" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters from David L. Firor</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e1a3d35a1bd904179a5b969d847bfde2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_bd5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters to his children and others, 1943-1944</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e705906495cf725004e03b3a16ecc607" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref48_3d4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters to his children and others, 1948-1953</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_723cf2aa2c3715829ed84070e6755ef4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref49_162" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>AEF University</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d14ffccd5a7d1e8398f0316d3ef09fc9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref50_8ft" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Maryland Agricultural College</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_853950cae86a078b4476b59096ed34bc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref51_mk0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John William Firor pictures</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4674b929cf7a020691582617248f3c20" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref52_pkb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Grandchildren</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a204f23118ab65cf4ea55ef5ab492b44" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref53_uso" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John William Firor diary</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1cf38139cab089def233edf90b5bef8f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref54_10y" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John William Firor letters World War I</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0bc917a6264ff5429e16799c747cc6a1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref55_2zd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Mary Valentine Moss</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f1202aa2721a47753499953a21151dd2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref56_7z9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Legal documents</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_081b7b87e93a365bf700a770bc2a7bb7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref57_pbn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Biographical notes</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_cd44c26a35ebba0cdf0457e338f4afe2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref58_xq2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Writing biography</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fa4c24f0a7df78dbc5138c5247c0c03a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref59_2zf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>France</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d5dbe6a042e54cc1b00adbd9c53155f8" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref60_vdl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>JWF letters</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8eb4874c1348b068920f61300e732dfb" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref61_w88" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>JWF book</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_deb2cae50be519e359ed871b6853a791" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref62_gtv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John William Firor, Sr.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_714a46fae3b3e98843dd39907906a597" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref63_h8t" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John William Firor scholarship</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e6ae406b3f55edd8d46297a56a4365dc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref64_hwd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>JWF Scholarship</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0af8614c6b69fb435a203a62c879ae04" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref65_vc2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Hall of fame</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_18e7256b9b502f76777547355b9ea56c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
