<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
         url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/garveyamyashwood/"
         >garveyamyashwood</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Amy Ashwood Garvey photographs, 1940s-1950s
                  <num>RL.10073</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Paula Jeannet</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>October 2014</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">005830015</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-11-01 16:17:13
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Amy Ashwood Garvey photographs</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Garvey, Amy Ashwood, approximately
               1895-1969</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="source">
            <corpname role="col" source="ingest">John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and
               African American History and Culture</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.10073</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 Linear Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1940/1959" type="inclusive">1940s-1950s</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_f9b3724a4b24d4cb70329705b0edbf20">Collection consists of 60 small
            black-and-white photographs dating roughly from the 1930s to the 1950s, belonging to Amy
            Ashwood Garvey, feminist and activist who traveled extensively and lived in West Africa,
            where most if not all of these images originated. The majority of the images are
            portraits of Amy Ashwood Garvey's many male and female acquaintances in Africa, who
            include female friends, politicians, heads of states, lawyers, and students. Other
            subjects include locales and native inhabitants of Nigeria and other unidentified
            places; gatherings such as meetings, a funeral, and a public hanging; and street and
            market scenes. Although there are photographs with inscriptions, names, and descriptions
            of the scenes, the majority are unlabeled; the few dates that appear are from the late
            1940s. The travel snapshots are likely to have been taken by Amy Ashwood Garvey, but
            there are images that were sent to her by individuals as mementos, and some images of
            her taken by another unidentified person. Acquired by the John Hope Franklin Research
            Center for African and African American History and Culture.</abstract>
         <physloc id="aspace_158c1fe7bc70b81953f8de4740e921a0">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_3634789a4b33bdee923afe8fdbe3fe24">Materials in
            English</langmaterial>
      </did>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_66a908f70f607c4dfd30cbb93c8a53cf">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Dating roughly from the 1930s to the 1950s, this collection of 60 small black-and-white
            photographs belonged to Amy Ashwood Garvey, feminist, activist for African and African
            American human rights, and first wife of Marcus Garvey. Most of the travel snapshots
            were likely to have been taken by her, but there are several that were clearly sent to
            her by individuals, and some that feature Amy Ashwood Garvey and were taken by another
            person. Although there are some photographs with inscriptions, names, and descriptions
            of the scenes, most are unlabeled; the few dates that appear are from the late 1940s. </p>
         <p>Almost if not all the photographs were taken in Africa, where Garvey traveled and lived
            after her divorce with Marcus Garvey in 1922. Other locations may include Ghana and
            Benin. Personal subjects include portraits, candid and formal, of the many male and
            female friends and acquaintances of Amy Ashwood Garvey, including politicians and heads
            of state; and native inhabitants, including a portrait of a tribal chief with two women,
            probably his wives. Most are in Western dress, but some are in traditional clothing. Amy
            Ashwood Garvey appears in at least three of the prints, and there is a portrait of the
            President of Liberia, William Tubman, with whom she had a serious long-term
            relationship. Other images include street and market scenes; school groups; a parade,
            meetings and ceremonial visits; a public hanging; a funeral gathering; and views of
            river landings, probably the River Niger.</p>
         <p>Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African
            American History and Culture at Duke University. </p>
      </scopecontent>
      <bioghist id="aspace_857706d947bcab82787e65c06e51bfe0">
         <head>Biographical note</head>
         <p>Amy Ashwood Garvey was a feminist, activist, and founder of the <title render="italic"
               >Negro World</title> newspaper. Her travels took her to many countries in West
            Africa, particularly Nigeria and Liberia, and she also lived for a time in Nigeria and
            in England. She was born in Port Antonio, Jamaica, January 10, 1897. She met American
            activist Marcus Garvey in Jamaica, then moved to New York City to establish with him the
            Universal Negro Improvement Association (UNIA) in 1914. They married in 1919 and
            divorced in 1922. Amy Garvey also had a long-term relationshiop with William Tubman,
            President of Liberia. Amy Ashwood Garvey died in 1969.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_b2b2020857f15869efa26257aac8a877">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_2c90bb379fca8b7655b89b0f42aa59f4">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <processinfo id="aspace_60c5cc32dcf8f8b96e398078e8142ae7">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by: Sara Reams, July 2014 Encoded by: Paula Jeannet, October 2014</p>
         <p>Accessions described in this finding aid: 2013-0090</p>
      </processinfo>
      <prefercite id="aspace_8b2833dfb8e5c7f01919c73612d00ef9">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Amy Ashwood Garvey Photographs, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_29131867991ebed8f89b1075f5373c88">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Amy Ashwood Garvey photographs collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein
            Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2013.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Africa, West -- Pictorial works</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Ghana -- Pictorial works</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Blacks -- Africa, West -- Pictorial works</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Nigeria -- Politics and government -- To 1960</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Politicians -- Africa, West -- Pictorial works</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Nigeria -- Pictorial works</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Africa -- Politics and government -- 1945-1960</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Africa -- Pictorial works</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Africa, West -- Pictorial works</geogname>
         <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs</genreform>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Africa, West -- Social life and customs</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Africa, West -- Social conditions</geogname>
         <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Garvey, Amy Ashwood, approximately 1895-1969</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Tubman, William V. S., 1895-1971</persname>
         <corpname role="col" source="ingest">John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and
            African American History and Culture</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref23_ezq" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Amy Ashwood Garvey photographs</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref7_gpo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>People</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_6509f1f4c6adb7279abebf6c6a7d304d">21 items</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_e9ec52cf5444e6d1c7e1c1e79a59cbba" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_08dfcc23b063c2437a0976d7e76eedd5"
                     parent="aspace_e9ec52cf5444e6d1c7e1c1e79a59cbba" type="folder">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_503df023b71d60a810be932d82454119">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>A series of 52 small black-and-white photographs consisting chiefly of
                     portraits, candid and formal, of Amy Ashwood Garvey's many friends and
                     acquaintances in Africa - female friends, politicians and heads of state; and
                     native inhabitants, including a portrait of a tribal chief with two women,
                     probably his wives. Most are in Western dress, but some are in traditional
                     clothing. The dates that appear on prints are from the 1940s. The majority are
                     unidentified. Amy Ashwood Garvey appers in at least two of the images, one of
                     which has several copies; one depicts a group of women on the "Shanahan" ferry
                     at the landing (probably in Asaba, Nigeria), with Amy Ashwood Garvey in the
                     center.</p>
                  <p>People whose names appear in captions are: William Tubman, President of
                     Nigeria; Felix Wambu and Lawrence Payne of Nigeria; Ben K. Tamakloe; Viscount
                     Bernard Montgomery and a "Chief Commissioner, N.P." in an unspecified location
                     (possibly taken during the Viscount's visit to Kaduna, Nigeria, in 1947); and
                     Gaius Ikuobase Obaseki of Benin, a member of the legislative council of Nigeria
                     (handmade Christmas card). One individual with a diploma is identified as a
                     "young African barrister, son of the Alaki Jay [alake?] of Abeyacouta
                     [Abeokuta?] Nigeria."</p>
                  <p>There are numerous photographs of groups: one is entitled "Oration at the grave
                     of Late H. Macauly" (Herbert Macaulay, Nigerian journalist and nationalist,
                     died in 1946), and one is of a side view of a group of seated women, and is
                     captioned "1949 Accra [Ghana]." Others include school groups, parades, and
                     gatherings for special visitors. There is also a scene of a public hanging. </p>
                  <p>A few of the photographs bear inscriptions to Amy Ashwood Garvey, and some
                     reveal photographer's markings. The prints measure from 2.5x2.5 to 3.25x5.25
                     inches and are in original order as received.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref6_h5r" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Places</unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Garvey, Amy Ashwood, approximately
                        1895-1969</persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate>undated</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_a0787a68f84a92e9c4abd5df0429f83f">8 items</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_815dee7f2a153f8336b02f09b3688f5c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_db578cb6aa42f1ad3be28946c8b6ba3d"
                     parent="aspace_815dee7f2a153f8336b02f09b3688f5c" type="folder">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4e4ddfc0459082b3a79f2c1bf1e853ae">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Nine small black-and-white photographs feature a view of a large river,
                     probably the River Niger, with a ferry landing; walled compounds; native
                     dwellings; a street lined with palms; and a European-style house. The only
                     caption in the group describes the appeal of the tree-lined street, and it is
                     stamped "Ekpe's Photo Service." Prints measure 2.5x3.5 inches to 3.25x5.25
                     inches.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <geogname source="lcsh">Africa, West -- Pictorial works</geogname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
