<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/girlgerms/">girlgerms</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Girl Germs Posters, 1996-1999 <num>RL.00454</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Meghan Lyon; machine-readable finding aid created by: Meghan
               Lyon</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">004320126</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-28 18:04:48
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Girl Germs Posters</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="ingest">Coalition for Positive Sexuality</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00454</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1996/1999" type="inclusive">1996-1999</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_c3fbf8564f680b70fedb158d312933a9">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_ea5de33b10873b014416e1562b759a5b">The Coalition for Positive Sexuality
            is a grassroots, not-for-profit, activist organization funded through grants and
            donations. CPS seeks to give teens information about sexual health and safe sex, and to
            facilitate dialogue in public schools about sex education. This collection consists of
            nine 18x24 posters produced by artist Jeanette May for the CPS Girl Germs
            campaign.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_c500b24d6ddc1f2f735935242645939a">
            <extent>9 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_4ab71f22f176c55906dc4c071864b986">Material in English and Spanish
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_877ae904cdf1561151d64a400b9b17af">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_eca6fec129f002d81398c410cf3d0bc3">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_621518205f2c4293a1de120adbe71142">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Girl Germs Posters, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_05e9d69eeb66a512c988cc50655de13c">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Girl Germs Posters were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2010.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_5049cb645edaf3c3122858396e3d1585">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Meghan Lyon, May 2010</p>
         <p>Encoded by Meghan Lyon, May 2010</p>
         <p>Materials may not have been ordered and described beyond their original condition. </p>
         <p>Accessions in this collection: 2010-0108.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_60a6160750c3011722f45ebe15ecc6f2">
         <head>Historical Note</head>
         <p>The Coalition for Positive Sexuality (CPS) was formed in Chicago in 1992 as a grassroots
            volunteer organization. Its founding members were from local high schools and groups
            such as Queer Nation, Emergency Clinic Defense Coalition, the AIDS Coalition to Unleash
            Power, and No More Nice Girls. CPS was formed as a response to a health crisis among
            Chicago teens; its first project was to write and distribute <emph render="italic">Just
               Say Yes</emph>, a booklet for teens on safe sex and sexuality. This booklet has since
            been distributed nationwide in both English and Spanish.</p>
         <p>CPS's second major initiative was the Girl Germs campaign, a poster series aimed at
            young women and addressing the issues of safe sex, sexual health, sexuality, pregnancy,
            and birth control. This series was produced by artist Jeanette May, a founding member of
            CPS, between 1996 and 1999. As explained by the CPS website, <emph render="doublequote"
               >although the posters speak specifically to young women, the posters prompt a
               dialogue meant to be over-heard by the general population. These posters are
               distributed to social service agencies, health clinics, juice bars, coffee houses,
               and anyone else who wants them.</emph>
         </p>
         <p>Today, CPS is based in Washington, DC, with volunteer members living throughout the
            United States. Its website is www.positive.org.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_790d3582286bdc2e6307d21b69474c40">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The collection consists of nine 18x24 posters created and distributed as part of The
            Coalition for Positive Sexuality's Girl Germs campaign in the late 1990s. These posters
            were created by artist Jeanette May, who was also a founding member of the CPS.</p>
         <p>The posters include a black-and-white image of teenage women along with texts offering
            information about sex and sexuality, as well as telephone numbers for additional
            resources. All posters are captioned in both English and Spanish. Subjects covered by
            the posters include abortion, condoms, water-based lubricant, sexuality (including
            homosexuality and bisexuality), sex education, and rape.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Abortion</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Reproductive rights</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Sexual intercourse</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Contraception</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Youth -- Sexual behavior</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Posters</genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">Hygiene, Sexual</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Teenagers -- Sexual behavior</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Sex instruction</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">First sexual experiences</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Sex -- United States</subject>
         <persname source="ingest">May, Jeanette</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Coalition for Positive Sexuality</corpname>
         <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and
            Culture</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Coalition for Positive Sexuality</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_iyy" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Girl Germs posters, 1996-1999</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_dc5ad9b51fe5b6431a994beab0523a4e">
                  <extent>1 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_7c743208d2596125537bfa205b73306c">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Each poster's title and text is listed below. Digital copies of the images and
                  text are available through artist Jeanette May's website,
                  http://www.jeanettemay.com/GirlGerms/GirlGermsPage.html</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_6ap" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Boys will be boys is over</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3e08d3fe96815cbbdb70f95dab2cbde1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_31f6cca461541fd99f3b9816824e6447">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Poster text: You know who you are. You are boyfriends, relatives, classmates,
                     and strangers. You think you have the right to push us around. Think again.
                        <emph render="doublequote">Boys will be boys</emph> is over. We’re told to
                     protect ourselves. We’re warned not to go out at night alone. We’re advised to
                     get out of abusive relationships. Well, we’re sick of trying to avoid you! You
                     know who you are. We will walk down the street wearing a short skirt, or
                     whatever we want, and it is not an invitation to you. And don’t flatter
                     yourself–we do not consider your taunts a compliment. We can’t always tell the
                     innocent flirt from the violent creep. You know who you are. Every guy is a
                     potential threat as long as society tolerates <emph render="doublequote">men
                        behaving badly</emph>. And if you’re a guy we actually like, that doesn’t
                     mean you can control us. We are not property and you do not own us. It’s about
                     power. Well, no more! We won’t stand for it. We are fearless. We are strong. We
                     demand respect. You know who you are ... and you need to stop.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_kam" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Girls have the right to a future</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_63ed92369eaa0d6943c2998857ada77a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5b5998be819e6a45d2eb1b8baa5a6568">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Poster text: Girls have the right to a future, with or without a baby. We need
                     our families’ support to help us to be good parents. The baby’s dad should help
                     out, too. We’re just like other girls–we want to finish high school, go to
                     college, get a job. But it’s hard. Sometimes we’re told to go to a school for
                     pregnant girls. That should be our choice. We should be allowed to stay in our
                     regular school with friends and teachers we know. Schools should have daycare
                     centers just like some businesses do. Some schools have special homebound
                     programs so we don’t fall behind when we first give birth. People’s attitudes
                     need to change, too. If people treat pregnant teens with respect, we will make
                     better choices about pre-natal care, adoption, and abortion. If people accept
                     the fact that teens have sex, we will get decent sex education, access to birth
                     control, and be less likely to get pregnant accidentally. People have to stop
                     treating pregnant teens and teen moms like sexual criminals.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_09g" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">We've got a different spin</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_13582d31e1e69cf5debc36344c0c4f88" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_73d2484e9facd0306a14df02b77df364">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Poster text: Does this shock you? It shouldn’t. Lesbian and bisexual girls
                     kiss, have sex, and fall in love everyday, everywhere. It’s not a fad. Those
                     heterosexual mating games like spin-the-bottle don’t work the same for
                     everyone. We’ve got a different spin on sexuality! We don’t need boys to have
                     fun. Lesbian and bisexual girls exist outside the stereotypes seen in movies
                     and on TV. We might have short or long hair, wear dresses or pants, play sports
                     or piano. You can’t pick out a lesbian just by looking, but we are here. We are
                     sisters, daughters, activists, students, and people you admire. We demand
                     respect and equality. We are proud to be who we are–lesbian and bisexual girls
                     of all kinds, making herstory.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_u6c" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">The more we know about sex</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_22b339a9723d8bc8fad86cc3ae7d9f52" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_17868365407b502942a19c186b20d287">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Poster text: Sex education should be more than biology and STD horror stories.
                     Yeah, we need to learn about menstrual cycles and how you get pregnant, but
                     girls need practical information, too. <emph render="doublequote">Just say
                        no</emph> isn’t sex education. Lots of teens have sex. The more we know
                     about sex, the better our choices. We need to know what kind of birth control
                     is safest for teens. We need to know how latex can protect us from STDs and
                     HIV. We need sex ed to include respect for gay, lesbian, bi, and straight
                     sexualities. Teachers, parents, and doctors should talk to us openly about sex.
                     We can teach ourselves by reading books and sharing info with our friends. We
                     can even do some research on ourselves. Hey, guys do it. Why not girls?
                     Exploring our bodies is fun and educational. Masturbation is safe sex–if can’t
                     hurt you. Anyone can do it, and lots of girls do. Remember–the clit is it!
                     Girls need to know how our bodies work and feel, so we can take care of
                     ourselves.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_man" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Scarlet letter</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e723f7c6ed4e8bf9b4e8a5c7a40f9768" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f1a926196454a8c07f1915f98452ba0b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Poster text: No one can punish us for liking sex! You think that girls who like
                     sex are sluts? Get real! Everybody has sexual needs–girls too! We will choose
                     to have sex or not to have sex. We’re talking about our bodies and our lives.
                     We may decide to have sex with a guy, or a girl, or both, or with ourselves!
                     Telling us to <emph render="doublequote">wait until marriage</emph> is way
                     off–especially if we’re lesbian, gay, or bisexual. They may not call us <emph
                        render="doublequote">adulteress</emph> anymore, but we’re still being
                     treated like criminals. Politicians accuse single moms of <emph
                        render="doublequote">destroying the family.</emph> Schools refuse to teach
                     us about birth control &amp; safe sex. Drugstores lock up the condoms. People
                     make it harder for us to get an abortion. Hey! We demand the right to be able
                     to take care of ourselves.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_qbg" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">My body my right</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_64ea69bab434b7962e658bd31bc45ccd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_35d3d3caf163349f51aa2ac114488518">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Poster text: The <emph render="doublequote">right to choose</emph> means women
                     control our own bodies. We will decide to have a baby or not–even if we’re
                     young, single, or poor! To really <emph render="doublequote">choose</emph> we
                     need abortion services, health care, and child care! Many states have Parental
                     Notification laws. They try to stop teens from having abortions by making us
                     tell our parents first. What’s up with that? Teen sex is healthy and natural.
                     We need birth control and safe sex information. We demand health care and child
                     care for teen moms. Abortion must be safe, legal, and affordable for women of
                     all ages. Fight to keep abortion legal! Not all women think abortion is cool
                     for themselves, but all women have the right to make their own choice.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_x5c" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Latex</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6c52a5f19e33d20f535a2943fbffa15d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1bf9bc6ecec8c190bb28a648ae93f6d4">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Poster text: Latex. The fashion accessory that goes with everything! Practice
                     safe sex! Wear latex condoms, latex gloves, and plastic wrap. Do it right and
                     latex will protect you from STDs, HIV, and unwanted pregnancy. Use a latex
                     condom with lubricant for vaginal or anal intercourse. Water-based lube helps
                     prevent condoms from breaking and helps prevent vaginal soreness. Plus lube
                     feels really great! Use a non-lubricated latex condom for oral sex (blowjob).
                     Use plastic wrap or dental dam if you’re going to be licking your partner’s
                     clit, vulva, or butthole. Be sure to cover the entire lickable area. Wear latex
                     gloves if you’re going to be putting your fingers in your partner’s vagina or
                     butthole. And use lots of water-based lube! You can get all this stuff at the
                     drugstore.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_fbd" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Secret to great sex</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_05f1424831ee0ca181912d7b325ea78b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_39fb562e8fb9ae9faf754574db69c515">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Poster text: The secret to great sex ... water-based lube! Have you heard about
                     water-based lubricant? Lube makes nookie feel fantastic! And you can get <emph
                        render="doublequote">personal lubricant</emph> at the drugstore. Lube is the
                     secret to smooth sex. Lube is pure pleasure–it makes sex wet and slippery! You
                     can use lube on your fingers when you’re touching someone else, or yourself. It
                     works great on sex toys, too. Lube is especially cool for women the first time
                     you have intercourse. Lube makes things go smoother, and it helps prevent
                     vaginal soreness. Water-based lube also helps prevent condoms from breaking.
                     Even if it’s a lubricated condom, add more lube to the outside for extra slide.
                     Avoid oil-based lubes, like lotions and Vaseline, which break latex
                     condoms.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_dfc" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Some girls like other girls</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3edbb77a9df3bb0efc67b6f5b17ff08a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f470b6ae4e0f428fcd7c3157824b3862">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Poster text: Millions of girls have the hots for other girls. We call ourselves
                     lesbian, dyke, gay, bisexual, queer, or even straight. But labels aren’t
                     important–we are! If you’re not sure if you’re interested in boys, girls, or
                     both, that’s fine. Everyone has questions about their sexuality at some time or
                     other, and exploring your sexuality can be an adventure. Have fun with it! If
                     you like girls, fabulous! Falling for a girl is perfectly natural. Just
                     remember that you have the right to love anyone. Be proud of who you are! It’s
                     true that some people are going to freak if you <emph render="doublequote">come
                        out</emph>. People who have a problem with us need to get over it! Tell your
                     friends and family when you’re ready. Good friends will love you just the
                     same.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
