<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
         url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/gouldjohn/">gouldjohn</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the John Mead Gould Papers, 1841-1944 <num>RL.00469</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Library staff; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Tanya Lee and Carrie Mills</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2014</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000855524</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-11-01 16:21:12
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>John Mead Gould papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Gould, John Mead, 1839-1930</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00469</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8.8 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1841/1944" type="inclusive">1841-1944</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_3bd2f80c35d40cfdeada0935f295b3e6">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_4a163ac6f68a1cbf952a2a9470e109b5">John Mead Gould was a Union Army
            officer and bank teller, of Portland, Maine. Correspondence, diaries, official papers,
            clippings and other printed materials, and other papers relating to Gould's service with
            the 1st Maine Infantry Regiment and its successors, the 10th and 29th Maine regiments,
            during the Civil War. Gould served as the regiments' official historian and was
            extensively involved in post-war reunions and veterans' claims. Subjects include Civil
            War campaigns and wartime and Reconstruction conditions in South Carolina, and the
            career of zoologist Edward Sylvester Morse. Also includes the diaries of Amelia Jenkins
            Twitchell Gould, 1860-1865, who taught a freedmen's school in Beaufort, S.C., and
            diaries written by Samuel McClellan Gould, a Presbyterian minister, 1841-1845,
            1890-1895. Other materials include photocopies of letters, 1906-1926, from veterans of
            Gould's Civil War regiment, mostly giving news about the deaths of former members, and a
            photocopy of an autobiographical and genealogical narrative by Gould and two
            photographs.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_64167f1ebb4a0a19d114ee93292ac643">
            <extent>3,617 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_d8c26d63bf41260844c6ee544f24ec08">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_d05328d4f07e86f4eb266d33045a63ec">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_94c904e4de937a025df30622c59f762e">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_6a6fdb19d3d5788c9f4a8f2cf71e589f">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], John Mead Gould Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_220a93145cd24a20f95587ec4d260e74">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The John Mead Gould papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a gift in 1967 and 1988.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_52811fae2f3b2a3cbb1d7af23877edf5">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library staff</p>
         <p>Encoded by Tanya Lee, Carrie Mills, and Paula Jeannet, March 2014</p>
         <p>Accession(s) described in this finding aid: 1967 and 88-084</p>
         <p>Parts of this collection have been given basic processing: materials may not have been
            ordered and described beyond their original condition.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_b4be683d11db35f6600188aaf8b40615">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>John Mead Gould was born in 1839 in Portland, Maine, the son of a local banker, Edward
            Gould. His closest friend beginning with his school years was Edward Sylvester Morse
            (1838-1925), who became a well-known biologist; there are some papers in the collection
            that relate to his life and career.</p>
         <p>Gould enlisted in the Portland Light Guards in April 1861, which then became part of the
            1st Maine Regiment, commanded by Colonel Nathaniel Jackson; he then re-enlisted with the
            10th Regiment in September 1861, which was commanded by Colonel George L. Beal (who
            later led the 29th Regiment). This regiment traveled and fought in Harper's Ferry,
            Winchester, Cedar Mountain, Antietam, and other places in Maryland and in the Shenandoah
            Valley. During this time Gould was promoted to First Lieutenant and Adjutant, a position
            which required him to maintain the regiment's records. Gould enlisted again in late 1863
            with the 29th Maine Regiment, under Nathaniel Banks, and saw action in the Red River
            campaign, Louisiana, and in the last campaigns of Virginia in 1864 and 1865. He was
            elected major of the regiment in 1864. Gould was in a hospital in Harper's Ferry when
            Lee surrendered on April 9, 1865.</p>
         <p>After the war's end, he traveled with the 29th Maine Regiment to Georgia and South
            Carolina, where he took on the duties associated with an occupying army. His comments in
            his diaries reflect on this time of reconstruction and chaos. He resigned his commission
            in February 1866 and moved to Yauhanna Ferry, South Carolina, where he lived until 1867,
            and profited from selling lumber to Maine shipyards. </p>
         <p>John Mead Gould returned to his home state of Maine in 1866 and married Amelia Jenkins
            Twitchell, whose diaries are also in the collection; the couple lived in South Carolina
            for a time, but financial troubles forced them to return to Maine in 1867. He and Amelia
            had three children, a daughter and two sons. Gould became active in the veterans'
            association, the Grand Army of the Republic (GAR); he also was appointed to serve the
            Maine Regiment as their chief historian and secretary. During this time he wrote a
            history of the regiment and other pieces of writing.</p>
         <p>In his later years, Gould entered the banking profession, and retired by 1915. His wife
            Amelia passed away in 1926 and John Gould died in 1930 at the age of ninety, in Bethel,
            Maine.</p>
         <p>[Adapted from a biography of John Mead Gould published on a descendant's website.]</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_c968c418d2315143c7b71934ca039cc0">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>This rich collection contains correspondence, diaries, official military papers,
            clippings and other printed materials, drafts of writings, photographs, and other papers
            documenting John Mead Gould's experiences in the Civil War, his activities in veterans'
            organizations, and his work as historian of the lst, l0th, and 29th Maine Regiments. </p>
         <p>The correspondence in the collection relates in part to Gould's service in the 1st Maine
            Regiment and its successors, the 10th Maine Regiment and the 29th Maine Regiment and
            contains descriptions of the situation in Washington, D.C., 1861; guard duty on the
            Baltimore and Ohio Railroad at Relay, Maryland, 1861-1862; the battle of Winchester,
            1862; the battle of Cedar Mountain, 1862; two fragments from field notes on the Maryland
            campaign and the battle of Antietam, 1862; the Red River expedition, 1864; operations in
            the Shenandoah Valley, 1864; and occupation duty in Darlington, South Carolina, 1865. </p>
         <p>There is family correspondence, especially for 1864; correspondence relating to Gould's
            attempt to establish a lumber business in South Carolina, 1866-1867; correspondence with
            other veterans after the war concerning Gould's history of the three regiments,
            validating pension claims, and veterans' organizations; correspondence of Adelthia
            Twitchell and Amelia Jenkins Twitchell, who went from Maine to teach freedmen in
            Beaufort, South Carolina, 1864-1865; and letters relating to the early career of the
            zoologist, Edward Sylvester Morse, a close friend of Gould's.</p>
         <p>Legal papers in the collection include commissions, discharges, furloughs, pensions, and
            papers from the superior provost court, Darlington, South Carolina, 1865-1866. Rolls and
            reports of the lst-l0th-29th Maine Regiment, 1861-1869, form the official papers of
            those units and concern supplies, finances, furloughs and other service records. The
            records of 65 consecutive reunions of the lst-l0th-29th Regiment veterans, 1869-1933,
            include lists of personnel, minutes, and obituaries. </p>
         <p>The letters written by Gould during the war, which he called his "journal," were bound
            into several volumes by his family. Although these are not with his papers, a long
            series of memorandum diaries by Gould remains in the collection. These little volumes
            begin in 1854 at Bethel Academy and continue until 1874, when Adelthia (Twitchell)
            Thompson and William E. Harward died. Along with Gould's Civil War diaries there is the
            diary of a Levi Johnson, Company B, 29th Maine Regiment, in South Carolina, 1865. The
            collection also contains the diaries of Gould's wife, Amelia Jenkins (Twitchell) Gould,
            1860, 1862-1863, 1864-1865; diaries written by Samuel McClellan Gould, a Presbyterian
            minister (Gould's uncle), 1841-1845, 1890-1895; and diaries written about excursions to
            Antietam, Cedar Mountain, and other battlefields of the Civil War, 1884-1912.</p>
         <p>Printed materials include clippings, broadsides, and pamphlets, many from the Civil War
            era. Accounts of Civil War prisons appear in the clippings as reminiscences. Casualties
            are reported in clippings directly after the Civil War battles in which the regiment
            fought. Broadsides contain poetry, veteran materials, and political brochures. The
            pamphlets pertain to veterans' activities.</p>
         <p>There is a substantial series of photographs of the men of the lst-10th-29th Maine
            Regiment in the war and at various reunions. Materials added to the collection in 1988
            include photocopies of letters, 1906-1926, from veterans of Gould's Civil War regiment,
            mostly giving news about the deaths of former members, and a photocopy of an
            autobiographical and genealogical narrative by Gould and two photographs.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Presbyterian Church -- Clergy -- Diaries</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Soldiers -- United States -- Diaries</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877) -- South Carolina</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 --
            Campaigns</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">South Carolina -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Regimental
            histories</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal
            narratives</geogname>
         <persname source="ingest">Gould, John Mead, 1839-1930</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Gould, Samuel McClellan, 1809-1894</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Morse, Edward Sylvester, 1838-1925</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">United States. Army. Maine Infantry Regiment, 10th
            (1861-1863)</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">United States. Army. Maine Infantry Regiment, 1st
            (1865-1868)</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">United States. Army. Maine Infantry Regiment, 29th
            (1863-1865)</corpname>
         <famname source="ingest">Gould family</famname>
         <persname source="ingest">Gould, Amelia Jenkins Twitchell</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_dhg" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence Series, 1853-1935 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_9f9ace44ce5a76df437ec2e6e97ff56d">
                  <extent>6 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_dmi" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1853-1864</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_131d3f2394209e9cbab77bf839e1e14e">
                     <extent>8 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_5638db1959ad89c90f395beadf5a38fe" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b5e099bdd6ba73e238a6988a99c2371c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Includes an information folder about John Gould Papers at Maine Historical
                     Society, and a folder of letters, 1853-1861 1st Maine Regiment.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_rgd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1865-1869</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_63dd92a6088c3e4f2aca29c7da0278f4">
                     <extent>8 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_970f7b45bdd8a6bbc3e5c6ab6188b40b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_4lk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1870-1871</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_0f5c5d85a485c03780d3ecfe9623ff61">
                     <extent>5 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_7d6d3d485a10f3e39ca96ad7ef2238cf" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_6hg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1872-1879</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_1132ee7a7f80ca5c1adb708e479367d3">
                     <extent>7 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_2b0f1342c77cf516f68999b3b7dce8c7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_cc5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1880-1899</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_ac66a7c64f65290cf74b72d4eab228a9">
                     <extent>7 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_f68b8a4ae186f24c26a7007325e54752" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_3gy" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1900-1935 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_60346460ae714f91e1371c77bef4281e">
                     <extent>6 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_a35371c4cc257bb9271cfa9c846afd6f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref27_i24" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Legal Papers Series, 1865-1866 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_ba36143c6f41931a8a470088e16f8920">
                  <extent>.5 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_ozk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Personal</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_05251fabe3816b8b5b0080f1be878589" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_i65" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Provost Marshal cases, 1865-1866</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d379d4b4e5c2df0040699e0017bad853" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_2bz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Soldiers</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a9f39afa88d7bb2eb2d95074a73fb283" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref32_e8a" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Financial Papers Series, 1860s and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_baf1d7b8a30cfd07e493ad88f48b51f5">
                  <extent>1 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref34_4eh" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>29th Maine Regiment (1860s) and the 10th Maine Regiment (1863), and
                     other papers</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_aeffcc1ec1beed58a8ff3697848daf6c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref35_u1j" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Writings Series, 1892 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_9ed78231bae910e0b6419870c3a36a9e">
                  <extent>1 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref37_ob1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="doublequote">History of the 1st-10th-29th Maine
                        Regiments</title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ca1dbe9a15368a5a91d3c0ca7be50352" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref38_g1d" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Manuscript on the Battle of Antietam, 1892</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6e57c0f0bc474a8bda0fb23ee9938e13" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref39_t67" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellany</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e31b8ac49219929a41741c666ed2a46f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref40_x24" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Printed Material Series, 1860s-1920s and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_0b74e04efae16fb86658586be5a07db1">
                  <extent>1 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref42_g9w" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Pamphlets</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a99ea5482044546653ba97b5c96b3389" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_d87" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Leaflets</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_140fec5f544986ad87bf2f7a47c01027" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref44_w04" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Broadsides</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_14dc37e79290d50f88b40e4bd0dfbfed" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref45_aus" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Newspaper clippings</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_49d8dfbaef9296b612a24e7cda6d608f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref46_ydw" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Reunion Papers Series, 1869-1933</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_4e72162251a310965831c84cfce4272e">
                  <extent>4 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref48_e1w" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1869-1899</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_3be7806026aa6db3c0a5311aa2621ac3">
                     <extent>7 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_e9649a7dfad780266ad23b20019f05fb" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">10</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref50_apq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1900-1922</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_08393e32ad333018e3ccc961cd1f4f9b">
                     <extent>7 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_d8715d262c22ac9048fd01d86e2cedb2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref52_o2s" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1923-1933</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_93d345d2426ce84141023349e0bccb62">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_c2ea843ee11dc8bc1f70897407d81b68" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref54_2ja" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Rolls and reports of 1st-10th-29th Maine Regiment</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_05aa12923594187cdf45da38d4ac7407">
                     <extent>1 box</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_feb264dd63cb1f6e5e08e21bae1c73c7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref56_24a" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Photographs Series, 1870s-1925 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_2eff27354efcdafa61b2eebe4cff1ab5">
                  <extent>3 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref58_erf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reunions, circa 1870s-1925</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_da27da4b9f2abceed32acabd6dcd418a">
                     <extent>22 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_1a76849239d92b096f96fb5b56cc4959" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref60_1on" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Excursion of 1889</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c150bd20ac0d72f84d6c6b18d2d28c23" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">15</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref61_d1u" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Excursion to Cedar Creek</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_58f4e3b997f7cfc0280581514d1d43d0">
                     <extent>3 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_2753b7906c1ee3d1e35d1d158b945a62" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">15</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref63_u7k" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Unknown battlefield</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_aa88c2461bd1652471ff4f19c55308b3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">15</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref64_1za" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Red River Dam</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1d64eb5e5836db281af8c7a7a8ad0de4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">15</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref65_tc2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Antietam, 1910 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_1b3e079e345bb7b9f2c9d586300d2b83">
                     <extent>2 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_0675cb0657fb956b8bae43200978d033" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref67_zqh" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Cedar Mountain, 1912 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_78a93de9cc2004c0d086a6ede027e5fa">
                     <extent>2 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_5a55c6ea0a13de9738533d7693cd7dee" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref69_kjs" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Veterans, soldiers, and others</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_90b9bd87a46b05451eb3cfb369812f86" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref70_uhm" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Prints of officers of 1st, 10th, and 29th Maine Regiments</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4f58d9540df09dfa162a955931d4a8ab" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref71_2p6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>29th Maine</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_42bb00ae4e12fa5aad83adeaa0bfe39f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref72_krt" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1st, 10th, and 11th of Maine</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fea94a9331b5a469bab92d509a643637" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref73_02m" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Long Island, Casco Bay, Maine and Portland, Maine</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9b7fe864771bfe8045114ebb317c0654" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref74_zyf" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Volumes Series, 1854-circa 1920 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_a05935fd724bb7030bdc406758f7e59b">
                  <extent>6 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_a51b1bfd2341ed17012a32744e49cfb5">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Boxes 19-22 in this series have been given basic processing; materials may not
                  have been arranged beyond original order.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref76_3wq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Directory of the 1st-10th-29th Maine Regiment (red covers), 1889-circa
                     1920 (32 volumes)</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_58ed5c1dc3feb0cf9dfb8b2715f6d7de" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">17</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref77_txi" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Directories of the 1st-10th-29th Maine Regiment (white
                     covers)</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_663ea57a20f25ea6365f12e450720dcb">
                     <extent>circa 60 volumes</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_9a7525c69f4d43ff77b24c9b75c157c6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">18</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d45044a8d99a99c110f65cb3cab24296">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>The career of a Louisiana freedman, Harry Johnson, who followed the regiment
                     home to Maine, is related in the white-covered volume marked "Jennings."</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref80_s4i" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Regimental records</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_358a8128b6c76ee859db4faba0211511">
                     <extent>18 volumes</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_cbd37ac0da601c358f9cc554f679452d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">19</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref82_ult" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Regimental records</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_bddfc7606c0e372ad60f584b149e4600">
                     <extent>8 volumes</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_08b418cf6441f2cac8758b928d953110" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">20</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref84_vem" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Diaries of Amelia Jenkins (Twitchell) Gould, 1860, 1862, 1863, 1865,
                     1889</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_6777b425e07f8187e9ac37b11cd708c3">
                     <extent>5 volumes</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_016720d837ad66f692ac2a82bc0fbd40" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">21</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref86_72c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Diaries of Samuel McLellan Gould, 1841-1845 and 1890-1895</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_ce62f37edc7ecfe5db122a6b648e98d2">
                     <extent>6 volumes</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_564d0d58dfb96ae8bfa5ccc0f5f56574" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">21</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref88_yla" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous financial records of John M. and Edward Gould</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_7b8b13a4bb2a9745c52a8ee472507d34">
                     <extent>8 volumes</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_721cf1d033a3746d990f187bce65aa9c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">21</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref90_vwk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Memorandum diaries of John Mead Gould, 1854-1874</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_21bfe1aa16252e7b15f38f5dba51a7e0">
                     <extent>15 volumes</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_dab1ebb4dc9d6b20d9102baa333ca556" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">22</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_558e3b14d90c4f6d083471a77cafd9a9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>With Gould's Civil War diary is that of Levi Johnson, Co. B, 29th Maine, in
                     South Carolina, 1865.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref94_efy" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Oversize Materials</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref95_ipn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photograph, 48th Reunion, 1-10-29 Maine Regiment Association, Long
                     Island, Maine, 1916, Aug. 10</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3968adf1549e6dc483fadfb955ac4d15" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-folder">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref96_0ua" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photograph, Randall B. Williams, 1924, July</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a0637ebf32cabb4c0936887d3c00ba72" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-folder">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
