<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/gracejohnpatrick/"
         >gracejohnpatrick</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the John Patrick Grace Papers, 1902-1940 <num>RL.00471</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Library Staff; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Meghan Lyon</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000855527</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-28 18:23:35
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>John Patrick Grace papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Grace, John P. (John Patrick), 1874-1940</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00471</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">26 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1902/1940" type="inclusive">1902-1940</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_64ea6b789e701150b57fabf15f5d4d9e">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_a5f1270fc4cce31f1c8b59d5e12f7a12">Politician and journalist, of
            Charleston, S.C. Personal and legal papers. Includes material on Charleston and South
            Carolina politics; the Charleston American, a newspaper founded by Grace; anti-English
            feeling at the time of World War I; American sympathy for Irish nationalism; enforcement
            of the Espionage Act against Grace for his wartime editorials; land speculation in
            Florida during the 1920s; Grace's speaking engagements on behalf of Alfred E. Smith
            (1928); his opposition to Roosevelt's nomination in 1932; and his attitude toward world
            events in the 1930s.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_d934cc17a30403955d08dc8c48641a73">
            <extent>12,082 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_0b59fe85a9c840fe9a93bdb78ac8f44d">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_3964f598cf9b37d5c9f5c4c9f6a7a1fc">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_1d8e34ef406ba768af57b4f012056f15">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_8de090885691c96fcf4cc5fe85a63e72">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], John Patrick Grace Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_2c81f99ca098047cb8e9c96980a2a29a">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The John Patrick Grace Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1956.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_8781ec0e22c15ffa5ffaf37e0387c8aa">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library Staff, 1970s</p>
         <p>Encoded by Meghan Lyon, January 2011</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_668b0272435fab80078ede5bdab9d950">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>John P. Grace was born on "factory hill" in Charleston, S.C., in 1874. He attended the
            Christian Brothers' School, Charleston High School, and received his law degree in 1902
            from Georgetown. In the course of his law career he was associated with the firms of
            Logan and Grace and Logan, Grace, and Cosgrove. He founded and edited the <title
               type="simple" render="italic">Charleston American</title> daily newspaper and was
            elected mayor of Charleston for two terms, 1911-1915 and 1919-1923. Until his death on
            June 25, 1940, he was influential politically in Charleston as well as in state
            political circles. He was a member of the Hibernian Society, the German Rifle Club, the
            Elks Club, the Knights of Columbus, and of several organizations dedicated to Irish
            liberty. He was also the attorney for the Central Labor Union of Charleston.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_ce2bbe41d6888550ad8df756bdfb6562">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The Grace papers are divided into several series: Correspondence, Miscellany, Legal and
            Financial Papers, Clippings and Printed Material, and Volumes. </p>
         <p>The bulk of the collection lies in the Correspondence series, dating 1908-1940, with
            topics ranging from Grace's personal news, business adventures, and his political
            career. The early letters, pre-1920, are largely concerned with Charleston politics.
            Correspondence from the mayoralty election of 1915, the election of the U.S.
            representative from South Carolina in 1916, and the mayoralty election of 1919 all
            reveal the corruption and violence that regularly accompanied Charleston elections in
            the early twentieth century. Grace was a candidate for mayor in 1911, 1915, and 1919. He
            appears to have been considered an upstart in Charleston politics; at least he claimed
            to be opposed to the rule of the reactionary aristocrats who, he thought, had controlled
            Charleston. Since Grace was Roman Catholic, religious prejudice was often injected into
            the elections campaigns in which he was active, particularly for the election of
            1919.</p>
         <p>The corruption of Charleston elections was also demonstrated by several governors when
            they called out the militia to keep the peace in Charleston during elections (for
            example, 1919), by the murder of a Grace man in 1915, and Grace's charge that Francis
            Marion Whaley bought his seat in the House of Representatives in the election of 1916.
            This accusation led to a hearing in the House of Representatives, which decided against
            an investigation, claiming a lack of evidence to support the charge of corruption.</p>
         <p>Another large amount of correspondence stems from Grace's publishing of the <title
               type="simple" render="italic">Charleston American</title>, a daily morning paper
            begun in 1916. From the many letters concerning the founding and progress of the paper,
            the problems and great expense connected with the publication of a daily paper become
            apparent. Also, there are comparisons of the progress of the <title type="simple"
               render="italic">Charleston American</title> with the established <title type="simple"
               render="italic">News and Courier</title>. </p>
         <p>In his <title type="simple" render="italic">Charleston American</title> editorials,
            Grace regularly criticized the ongoing war in Europe. His pro-Irish opinions were
            accompanied by accusations that England had begun the war in order to preserve its naval
            and commercial superiority. He wrote that the United States had been flooded by British
            propaganda, and considered British naval policy to be a more flagrant violation of
            neutrality than German submarine attacks. </p>
         <p>Grace wanted the United States to observe strict neutrality, as Wilson had proposed.
            When the United States entered the war, Grace was extremely angry, calling it "Wilson's
            War." His editorials were so critical of Wilson and so pro-German that Grace, on the
            basis of the Espionage Act, was cited to appear for a hearing, and the <title
               type="simple" render="italic">Charleston American</title> temporarily lost its third
            class mailing privilege.</p>
         <p>Although Grace did not hold office after 1923, he was active in politics until his
            death. Correspondents included Governors Thomas Gordon McLeod (1923-1927), John Gardiner
            Richards (1927-1931), Ihra C. Blackwood (1931-1935), and Olin D. Johnston (1925-1939).
            Grace appeared closest to Richards, asking and receiving many favors. Grace despised
            Blackwood, however, and denounced him publicly for removing Grace from the state's
            highway commission.</p>
         <p>Throughout the 1920s and 1930s, Grace also corresponded with a number of national
            politicians. In 1922, he received a letter from his friend and Representative from South
            Carolina, W. Turner Logan, who spoke of joining the "Bolsheviks, Borah, LaFollette and
            Frasier," and explained that this alignment was not a third party movement but "simply
            progressive." Grace also exchanged letters with Millard E. Tydings, James F. Byrnes,
            Hamilton Fish, Jr., James A. Reed, Pat McCarran, George W. Norris, James E. Murray,
            Eugene Talmadge, Ellison D. Smith, and William W. Ball.</p>
         <p>Grace was active in the presidential election of 1928, and was invited by Tydings to
            make a series of addresses in behalf of Alfred E. Smith, the Democratic candidate. In
            the course of this election, some of Grace's letters reveal his political philosophy,
            and this was elaborated in his letters during the 1930s. In connection with the
            presidential election of 1932, Grace was sorely disappointed when Franklin D. Roosevelt
            won the Democratic nomination over Al Smith. Grace accused Roosevelt of being an ingrate
            and an opportunist, and remained a severe critic of Roosevelt, especially concerning
            Roosevelt's treatment of the Supreme Court. </p>
         <p>Also of interest in correspondence from the 1920s are Grace's speculation in Florida
            real estate, his losses growing out of the depression, and his opinion (from 1934) as to
            the causes of the depression. </p>
         <p>During the 1930s, Grace wrote at length on world politics. The letters are particularly
            good for discerning his political philosophy, his reasoning with respect to the entrance
            of the United States into World War I, and his opinion as to the developments in Europe
            that led to World War II. While he disapproved of some of Hitler's tactics, Grace wrote
            in 1938 that Hitler was one of the greatest men of the day. Important also is the long
            letter from George Norris explaining why he had voted against the entrance of the United
            States into World War I. </p>
         <p>The Legal and Financial Papers series, dated 1885-1939, includes documents connected
            with the business of the <title type="simple" render="italic">Charleston
               American</title>, the Chesapeake Bay Bridge Co., the Cooper River Bridge Co., the
            Whaley hearing, and the O.B. Limehouse Case, among others. Cases are arranged
            alphabetically; the remainder of the series is sorted chronologically. The financial
            papers also contain many bills and receipts. </p>
         <p>The remaining papers are sorted into Miscellany, Clippings, and Printed Material. The
            Volumes series includes three scrapbooks of newspaper clippings.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1928</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Journalists -- South Carolina -- Charleston</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Charleston (S.C.) -- Politics and government</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918 -- Public Opinion</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Politics and government -- 1901-1953</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">South Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Home rule -- Ireland</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Irish question</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Journalists -- Political activity</subject>
         <persname source="ingest">Grace, John P. (John Patrick), 1874-1940</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Grace, John P. (John Patrick), 1874-1940</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_w4l" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence, 1908-1940 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_f15b9c2fe40f2eb5fa2b275c3e5c3a53">
                  <extent>15 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_166" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1908-1916 May</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_355df0d05f02db207ff18f7c05a2f81b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_uoo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1916 June-December</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5fcc6d3bfb213f9edadc2333d9b66917" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_42c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1917 January-July</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a3b29f24d553f845b5cdf3b6ce3d6fa7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_qlq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1917 August-1919 August</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_cb270ada04c3308fa6dbd8cadcc87bcf" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_kzr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1919 September-1920</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9fa2778a2a3069da1bf1561f418174a9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_ua3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1921-1922</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e3e2662c7fd0e94d2803f036acc0aeff" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_yt6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1923 January-1927 August</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_7090b496766bc925e2e1e6031da6d4b8" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_rgf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1927 September-1929 June</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_951158ea1866b77f6c68ca0081545396" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_sg5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1929 July-1930</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_bc920bfc3bf5d28c784bbc745eba9935" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_eea" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1931</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6c96d9869b2de5ec67e469f4a43c03e1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">10</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_rea" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1932-1933 May</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fed6ae41fa8e681cea8e6f08e0ea9043" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_0kp" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1933 June-1935 July</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_33145b04b5a8fea6606cffe4cddb199a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_7mr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1935 August-1937 May</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ec282484ba28f671dd4061d04e2e8122" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_sor" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1937 June-1938 November</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3730f7b71642386e38730958c8582af2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_5g1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1938 December-1940 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d93404a49de0fcfea9fd34fa1f999ad7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">15</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref29_hsl" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Miscellany, 1870-1940 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_fa06154adc6687b451fb88aa5a933e93">
                  <extent>3 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_1xn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1870-1929</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6125488ba0fbf54222692a3cc38b5c11" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">15</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_pts" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1930-1940 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1bad3615319365d0e1d7d127edfb8df1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref33_9kr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d3faec5833c0462c54feeb1db5c8226f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">17</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref34_st3" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Legal and Financial Papers, 1885-1939 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_972f4a4ba50b0b86b999ba565a35d271">
                  <extent>8 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref36_gwf" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Legal Papers (by date)</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref37_s8x" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>1885-1913</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_cc72ffbde5757f4a03b8d3ade6df0d8a" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">17</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref38_d6w" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>1914-1919</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_1ad15508f5d185fbc798853eb3744779" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">18</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref39_id6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Financial Papers (by date)</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref40_av2" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>1911-1919</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_3272ba4b71c4715411bdbe7d75fa3b84" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">18</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref41_exs" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>1920-1939 and undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_3306f6773af8e1c1b22ac1777555004b" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">19</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref42_qmo" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Legal Papers (by cases)</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref43_4md" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_06182159c8722a19c411abbfbc7b6e2f" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">19</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref44_czp" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-C</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_e0d28de3684003344f41f2114d2be9b3" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">20</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref45_p2h" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>D-L</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_02a2f38ffee2c7548810baef43231777" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">21</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref46_g3o" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>M-S</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_000230c9fef3cff73ada0a6e53e018c3" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">22</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref47_u7l" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>S-T</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_c39d5999c5ce32c2e445aac0adce5334" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">23</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref48_s7d" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>U-W</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_a1211f14de6fdafcaeeaa800d56d0be7" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">24</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref49_un1" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Clippings and Printed Material</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_44657b00a487bcfc6d3773b2408058d3">
                  <extent>3 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref51_myn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Clippings</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2fcc0646f69b015859832d9a6efb75b3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">25</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref52_e7v" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed Materials</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_10a652dbc39638841750cc0b50a96dd9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">25</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref53_op0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed Materials</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3535692b66ce317bdfde728d8b937e5a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">26</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref54_46j" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Volumes</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_8fb2e043aef7f7984369f55ff08e2a7f">
                  <extent>3 volumes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref56_lhk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f37e0c32ac91b660f60c3c4857a2dfa5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">L:5708</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref57_ouw" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b424b44b3eed7c87a3993d26e77a617d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">F:5709</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref58_erg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Scrapbook</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f0ec6f345a68cea360f3be19871af4c7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">F:5710</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
