<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/grimballjohnberkley/"
         >grimballjohnberkley</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the John Berkley Grimball Papers, 1727-1930 <num>RL.00482</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Library Staff; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Meghan Lyon</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000855550</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-28 18:26:53
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>John Berkley Grimball papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Grimball, John Berkley, 1800-1892</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00482</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1727/1930" type="inclusive">1727-1930</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_88fa821f9af5b65da3a0a2e5929c1212">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_4adfab492089ace756e643339c9ea078">Planter, of Charleston, S.C.
            Correspondence and other papers of Grimball, of his family, and of the VanderHorst
            family. The bulk of the material is for 1840-1900 and pertains to the life of a planter
            during the Civil War and Reconstruction. Correspondence concerns life in the Confederate
            services, wartime depredations in South Carolina, the Confederate migration to Mexico
            and life and politics in that country after 1865, and life and economic conditions in
            the South during Reconstruction.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_dfd7d0fc1a1137689021739d49cf7ace">
            <extent>1610 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_7de4648cb0c359af18df45f559868fff">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_0d2bc38d7678e0bcfefeca1e64f8d68f">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_5b38893f913b49e8b7edd71797d35031">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_bff56df28067f5245ca519449e5e7466">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], John Berkley Grimball Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_f1edba06be6ce115c6b6f7f8e01654cb">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The John Berkley Grimball Papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library in 1950-1958.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_013209d14afdeb8a67b5a5052514b95c">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library Staff, 1959</p>
         <p>Encoded by Meghan Lyon, Aug. 2011</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_5061a1040e8494101e47da8feafc2f8f">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>John Berkley Grimball, son of John Grimball, was born June 23, 1800 and died Mar. 7,
            1893. On Mar. 10, 1830 he married Margaret Ann Morris (called Meta), daughter of Col.
            Lewis Morris and Elizabeth (Manigault) Morris of Morrisania, N.Y. and Wilton, St. Paul's
            Parish, S.C. She died in 1881. Both are buried at Magnolia. Grimball and his wife had at
            least eight children.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_5086b5385b47781e08b8161681848d4c">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Letters and papers of John Berkley Grimball (1800-1893) of Charleston and Spartanburg,
            S.C., and of other members of his family; and also letters and papers of Mrs. Elias
            Vander Horst and others of the VanderHorst family of Charleston. The bound volumes in
            this collection consist of a volume of Grimball genealogy and two receipt books of the
            VanderHorsts. There are two charcoal etchings by W. Courtenay Corcoran, one of with is a
            picture of Fort Sumter in 1860 the other a picture of the East Battery, Charleston; and
            a daguerreotype of J. Berkley Grimball.</p>
         <p>The Grimball papers give what is perhaps a rather representative view of the problems of
            the planter class of the South during the Civil War and Reconstruction. J.B. Grimball
            was in Charleston during most of the war, and he and his wife, who was living in
            Spartanburg, corresponded frequently. There were six Grimball sons: William H., Arthur,
            Berkley, Lewis M., John, and Harry. All of them except Harry saw service in the Civil
            War, four of them being in the army and one in the Confederate navy. At the first of the
            conflict William H. and Arthur were stationed at Fort Sumter. Later William, a first
            lieutenant in the 1st South Carolina Artillery, was at Fort Repley, Laurens St. battery,
            and Fort Johnson. After leaving Fort Sumter, Arthur was for a time at Simmons' Bluff.
            Berkley was on Johnson Island and at Camp Echo. Lewis M. was a surgeon in the army, and
            served in S.C., Georgia, and N.C. John went to the U.S. Naval Academy before the war,
            and served on the U.S.S. <title type="simple" render="italic">Macedonia</title>. He
            wrote letters home about a trip to Tripoli and to Naples. By Jan. 5, 1861, however, he
            had become a lieutenant in the S.C. navy. In July 1862, he was aboard the C.S.S.
            Arkansas on the Yazoo River and the next year was writing from Paris and Rouen, having
            been also in London. In Aug. 1864, he was still in Paris, but by the next month he had
            gone to Liverpool. On. 24 he left there on the steamer <title type="simple"
               render="italic">Laurel</title>, and on the 29th of that month boarded the <title
               type="simple" render="italic">Shenandoah </title>at sea. His service as an officer on
            that vessel continued until Nov. 1865 when it was taken by the British into the port of
            Liverpool. The captain of the <title type="simple" render="italic">Shenandoah
            </title>was James Iredell Waddell of N.C. The letters from these boys to their parents
            while in service are rather numerous. William died before the war ended.</p>
         <p>Among the war letters of John Grimball is a twenty-page one which he started on Dec. 23,
            1864. It contains information about their sailing to the desert island of Madeira and
            then to the two Desertas islands; a report of their transfer there from the Laurel to
            the Shenandoah, the of the capture of the Dolphin and the destruction of the Aline, Burk
            Edward, Charter Oak, Kate Prince, Lizzie Stacy, and Susan by the Shenandoah and of their
            sailing to the Indian Ocean. At the end of his letter he says that they have the just
            anchored off Melbourne. When he returned to Liverpool in the fall of 1865 he wrote of
            the cruises of the Shenandoah in the Pacific and Artic oceans, of the captures made, of
            their surrender to the British, and of their being told that the war was over and that
            Jefferson Davis had been captured in a pair of hoops.</p>
         <p>Two letters of interest from H.H. Manigault to J.B. Grimball were written at his
            plantation near Adams Run, St. Paul's parish, S.C., in July 1863 and on Feb. 10, 1865.
            The former letter tells of slave revolts on Manigault and neighboring plantations and of
            the desertion of the slaves, and the latter makes a reference to the exodus of the
            people from that area.</p>
         <p>On Nov. 13 and 15, 1865, J.B. Grimball wrote his wife telling her about the valuables
            which were stolen from two families by the Yankees, that a house was burned because its
            owner would not take the oath of allegiance, of his having seen U.S. Colored Troops for
            the first time, and of reports that it was "very doubtful if any of the lands -- the
            islands especially will be restored to the owners," that the African Americans on
            Fenwick's Island were armed and had announced that no white men would be allowed on the
            isalnd, and that the affairs on Edisto Island were in about the same shape that they
            were on Fenwick's Island.</p>
         <p>There is correspondence in connection with some of the Grimballs' securing pardons from
            President Johnson and copies of loyalty oaths. The first postwar letters of Lewis
            Grimball reveal the struggle he was having as a country physician. Those of Berkley and
            Arthur also mention some of their problems in trying to get established. For some months
            after the <title type="simple" render="italic">Shenandoah </title>reached Liverpool,
            John was either in England or with his Uncle Charles at Caen, France. He and other
            officers of that ship feared that if they returned to the U.S. they would be tried and
            convicted as traitors. He and two of his fellow officers finally sailed for Mexico,
            while five others headed for La Plata. On May 20, 1866, he wrote from Cordova of the
            problem of securing labor for the settlements, and of the raids of "Liberals" on two of
            them. In a series of letters to his parents, he says that he and other former
            Confederates in Mexico cannot obtain land there, because all the government grants have
            been taken. He discusses land prices, crops, crime, Mexican politics (including Emperor
            Maximilian), and a series of liberal raids. In 1870 he was in New York practicing law.
            All of the remainder of his letters in the collection were written from there.</p>
         <p>Other letters demonstrating the hard times that the Grimballs faced in the post-war
            period come from J.B. Grimball himself. In Nov. 1865, he wrote to J.M. Porter in New
            York, telling him that the war had made a complete wreck of his fortunes, and that he
            would have to surrender his plantation to Porter and his sister, the ones from whom he
            had bought it. There is a contract dated Mar. 13, 1866, between Robert Deas, a freedman,
            and J.B. Grimball, proprietor of the Grove and Pinebury plantations in St. Paul's
            parish; and letters from A.R. Deas and Lewis and Arthur Grimball about affairs on J.B.
            Grimball's plantations.</p>
         <p>J.B. Grimball had at least two daughters: Elizabeth and Gabriella. Elizabeth married
            William Munro, an attorney of Union. Another woman, Charlotte, frequently appears in the
            letters; it is unclear whether she is Charlotte Grimball or Charlotte Manigault (or if
            there are two Charlottes). There are letters to and from the Grimball daughters.</p>
         <p>Other papers of this collection include a copy of General Orders, no. 18, Headquarters
            Army of Tenn. near Greensboro, N.C., Apr. 27, 1865; letter from the President of
            Princeton College in 1888 supporting the Anti-Liquor League; a bound volume which is a
            letter and memorandum book containing, among other things, letters from Ridgeville,
            copies of J.B. and Arthur Grimball's wills; a daybook; an account book of J.B. Grimball
            showing his dealings with the Bank of S.C. between 1861 and 1865; a record book of wages
            paid servants by Berkley Grimball between 1895 and 1899; letter written in 1896 by
            Elizbeth Grimball at a school in Plymouth, Mass.; letter reporting Berkley Grimball's
            death in 1899; memorandum book comprised of lists of shares, bonds, and dividends;
            tablet containing several letters from E.B. Munro; newspaper clippings, including one
            with a picture of Elizabeth Grimball; handbills; and invitations.</p>
         <p>There are in this collection quite a number of VanderHorst papers. These are comprised
            largely of letters from S. Rutherford of Morrisania, an estate that was located in N.Y.,
            to her sister, Mrs. Elias VanderHorst of Charleston. In one of these letters she
            mentions her plan to engage in establishing an infant school in Harlem, and in another
            she tells of having seen Pierce Butler, who reported on Gabriella and her small
            daughter. She also mentions John Butler.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Soldiers -- Confederate States of America --
            Correspondence</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Mexico -- Politics and government -- 1867-1910</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877) -- South Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Political refugees -- Confederate States of America</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Plantation owners -- South Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Plantations -- South Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">American Confederates voluntary exiles -- Mexico</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Southern States -- Economic conditions</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">South Carolina -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Destruction and
            pillage</geogname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Confederate States of America. Navy -- Sea life</corpname>
         <famname source="ingest">Grimball family</famname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Confederate States of America. Army -- Military life</corpname>
         <famname source="ingest">VanderHorst family</famname>
         <persname source="ingest">Grimball, John Berkley, 1800-1892</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_ugq" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Papers, 1764-1930 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_f15710280a1056ebb9e3f713ebdca520">
                  <extent>6 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_1y7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Papers, 1764-1860</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_85e91006dcd3f82789988b832512e259" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_2gx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Papers, 1861-1863</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a166a468daf7691f25de46c0c94ebe89" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_0yg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Papers, 1864-1866</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5778da9e63ff9912e2c05286e9a02810" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_vt9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Papers, 1867-1878</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a25d70adc220cd5d4a1c8aba62e14d14" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_m7y" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Papers, 1879-1899</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a6d5f52fc911c667d993c554bafbe6e7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_t2k" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Papers, 1900-1930 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8ce1a6dbb91c5d476b8afd59e31f6351" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref20_36m" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Volumes</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_df87b78c2e8ed003219e5226f550bc58">
                  <extent>3 volumes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_hrj" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e2db8cad75e89da73ee5d49223bded02" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:5326</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_g78" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6de613af09691570c3e99d6420b0c4b3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:6722</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_gez" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volume</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5a006c3f63163d9bfe0926c4df06fdfc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:6723</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
