<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/healyjeanette/">healyjeanette</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Jeanette Reid Healy Papers, 1920-1922
          <num>RL.11092</num></titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>2015</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000894217</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-11-07 11:31:35
          -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Jeanette Reid Healy papers</unittitle>
      <unitid>RL.11092</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.0 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1922" type="inclusive">1920-1922</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_b9a5799ce315e22de4e64fa67a93e62b">Diaries from Jeanette Reid Healy's
        honeymoon, 1920-1922, kept as she and her husband Augustine Healy traveled around the world.
        Countries visited include Japan, China, Vietnam, Cambodia, Singapore, India, Pakistan, and
        Kenya. Includes 169 photographs of the couple's safari in Kenya, including images of William
        Judd, their guide.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_712ca0a18c215aae438844b1b8d9ebe9">Materials in English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="aspace_cfb3a6dff3088603e414c7b781914a75">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Jeanette Reid Healy married Augustine (Gus) Healy on April 28, 1920, in Chicago. The couple
        then took a two year honeymoon trip around the world (1920-1922). New York Passenger Lists
        record that the couple returned to New York on Dec. 27, 1922.</p>
      <p>According to Augustine's 1920 passport application for the trip, he was born in Chicago on
        Dec. 17, 1894. He was 26 when he married Jeanette. He served in the U.S. Army during World
        War I, and was stationed in France. At the time of their honeymoon, in 1920, he was a
        businessman.</p>
      <p>Jeanette Reid Healy was born in Kansas City, Missouri, on July 18, 1891, to parents William
        J. Reid and Jeanie Lockard. She was 29 when she married Augustine.</p>
      <p>After the conclusion of their wedding trip, the couple became interested in equine sport,
        particularly foxhunting. In 1923 they built Firleigh Farms, a winter foxhunting retreat in
        Moore County, North Carolina. They appear to have split their time between Chicago and North
        Carolina. The 1930 census shows that they lived in Moore County, where Augustine's
        occupation was listed as "farmer." The Healys were leaders in the Moore County Hounds
        hunting club, which formally incorporated as the Moore County Company, Inc., in 1929.
        Augustine Healy conveyed Firleigh Farms to Jeanette Reid Healy in 1934, presumably as part
        of the couple's divorce settlement. She continued to live at least part-time at Firleigh
        Farms for the duration of her life. Augustine Healy remarried twice: Eulalia Sceeley
        (married 1939, divorced 1957) and Harriet Pardridge Healy, his brother's widow (married
        1957). According to his death certificate, Augustine died on February 2, 1975 in Palm Beach,
        Florida; he was survived by his wife, a son, and two grandchildren. According to Jeanette's
        death certificate, she died on November 19, 1961 in Southern Pines, North Carolina. She had
        no children.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_7fe9b9e78ffe3060825bdbf3b1b00100">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
        research use.</p>
      <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_b701ccd0cbed92066ab520fd3fdd5293">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_a302f94feaebb2cc161849a773490189">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Jeanette Reid Healy Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library as a gift in 1965.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_2dffd4effcf5871be95a20a659c87060">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Jeanette Reid Healy Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_b0f2292758a9180ef6a0e2898e94c6da">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Meghan Lyon, November 2015</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_04f776c25b0ff44c4454aed960e27d3b">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>Diaries of Jeanette Reid Healy, of Chicago, Ill., describing her two-and-a-half-year
        honeymoon with husband Augustine Healy touring Japan, Korea, China, the Philippines, Hong
        Kong, Cambodia, Malaysia, Thailand, Singapore, India, Pakistan, and Kenya, principally
        describing the tourist sights and places they visited. Jeanette includes her impressions of
        the local landmarks, temples, museums, scenery, and people, often describing native dress,
        hairstyles, and appearances. The Healys were passionate hunters, particularly Augustine, so
        the diaries include detailed descriptions of their tiger and bear hunting in India, as well
        as their three-month African safari with extensive big game hunting of elephants, lions,
        rhinosaurus, and large deer. They were guided by William Judd; a clipping of his death
        notice is included. Included are 169 photographs from their safari, as well as the diaries'
        original book sleeve, bound in zebra skin.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Safaris -- Kenya -- History -- 20th century</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Kenya -- Description and travel</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">India -- Description and travel</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Japan -- Description and travel</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Kenya -- Description and travel</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">China -- Description and travel -- 18th Century</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Hong Kong (China) -- Description and travel</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women travelers</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women travelers -- Diaries</subject>
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Healy, Augustine</persname>
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Judd, William C. (Bill)</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_6b9e2661d0fed513d64912eb51aadaf4" level="item">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Vol 1</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1920 May 6-1920 Dec. 18</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_58d9e3447ddffde5d47e0bf73ab464fc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
          <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r48w3b66c"
            xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new"
            xlink:title="Jeanette Reid Healy diary, May 1920-December 1920"
            xpointer="ark:/87924/r48w3b66c"/>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_c36174879c3a4ea9062d654d49235393">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Contains Healy's description of the couple's tour of Japan, from May through October
            1920. Includes her visit to the following places, among others: Yokohama, Tokyo,
            Kawakura, Matsushima, Aomori, Sappora, Nikko, Nagano, Mt. Fuji, Nara, Kyoto, and Kobe.
            Healy writes about her encounters with various aspects of Japanese culture and people,
            particularly geisha, public baths and onsen spas, cuisine, kimonos, Mikimoto pearls,
            temples, and the Ainu people.</p>
          <p>The couple left Japan for Korea on Oct. 5, 1920. They spent time in Seoul, visiting
            with the YMCA hospital and colleges there. Healy also writes about attending a baseball
            game, and summarizes her interactions with various members of the Korean Independence
            Movement, including the Radical and Conservative independence parties.</p>
          <p>They left Korea after about a week and went to Peking, China, arriving Oct. 11, 1920.
            Healy writes about visiting the Temple of Heaven, the Western and Ming Tombs, the Great
            Wall, and Taianfu. They set up a house near the Marine base and lived in Peking for
            about a month. She describes the process of establishing a house with servants. Finally,
            the couple departed for Manila at the end of 1920, arriving Dec. 15. The volume ends on
            Dec. 18, 1920.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_6e9ce2efd58b7d9c05af4bbc47e034a4" level="item">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Vol. 2</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1920 Dec. 19-1921 Apr. 25</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_4c928308a4dbafe97689c167e8b2c9f6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
          <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r4p55gm93"
            xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new"
            xlink:title="Jeanette Reid Healy diary, December 1920-April 1921"
            xpointer="ark:/87924/r4p55gm93"/>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_150386f1e10b0f37b86e8dfe99e5d31b">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The diary is labeled "Jeanette Reid Healy, Pekin, Nov. 1920," but actually begins with
            an entry from Dec. 19, 1920, while the couple is in Hong Kong. Healy's entries in Hong
            Kong frequently mention playing golf and shopping. They also took a side trip to Macao
            before leaving for Saigon on Jan. 6, 1921.</p>
          <p>Their trip to Saigon was largely centered around planning a trip to Angkor Wat. The
            Healys traveled to Phnom Penh on Jan. 9, 1921, and toured the palace of Sisovah I before
            heading to Siem Reap and the temples of Angkor. Healy writes about visiting Angkor Wat,
            Angkor Thom, and Ta Prohm.</p>
          <p>Later in January the couple went to Bangkok, Thailand, and toured the temples there,
            and then toured Johar Bahru, Singapore, and Penang in Malaysia. Healy describes
            acquiring a Hindu slave; it is unclear how long he accompanied the couple.</p>
          <p>The couple arrived in Darjeeling, India on Feb. 20, 1921, and then traveled through
            Tibet and the Kanchenjunga mountains. Healy writes about seeing Mt. Everest, as well as
            hunting and hiking in the region. They visited the following places: Gangtok, Kalimpong,
            Ghat, Agra and the Taj Mahal, Delhi, Kalka, and Srinagar in the Kashmir Valley. The
            volume ends on Apr. 25, 1921. </p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_39e5f1d98df31705eeace47ef59cfd8a" level="item">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Vol. 3</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1921 May 15-1921 Nov. 21</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_a0e7633da21eda43566d8848e12956f9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
          <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r4rx95j4s"
            xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new"
            xlink:title="Jeanette Reid Healy diary, April 1921-November 1921"
            xpointer="ark:/87924/r4rx95j4s"/>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_aaabfba7213de402f340ee5a40beaa95">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The volume is title "Jeanette Reid Healy, Srinagar, Apr. 1921," and begins with an
            entry dated May 15, 1921. This volume describes the Healys' journeys around India and
            Pakistan, including the following places: Kuari Pass, Deosai Plains, Shizar, Khalatse,
            Himis, Nimu, Leh, Nurla, Kharbu, Pahalgam, Bawar, Bemi Sama, Kanabal, the Pir Panjal
            mountain range, and ending in Peshawar. The majority of the diary discusses their travel
            conditions, with some description of Augustus's hunting expeditions for ibex, bear,
            marmots, and red fox (of which he was largely unsuccessful). While in Bemi Sama, the
            couple participated in a bear beating: villagers beat the brush and forest, driving the
            bear toward the hunters. Healy describes this event in great detail. The volume ends on
            Nov. 21, 1921.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_92cfd67a844eec41d3982e3c910f503a" level="item">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Vol. 4</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1921 Nov. 22-1922 Oct. 6</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_dc687e54b9369550665484a5f6d16784" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
          <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r44m93g2d"
            xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new"
            xlink:title="Jeanette Reid Healy diary, November 1921-October 1922"
            xpointer="ark:/87924/r44m93g2d"/>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_f6c35375819b2d6c5b70786d10faf1f7">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The volume's first entry is Nov. 22, 1921, in Srinagar, Kashmir. Locations visited
            between November 1921 and June 1922 include: Peshawar, Tope, Bhopal, Delhi, Bombay,
            Bangalore, Mysore, Srinangapatna, Ooty, Kadur, and Madras. While in Ooty, Augustus went
            on several tiger hunts, but was unsuccessful. Healy also describes visiting the museum
            in Bangalore. While in Madras, the couple toured tea plantations, the jungle, gardens,
            and visited the city's museums and aquarium. They sailed from Bombay on Jun. 14,
            1922.</p>
          <p>The Healys arrived in Nairobi and then traveled to Simba Station, Kenya, meeting with
            several notable Westerners including Major Radclyffe Dagmore, Leslie Tarlton, and
            William Judd. They hired Judd to be their safari guide on July 5, agreeing to a sum of
            1000 pounds for 3 months. Pages 128-222 describe their safari in the lands of the Maasai
            tribe, which included hunting lions, zebra, rhinosaurus, leopards, all sorts of deer,
            and elephants. Healy describes her own successful shots, as well as Gus's big kills.
            They returned to Nairobi on Oct. 6, 1922, when the diary abruptly ends.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_5ca3be0aafcbcab0ed77b77475ac33a1" level="item">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Zebra-skinned diary case</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1922</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_f09c4845168341749693d522173fa40b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_d7d388dd048b2c751c219950d3e1916e" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Photographs of the Healys' safari</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1922</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_71428aae618cc0646b55f8fce9cea897" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >2</container>
          <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r4dn42123"
            xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new"
            xlink:title="Photographs of the Healys' safari, 1922" xpointer="ark:/87924/r4dn42123"/>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_2c093d3fbc66a727e026a47e8aed58db">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>169 photographs of the Healys' safari, guided by William Judd in Kenya, 1922. The
            photographs document their big game kills, including elephants, lions, rhinosaurus,
            leopards, and assorted deer. Also includes photographs of Maasai people, who appear to
            have been employed as guides and servants for the Healys, as well as images of the
            Healys' camp; their guide, William Judd; and a few assorted photographs of a ship,
            presumably taken during their journey back to the United States.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
