<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/hedrickbenjamin/"
         >hedrickbenjamin</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Benjamin Hedrick Papers, 1848-1893 <num>RL.00524</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Library Staff; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Meghan Lyon</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000856905</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-28 19:46:04
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Benjamin Hedrick papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Hedrick, Benjamin Sherwood, 1827-1886</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00524</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">20 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1848/1893" type="inclusive">1848-1893</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_d32ee83f4cf271a61a6b3163761dcec4">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_9341d42fe46b3e45ef3fdb99011afb2b">Professor of chemistry at the
            University of North Carolina, 1854-1856, and U.S. Patent Office official, 1861-1886.
            Chiefly letters to Hedrick. The early correspondence is between Hedrick and Mary Ellen
            Thompson, his future wife. Other correspondence concerns life at the University of North
            Carolina, Hedrick's dismissal from the University in 1856 for his Republican and
            anti-slavery opinions, and his life in the North during the Civil War period. Many of
            the post-1861 papers relate to Hedrick's position as chemical examiner at the Patent
            Office. Other topics include Reconstruction, the economic plight of the South, and
            politics, including Hedrick's attempt to win political office in North Carolina (1868).
            Correspondents include Kemp P. Battle, Daniel R. Goodloe, Horace Greeley, Hinton Rowan
            Helper, David L. Swain, John Torrey, and Jonathan Worth.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_e54498ec6097da78a05053799692bff5">
            <extent>6037 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_772445a34af9daa51ea2bb2bdf68daf1">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_3db6d7e9115c312844950d90c9792d56">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_4f024da02534b53501290278c9b83664">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_b6ecc84e0f9ab1bae997bad015b4def4">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Benjamin Hedrick Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_f868714eae7f6bcc21e5b8ad1a661b2b">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Benjamin Hedrick Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library in 1959.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_9dff35f818f4bff427c675f17198df4c">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library Staff, 1960s</p>
         <p>Encoded by Meghan Lyon, January 2011</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_c4a68b77f201dd27b664972838423ed8">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <chronlist>
            <head>Chronology List</head>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1827</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Born, Davidson County, N.C.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1851</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Graduated with highest honors, University of North Carolina at Chapel
                     Hill</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1851-1854</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Clerk, Nautical Almanac, Cambridge, Mass.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1852</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Married Mary Ellen Thompson</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1854-1856</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Professor of Chemistry Applied to Agriculture and the Arts, University of
                     North Carolina at Chapel Hill</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1856</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Expelled from UNC for views on slavery; left North Carolina</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1856-1857</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Travelled the northern states, looking for work</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1857</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Chemist, New York</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1858</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Clerk, Mayor's office, New York City</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1859</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Teacher, Cooper Union</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1861-1886</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Examiner, Patent Office, Washington, D.C.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>April 1865</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Agent, American Union Commission; toured N.C. and examined schools</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>January-March 1868</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Attended N.C. Constitutional Convention, Raleigh</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1868</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Candidate for Congress, N.C. 4th District (was defeated)</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1886</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Died, Washington, D.C.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
         </chronlist>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_87030a699b3b94ec87447fc509a52960">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>This collection consists mostly of letters to Benjamin S. Hedrick, Professor of
            Chemistry at the University of North Carolina, 1854-1856, and Examiner in the Patent
            Office, Washington, D.C., from 1861 until his death in 1886. In 1856, expelled from the
            University for his attitude on slavery, he found it necessary to leave North Carolina.
            However, it is evident from his correspondence that he maintained an intense concern for
            the welfare of his native state and employed his influence in Washington for the benefit
            of the state during the Civil War and Reconstruction period.</p>
         <p>The collection consists largely of correspondence between the Hedricks and their friends
            and colleagues. Early correspondence from 1848-1854 includes family news and affairs.
            Letters of courtship between Benjamin Hedrick and Mary Ellen Thompson, dated 1851-1852
            (before their marriage), mainly detail personal news and opinions on new fashions and
            trends, such as bloomers, temperance, and women's rights. Political events are also
            mentioned, including the Railroad Jubilee of September 1851, as well as Hedrick's
            impressions of Harvard and details about his activities while travelling in the
            North.</p>
         <p>Letters from 1854 discuss Hedrick's decision to accept the professorship position at the
            University of North Carolina and his subsequent plans for the program there. In 1856,
            Hedrick's article opposing slavery and endorsing John Fremont and the Republicans was
            published in the <title type="simple" render="italic">North Carolina Standard</title>.
            The collection includes both clippings, minute excerpts, and correspondence about his
            subsequent expulsion from the University. Also included are details about the publicity
            and negative reactions to Hedrick's views; one letter from Mary Ellen Thompson Hedrick
            recounts UNC students burning Hedrick in effigy. Letters from the Hedricks' friends and
            supporters describe their own troubles in finding work as a result of backing Hedrick,
            and also include updates on the political climate throughout the country. Hedrick's
            grandfather, Benjamin Sherwood, is a regular correspondent from Marion County, Iowa, and
            provides regular news and opinions on the conditions of the Midwest. He opposes slavery,
            Democratic Party, and immigration from Catholic countries, and favors letting the
            Southern states secede. His letters also include family history along with updates from
            Marion county activities. Know Nothings, President Buchanan's cabinet, and Kansas
            bloodshed are all discussed in letters from 1856-1857. </p>
         <p>After Hedrick's expulsion and departure from North Carolina, incoming letters from
            friends and family offer news and updates on Chapel Hill residents, including University
            of North Carolina adminstrators and professors; schools; crops and prices; as well as
            family news, courtships, and events. Several letters mention Hinton R. Helper's book,
               <title type="simple" render="italic">The Impending Crisis of the South: How to Meet
               It</title>, which Benjamin Hedrick helped promote in 1858. At one point, Hedrick is
            warned against travelling in North Carolina until after the presidential election, for
            his own safety.</p>
         <p>Following Lincoln's election in 1860, Benjamin Hedrick's letters describe the flood of
            Republicans moving to Washington, including his own relocation and pursuit of an
            appointment in the Patent Office. Included is a letter from March 1861 where he
            describes meeting President and Mrs. Lincoln. Meanwhile, letters to Hedrick from North
            Carolina mention secession fervor in Charleston, South Carolina, as well as preparations
            for arming white citizens against slave revolts or riots. The North Carolina convention
            and its delegates are discussed, as are preparations for war in both the North and the
            South. Hedrick writes about the feelings in Washington, while his stepsister describes
            sewing uniforms for soldiers in New Bern, North Carolina.</p>
         <p>There is little material directly related to the Civil War, apparently due to
            interruption of mail service between North Carolina and Washington. The letters within
            the collection include mention of several battles, including Fort Sumter, Bull Run,
            Gettysburg, and Chickamauga. The homefront is also reported on, including North
            Carolina's conscription laws, the confiscation of Union-sympathizers' property, the
            arrival of refugees, and the condition of UNC's campus. Politics are another frequent
            topic, including the Copperheads. </p>
         <p>One interesting component of the collection is a group of letters from John A. Hedrick,
            Benjamin Hedrick's brother and Internal Revenue Collector at Beaufort, N.C. John
            Hedrick's original letters are interfiled chronologically with the collection, and also
            exist in typewritten form, filed together at the end of letters from 1863. His reports
            from Beaufort mention the health and condition of the city; the arrival of refugees
            after the battle for Plymouth in April 1864; the spread of measles and smallpox; and his
            thoughts on the Massachusetts 55th Regiment, an African American regiment stationed in
            North Carolina. In February 1865, John Hedrick writes that the presence of African
            American Union troops keep Confederate troops away, since they do not like to fight
            black soldiers. His correspondence also mentions the death of Lincoln and Johnston's
            surrender to General Sherman. Post-war letters discuss North Carolina politics,
            universal suffrage, and crop-sharing by former slaves. He denounces W. W. Holden, the
            North Carolina provisional governor, and encourages Benjamin Hedrick to run. Later
            letters describe the North Carolina Constitional Convention and subsequent election of
            1868, where both brothers ran for Congress (Benjamin for the 4th District, John for the
            2nd District).</p>
         <p>Another notable sub-group of letters about the Civil War come from prisoners of war at
            Point Lookout, Old Capital, Camp Elmire, Fort Deleware, and Johnsons' Island prisons.
            The prisoner letters exist only in typewritten form; no originals remain with the
            collection. </p>
         <p>Following the surrender, correspondence transitions to discuss North Carolina's
            adjustment to Reconstruction. Benjamin Hedrick's visit to North Carolina results in a
            report to the Secretary of the Treasury that Carolina wants peace, and that hunger,
            crime, and speculation are serious problems for the population. Some letters to Hedrick
            complain about freedmen and their labor. Several correspondents discuss the poverty they
            face in the post-war period, both from their loss of property to the Confederacy and in
            their loss of slaves to emancipation. Many write to Hedrick asking for seeds. One
            notable letter to Hedrick from February 2, 1866, comes from Milly Walker, a former slave
            of D.L. Swain, who is searching for her father and three children, who had been owned by
            Dr. Shoaf of Washington.</p>
         <p>Another common topic in 1865 is Hedrick's efforts in establishing Internal Revenue
            districts throughout the state, resulting in much correspondence about the various posts
            and jobs that resulted. </p>
         <p>The political letters of value are found mostly between 1865 and 1870. There is much
            discussion of the election and its various components, including candidates W.W. Holden
            and Jonathon Worth; secret political parties, including the Red Strings; the distrust
            towards the military government; and the issue of universal suffrage. The Test Oath is
            strongly criticized as impossible, and North Carolina statehood, disenfranchisement, and
            inclusion into the Union is a regular concern for correspondents, including Hedrick.
            Many letters denounce W.W. Holden as provisional governor, who is accused of
            electioneering among the state's freedmen. Hedrick is asked multiple times to promote
            Jonathon Worth among Northern newspapers. Hedrick's own political ambitions are
            regularly discouraged by his wife, who in 1857 also writes that he should not accept the
            presidency of UNC. Several letters in 1858 mention signs of the Ku Klux Klan. Others
            discuss national politics and the impeachment of President Johnson. </p>
         <p>Letters from late 1868 and early 1869 detail the takeover of the University of North
            Carolina by Col. C.L. Harris and the subsequent appointment of Solomon Pool as
            president. With Holden as governor, Internal Revenue business in North Carolina beomes a
            regular topic of correspondence. In May 1869, Hedrick writes of his changing interest
            from politics to the growth of industry and the activities of the Patent Office. Later
            letters contain reports on North Carolina news and events, including the activities of
            the Ku Klux Klan, Governor Holden's impeachment, the Greensboro railroad, a report on
            the revitalization of UNC, and other political news. </p>
         <p>Another significant part of the collection consists of patent papers from Hedrick's
            career in the Patent Office, including reports and other information on disputed patent
            cases. </p>
         <p>In addition to the patent papers, there is an extensive and varied collection of printed
            materials that is helpful in glimpsing the personal, professional, and social life of a
            civil servant in post-Civil War Washington. Besides the usual accumulation of
            advertisements, calling cards, etc., there are numerous items on the Freemasons, the
            Cosmos Club of Washington, the American Association for the Advancement of Science and
            Art, and the formative years of the American Chemical Society, among others. One group
            of items deals with the litigation of the bankrupt house of Jay Cooke and Co., in which
            Hedrick had holdings. Another series of items contains commenement announcements, etc.,
            from the various schools and colleges with which the Hedrick family was associated
            (including Georgetown University, New York University, the United States Naval Academy,
            Cooper Union, Johns Hopkins, Rutgers Female Institute of New York City). Other items
            relate to political events of the mid-nineteenth century, such as a group of memorial
            exercises for Samuel F.B. Morse, James A. Garfield, and Charles Darwin, as well as an
            invitation to the services for the removal of James Monroe from New York to Richmond in
            1858. There are also a number of printed pieces relating directly to the events of the
            Civil War and Reconstruction era, including broadsides, announcements, pamphlets, and
            clippings. </p>
         <p>Bills and receipts cover four decades of business transactions, beginning with Hedrick's
            college days. Among the miscellaneous items are drafts of political speeches, newspaper
            articles (mostly ante-bellum), and an assortment of school papers and genealogical
            items. The bound volumes accompanying the collection are three memoradum books and one
            daybook.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877) -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Antislavery movements -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">College teachers -- Political activity</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Governors -- North Carolina</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Southern States -- Economic conditions</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Unionists (United States Civil War) -- North Carolina</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950</geogname>
         <persname source="ingest">Worth, Jonathan, 1802-1869</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill -- History</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Battle, Kemp P. (Kemp Plummer), 1831-1919</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Goodloe, Daniel R. (Daniel Reaves), 1814-1902</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Hedrick, Benjamin Sherwood, 1827-1886</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Hedrick, John</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Hedrick, Benjamin Sherwood, 1827-1886</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Holden, W.W. (William Woods), 1818-1892</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Ku Klux Klan (19th cent.)</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Hedrick, Mary Ellen Thompson</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Helper, Hinton Rowan, 1829-1909</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">United States. Patent Office -- Officials and
            employees</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill -- Faculty</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Swain, David L. (David Lowry), 1801-1868</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Torrey, John, 1796-1873</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref13_z9m" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence, 1848-1893 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_a16c0817910acd1bcd962c2dd06a230f">
                  <extent>15 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_gtj" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1848-1861</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d53cc5733f1eb5ea9aa7b10369db7eda" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_vym" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1861 May-1863 December</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_55ada7613d1d0e71a98fb5fc1485366a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_3ft" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Typescripts of letters from POWs, 1863-1864</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_95a3f5db7e9418fa2cc98c9883396d0a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_uml" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters from John A. Hedrick, 1862-1864</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4c2adc21a4fbfe59a1fbb146f5a9f481" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_f9c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1864</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ec06626d5f69c2da9a21f6249e157433" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_ef6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1865</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ebf361efa1d198567cdc020f7793b79e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_urd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1866</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_706faf1e1d90cc1649143405a5abb2ff" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_it7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1867 January-August</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_dcdfe3628470c3101a8d1e839e2bc355" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_r2w" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1867 September-1868</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3752dbf4566bbd4b583eaa93e2595f97" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_j73" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1869</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_95d9b9be265d1d50a828d35e5f00862b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_i1z" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1870-1871 July</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d5a36364de48dd0d1d2c9e7eaf22f2a6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_y9p" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1871 August-1872</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ec21b33c3c5f47794c14456ebd7f1b5b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">10</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_lbr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1873</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_28eb91989403d605b831db926222d182" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_97j" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1874</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ef16037c93e1b841c9a04dffcabcd9da" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_jpe" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1875-1876</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c3322f981a7f8b85bd8489a346597604" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_r47" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1877-1879 May</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_67f7eafe7427c047c134467a265f474d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_wir" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1879 June-1893 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c49daaef210cdb52330abb46413e7016" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">15</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref32_hba" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Patent papers, miscellany, printed materials, and volumes, 1850s-1885 and
                  undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_554b080e8cd72d2a1853af5e88c3467a">
                  <extent>5 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref34_zry" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Patent papers, 1862-1885</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_7bad1f45f158ccbd54e87803f7e49f59" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_vuo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Patent papers, miscellaneous dates</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f0a0574227935e47e8f7aca0a4b9c76f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">17</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref36_v4a" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bills, receipts, etc., 1850s-1880s and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8b828f5e11ac6b4fff7ce8b14d022a1e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">18</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref37_xjl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellany, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fb71441546ba5ac35760f184567d5c4a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">18</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref38_ptn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellany, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_dec6bbe9a2b53d3b9a92a44bbcc285a0" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">19</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref39_w7x" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed materials and clippings</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_518dbeb60c9e15f1b225f6343364336d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">19</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref40_4kr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed materials</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b399d47aa66cef86dec7f53b11128054" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">20</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref41_zt9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volumes (4)</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2054313ac3e3386d333020ee8759a47d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">20</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
