<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
         url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/henkelfamily/">henkelfamily</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Henkel Family Papers, 1812-1953 and undated
                  <num>RL.00532</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein staff; machine-readable finding aid created by: Paula
               Jeannet and Jennifer Snow</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2011</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000856919</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-11-01 16:21:24
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Henkel Family papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <famname source="ingest">Henkel family</famname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00532</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1812/1953" type="inclusive">1812-1953 and undated</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_873992b7465f8dbf614416ba5ffb2ce5">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_584d68c58fa8494500796d7b6190844f">Solomon, Ambrose, and Socrates
            Henkel were prominent Lutherant churchmen active in Virginia, Tennessee, and North
            Carolina. Correspondence (1812-1894), account books, and notes for sermons, articles and
            lectures, belonging to the Henkel family. The primary authors are Solomon and Ambrose
            Henkel, and their nephew, Socrates Henkel, prominent Lutheran churchmen. Includes
            information on the Lutheran Church in Virginia, Tennessee, and North Carolina, and on
            the publishing house Henkel Press, Inc., at New Market, Virginia. Some of the material
            is in German. The correspondence touches on many subjects, chiefly church matters, but
            there is a small group of Civil War letters from Henkel family members recounting
            battles (Fort Sumter; Mine Run, Va.), Union occupation, and camp life. One letter from
            1860 mentions the hanging of an abolitionist. Also included is a diary begun in 1802,
            written by Paul Henkel, with a transcription; there are also miscellaneous writings,
            items relating to religious music, and advertisements.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_63bed13a504603fc4c0bc16019067b0e">
            <extent>165 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_61b51c216748c19cd86beac2dd91ca3f">Material in English and German
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_14b252015f60b73471c663178f125c65">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_4496ac926083115d1f7c585baf014d7a">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_5daa612b571a38ce278be1e47a97fc22">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Henkel Family Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_61017a4bade531ceea9a671651a0fac3">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Henkel Family Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a gift from 1938-1958.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_15e55e5796e1ef5b6ddc584e2eb5fc6b">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by RMBSCL staff</p>
         <p>Encoded by Paula Jeannet and Jennifer Snow, April 2011</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_ab0bbd14219e7b1c8384f74ba3865c8f">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Solomon, Ambrose, and Socrates Henkel were prominent Lutherant churchmen active in
            Virginia, Tennessee, and North Carolina.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_4e865ca4866a0f47354bbad13dfe341b">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The Henkel Family Papers span the years from 1812-1953 and include correspondence
            (1812-1894), account books, and notes for sermons, articles and lectures, belonging to
            the Henkel family. The letters are described individually in this inventory. The primary
            authors are Solomon and Ambrose Henkel, and their nephew, Socrates Henkel, prominent
            Lutheran churchmen. Includes information on the Lutheran Church in Virginia, Tennessee,
            and North Carolina, and on the publishing house Henkel Press, Inc., at New Market,
            Virginia. Some of the material is in German. The correspondence touches on many
            subjects, chiefly church matters, but there is a small group of Civil War letters from
            Henkel family members recounting battles (Fort Sumter; Mine Run, Va.), Union occupation,
            and camp life. One letter from 1860 mentions the hanging of an abolitionist. Also
            included is a diary begun in 1802, written by Paul Henkel and transcribed by R. R. H.
            Baur; there are also miscellaneous writings, items relating to religious music, and
            advertisements.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <index id="aspace_31f4422e8996b7e8b148c9d534477108">
         <head>Index to Correspondence</head>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1812 July 5, Henry Rupert, Mason Co., Va., Point Pleasant, to (Ambrose H.)
               "Lieber Schwager" (German)</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1815 3 Aug., warrantee deed, John Roush, Mason Co., Va., to Ambrose H. One lot
               and 2 portions of another in or near Point Pleasant, "part of Michael Secrist's five
               acre lot." Witnesses: Gideon H., Andrew H., Henry Rupert.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1815 Dec. 28, Solomon H. to Samuel Strakler, member General Assembly, Richmond.
               Application for copyrights.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1816 June 1, Henry Othane, no origin, to (Doctor Henkel), request for
               medicine.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1816 July 3, Joseph Funk, Rockingham Co., to William Marshall, Clerk of District
               of Va., Richmond, Application for copyright. Enc. title page, "Die allgemein
               nutzliche Choral - Music." Harrisonburg: Laurentz Wartmann.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1817 Feb. 9, recto numbered 1 to 10 hymn stanza (German)</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1817 Sept. 15, Solomon H. to no name re copyright, no date, Copy Ms Title pages:
               "Das Kleine ABC Buch" etc. and "Der Christliche Catechismus" etc. (1817) Title page
               "Das grosse ABC Buch" etc.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1818 Feb. 11, verso numbered 1 to 6 hymn stanza (German)</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>13 June 1820, no signature, (Paul H.?), "bei den David"(Lincolnton NC) to Solomon
               H. Report on meeting of N.C. Synod, 1820 May 28.(German)</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1821 Aug. 26, Johannes Beck and others (7 signatures)(Lexington, NC) to David H.
               Request for pastoral services. (German)</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1821 July 15, John Miller Winchester to Solomon H. Postmaster. Re loss of a
               letter from Miller and of money en route.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1821 Oct. 6, Schulhaus Kirche (Lincoln Co. NC) 22 signatures to ELTS.
               Certification of Daniel Lutz as delegate and request for assistance of David H.
               (German)</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1822 Aug 8, Georg Gutmann to Ambrose H. and __ H. Excuse for absence from Synod.
               Request for clarification re decisions of Synod by majority vote. (German)</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1826 Nov. 5, Friedrich Wilhelm van der Hoot, Shenand. Co., Tenn., to Ambrose H.
               (German)</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1827 Jan. 9, David H. (no origin) to Lieber Bruder (no address).
               Personal.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1827 Sept. 23, David H., Lincoln Co., NC, to 6 Virginia congregations. Report on
               Synod meeting and request for contributions for printing minutes. (German)</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1828 Dec. 22, Geo. H. - - -, Baltimore, to Solomon H. Re an order of supplies for
               Henkel's stove.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1831 June 1, C.T. Page, Alexandria, to Solomon H. acknowledging receipt of
               money.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1831 July 3, J.H. Whitly, Richmond, to D. Boyd (no address). Note forwarding
               "nine piece Henkel and Funk copyright manuscripts, etc. for your
               consideration."</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1832 April 6, John N. Stirewalt, Waynesborough, Va., to Ambrose H. Re preaching
               appointment for Ambrose and family matters.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1832 April 17, Catherine H., Oxfords Ford, Lincoln Co., NC, to Ambrose H. and
               Mrs. ____ H. Re death of husband (David H.) and resulting matters of family
               business</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1832 Aug. 13, Rankin "N.C. Buncombe" outside: "Ashev. N.C." to ELTS, outside:
               Ambrose H. Sec. Hokesville P.O. Lincoln Co. N.C. Excuse for absence and review of
               year's ministry in Tenn. and Ga. States position re doctrine and
               "ceremonies."</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1832 Sept. 14, J.N. Stirewalt, Rowan Co., NC, to Ambrose H. Report on Synod. "Our
               friends have lost their right in the organ church..." Resolution to revise Old
               Church-Hymnal Book (by P.H.) Ambrose is to criticise "both Doct. and Language, etc.
               etc."</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1834 April 3, D. Danner, Middletown, Va., to Solomon H. Request for S.H. to
               become agent for a transportation route between Winchester and Harrisonburg. Stations
               and fares listed.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1835 Jan. 18, Jacob Stirewalt (Rowan Co. N.C.) to much esteemed Uncle (Ambrose
               H.), personal.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1835 April 5, Jacob Stirewalt, ditto, personal.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1836 March 10, J.N. Stirewalt, Rowan Co., NC, to Dear Brother in law (Ambrose
               H.), personal.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1838 Feb. 10, Adam S. Link, Green Co., Xenia O., to Ambrose H. Request for help
               in transferring from O. to Va. "I find I can not get along in this western country as
               it regards doctrine..." Wants to become Ambrose's assistant.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1838 March 1, G.M.T.S. Pennybacker and S.T. Newland, Pine Forge, to Solomon H.
               Bill of lading for "Bar Iron at $120. per ton - - - $125.35 1/2."</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1838 June 25, Rob. B. Wolfe Winchester to Solomon H. re transfer of money,
               availability of a "clipping machine" and sending of pigs.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1839 Jan. 8, B. Blackford and son, Isabella Furnace, re order of a stove and
               price of "Plaister Breakers."</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1839 July 30, Lloyd Logan, Winchester, to Solomon H. Bill for 1 Gross Bonnet
               Board... $5.50 and 1 Box Plug Tobacco... $28.20.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1839 Oct. 1, John Harr, Sullivan Co., Tenn (Whites Stove), to Solomon H. re
               shipment of books.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1840 May 4, John Harr, ditto, to Solomon H. order for 25 hymnbooks.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1840 Feb. 10, Henry Wetzel, Mount Solon, August Co., Va., to Solomon H. Re
               conflict in Pendleton congregations over raising subscription for Wetzel Two at least
               want Rev. Geo. Schmucker who has been selling S.S. Schmucker's book in P. Co.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1842 May 19, G. Jordan, Luray, Va., to Solomon H. Re shipment of cotton
               yarn.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1842 Dec. 2, Polycarp H., Lincoln Co., NC, to Ambrose H. Personal.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1843 Aug. 29, Catherine H., Carawba Co., NC, to Ambrose H. Personal: Death of
               "old grandmother" (Paul's widow).</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1845 Sept. 19, Wm. Huncher, Sullivan Co., Tenn., to ELTS Zion Church Shen. Co.
               Va. Excuse for absence.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1846 July 20, Polycarp H., Caldwell City, NC, to Socrates. Personal: Polycarp's
               ministry. Adam Miller.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1847 July 31, P. Hoke, Lincolnton, NC, to Ambrose H. Re "Adam Miller's
               unfortunate case."</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1847 Aug. 24, Polycarp H., Flint Rock, Catawba Co., NC, to Rev. Uncle (Ambrose).
               Personal/Synodical: preparing to open his case again. "...the North Carolina
               generalists will be at our next Synod in order to try to affect (sic) a
               union..."</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1849 July 8, Eleonora H., Catawba Co., NC (Jacobs Fork), to Dear Brother
               (Socrates). Personal: re family members, birth, marriages.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1850 Jan., no signature, New Market, to "Esteemed friend," no address. Personal
               (woman).</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1850 May 8, Meredith Spencer and Co., Baltimore, to A. Henkel and Son. Shipment
               of Dry goods $75.41.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1850 May 30, Polycarp H., Jacobs Fork, Catawba Co., NC, to Socrates H. Personal:
               reference to Book of Concord.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1850 Aug. 15, ditto, personal: transfer of money.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1851 March 3, ditto, personal: Book of Concord, family names.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1851 April 30, ditto, re Adam Miller case.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1852 Feb. 18, ditto, personal: death of Mrs. Adam Miller.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1853 Jan. 22, John F. Stirewalt, Rowan Co., NC, to Ambrose H. Send D.H. Herald of
               Liberty. "I need one of those books to whip the Generalists here." (See P.C. to A. 24
               Aug. 1847).</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1853 Sept. 6, Polycarp H., Jacobs Fork, Catawba Co., NC, to Socrates H. Personal:
               Rebecca's health, "Miller is still fighting," P.C.'s ministry.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1853 Oct. 1, A.J. Fox, Mount Toth, Ala., to ELTS Emmanuel Ch. Sullivan Co. Tenn.
               excuse for absence.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1853 Dec. 6, Joel Swartz, Cedar Creek (Va.), to Socrates H. Wishes to return to
               ministry from teaching.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1854 Aug. 25, Rebecca H., Jacobs Fork, Catawba Co., NC, to Socrates H. Personal:
               requests help with his churches for PCH, Miller case, family references. P.S. by
               Polycarp - large order for Henkel publications.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1855 July 2, F.K. Killian, Waynesboro, Va., to Socrates H. Suggests "forming a
               Conference in the valley."</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1855 July 29, Simon Clem to Socrates H. "Thanks for getting board for my
               daughter."</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1857 April 13, J. Killian, Waynesboro, Va., to Socrates H. Re travel / time
               problem in attending "your communion meeting" and "our Conference." Need to report
               proceedings of Va. Conference in the Lutheran Standard.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1857 June 22, H. Wetzel, Mount Solon, Va., to Socrates H. Re date of first
               meeting of "our Conference." Need to counteract influence of Presbyterians thru their
               ecclesiastical meetings. P.S. re an apprenticeship in the printing business. Second
               hand: draft of invitation to annual examination at New Market Female
               Seminary.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1857 Aug. 24, D. Kunkle, Pond Gap, Va., to S. Paul, Mt. Solon, Va., re collecting
               a note.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1857 Sept. 12, J. Killian, Waynesboro, Va., to ELTS, Little Chucky Green Co.,
               Tenn., Excuse for absence. "I (J.K. Hancher) have taken a vote of my congregations
               and find them unanimously opposed to a division of Synod..."</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1858 Jan. 12, J.H. Hunton, Pleasant Dale, to Socrates H. Re payment of a
               subscription to Lutheran Standard. Description of what he would like in a wife. Asks
               help and advice.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1858 Feb. 4, David S.H. (child), Newton, NC, to Socrates H. Re school, family
               references, death of brother Philip.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1858 March 23, Adam Ketteman, Hardy Co., Va., to Socrates H. Requests S. to
               supply.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1858 Nov. 15, Polycarp H., Newton, NC, to Socrates H. States position re
               formation of "Missionary Conference" in Va. Effects on division of Synod (NC-Va).
               Position of Jacob Stirewalt. Remarks on revision of Constitution and grades of
               ministry.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1859 March 8, ditto, reference to revision of "confessional basis" at Synod.
               Recommendation of John I. Bennick for theological studies. Personal Matters.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1859 May 23, H. Wetzel, Baltimore, to Socrates H. "Tell SGH I am translating the
               Postil." Attended "Predigers Conference," Statement re Communion, private confession.
               Personal matters.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1860 Jan. 3, Polycarp H., Newton, NC, to Socrates H. More re. revision of
               Constitution (see 1859 March 8), one abolitionist hanged, statement re professional
               ethics, personal matters.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1860 Jan. 11, Martin Sondhous, Logan Hocking Co., O., to Socrates H. re his
               dismissal from his Va. pastorate.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1861 May 4, Lucius C. Worley, Fort Moultrie, Charleston, SC, to "Dear Cousin."
               Personal experiences during "Battle of Sumpter."</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1861 Oct. 8, J.B. Hawkins, Fort Moultrie, to J.C. Worley, personal
               matters.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1861 Nov. 13, Mary Be-onson, Mt. Meridian, Augusta Co., Va., to Mr. Worley.
               Please return my letter.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1861 Dec. 17, Samuel G.H., New Market, to J.C. Worley (no address). Directions
               for taking medicine.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1862 March 14, H. Ingold, Flint Rock, Catawba Co., NC., to Socrates H. and wife.
               Re death of wife.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1863 July 31, P.P. Henkel, Richmond, to "Dear Cousin" (no address). War
               conditions in coastal N.C.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1863 Dec. 5, Casper C.H., Camp Stewart's Brig., to "Dear friend Davie." Details
               of a battle, Mine Run, Va.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1864 March 30, Polycarp H., Newton, NC, to S. Henkel. Re call meeting of Synod,
               trouble over proposed revision of constitution.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1864 Sept. 15, C. Henkel ("your brother"), Camp near Winchester, to Socrates H.
               Personal.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1865 Feb. 22, Polycarp H., Newton NC, to S(ocrates) H. Attitudes and predictions
               re outcome of war. Son David's service as chaplain.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1865 Dec. 20, ditto, Yankee occupation. Debate with Baptist R.H. Moody in Burke
               Co. on subject of baptism.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1868 Dec. 29, ditto, Son David's personal troubles.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1869 Jan. 1, ditto, More re son David.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1869 July 18, Rebecca H., Catawba Co., NC, to "Respected Brother" (Socrates); and
               Eleonora H. to "Dear Brother," family matters, report on marriages.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1869 Sept. 3, Thos. Crouse, Sandy Creek, Randolph Co., NC, to S. Henkel. Order
               for copies "Luther's Church Postil."</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1869 July 30, E.H. McDonald, Louisville, to "Dear William." Re lost note and
               personal matters.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1873 July 14, A.W. McKim, Luray Va., to Henkel and Co. Re printing catalogue for
               "Luray Female Institute."</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1873 Nov. 23, J.R. Moser, Gravitton, Wayne Co., Mo., to S. Henkel. Report on "our
               conference," recent meeting and relations with St. Louis Conference of the Mo.
               Synod.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>n.d. Rev. I . Henkel A.M. to ___ New Market Re relation of Conference to Synod.
               (portion of letter only)</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1881 July 10, Lisette, "Oceanside" Summer Rest, to Ambrose H. 25 pages.
               Reconciliation with A. Relationship of young people. Plans re "establishing a large
               printing, binding and engraving house..." Father is a pastor (Wilmington?). Meeting
               of NC Press Assoc. Winston NC.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>1894 Nov. 1, Cillie Tropper (?) to "Sister," personal.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>No year, March 20, R.I.H., Mt. Fern, Madison Co., Va., to "Rev. S. Henkel."
               Business and report on unseccessful operation in camp on John's nose.</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>Undated, Bill S.D. Henkel and Bros. to C. Hostler "1/2 doz. Boxes Pills at
               $2.00."</title>
         </indexentry>
         <indexentry>
            <title>Undated, Booklet, sample of forms for legal documents. At end on reused sheet,
               "1825 January 8th at meeting of ___ board of the Trustees of the Walnut Spr___ School
               and meeting house. Present (5 names) ... to elect a member as Trustee in the room of
               Philip Miller deseased." On cover: Daniel Stickley.</title>
         </indexentry>
      </index>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Virginia -- Religious life and customs</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Tennessee -- Religious life and customs</geogname>
         <genreform source="aat">Diaries</genreform>
         <geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal
            narratives, Confederate</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Soldiers -- Virginia -- Correspondence</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina -- Religious life and customs</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Virginia -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives,
            Confederate</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Publishers and publishing -- Virginia -- New Market</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">German Americans -- Virginia</subject>
         <corpname source="ingest">Henkel Press (New Market, Va.)</corpname>
         <famname source="ingest">Henkel family</famname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Lutheran Church -- Southern States</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Lutheran Church -- Sermons</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Lutheran Church -- Clergy -- Correspondence</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_8tk" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Henkel Family Papers, 1812-1953 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_ac6086cc1fea364bb51876b1f9dd78a8">
                  <extent>12 folders</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_zuz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Information folder on collection</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a6894d6550a023847fe1757b6272df3c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_kuy" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1812-1910 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_21282e4b6b9f0fee7d189c353465d6e4">
                     <extent>3 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_d11f13fbb539c70d5338defcc5319281" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_4hc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellany (various writings, advertisements)</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ba344092279931f3bfd3dc57158a9839" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_0io" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Print materials 1891-1953, and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5a37c25a4f07b32c1727d992f2f5b964" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_m7n" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Paul Henkel diary, 1802-undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4c659011ee8584d2d66cc178f245d318" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_87ecf0e570504e4c356fffb7098298e0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Transliteration and transcript by Dr. R.H. Baur.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_fbu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volumes, writings</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_5b985841ef12588cc1688a5252ae7f49">
                     <extent>5 folder</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_629e2589735208f2c806f511b0c003cd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
