<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/hubbellruth/">hubbellruth</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Ruth Ann Hubbell Papers, 1905-1986 and undated, bulk 1926-1972
                  <num>RL.00583</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Aaron Thornburg; machine-readable finding aid created by: Aaron
               Thornburg</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000856925</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-28 20:30:00
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Ruth Ann Hubbell papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Hubbell, Ruth Ann</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00583</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.2 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1905/1986" type="inclusive">1905-1986 and undated, bulk
            1926-1972</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_0286402d61e206265776fac8a29f0bea">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_c6a35b04e69da8b3282d78a1fae8ed24">Poet and librarian, of Washington,
            D.C. Also sister of Jay B. Hubbell, Professor of American Literature, Duke University.
            The Ruth Ann Hubbell papers span the years from 1905 to 1986, with the bulk dating from
            1926 to 1972. The collection consists mainly of correspondence between Ruth Ann Hubbell,
            her brother Jay Broadus Hubbell, and other members of the Hubbell family, but there are
            also some materials on the establishment of the Hubbell Center at Duke University, a
            small group of photographs, and folders of writings by Ruth Ann Hubbell, Jay Broadus
            Hubbell, Paul Edgar Hubbell, and other individuals. The collection is divided into six
            series: Clippings, Correspondence, Jay B. Hubbell Center for American Literary
            Historiography, Miscellany, Pictures, and Writings.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_f118c30e5e5022526fdc8eb745a44f9a">
            <extent>200 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_1bbcb741a7b0a3d8bfc9b4c6c509b8c2">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_447300d57591c9e1ece825186d4fce53">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_90912aaa6c691f61505131e111cf48a2">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_6a2dee5e90080e1bcdae30524ddab349">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Ruth Ann Hubbell Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_b67c525368eeab4dcfc1114698538d30">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Ruth Ann Hubbell Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a gift in 1980 and 1986.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_0fc01196d58eedf9e79e0dd2e45c6348">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Aaron Thornburg, April 2009</p>
         <p>Encoded by Aaron Thornburg, April 2009</p>
         <p>Accessions from 1980 and 1986 were merged into one collection, described in this finding
            aid. </p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_d70e1bd145abcbb3bb366ceaa3fe794a">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Ruth Ann Hubbell was born in Smyth County, Virginia and grew up in western Virginia and
            North Carolina. She attended high school in Elkin, North Carolina. She received a B.A.
            from Meredith College in Raleigh, North Carolina, in 1919 and began teaching at the
            primary level. She returned to graduate study at Columbia University in New York, where
            she received a Master's in English in 1921. Then she studied psychology for a year at
            New York University. She taught briefly at Denton, Colorado; Appalchian State Teachers
            College, Boone, North Carolina; and Intermont, Virginia. She returned to New York and
            studied Library Science at New York City College, receiving a certificate in 1926. She
            then accepted a position in the Public Library in Washington, D.C. as Reference
            Assistant and Assistant Director of Adult Work. She remained there from 1926 to 1932,
            when she trasferred to the Northeast Branch as Reference Librarian. In 1939, she
            returned to the Central Library as Readers' Advisor in Literature where she worked for
            two years before going to the Georgetown Branch as Reference Librarian. At the time of
            her retirement in 1965, she was Reference Librarian and First Assistant in the
            Georgetown Branch. After retirement, she traveled extensively and was active in church
            and club work. She wrote a number of poems that were accepted for publication in
            numerous magazines. Copies of many of these poems were sent to her brother, Jay Broadus
            Hubbell, professor of literature at Duke University, and may be found in the
            biographical materials in the Jay B. Hubbell Papers in the Rubenstein Library at
            Duke.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_4b526b7b146ec81c0e8f6dd7887f48f0">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The Ruth Ann Hubbell Papers span the years from 1905 to 1986, with the bulk dating from
            1926 to 1972. The collection consists mainly of correspondence between Ruth Ann Hubbell,
            her brother Jay Broadus Hubbell, and other members of the Hubbell family, but there are
            also some materials on the establishment of the Hubbell Center at Duke University, and
            some photographs and writings of Ruth Ann Hubbell, Jay Broadus Hubbell, Paul Edgar
            Hubbell (their brother), and other individuals. The collection is divided into six
            series: Clippings, Correspondence, Jay B. Hubbell Center for American Literary
            Historiography, Miscellany, Photographs, and Writings. These series are described fully
            below.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">American literature -- Southern States -- History and
            criticism</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">American poetry</genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women poets</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women authors</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Poets, American -- 20th century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Scholars -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">College teachers as authors</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Scholars -- Correspondence</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">American literature -- Study and teaching</subject>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Faculty</corpname>
         <famname source="ingest">Eller family</famname>
         <persname source="ingest">Hubbell, Ruth Ann</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Jay B. Hubbell Center for American Literary
            Historiography</corpname>
         <famname source="ingest">Hubbell family</famname>
         <persname source="ingest">Hubbell, Jay B. (Jay Broadus), 1885-1979</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Modern Language Association of America. American Literature
            Section</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_ler" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Ruth Hubbel Papers</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref13_97n" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Clippings Series, 1953-1982 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_61a0d3789ba4a077576bed76494894b4">
                     <extent>1 folder</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_88a96f22a1000494ecc57bf43256f73c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d91b061ed976f21804c5b2a9f2c62c43">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Folder containing clippings of book reviews written by Jay Broadus Hubbell,
                     reviews of books written by Jay Broadus Hubbell, obituaries of Ruth Eller
                     Hubbell (mother of Ruth Ann and Jay Broadus Hubbell), notices of exhibits of
                     materials from the Jay B. Hubbell Center for American Literary Historiography
                     displayed in Perkins Library, and other matters.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_r9u" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence Series, 1905-1986 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_cb47d34c63c554adcb6094ac74c7bbcc">
                     <extent>8 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_0884b733a8b3d95f9f475fc330539ed4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ed1979d78c0a55103d6198a26b00667f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Contains mainly letters from Jay Broadus Hubbell to his sister Ruth Ann and
                     their parents. Most of the parental letters are to Ruth Eller Hubbell, mother
                     of Ruth Ann and her siblings, who after her husband's death in 1941 lived in
                     Washington near Ruth Ann. Among the early letters are a few from Eller and Paul
                     Hubbell, brothers of Ruth Ann and Jay Broadus, to Jay Broadus relating to their
                     experiences and asking advice on courses to be taken as students at Fork Union
                     Military Academy, Fork Union, Virginia. Letters from Ruth Ann to Jay Broadus
                     are also present in the series. Although many of the letters discuss family
                     concerns, Jay Broadus also tells of his writings, organizational work, and his
                     teaching at Southern Methodist University, Duke University, Vienna, Athens,
                     Columbia, Kentucky, Virginia, and Clemson universities. Jay Broadus discusses
                     the differences between students in Vienna and Athens, comparing them to
                     American students. Dispersed throughout the stationary letters are postcards
                     and greetings cards. Clippings or photographs accompany some of the
                     correspondence.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_7zm" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Jay B. Hubbell Center for American Literary Historiography Series,
                     1975-1977</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_466834b318d0a09205bc03a175beba60">
                     <extent>1 folder</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_98809d23b0a2be45fa71ccbbf765153a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ca6cbc2bccd08da0446d7828dbe4039a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Comprised of a small number of items relating to the establishment of the Jay
                     B. Hubbell Center. Included among these is a proposal for the Center; a copy of
                     the February 6, 1976, <emph render="italic">The University Letter</emph> of
                     Duke University announcing the establishment of the Center; an announcement
                     card for the Center; a photocopy of the announcement of the establishment of
                     the Center that appeared in the November 1976 issue of <emph render="italic"
                        >American Literature;</emph> an announcement written by Jay B. Hubbell
                     explaining the Center's mission, collection, and desired materials; two copies
                     of an article about the Center written by Louis J. Budd that appeared in the
                     Spring 1977 issue of <emph render="italic">Resources for American Literary
                        Study</emph>; and a copy of the September 1976 issue of Duke University
                     Libraries' newsletter, <emph render="italic">Library Notes</emph> that contains
                     an announcement of the establishment of the Center.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_w9j" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellany Series, 1925, 1936, 1947, 1975, 1978, and
                     undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_7bc0eac46d229482a78e667debd3f633">
                     <extent>1 folder</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_dc21b885acaba7411f177bdec97ab641" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_810873cc4c242044c4edb8ea46fdf705">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Comprised of a single folder of varied and most often undated materials. A
                     large proportion of the materials in this series are printed materials. These
                     printed materials include information pamphlets for historical sites, museums,
                     a convalescent center, and other institutions in the Raleigh/Durham/Chapel
                     Hill, North Carolina, area as well as for sites on Duke University and
                     University of North Carolina-Chapel Hill campuses. Advertising and marketing
                     pamphlets for books written by or produced in honor of Jay B. Hubbell as well
                     as a marketing pamphlet for a collection of poetry written by John Hall
                     Wheelock are included. An informational bulletin for the tenth session of The
                     Writers' Conference held at the University of New Hamphire in 1947 and a 1978
                     informational newsletter advertising summer events at Duke University are also
                     in the series. A 1925 Bulletin of Southern Methodist University announcing
                     awards for the Fourth Annual Poetry Contest is also included. A business card
                     for "Jay B. Hubbell, Ph.D., Professor of American Literature" completes the
                     printed materials. A number of handwritten or hand-typed lists are also
                     included in the series. Of potential research interest is a handwritten "List
                     of Books by Jay B. Hubbell with others he owned or valued" and a typed list of
                     "Graduate Students in English Department Duke University" including their
                     dissertation topics, page length, advisors, and years. In addition, the series
                     contains a few personl items, such as a book plate of Ruth Anne Hubbell (that
                     bears the coat of arms of the Hubbell family), a Mu Sigma Rho banner from
                     Richmond College, a "Prayer of St. Francis" bookmark, and other items.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_0ja" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photographs Series, 1918, 1949, and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_7b8bc1e093f099a3fd538946efcf7fd2">
                     <extent>1 folder</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_6bac6e2195f4e3b5f019f1103f47b536" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0f6c1f7c59bfa2cee54849249dd18ca6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Comprised of a single folder containing thirteen photographs of family,
                     friends, acquaintances of Jay Broadus and/or Ruth Ann Hubbell. These include
                     photographs of Ruth Eller Hubbell (Jay Broadus and Ruth Ann Hubbell's mother),
                     David Shelton Hubbell (Jay Broadus and Ruth Ann Hubbell's father), two
                     photographs of Jay Broadus Hubbell as a young man, a 1918 photograph of Jay
                     Broadus Hubbell in military uniform, two group photographs from the Writers'
                     Conference at the University of New Hampshire in 1949, a 1949 photograph of
                     Robert Frost, a photograph of a quartet of friends of Jay Broadus Hubbell from
                     Tulane University, and four photographs of an unidentified male.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_fjm" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Writings Series, 1910-1986 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_520969d24d833d959dffe9cedea46353">
                     <extent>6 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_71c8d39f5bf269b1b5ae11e5f532413f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c63aaeac308e00c91e4dcfdedc43552d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Comprised of six folders containing the writings of Ruth Ann, Jay Broadus, and
                     Paul Edgar Hubbell, as well as writings of miscellaneous other authors. The
                     first folder in this series contains <emph render="italic">Prose and Poetry by
                        Ruth Ann Hubbell</emph> a saddle-stiched volume. The second, third, and
                     fourth folders in this series contain writings of Jay Broadus Hubbell in
                     journals, books, and other formats. The fifth folder in the series contains
                        <emph render="italic">American Poems from Grant Street Volume IV being Grant
                        Street Verse Volume X with Michigan Poets Plus</emph> by Paul Edgar Hubbell,
                     brother of Ruth Ann and Jay Broadus Hubbell. The final folder of the series
                     contains various writings by miscellaneous authors, including
                     obituaries/memoriams of Jay Broadus, a resolution expressing mourning for the
                     death of Jay Broadus, remarks of Henry Nash Smith (a former student of Jay
                     Broadus) on the occassion of being awarded the Jay B. Hubbell Medallion, and
                     two books of genealogical relevance to the Hubbell and Eller families.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
