<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="https://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/jwtstaffminutes/">jwtstaffminutes</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Staff Meeting Minutes, 1927-1938
            <num>RL.00749</num></titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: Rhonda Mawhood; machine-readable finding aid created by: Stephen
          Douglas Miller, Alvin Pollock</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>1994</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">002471957</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-07-23 16:16:58
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2014</date>
        <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported to
          Archivists Toolkit</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>J. Walter Thompson Company. Staff Meeting Minutes</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname source="ingest">J. Walter Thompson Company</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.00749</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.8 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1927/1952" type="inclusive">1927-1938, 1951-1952</unitdate>
      <physloc id="aspace_3e06d10987d378ea2f483c89a6e4b7e5">For current information on the location
        of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
      <physdesc id="aspace_5790ee847e24f8c9647b4f7b9df739d3"><extent>3600 Items</extent></physdesc>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_4700b6f53bbc93cd3b7156eb3c642e7b">English. </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_66b90abb02d9744a15d0c07f04d3e33b">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Access to the originals is restricted. Photocopies are available for general use.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.</p>
      <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_4ed3ef021dc0cbaffa7e817c2eedb16b">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in the J. Walter Thompson Company. Staff Meeting Minutes have not
        been transferred to Duke University. For further information, see the section on copyright
        in the Regulations and Procedures of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript
        Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_36c99bc8732c2857624a9183eaf26d34">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], J. Walter Thompson Company. Staff Meeting Minutes, 1927-1938,
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_90eb68c63f4a46ed20719908bc48e817">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Staff Meeting Minutes were transferred to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library from the J. Walter Thompson Company in 1987.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo id="aspace_4978ffe08414f91008712865d63875da">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processing of this collection was supported in part by gifts from the J. Walter Thompson
        Company Fund and the John and Kelly Hartman Foundation.</p>
      <p>Processed by: Rhonda Mawhood</p>
      <p>Completed August 22, 1994</p>
      <p>Encoded by Stephen Douglas Miller, Alvin Pollock</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_f9f1126f33204269b9cd0e0cb006a85d">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>Chiefly verbatim minutes of staff meetings of the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT)
        including Account Representatives' Meetings, Creative Organization Meetings, JWT Forum,
        Monday Evening Meetings, and Apprentice Group Meetings. Also included are advertisements,
        photographs, and other printed material attached to minutes as background material for the
        meetings. Topics discussed at the various staff meetings include account histories, new
        business prospects, market research, activities of foreign and domestic JWT offices,
        development and use of advertising media (print, radio, billboards, film, television),
        social trends, and general business conditions. Some minutes include market research
        reports.</p>
      <p>The Account Representatives' Meetings deal mostly with specific accounts and offices, and
        with business conditions. The Creative Organization Meetings and JWT Forum usually consisted
        of a lecture by a staff member and focused on advertising practices and account histories.
        The Monday Evening Meetings were a lecture series featuring prominent outside speakers on
        general interest topics. The Apprentice Group Meetings were luncheon lectures by senior
        staff members. Among the outside speakers at the various staff meetings were Clarence
        Darrow, Edward J. Steichen, and Margaret Bourke-White. Speakers from inside the company
        included Stanley B. Resor, John B. Watson, William L. Day, William C. Esty, and Ruth Waldo.
        All minutes are from the New York office of JWT. All minutes are from the years 1927-1938.
        There are some gaps within those years.</p>
      <p>The collection contains a set of photocopies of the all the meeting minutes, designated as
          <emph render="doublequote">Use Copies.</emph> Also included is a set of originals of all
        the meeting minutes which are restricted.</p>
      <p>A summary list of the meetings, with selected topics of discussion and speakers, follows
        the container list. In addition there is also an detailed index compiled by company staff,
        which may be contemporaneous with the minutes. The indexes for the meetings are filed at the
        end of each series. The company index is fuller than the summary list, but its form is
        idiosyncratic and cumbersome.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Advertising agencies -- Management</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Advertising agencies -- United States -- History</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Minutes</genreform>
      <subject source="lcsh">Advertising agencies -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Advertising agencies</subject>
      <corpname source="naf">John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising &amp; Marketing
        History</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">J. Walter Thompson Company</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref10_lmx" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Use Copies</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref11_y8v" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Account Representatives' Meetings Series, 1927-1932</unittitle>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_e0bc0fa3d4a26832d90da1740f7e336e">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The minutes of weekly Representatives' meetings form the bulk of all minutes.
              Representatives and guest speakers from within and outside JWT discuss advertising
              campaigns and their results, account histories, new business prospects, strengths and
              weaknesses of advertising media (magazines, newspapers, billboards, radio, and TV),
              ethics and standards in advertising, and general business conditions.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_c932fe70101fbe80da3598e30040878f">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The contents are arranged in chronological order with some gaps. There are occasional
              inserts to minutes, such as advertisements, photos of store window displays from 1932,
              and a booklet on "Indian Sign Language" by Chief Buffalo Child/Long Lance, a Hollywood
              actor (introduction by athlete Jim Thorpe).</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_f127680a36e1d508bf209b15e77aaf53">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The minutes cover the period when JWT was expanding abroad, particularly in the
              Canadian and South American markets, and include reports from employees of foreign
              offices. These give their impressions of other countries, the countries'
              "progressivism" (by such criteria as industrialization), and their various racial and
              linguistic groups. They also outline JWT employees' goals for foreign expansion of US
              business. Research reports on foreign markets give data such as literacy figures,
              population densities, and per capita incomes, and refer to social and political trends
              (including anti-Americanism). There is occasional correspondence from employees in
              Europe and Asia.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_8843c7250554af37ecfe8ad58430f4c4">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>A wide variety of JWT accounts are discussed, making these minutes an important
              resource for anyone interested in particular campaigns. Minutes include market
              research reports on JWT clients and their competitors. There are discussions of new
              products entering the market (e.g. concentrated orange juice), and the development of
              new advertising media, especially the exploitation of outdoor billboards (important as
              automobiles became more numerous), radio, and advertising films and TV. The August 9,
              1927 minutes discuss cigarette advertising, while those from October 3, 1928 discuss
              Moxie, a competitor of Coca-Cola. The May 1, 1929 minutes discuss the Cream of Wheat
              HCB Club for children, an example of advertising to children through mothers and
              schools. Arranged chronologically by meeting date.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref12_ck7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Meeting Minutes (1927, January 11-1929, April 24)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_1ac074db2eb67dd93573bbea08257e5e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">U1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref13_odr" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Meeting Minutes (1929, May 1-1930, August 26)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_8eaf16d6fd6b5c71b769903442f9fd26" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">U2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref14_596" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Meeting Minutes (1930, September 9 -1931, May 26)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_56764a6d209ad08fc0f3d403ba487f58" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">U3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref15_fw6" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Meeting Minutes (1931, June 2-1932, February 16)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_9cd6ac22d299e65db5682acec4f88d6e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">U4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref20_lrk" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Creative Organization Meetings Series, 1932-1934.</unittitle>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_e975658508846610b870770a682a6007">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Creative Organization staff meetings were held on a weekly basis between March 1932
              and May 1933, with additional meetings in January and February 1934. Top company
              officials and creative staff attended the meetings, at which one staff member usually
              lectured on a subject such as advertising practices and media, trade advertising and
              advertising to specific groups, client campaigns, research, foreign office activities,
              and legal aspects of advertising. Some of the meetings included question and answer
              periods.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_ad0367924a9a07e6a91399e4204defcc">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The contents are arranged in chronological order. The series consists of typed copies
              of the minutes. Photographs, charts, advertisements, and printed material are
              sometimes attached to the minutes. Minutes of the Nov. 9 and Dec. 14 meetings include
              photos of store window and counter displays.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_246f307d54380a266465225a3d57e87b">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Presentations include a talk by Ward Greene, Executive Editor of King Features (the
              selling agent for Hearst news wire services and director of International News Photos
              and American Radio News Corporation). There is a report on consumer behavior at the
              1933 Chicago World's Fair, and the text of a talk by Mr. Hooper of Daniel Starch's
              Advertising Service, analyzing magazine readers' reception and retention of texts. The
              social theory of "technocracy" was the topic of two speeches, one in favor by Quincy
              Howe, editor of Living Age magazine, and one against by Mr. Van Deventer, editor of
              Iron Age magazine. Relevant articles from their publications are attached. The
              question of "scientific" advertising, and the American Medical Association's reaction
              against it, is discussed, as is the related issue of Federal Trade Commission
              regulation of advertising. There is a copy of an October 1934 speech, with handwritten
              corrections, by Miss F.A. Bell (a JWT employee) on legal aspects of advertising, that
              was never delivered to the group. Bell did speak on that topic to the Men's and
              Women's Apprentice Groups in 1936, so the 2 speeches allow comparison over time. Both
              contain examples of legal difficulties arising from Fleischmann Yeast testimonials.
              Some minutes contain ideas for campaigns that were not used or were quickly pulled,
              such as the November 16, 1932 discussion of a proposed campaign for Eastman Kodak that
              suggested taking photos of family members before they died and were lost forever.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_f2dbb15a64d0406de5d803526a12b688">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Arranged chronologically by meeting date.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref21_mia" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Meeting Minutes (1932, March 5-1933, March 29)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_4e571170590a4034906aae513e450b99" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">U5</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref22_lou" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Meeting Minutes (1933, April 12-1934, October 11)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_cc595b79d734b05c22f29c986d38011b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">U6</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref27_1b1" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>JWT Forum Series, 1936-1938.</unittitle>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_afeaf33c50b0dc5f02c4e8ee1c4ad545">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>JWT Forum is a resumption of the Creative Organization staff meetings. The new
              meetings, attended by top company officials and the creative staff, were held
              bi-weekly and featured lectures by staff members. Discussions included advertising
              practices and media, client campaigns, activities of domestic branch offices, and
              legal aspects of advertising.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_b28feba1180d31b674618caa5506e5c7">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The JWT Forum subseries consists of typed copies of minutes of meetings held between
              1936 and 1938. Charts and advertisements are attached to some of the minutes, as well
              as one photograph of "outstanding premiums" offered to consumers through ads in 1938.
              A booklet reproduction of a slide presentation for Shell Oil, with drawings by Walt
              Disney, is attached to a summary of that presentation given to JWT Forum , June 9,
              1937. Several large items have been placed in an oversized container.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_fb2cf42d9813135bbc1bb4262eeca3c1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Presentations include talks by Howard Henderson, Arno Johnson, William Resor, and
              James Webb Young among others. They deal with advertising and motion pictures and
              other media, the history of advertising, its criticism. and regulation under the New
              Deal. Howard Henderson's April 6, 1937 presentation on advertising history includes
              copies of ads from Life, 1884-1918. Some presentations incorporate JWT market
              research. Clients discussed include the Eastman Kodak Co., Curtis Publishing Co.
              (Ladies' Home Journal), Lever Brothers, and Shell Oil Co. Talks often centered on
              innovative approaches or potentially troublesome accounts, such as Tampax (folder 2),
              Ballantine beer, and Bromo-Seltzer, which was advertised to men after JWT discovered
              its largest single use was for hangovers.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_1fa271674ab78cb09635d89c38305df0">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The minutes give insight into the relations between advertising and social and
              political trends, and into advertisers' perceptions of the limits of acceptable public
              discourse. Several speeches include racial or ethnic jokes. Others have titles such as
              "Is Advertising Honest?," "Is Advertising Copy in a period of Decadence?," and "Bad
              Taste in Advertising." William L. Day's Dec. 7, 1937 presentation deals with the
              international political situation and the relation of public opinion to
              advertising.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_17a43fa450c5d02dfbbfc29853c884af">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Arranged chronologically by meeting date.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref28_gsm" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Meeting Minutes (1936, January 7-1938, October 5)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_777d5d86db93a8b8b6787409d989dd70" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">U6</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref34_1uw" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Monday Evening Meetings Series, 1930.</unittitle>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_b29cdbca79b2d22382043d6d997259fd">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Monday Evening Meetings were enrichment lectures by outside speakers presented each
              week from March through May 1930 in the JWT lecture hall. Speakers included editors
              and publishers, Clarence Darrow, Rudy Vallee, and motion picture censor Will Hays.
              Stanley Resor also gave one talk about his trip to the JWT San Francisco and Los
              Angeles branch offices. All surviving speeches are by men.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_69e3ee86c93b202498393bea445d1212">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Monday Evening Meetings subseries consists of typed copies of the speeches and
              the question and answer sessions.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_30a0307e74f95eddbb6c80b55dc1510f">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The speeches offer insights into various business, social, and cultural issues of
              1930. Clarence Darrow discussed his life story and philosophy, his conception of
              justice, and the connections between poverty and crime. William L. Chennery, editor of
              Collier's magazine, discussed the strategies behind the recent growth of that
              magazine, while James Quirk, editor of Photoplay, stressed similarities between the
              movie business and advertising as sellers of ideas and emotions. Resor's speech gives
              an Easterner's impression of the American Southwest and California, and of California
              universities and hospitals. Besides music, Rudy Vallee spoke of his early acquaintance
              with Rudolph Valentino and Helen Kane. Will Hays' presentation gives examples of
              changes made to movies, such as the head of the Boy Scouts of America using influence
              to have a scene of Kit Carson getting drunk cut from "Covered Wagon" because Carson
              was a role model for Scouts. Hays also discussed his cooperation-operation with the
              YMCA and other organizations and his agreements with the Authors' League of America
              regarding scripts and with advertisers regarding film ads. He responded to a question
              about the linguistic problems of making US films for foreign audiences.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_3f36119c13b7d7def3885b7fff141859">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Arranged chronologically by meeting date.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref35_zlf" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Meeting Minutes (1930, March 3-May 26)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_cd2040d1d68b50d07bf884856b32dee5" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">U6</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref40_8ne" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Men's and Women's Apprentice Group Meetings Series, 1936-1938.</unittitle>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_f8a491ed04d099fea97cb28a9058becb">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Men's Apprentice Group, made up of new NY Office employees, was established in
              1935. Members of the group attended weekly luncheon meetings chaired by Howard Kohl
              and generally featuring a company speaker. The group also published a bi-weekly
              newsletter from 1935 to 1938 originally called the Junior News Letter and then the
              Flash. A Women's Apprentice Group was founded in 1937 but no additional information
              about the group has been found.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_c802ab0016de50339335c3f1fd02a1ac">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The Men's and Women's Apprentice Groups subseries consists of speeches given by Miss
              F.A. Bell to the two groups from 1936 to 1938, and records of question and answer
              periods. Copies of only 3 presentations have survived.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_e595aba4278cbbb0540593ff63843e0d">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Subjects of the talks were the legal aspects of advertising, Federal Trade Commission
              regulations regarding unfair or deceptive advertising, and the functions of the
              Information and Records Division of the Research Department. The legal use of
              testimonials in advertising was a topic of particular concern since companies such as
              Fleischmann Yeast had legal troubles (settled out of court) over allegedly false
              testimonials.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_8eaa07c8fa045262f122671e056baed0">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Arranged chronologically by meeting date.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref41_c2u" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Meeting Minutes (1936, September 3-1938, October 7)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_118a198c3cfda9e3109c79209ad75e3c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">U6</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_1db7676bf5d4d788a77ada76dced0cb3" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chicago Office Junior Forum</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1951/1952" type="inclusive">1952-1952</unitdate>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_10415e7ada2607beed24f0e5b12acbc4" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Meeting Minutes</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_feea17ace8ed9350134815d0306e7ab3" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">U6</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref46_fy1" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Restricted Materials Series, 1927-1938.</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_c4e255b482163f2264a4a4808d05274d">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>Original meeting minutes for the Account Representative Meetings, Creative Organization
            Meetings, JWT Forum Meetings, Monday Evening Staff Meetings, and Men's and Women's
            Apprentice Group Meetings.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref47_mpj" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Account Representatives Meeting Minutes (1927, January 11-1928, August
              29)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_762de94bd31eb6c35f100e4195ed8061" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_e6c6e8a24fe9bdb850eb2bdff1b8714a" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Account Representatives Meeting Minutes (1928 September 12-1929 April
              17)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_c4d22a0307936655d51b5e711f2b1d74" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1a</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref48_xab" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Account Representatives Meeting Minutes (1929, May 1-1930, August
              26)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_bc833f46fb74065aa7f45d772afde28c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref49_c3m" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Account Representatives Meeting Minutes (1930, September 9 -1931, May
              26)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_b428cc00687f3f37719d75e54487a6c4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref50_yvq" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Account Representatives Meeting Minutes (1931, June 2-1932, February 16);
              Index 1927-1932</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_9c783bbef093c381dea1cfb947c91916" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref51_671" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Creative Organization Meeting Minutes (1932, March 5-1933, March
              29)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_bd50206faf308e8d157d583f55aceb7a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref52_wrh" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Creative Organization Meeting Minutes (1933, April 12-1934, October 11);
              Indices</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_f6986dc731d1c16e036e832c92ef2b23" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref53_5aq" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>JWT Forum Meeting Minutes (1936, January 7-1938, October 25)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_1ab8911120421f88eb3da5c0c76f461f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">7</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref54_f50" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Monday Evening Staff Meeting Minutes (1930, March 3-May 26)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_f84462dedc10bedde2557fd8e7cd1340" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_b15bbad4a558d3ac9d9a0d51fe10c348" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Monday Evening Staff Meeting Minutes Index by subject and speaker,
              1930</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_47d7dbdbd6d55a97b2c98e6dea0b0ae9" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref55_kxh" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Men and Women Apprentice Group Meetings (1936, September 3-1938, October
              7)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_8cd4886175ed9de7125e9f6332592f3e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_9eb2c8fb9c9f1ae1ba080d4ddfbd110a" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chicago Office Junior Forum</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1951/1952" type="inclusive">1951-1952</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_54ccd9996f2bef20c1fd8f7a1fb28a21" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">9</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
