<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/jwtworldwariicollection/"
         >jwtworldwariicollection</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. World War II Advertising
               Collection, 1940-1948 and undated <num>RL.00761</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Elizabeth Dunn, Katherine Ross; machine-readable finding aid
               created by: Richard Collier</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003422301</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 01:07:56
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>J. Walter Thompson Company. World War II Advertising collection</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="ingest">J. Walter Thompson Company</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00761</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.8 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1940/1948" type="inclusive">1940-1948 and undated</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_7b6ca5fa1a6cf4c976c9e651046ae32f">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <physdesc id="aspace_e035633531f8507b56c4e685d562a749">
            <extent>150 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_3620a73dc7024278b335e40cd5d660e7">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_9006f2662caaf2eac09037c7fc0d7eab">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_c726d981bc5c55e8facff71c50eb03ec">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_c0d8b70bd2dd93898505bed57e9780a4">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], J. Walter Thompson Company. World War II Advertising
            Collection, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_501cd53b19ee8bc2760bd1433e83e357">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The J. Walter Thompson Cmpany. World War II Advertising Collection was received by the
            David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library as a gift from the J. Walter
            Thompson Co. in 1987.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_c5f489976576ad9ae31d559d33185260">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Elizabeth Dunn, Katherine Ross</p>
         <p>Completed July 30, 1997</p>
         <p>Encoded by Richard Collier</p>
         <p>Processing of this collection was supported in part by gifts from the J. Walter Thompson
            Company Fund and the John and Kelly Hartman Foundation.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_fd888fd3eacca5ddb4facaca2154e6b8">
         <head>Historical Note</head>
         <p>In April 1941 Stanley B. Resor, then president of the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT),
            outlined the advertising industry's role in the coming conflict. In an article published
            in New York City Sunday newspapers, he spoke of advertising agencies' two goals: to keep
            consumers purchasing goods in order to help offset war expenses, and to relate the <emph
               render="doublequote">truths</emph> behind the government's policies and programs. </p>
         <p>The J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) contributed to the war effort during World War II
            in two ways: by creating ads supporting government policies, and by granting its
            employees time off for their own war work. JWT's government accounts included the War
            Manpower Commission, handled by Helen Lansdowne Resor and James Webb Young; the Naval
            Aviation Cadet program, handled by Sam Meek; Woman Power, handled by William E.
            Berchtold; and the U.S. Cadet Nurse Corps, developed by Ruth Waldo and handled by Thayer
            Jaccaci. In each of these accounts, as in most campaigns formulated for the government,
            sponsors in private industry were sought. For instance, advertisements for the U.S.
            Cadet Nurse Corps were sponsored by the Eastman Kodak Company. In addition to the
            sponsorship of government advertising programs, clients adjusted their own campaigns to
            reflect America's war-time conditions. Advertising campaigns were also formulated for
            religious and charitable organizations. Both the British War Relief Society and the Navy
            Relief Society benefitted from the advertising expertise of J. Walter Thompson Company
            personnel. International offices of the Company became involved in a number of ways. The
            London Office, for example, prepared a conservation program for the Ministry of Food,
            while the Australian Office implemented an Australian-American goodwill campaign. </p>
         <p> Company personnel were granted leaves of absence or time for civilian work of
            importance to the war. Among these were James Webb Young, chair of the War Advertising
            Council, tyhe predecessor to the Advertising Council; Samuel W. Meek, consultant to the
            Navy Department; and Walter O'Meara, Deputy Administrator for Information, Office of
            Price Administration. Those who remained in the office devoted some of their time and
            talent to aiding such organizations as the Camp Shows for Service Men, the Citizen
            United for Democracy, and the National War Fund.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_c70c37984f726228d7a5383449b439b7">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The J. Walter Thompson Company World War II Advertising Collection documents the
            war-related activities of the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) advertising agency during
            1940-1948, including a few post-war assessments. In particular, it shows JWT’s
            contributions to the war effort by its in-house documentation and work on government,
            civilian, and war-supporting charitable organization accounts. Materials include lists,
            memos, press releases, correspondence, notes, and advertisement tearsheets and proofs.
            Many of the materials in this collection are products of campaigns conducted under the
            auspices of the War Advertising Council, as well as those sponsored by civilian clients.
            These advertisements and pamphlets supported food rationing, fuel and rubber
            conservation, the purchase of War Bonds, the United Services Organization (USO),
            military recruitment, and women's employment in war-related jobs. Other advertisements
            arose from JWT's work in 1941 and 1942 for the Navy Relief Society. Items produced by
            the JWT London Office supported British War Relief (Ministry of Food, 1940-1941) and the
            Food Facts series (recipes and cooking tips for foods available despite rationing). </p>
         <p>The collection includes corporate-sponsored advertisements relating to the war effort.
            Companies represented include: the American Association of Playing Card Manufacturers
            (recreation for convalescent service-men, in cooperation with the Red Cross); Anthracite
            Industries, Inc. (fuel conservation); Eastman Kodak Company (U.S. Cadet Nurse Corps);
            and the Institute of Life Insurance (ads to fight inflation produced in cooperation with
            the Office of Economic Stabilization, and a <emph render="doublequote">Keep Well</emph>
            campaign). Other advertisements were backed by Lambert Pharmacal Co. (women's
            employment); Libbey Glass Company (recruitment of women Marines and nurses' aides);
            National Retail Dry Goods Association (nurse recruitment); Owens Illinois-Glass Company
            (paper salvage); Petroleum Industry War Council (campaigns for saving tires, rubber, and
            gasoline); Shell Oil Company and other petroleum and rubber companies (salvage of scarce
            materials); and Textron (nurse recruitment).</p>
         <p>Related materials may be found elsewhere in the J. Walter Thompson Co. Archives,
            including the papers of JWT executives such as Samuel W. Meek, Walter O'Meara, Helen
            Lansdowne Resor, Stanley Burnet Resor, Ruth F. Waldo and James Webb Young. Similar
            materials may also be found in the R.C. Maxwell Company Outdoor Advertising Archives;
            the War Effort Mobilization Campaigns Poster Collection; and the Outdoor Advertising
            Association of America (OAAA) Archives.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_f3043d0c7e1ba0fb8247246550dac5a6">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>Additional information about J. Walter Thompson Company's war efforts may be found in
            various collections of the J. Walter Company Archives: the <emph render="bold">Writings
               and Speeches Collection</emph>, especially the folders on <emph render="bold">Arno
               Johnson</emph>, 1944-1946, and <emph render="bold">Stanley B. Resor</emph>,
            1940-1957; in the <emph render="bold">Domestic Advertisements Collection</emph>, various
            clients, 1940-1945; the <emph render="bold">Newsletter Collection</emph>, especially the
               <emph render="italic">JWT (Service) Newsletter</emph>, 1942-1945, and the <emph
               render="italic">J. Walter Thompson Company News</emph>, 1945; in <emph
               render="italic">A Primer for Postwar Prosperity</emph> and associated correspondence;
            and in <emph render="italic">A Review of Recent Advertising Aiding the War Effort by the
               Clients of J. Walter Thompson Company</emph>, circa 1945.</p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising Council</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising agencies</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertisements</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Employment</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Rationing -- Great Britain</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Public relations</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Navy Relief Society</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Great Britain. Ministry of Food</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">War Advertising Council</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Memoranda</genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">Savings bonds -- United States -- History</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Rationing -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women -- United States -- History -- 20th century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Women -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">United Service Organizations (U.S.)</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- War work</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Mass media and the war</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Food supply -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Propaganda</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- England</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women in advertising -- United States -- History -- 20th
            century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Food supply -- England</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Finance -- United States</subject>
         <corpname source="ingest">John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising &amp; Marketing
            History</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">J. Walter Thompson Company</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">J. Walter Thompson Company</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_9p3" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>War Campaigns, 1940-1948</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref13_a9t" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Campaigns for Government Policies and Agencies, Other Than War Bonds,
                     1941-1945</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_63c1171afd69aae5fdc31a846c9fc1cf">
                     <extent>2 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_07df0acab6dfcbdda47fe94b54b71f32" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_c4s" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Civilian Clients' Advertising, Other Than War Bonds,
                     1941-1945</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4533d863578c08f003101638831f22ca" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_opu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1942 Feb.1-1943 Apr. 28</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6e8f74062501b71772d779cb2deb5402" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_kt7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>JWT Personnel in the Government or Volunteer Services,
                     1941-1945</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_949b522dae7d61b541282cd8747f0306" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_mpv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Lists of War Campaigns Prepared, 1944 Mar. 28-1948 June 3 and
                     undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_24bcb219a9445d4c1e1c59609d654c2c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_1a0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>London Office Campaign, Food Facts, 1940-1945</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_33c711831fab6344673c0508898a1eeb" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_9ly" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>War Bond Advertising, Proofs and Lists, 1943-1945</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_857aeca3543a3681183a36949b097505" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref21_ddm" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Oversize Materials</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_rrl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Government Policies and Agencies Campaigns, 1941-1945</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_7cb4ad52342abed4b1050cda4c919468">
                     <extent>2 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_ce8361f23f45329f20da86347ce81eb3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_ytz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Recruiting Women for War-Related Work, 1944 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_51d6e0a449c252b24b8e62510c39347b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_uci" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Religious and Charitable Organizations, 1942 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_15e5b0ef2511789c599ac8a0f786ffdd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_9b5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>War Bond Advertisements, 1943-1945</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_297abc43cb8c388a1206b47d040e300f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_7f7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Oversize Proofs and Tear Sheets of Advertisements, 1941-1945 and
                     undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0a7db68e07473e584a4c3e331d476594" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-folder">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
