<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/jwtwoodell/">jwtwoodell</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Shirley F. Woodell Papers,
               1943-1958 <num>RL.00760</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Donna Longo DiMichele; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Stephen Miller, Duke University David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;amp; Manuscript
               Library</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">001530662</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 01:07:38
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>J. Walter Thompson Company. Shirley F. Woodell papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="ingest">J. Walter Thompson Company</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00760</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.7 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1943/1958" type="inclusive">1943-1958</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_36fd9deff1ef4a5f4edd3a8cc9a0c68e">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <physdesc id="aspace_44f1da67768b05b1caacef2586aeb194">
            <extent>1900 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_8e4db627b3d8867eafc5de6d523387cd">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_10e60674c2dcf827cd7dab2c54286ab7">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Access to some portions of the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives is restricted.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_e06f782daa834b910a6221d80ed96f4b">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives have not been
            transferred to Duke University. For further information, see the section on copyright in
            the Regulations and Procedures of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript
            Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_b4cf0fd527c1aae50fd6181db9fee0c1">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], J. Walter Thompson Company. Shirley F. Woodell Papers, David
            M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_623160df94136a5f124911fd4e577ea1">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Shirley F. Woodell Papers were transferred to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library from the J. Walter Thompson Company in 1987.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_58e8995ba5c1559f48ada94fe001efaf">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by: Donna Longo DiMichele</p>
         <p>Completed October 11, 1993</p>
         <p>Processing of this collection was supported in part by the J. Walter Thompson Company
            Fund and the John and Kelly Hartman Foundation.</p>
         <p>Encoded by Stephen Miller</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_0f5d41553734174e5ed285e29d5adba7">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <chronlist>
            <head>Chronology</head>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1907, Sept. 25</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Born, Louisville, Ky.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1907-1919</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Lived in Havana, Cuba</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1926-1928</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Export advertising clerk, Holeproof Hosiery Company, New York</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1927</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>A.B., Columbia University</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1928-1941</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Advertising manager, Packard Motors Export Corporation, New York</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1938</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Founder and first President of the International Advertising
                     Association</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1941-1943</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Sales manager, International Division, National Broadcasting Corporation,
                     New York</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1943-1944</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Account executive, Foreign Department, McCann-Erickson Corporation, New
                     York</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1944-1945</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>United States Navy Department</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1946-1960</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>J. Walter Thompson Company, International Department</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1960</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Retired from the J. Walter Thompson Company; lecturer at the business
                     school of The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill; International
                     Advertising Association <emph render="doublequote">Man of the Year</emph>
                     award</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
         </chronlist>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_c5d7acd37fdfb1d17dd05fe6bfeb5288">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The papers of Shirley F. Woodell span the years 1943 to 1958. They consist of
            correspondence, memoranda, reports, maps, notes, itineraries, and a photograph album.
            The collection documents the operations of the J. Walter Thompson Company in Mexico, the
            Caribbean area, and Latin America, primarily through correspondence and reports written
            by Woodell during and immediately after his business trips. The bulk of the collection
            consists of Woodell's accounts of his field trips written, often daily, to J. Walter
            Thompson Company executives and staff. There is also correspondence to representatives
            of some of the company's clients. The collection documents the process of marketing a
            wide variety of American products, from cosmetics to automotive parts, in an
            international market. Local uses of products and the ways in which competitive products
            affected the markets for clients' products were also described because local economic
            and cultural factors affected decisions about advertising and distribution.</p>
         <p>The correspondence and reports convey information relevant to advertising, however the
            collection also includes more general observations of an American traveler in foreign
            countries. Social customs, traditional cultures, political situations, and Indian
            peoples of many countries are noted throughout the manuscripts. Clients of the J. Walter
            Thompson Company represented in the collection include Chesebrough-Pond's, Ford Motor
            Company, Eastman Kodak Company, J.B. Williams Company, Kraft Foods Company, Pan American
            World Airways, Parker Pen Company, Reader's Digest Association, and Standard Brands
            Incorporated. A business trip Woodell made during his earlier employment with
            McCann-Erickson Worldwide is also documented. A record of one business trip to England,
            France and Belgium is included.</p>
         <p>In correspondence, memoranda, and reports, Woodell describes meetings with product
            distributors, retailers, dealers, and other advertising executives, including
            information about their business operations as well as their personal characteristics.
            Print and radio advertisements, billboards, and signs are discussed with regard to both
            their market success and attendant production problems. Costs, production facilities,
            and translations from English to Spanish, Portuguese, or French were often problematic.
            Traveling on behalf of his company and its clients, Woodell was responsible for a myraid
            of details and conducting business at a distance from the company's New York office was
            often difficult. He was occasionally exasperated by delays or apparent lack of attention
            to his requests for information or assistance. Woodell also describes his
            accommodations, parties and other social functions that he attended.</p>
         <p>The Photograph Album, titled <emph render="doublequote">Friends,</emph> contains candid
            portraits of personnel from the J. Walter Thompson Company's New York Office and its
            various International Division offices, and representatives of the company's client
            businesses.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Marketing -- Latin America</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising agencies</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Mexico -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Latin America -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising executives</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Caribbean Area -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <corpname source="ingest">John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising &amp; Marketing
            History</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">J. Walter Thompson Company</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">McCann-Erickson Worldwide</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Kraft Foods Company</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Eastman Kodak Company</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Chesebrough-Pond's.</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">J. B. Williams Company</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Ford Motor Company</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Woodell, Shirley F., 1907-</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Pan American World Airways, Inc.</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Parker Pen Company</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Reader's Digest Association</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Standard Brands Incorporated</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_8ji" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Office Files and Correspondence, 1943-1958.</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_b2a3832df9fc18b9976a620cc8ea6d81">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Includes chiefly carbon copies of correspondence, memoranda, reports, expense
                  reports, a survey form, maps, notes, and itineraries. Arranged
                  chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_70c97bf86b689b5d334fd9b6f167488a">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>N.B. Cross-references for client names: duPont, see E.I. duPont de Nemours and
                  Co.; Kodak, see Eastman Kodak; RCA, see Radio Corporation of America; and Squibb,
                  see E.R. Squibb and Sons.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref13_qrz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1943, Sept.-Nov.:for McCann-Erickson Corp.: Panama, Guayaquil,
                     Guatemala, Mexico, San Salvador, Honduras, Nicaragua, and Costa
                     Rica</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b745e86648317ba7867952bea380fd29" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref14_pbf" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Chesebrough Manufacturing Corp.. Vaseline; Mack Truck;
                        Schenley Distillers Corp.; Standard Oil Company of N.J.)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_53136ea2ebd523159b0b8d734ed8cf5a" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_806" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1945, Nov.: Cuba and Panama</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref16_6ik" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Ford Motor Co.)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_8a450aaa7067cc45d5ee0453802c8415" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_aat" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1946, June-July: Cuba, Haiti, Dominican Republic, Mexico, Panama,
                     Venezuela, Costa Rica, Puerto Rico, and Colombia</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref18_qfo" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Chesebrough-Pond's; Eastman Kodak Co.; Ford Motor Co.;
                        Gillette Safety Razor Co.; Kraft Foods Co.; Libby, McNeill and Libby; Pan
                        American World Airways; Parker Pen Co.; Radio Corporation of America;
                        Reader's Digest Association; and Standard Brands)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_870a18443159b67e728c40a6e7f5fb12" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_1vr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1947, Jan.-Mar.: Cuba, Chile, Jamaica, Brazil, Venezuela, Trinidad,
                     Argentina, Peru, Colombia, Panama, and Mexico</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref20_jzr" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Buxton; Chesebrough-Pond's; Eastman Kodak Co.; E.R. Squibb
                        and Sons; Ford Motor Co.; Gillette Co.; J.B. Williams Co.; Kellogg Co.;
                        Kraft Foods Co.; Libby, McNeill and Libby; Pan American World Airways;
                        Parker Pen Co.; Radio Corporation of America; Reader's Digest Association;
                        and Standard Brands)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_72f792455c409da2d1d7a86a11cbebcc" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_0mr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1947, Aug.-Oct.: Mexico, Guatemala, Nicaragua, Costa Rica, Colombia,
                     Venezuela, Puerto Rico, Haiti, and Cuba</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref22_0re" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Buxton; Chesebrough-Pond's; Eastman Kodak Co.; E.R. Squibb
                        and Sons; Ford Motor Co.; Gillette Co.; J.B. Williams Co.; Kellogg Co.;
                        Kraft Foods Co.; Libby, McNeill and Libby; Pan American World Airways;
                        Parker Pen Co.; Scott Paper Co.; and Standard Brands)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_a7f629db72153daf7c8955ae545b1903" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_0vg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1948, May-Aug.: Mexico, Guatemala, Panama, Colombia, Venezuela, Puerto
                     Rico, and Cuba</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref24_bau" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Burroughs Adding Machine Corp.; Caterpillar Tractor Co.;
                        Chesebrough-Pond's; Eastman Kodak Co.; E.R. Squibb and Sons; Ford Motor Co.;
                        Gillette Co.; J.B. Williams Co.; Kellogg Co.; Kraft Foods Co.; Libby,
                        McNeill and Libby; Pan American World Airways; Parker Pen Co.; Radio
                        Corporation of America; Reader's Digest Association; and Standard
                        Brands)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_34140932ccfd47986e1f8a8d8d6955d7" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_rff" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1949, Jan.-Feb.: Panama, Colombia, Venezuela, Puerto Rico, and
                     Cuba</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref26_19w" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Burroughs Adding Machine Corp.; Caterpillar Tractor Co.;
                        Chesebrough-Pond's; Eastman Kodak Co.; E.R. Squibb and Sons; Ford Motor Co.;
                        Gillette Co.; J.B. Williams Co.; Kellogg Co.; Kraft Foods Co.; Libby,
                        McNeill and Libby; Pan American World Airways; Parker Pen Co.; P. Ballantine
                        and Sons; Radio Corporation of America; Reader's Digest Association; and
                        Standard Brands)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_e45168d7bba6b7f574311913df0a4322" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_uj3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1949, May: England, France, and Belgium</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_db1d544fc266e5619e6d7271c58e44c1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref28_rox" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: British Broadcasting Corp.; Burroughs Adding Machine
                        Corp.; Buxton; Caterpillar Tractor Co.; Eastman Kodak Co.; Ford Motor Co.;
                        J.B. Williams Co.; Pan American World Airways; Parker Pen Co.; Radio
                        Corporation of America; Socony-Vacuum Co.; and Standard Brands)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_cebdbb469cfc225544744668e8b1bf2a" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_510" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1950, Jan.-Mar.: Mexico, Panama, Colombia, Venezuela, Puerto Rico, and
                     Cuba</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_05ce0a3cdc17320ecf8a5f2c4d4dccb8">
                     <extent>2 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref31_2jz" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Burroughs Adding Machine Corp.; Caterpillar Tractor Co.;
                        Celanese Corp.; Champion Spark Plug Co.; Chesebrough-Pond's; Domit; Eastman
                        Kodak Co.; E.R. Squibb and Sons; Ford Motor Co.; Goodrich Co.; Guanos Y
                        Fertizantes; Kellogg Co.; Kraft Foods Co.; J.B. Williams Co.; Pan American
                        World Airways; Parker Pen Co.; P. Ballantine and Sons; Pepsi-Cola Co.;
                        Proctor and Gamble Co.; Radio Corporation of America; Reader's Digest
                        Association; Rolex Watch USA; Sears, Roebuck and Co.; Socony-Vacuum Co.; and
                        Standard Brands)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_36eab3c7cf6a344155e17b1f66431ec0" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_n3b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1951, Feb.-May: Cuba, Haiti, Puerto Rico, Dominican Republic, Curacao,
                     Venezuela, Colombia, Panama, Costa Rica, Nicaragua, Honduras, El Salvador,
                     Guatemala, and Mexico</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref33_q9p" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Burroughs Adding Machine Corp.; Carter Products;
                        Caterpillar Tractor Co.; Celanese Corp.; Champion Spark Plug Co.;
                        Chesebrough-Pond's; Eastman Kodak Co.; E.R. Squibb and Sons; Ford Motor Co.;
                        J.B. Williams Co.; Kellogg Co.; Kraft Foods Co.; Pan-American World Airways;
                        Parker Pen Co.; Radio Corporation of America; Reader's Digest Association;
                        Socony-Vacuum Co.; and Standard Brands)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_732d5f9997cbb759ec0ca4de83c56cbf" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref34_acb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1951, Feb.-May:Final Report, Pan American World Airways LAD Field
                     Trip</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a6e81b9f52ed4ac56ac0c4a6f1751550" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_dgf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1953, Feb.-Apr.: Cuba, Haiti, Puerto Rico, Venezuela, Colombia,
                     Ecuador, and Panama</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref36_ikv" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Brown and Williamson Tobacco Co.; Burroughs Adding Machine
                        Corp.; Carter Products; Champion Spark Plug Co.; Chesebrough-Pond's; Eastman
                        Kodak Co.; E.R. Squibb and Sons; Ford Motor Co.; J.B. Williams Co.; Kraft
                        Foods Co.; Lever Brothers Co.; Libby, McNeill and Libby; Mentholatum Co.;
                        Pan American World Airways; Parker Pen Co.; Reader's Digest Association; and
                        Standard Brands)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_f7f8570260433d8a51c45360c73964a1" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref37_74w" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1953, Apr.: Cuba, Haiti, Puerto Rico, Venezuela, Colombia, Ecuador, and
                     Panama</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref38_scr" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Brown and Williamson Tobacco Co.; Eastman Kodak Co.; E.R.
                        Squibb and Sons/Squibb Inter-American Corp.; Ford Motor Co.; J.B. Williams
                        Co.; Kraft Foods Co.; Lever Brothers Co.; Life International; Mentholatum
                        Co.; Pan American World Airways; Parker Pen Co.; Reader's Digest
                        Association; Scott Paper Co.; and Standard Brands)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_875e4cd96d6eadc73b1c9d58aefb10b2" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref39_seu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1954, Feb.-Mar.: Colombia, Venezuela, and Puerto Rico</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref40_vjz" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Aluminum Import Corp.; Brown and Williamson Tobacco Co.;
                        Burroughs Adding Machine Corp.; Champion Spark Plug Co.; Chesebrough-Pond's;
                        Eastman Kodak Co.; E.R. Squibb and Sons; Ford Motor Co.; International
                        General Electric; J.B. Williams Co.; Kellogg Co.; Kraft Foods Co.; Lever
                        Brothers Co.; Mentholatum Co.; Pan American World Airways; Parker Pen Co.;
                        Reader's Digest Association; Standard Brands; and Timken Roller Bearing
                        Co.)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_fa27bb21cc5c9e1ac07f76f9c5eee33a" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref41_xmx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1954, Oct.-Dec.: Cuba, Puerto Rico, Venezuela, Colombia, and
                     Peru</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c3ec339c3e49f21def245e82c366d325" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref42_5p3" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Aluminum Import Corp.; Brown and Williamson Tobacco Co.;
                        Burroughs Adding Machine Corp.; Carter Products; Champion Spark Plug Co.;
                        Chesebrough-Pond's; Eastman Kodak Co.; E.R. Squibb and Sons; Ford Motor Co.;
                        Kellogg Co.; Kraft Foods Co.; Lever Brothers Co.; Mosler Safe Co.; Pan
                        American World Airways; Parker Pen Co.; Reader's Digest Association; R.T.
                        French Co.; Scott Paper Co.; Socony-Vacuum Co.; Standard Brands; Sylvania
                        Electric Products; and Timken Roller Bearing Co.)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_97620a608d72c00ba76b9d968b6d8ae6" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_uqq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1955, July-Oct.: Puerto Rico, Venezuela, Brazil, Argentina, Chile,
                     Colombia, Panama, Mexico, and Cuba</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref44_ybx" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Aluminum Import Corp.; Brown and Williamson Tobacco Co.;
                        Burroughs Adding Machine Corp.; Champion Spark Plug Co.; Chesebrough-Pond's;
                        Eastman Kodak Co.; E.R. Squibb and Sons; Ford Motor Co.; Gillette Co.; J.B.
                        Williams Co.; Kraft Foods Co.; Lever Brothers Co.; Mentholatum Co.; Mosler
                        Safe Co.; Pan American World Airways; Parker Pen Co.; Reader's Digest
                        Association; R.T. French Co.; Scott Paper Co.; Socony-Vacuum Co.; Standard
                        Brands; Sylvania Electric Products; and Timken Roller Bearing
                        Co.)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_34aa5197c33bc880af801998dd1da27b" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref45_tso" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1956, Nov.-Dec.: Venezuela, Colombia, and Peru</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref46_yb2" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Burroughs Adding Machine Corp.; Carter Products; Eastman
                        Kodak Co.; Goodrich Co.; Kellogg Co.; Kraft Foods Co.; Lever Brothers Co.;
                        Mentholatum Co.; National Carbon Co.; Pan American World Airways; Scott
                        Paper Co.; Scripto; Standard Brands; and W.R. Grace Co.)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_e3ced0b30cf1828da7a473986f52d5fc" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_s8c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1957, Jan.-Apr.: Cuba, Mexico, Colombia, Peru, Chile, Argentina,
                     Brazil, and Puerto Rico</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref48_4wh" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Burroughs Adding Machine Corp.; Carter Products;
                        Chesebrough-Pond's; Eastman Kodak Co.; Ford Motor Co.; J.B. Williams Co.;
                        Kraft Foods Co.; Lever Brothers Co.; Mentholatum Co.; Mosler Safe Co.;
                        Murine Co.; Owens-Illinois Corp.; Pan American World Airways; R.T. French
                        Co.; Scripto; and W.R. Grace Co.)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_3cbcbdcb42ad799f335e026ab9413e27" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref49_gpr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1958, Jan.-Feb.: Puerto Rico, Cuba, Mexico, Peru, Colombia, and
                     Panama</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref50_6a2" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Burroughs Adding Machine Corp.; Carter Products; Champion
                        Spark Plug Co.; Chesebrough-Pond's; Eastman Kodak Co.; Ford Motor Co.; H.F.
                        Ritchie; Kraft Foods Co.; Mentholatum Co.; National Carbon Co.; Pan American
                        World Airways; Reader's Digest Association; R.T. French Co.; Scott Paper
                        Co.; Scripto; S.C. Johnson; Standard Brands; and W.R. Grace Co.)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_3cec0312a03a63ec16c298927be4d74d" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref51_g6i" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1958, Jul.-Aug.: Cuba, Puerto Rico, Venezuela, Colombia, and
                     Panama</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref52_pua" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>(Clients: Aluminum Import Corp.; Brown and Williamson Tobacco Co.;
                        Burroughs Adding Machine Corp.; Carter Products; Champion Spark Plug Co.;
                        Chesebrough-Pond's; E.I. duPont de Nemours and Co.; Eastman Kodak Co.; Ford
                        Motor Co.; General Milk; J.B. Williams Co.; Kellogg Co.; Kraft Foods Co.;
                        Mentholatum Co.; Mobil Oil Corp.; Murine Co.; Pan American World Airways;
                        Reader's Digest Association; R.T. French Co.; Scott Paper Co.; Scripto;
                        Standard Brands; Sylvania Electric Products; Tobal; and W.R. Grace
                        Co.)</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_5e88b0f36585ee987565103c2cdaf490" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref53_dgk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1958, Dec.,Trip to Montevideo and Latin America, Tourist
                     Commission</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8f8a5e6ad015a898e46ebe1b37752a20" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref56_rwq" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Photograph Album, 1950s and 1982.</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_b6d3e6fb509e856229af163b50992a48">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Photographs, one letter (1982), and one clipping. The album was partially
                  dismantled prior to receipt from the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref57_co6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1950s, 1982</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_b52f2012006993f6597d8ece6e955b15">
                     <extent>1 folder</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_82c475f7e30b4492b1577b181bdc4202" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref60_yfi" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Oversize Materials</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref61_yq0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photograph Album, 1950s and 1982</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1a99a49699d19f4df92eb5f20b9baf08" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
