<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/kaplankivie/">kaplankivie</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Kivie Kaplan Papers, 1968-1971 <num>RL.00768</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Bob Malme; machine-readable finding aid created by: Bob
               Malme</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">005140926</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 01:24:02
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Kivie Kaplan papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Kaplan, Kivie, 1904-1975</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00768</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1968/1971" type="inclusive">1968-1971</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_a5d0cfbaec6b7d4dd17f7269598af1ea">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_e76148549b731bbb0d68e6febcd2ed35">Kivie Kaplan was born on April 1,
            1904 in Boston, Massachusetts, the youngest of three sons of Benjamin and Celia
            (Solomont) Kaplan. He joined the NAACP in 1932 and was elected to the National Board in
            1954. He was elected president in 1966 and served until his death in 1975. This
            collection contains correspondence and associated materials of Kivie Kaplan, president
            of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) from 1966 to
            1975. The bulk of the materials are sixteen of Kaplan's letters sent to Harold Gilden, a
            noted Chicago labor attorney. The letters span the years 1968 to 1971 and provide
            information about the activities of Kivie Kaplan, while at the NAACP headquarters and
            speaking to gatherings around the country. Among the people referenced in the letters
            are Martin Luther King, Jr., the Rev. Jesse Jackson, and prominent civil rights
            activists in Mississippi and Chicago. The letters also discuss Kaplan's philanthropic
            activities. The collection also includes eight separately printed items related to the
            NAACP and the civil rights movement and two NAACP 'Life Member' plaques.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_f26891813c7e73fa52bbbf41bf547000">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_94265a2df87354e6378a777f687f90ff">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_085e1d773766856544927c368306b3ce">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_8b7a012451860438a4d77391bdff8ad9">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Kivie Kaplan Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_94b8de3937c600e897ec9cc08ea83e0e">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Kivie Kaplan Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a purchase in November 2011.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_3c9794168103c52ef1aa0f0b7538a8b7">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Bob Malme, June 2012</p>
         <p>Encoded by Bob Malme, June 2012</p>
         <p>Accession(s) described in this finding aid: 2011-1026</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_8c89cf50615d1982a44c5563e280cf7d">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Kivie Kaplan was born on April 1, 1904 in Boston, Massachusetts. He was the youngest of
            three sons of Benjamin and Celia (Solomont) Kaplan. He attended English High School and
            Bryant and Stratton School in Boston. In 1924, Kivie Kaplan and his brothers, Joseph and
            Archie, took over their father's leather businesses. Kaplan successfully helped run the
            tanneries until 1962 when he retired to devote all of his time to philanthropic
            work.</p>
         <p>He had joined the NAACP in 1932 and was elected to the National Board in 1954. He was
            also the National Chairman of the NAACP Life Membership Committee and saw life
            memberships increase from a few hundred to several hundred thousand during his tenure.
            In 1966, he was elected as President of the N.A.A.C.P. a post he held until his death.
            As President of the N.A.A.C.P., Kaplan spoke throughout the United States on its behalf
            and sought financial contributions wherever he could. Kaplan was also a trustee of two
            black colleges: Lincoln University in Pennsylvania and Tougaloo College in
            Mississippi.</p>
         <p>Kivie Kaplan was also involved in Jewish affairs and was a member of the Board of
            Trustees of the Union of American Hebrew Congregations (U.A.H.C.). He was a member of
            the U.A.H.C.'s Executive Committee as well as its Social Action Commission. He
            contributed money to the Jewish Memorial Hospital in Boston and Brandeis University.</p>
         <p>Kaplan received numerous awards and honorary degrees. Among these were the Amistad Award
            of the American Missionary Association, and honorary degrees from Wilberforce
            University, Wilberforce, Ohio, Hebrew Union College, and Lincoln University in
            Pennsylvania.</p>
         <p>In 1925, Kivie Kaplan married Emily Rogers. They had three children, Sylvia (Grossman),
            Jean (Green), and Edward. Kivie Kaplan died on May 5, 1975.</p>
         <p>Source: <extref
               xlink:href="http://americanjewisharchives.org/aja/FindingAids/kaplan.htm">American
               Jewish Archives Website</extref>
         </p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_f361290ceca0b9986e1d6b5422fe3570">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>This collection contains correspondence and associated materials of Kivie Kaplan,
            president of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) from
            1966 to 1975.</p>
         <p>The bulk of the materials are sixteen of Kaplan's letters sent to Harold Gilden, a noted
            Chicago labor attorney who served on the National War Labor Board in 1943 and was named
            by Presidents Kennedy and Eisenhower to an Emergency Board to investigate labor disputes
            in 1960 and 1961, and his wife, Elise Gilden. The letters document the growing
            friendship between the Gildens and the Kaplans preceding their first meetings in person
            and eventually leading to the Gildens becoming lifetime members in the NAACP. The
            letters span the years 1968 to 1971 and provide information about the activities of
            Kivie Kaplan, in his leadership position at the NAACP and speaking to gatherings around
            the country.</p>
         <p>Among the people referenced in the letters are Martin Luther King, Jr. (with an attached
            photograph of King and Kaplan taken in 1958), the Rev. Jesse Jackson, Charles Evers and
            Rabbi Abraham Ruderman, two prominent Civil Rights activists from Greenville,
            Mississippi. Dr. Aaron Henry, a community leader in Clarksdale, Mississippi and Rabbi
            Arnold Wolf of Chicago. The letters also document Kaplan's efforts at working to lower
            the voting age to 18 (through the NAACP's Youth Mobilization Program) and attendance at
            various marches and demonstrations, including the 1969 Peace March in Washington, DC.
            The letters also discuss Kaplan's philanthropic activities including work on behalf of
            the American Friends for Religious Freedom in Israel. The letters are arranged in
            chronological order.</p>
         <p>The remainder of the collection includes eight separately printed items (plus
            enclosures/newspaper clippings, etc.) related to the NAACP, the civil rights movement,
            and African-American/Jewish relations, and two NAACP 'Life Member' plaques of Howard and
            Elise Gilden.</p>
         <p>For a detailed description of each item in the collection, see the Dealer Description
            included with the collection.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Civil rights movements -- United States -- History -- 20th
            century</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Clarksdale (Miss.)</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Greenville (Miss.)</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- 1961-1969</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Jews -- Relations with blacks</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Civil rights workers -- Mississippi</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Civil rights -- United States -- History -- 20th century</subject>
         <persname source="ingest">Gilden, Harold</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Henry, Aaron, 1922-1997</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Evers, Charles, 1922-</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">National Association for the Advancement of Colored People --
            History -- 20th century</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Jackson, Jesse, 1941-</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Kaplan, Kivie, 1904-1975</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Wilkins, Roy, 1901-1981</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Wolf, Arnold Jacob</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">National Association for the Advancement of Colored
            People</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Ruderman, Abraham</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Young, Whitney M.</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_o5i" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Kivie Kaplan Papers, 1968-1971</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_6d154a30e347e1e81eb873182ecc116f">
                  <extent>1 box; 25 items</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_0bi" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1968</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d7b78373f7a0a040af9a2a95cc2ecaf7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_2f654b7965c7ef0d3c8bb0ee83f094a3"
                     parent="aspace_d7b78373f7a0a040af9a2a95cc2ecaf7" type="folder">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_4nc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1969</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_66fd322b2e1097fe062d3cfe08596205" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b70d20cf5bc3dae1858aadeb4f4836e0"
                     parent="aspace_66fd322b2e1097fe062d3cfe08596205" type="folder">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_kni" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1970-1971</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_49eb070deac7cdbd960521fff721ec82" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_3bed1c4269127fda58dbd6b49893c8b1"
                     parent="aspace_49eb070deac7cdbd960521fff721ec82" type="folder">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_4tk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed Materials, Re: Kaplan Family</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fc3ae4f71af8127ef930e53cb95fb62f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_77f0b395706821b7d53e415a94890b9a"
                     parent="aspace_fc3ae4f71af8127ef930e53cb95fb62f" type="folder">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_cnz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed Materials, Re: Civil Rights Issues</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_511f022ecff9a866fdfe002264422a8b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_14abe09f71ece81dd6c8fb014d6ecf4c"
                     parent="aspace_511f022ecff9a866fdfe002264422a8b" type="folder">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_3qi" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Plaque</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_91d3d525ae6029fdd0ef5be2331b2bc2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_8515f175f5d42ec212390a1b3b73e694"
                     parent="aspace_91d3d525ae6029fdd0ef5be2331b2bc2" type="folder">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_eau" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Plaque</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f678d800aac37345d2d8dd8a9121c696" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7ba4e541428437bcf22fa8bc2a7465c1"
                     parent="aspace_f678d800aac37345d2d8dd8a9121c696" type="folder">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
