<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/leckie/">leckie</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the W. Robert Leckie Papers, 1768-1906 and undated
          <num>RL.11344</num></titleproper>
        <author>Paul Sommerfeld</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>2016</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000864916</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-11-30 12:53:41
          -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>W. Robert Leckie papers</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Leckie, W. Robert</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.11344</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1768/1906" type="inclusive">1768-1906 and undated</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_27923bd1b802f520c05e03ec7ef6cbc6">Although filed under the name Leckie,
        the collection primarily consists of the papers of two individuals: W. Robert Leckie, and
        his son-in-law, William Hendrick. The papers of Leckie, who was educated in Scotland, are
        concerned with construction of public buildings, canals, arsenals, aqueducts,
        fortifications, masonry of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal, and surveying and building of
        walls in the District of Columbia. The papers of Hendrick and those of his wife, after his
        death, constitute a long record of the sales of plantation products and the purchase of
        supplies from commission merchants in Petersburg, Virginia, and the operation of a series of
        corn and grain farms. </abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_8664ad216c2f8e0643099d226c6a1510">Materials in English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <arrangement id="aspace_aef59b8ec869f07f39f9d7a903e5de4f">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>The collection is sorted into two series: Correspondence and Papers, and Ledgers. Both
        series are arranged chronologically.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <bioghist id="aspace_ae7c389a6b1cf679a086afd6541b8df9">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>W. Robert Leckie was a civil engineer educated in Scotland. After emigrating to the United
        States, Leckie engaged in the construction of public buildings, canals, arsenals, aqueducts,
        fortifications, masonry of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal, and surveying and building of
        walls in the District of Columbia. He had at least three sons and two daughters, one of
        whom, Mary Ann, married William Hendrick in Mecklenburg County, Virginia. He built canals in
        South Carolina, constructed the public buildings of York County, South Carolina, was
        superintendent of the masonry work of the Chesapeake and Ohio canal, built walls around the
        Botanical Gardens in Washington, D.C., and did much of the survey work in the city. He also
        likely built an arsenal at Fayetteville, North Carolina. At the height of his business in
        the 1820s and 1830s, he collected fees in excess of $14,000. Leckie died shortly before 28
        August 1839. </p>
      <p>William Hendrick of Palmer Springs in Mecklenburg County, Virginia, married Mary Ann Leckie
        at an unknown date. Hendrick was a planter; he owned roughly 3000 acres in both Mecklenburg
        County and Warren County, North Carolina. His farms included over 85 slaves in 1857. His
        chief products were tobacco and corn. Several of Hendrick’s children attended Princeton
        University in Princeton, New Jersey, the Virginia Military Institute in Lexington, and other
        various academies. They wrote letters while away from home. Hendrick died around the year
        1857. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_1964956216829d2a5ce3ba0a51971a14">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
        research use.</p>
      <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_523f2313b172dbed743364f116989ccc">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_b4b82f1918398130d4a0ffd4f62806dc">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The W. Robert Leckie Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1936.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_241364f19b1964dfcbf9ea7e21a16293">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], W. Robert Leckie Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_4f4d5d5636134b72cee3eddf852b1eea">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Paul Sommerfeld, November 2016</p>
      <p>Accessions described in this collection guide: 1936, 2008-0220</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_beec3dbe657f40380f7d2ee7949f953d">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>The collection is divided into two series: Correspondence and Papers, and Ledgers. The
        papers of W. Robert Leckie and William Hendrick overlap; both series contain records of
        Hendrick's ancestors. Both series are arranged chronologically by year. </p>
      <p>In the Correspondence and Papers series, the papers of W. Robert Leckie are concerned with
        the construction of public buildings, canals, arsenals, aqueducts, fortifications, masonry
        of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal, and surveying and building of walls in the District of
        Columbia. The papers focus primarily on the prices of commodities used in construction work,
        rather than on qualities of military architecture itself. Also included are the records of a
        lawsuit between Leckie and James Couty; papers relative to experiments in the production of
        lime, cement, and bricks; nine letters from Isaac Roberdeau revealing practices of engineers
        of the period; and a 91-page bound report of the commissioners appointed by the president
        for planning the defense of the United States. This report, though undated, was probably
        made after the War of 1812 and includes extensive details relative to the problems of
        defense, including topography, waterways, roadways, population, distances, and probable
        expenses of constructing forts. Some of Leckie's papers reflect his efforts to obtain
        contracts for the construction of such buildings at the Augusta Arsenal. </p>
      <p>The papers of William Hendrick and Mary Ann Leckie, his wife, constitute a long record of
        the sales of plantation products and the purchase of supplies from commission merchants in
        Petersburg, Virginia, and the operation of a series of tobacco and corn farms. In addition,
        Hendrick's children wrote letters from Princeton University, Princeton, New Jersey; Virginia
        Military Institute, Lexington; and various other academies. Also includes two writing
        exercise books for children. </p>
      <p>In the Ledgers series, among the volumes from Leckie are the following: diary and accounts,
        1828-1829, of engineering contracts and cement stone quarries at Shepherdstown, Va., Seneca,
        Md., Baltimore, and a point near the Monocacy River; a memorandum book containing data for
        surveying water lines, leveling streets, and building aqueducts in Georgetown and
        Washington, D.C.; and a memorandum book of John Leckie, associated with his father, W.
        Robert Leckie. Among the volumes from Hendrick are several plantation account books, a
        memorandum book, and accounts of a mercantile firm. The account books dated 1799 and earlier
        were kept by Hendrick’s forbears.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Military engineering</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Plantations -- Records</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Defenses</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Commission merchants -- Virginia -- Petersburg</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">College students -- Correspondence</subject>
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Hedrick, William, -1857</persname>
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Leckie, Mary Ann</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_2cf78c36a08ad9e1227340f70ada02c2" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence and Papers</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1768-1906 and undated</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_3bb6a4080336cb01315c01587908bff3">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>In the Correspondence and Papers series, the papers of W. Robert Leckie and William
            Hendrick overlap. Both series are arranged chronologically by year. </p>
          <p>The papers of W. Robert Leckie are concerned with the construction of public buildings,
            canals, arsenals, aqueducts, fortifications, masonry of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal,
            and surveying and building of walls in the District of Columbia. The papers focus
            primarily on the prices of commodities used in construction work, rather than on
            qualities of military architecture itself. Also included are the records of a lawsuit
            between Leckie and James Couty; papers relative to experiments in the production of
            lime, cement, and bricks; nine letters from Isaac Roberdeau revealing practices of
            engineers of the period; and a 91-page bound report of the commissioners appointed by
            the president for planning the defense of the United States. This report, though
            undated, was probably made after the War of 1812 and includes extensive details relative
            to the problems of defense, including topography, waterways, roadways, population,
            distances, and probable expenses of constructing forts. Some of Leckie's papers reflect
            his efforts to obtain contracts for the construction of such buildings at the Augusta
            Arsenal.</p>
          <p>Correspondents with Leckie include: Daniel Carroll, W.F. DeSaussure, Charles Gratiot,
            and Alexander Macomb. One letter is of particular interest: an 1829 letter from Leckie
            to Joseph Elgar, Commissioner of Public Buildings, for “bringing water to the Public
            Buildings” on Capitol hill in Washington D.C. Correspondence after 1835 is largely
            comprised of communication between members of the Hendrick family, including letters
            from the Hendrick’s children at Princeton University, Princeton, New Jersey; Virginia
            Military Institute, Lexington; and various other academies.</p>
          <p>The papers of Hendrick and those of his wife, after his death, constitute a long record
            of the sales of plantation products and the purchase of supplies from commission
            merchants in Petersburg, Virginia, and the operation of a series of tobacco and corn
            farms. Also includes two writing exercise books for children. </p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_6bd1dfa1b74bc59a48c8f0caff0cafa8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and papers</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1768-1829</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_aeb4d51741bb43dcfcee1ed7337ae771" label="mixed materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_016cff3fda805e5839d62f7dfb472b81">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Correspondence, looseleaf financial ledger documents</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_5801c19794d54eac350ae03c55d7327b" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and papers</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1830-1844</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_1f8f888e160b1716fbf77838d6c2894c" label="mixed materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_a6ed5028eb8e9bd728ac2dca287efc5c">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Correspondence, financial documents, checklists of belongings, loosely bound account
              book</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_e1684ff2df962fa4e304326893472b5d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and papers</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1845-1906</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2d5231ee4cb2fe6261b397d66b7b9d00" label="mixed materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_6d02e71b123d157b57b629ccbf9d6a56">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Correspondence, financial documents</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_6d4606d7e495851fad40b7d0f2064c0f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and papers</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d6016286322c3e3be3ace1ab004262b8" label="mixed materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_23ced713575e826475e509ce861d4518">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Correspondence, financial documents</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_5994e86ce37f95521c18e11a0fda795d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Report of the United States Commerce of Defence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1821</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_7aaf4be4fad8f696f406b124b257f7e1" label="mixed materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_1bc199d79dbeec0b4428c6f682246ac4">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Handwritten bound volume</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_d16a5b6acf5fa0edff00a727e3e59db5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Mary Ann Hendrick exercise book in writing</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1824</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_1d6d81fbaaa85136ce56a6b4a755d69c" label="mixed materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_d3cf3e6b4964a2c1ce53423823c45db9">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Yorkville, South Carolina</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_91663d3ef526b129e1b9c8ea155ef98c" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Henry Clay Hendrick exercise book in writing</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1854</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_8b142c4577db320c3a66ede20ced3b3f" label="mixed materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_d88548ec0b7f75ff4b90aeed2c4ef198">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Logsdale, Virginia</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_f0ed0dafd77d42b368e30c9a3b5d7bfd" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Ledgers</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1792-1851</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_fcf988af0a486c00370df47478568f23">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>In the Ledgers series, among the volumes from Leckie are the following: diary and
            accounts, 1828-1829, of engineering contracts and cement stone quarries at
            Shepherdstown, Virginia, Seneca [Maryland?], Baltimore, Maryland, and a point near the
            Monocacy River; a memorandum book containing data for surveying water lines, leveling
            streets, and building aqueducts in Georgetown and Washington, D.C.; and a memorandum
            book of John Leckie, associated with his father, W. Robert Leckie. Among the volumes
            from Hendrick are several plantation account books, a memorandum book, and accounts of a
            mercantile firm. The account books dated 1799 and earlier were kept by Hendrick’s
            forbears.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ef577a3edee742a7ef755b5e08892334" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>William Hendrick account book</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1792-1793</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_83fd316d42987fe9d1b91ebb1d6b18d0" label="mixed materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_44d8cc1aa3ac67f3ab46b894663d5542">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Handwritten bound volume; Mecklenburg County, Virginia</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_7014320bd0126cd9a0b9dd7bcac1189d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>William Hendrick account books</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1794-1795</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_6a1ca2ac2c6b6a3fdebe803f6beaa681" label="mixed materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_c6f843e91852611e581d8e05a2327dc1">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains 6 handwritten bound volumes of financial transactions; Palmers Spring,
              Mecklenburg County, Virginia</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_abd75fc0912e43eb1d194d1ca76273e2" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>William Hendrick account books</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1795-1829</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d7ab2f0edc7c65444b4e5b6ba9aa9b30" label="mixed materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_f9ef0f45eec7491cdab11d5c03247e72">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains 3 handwritten bound volumes of financial transactions; Palmers Spring,
              Mecklenburg County, Virginia</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_033df98afbaf0e4d07a8c406e088136b" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>William Hendrick account book</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1829-1833</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_cc03e4ee78e4cb480d7c30eece96bc2c" label="mixed materials"
              type="volume">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_7ba8c782da3eab5a56296edec1ce88e0">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Brunswick county, Virginia</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_5ec42784dafdab23dbe2836bbfb5ba7b" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>William Hendrick account book</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1836-1837</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_855f2af0161b580fd077dbbcd3cf72ca" label="mixed materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_d53a8550ee7e6a10287852db043df1e5">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Brunswick County, Virginia</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_67e768b2173996839f173d8926f64f85" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>William Hendrick account book</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1839-1851</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_25998f678da4fb56270a8ab6c08b13dd" label="mixed materials"
              type="volume">2</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_8659b511cc64d723f5a594bb08e926d7">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Logsdale, Virginia</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_84307c5b8e32db8ff1d61ca1825ad6b4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal of Work Done in 1833</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1833-1834</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_b906f9c386ebb709cdd615dbf2cff6f7" label="mixed materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_6913ecb5cb8ddbb3bcbe32cd5556265b">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Notebook ledger of work done "by the carts and horses in 1833"</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_88efc0a41a07017389c936c30757af0c" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>W. Robert Leckie diary and account book</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1828-1829</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_8fca5c2554c4ee0fc8f0783a573724ef" label="mixed materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_e33d648999ae10a85a4b164e2509b2fa">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Handwritten bound volume of diary entries and records of financial transactions</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_873471d630991b97cda7a60c7534a749" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>John Leckie memorandum book</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1830</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2752c9881fa13e8e397067a3a6d79b7a" label="mixed materials"
              type="box">7</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_b3fc2f5848842ad7d99c85226d280896">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Memorandum book of John Leckie, associated with his father, W. Robert Leckie</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_c99f2207e100522e4fe0553913858d1d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>W. Robert Leckie memorandum book</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1832</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_8fac3c919bc4ffbbfb1a7c6b193b5ffe" label="mixed materials"
              type="box">7</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_2734b728274c1bfa81125b06a5f90fba">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Memorandum book containing data for surveying water lines, leveling streets, and
              building aqueducts in Georgetown and Washington, D.C.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
