<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/lloydnestiav/">lloydnestiav</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Nestia V. Lloyd Diaries, 1923-1925
          <num>RL.11563</num></titleproper>
        <author>Christian Cleaveland, Meghan Lyon</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>2017</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">008121061</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-12-14 16:23:11
          -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Nestia V. Lloyd diaries</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Lloyd, Nestia V., b. 1902</persname>
      </origination>

      <unitid>RL.11563</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.2 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">3 volumes</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1923/1925" type="inclusive">1923-1925</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_1290f00f3ce0100e8b572a8782019915">Three annual diaries (1923-1925) kept
        by Nestia V. Lloyd, a young woman (b. 1902) living with her parents in London and
        Wales.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_95e31f1093b70ef58cd9956e7fa9bd40">Materials in English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="aspace_553a2507b95be3c8feef6a9497781e56">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Nestia V. Lloyd (b. 1902) was an unmarried woman who lived with her parents in London and
        near Colwyn Bay in Wales during the years 1923, 1924, and 1925.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_9d7be27fccc2e66c2faa46d9b1e65ab8">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_2d1d2cb035388e79a211217899d4e68b">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_949a7bf14bee7aa659545c3d9492881c">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Nestia V. Lloyd Diaries were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library as a purchase from Lisa Unger Baskin in 2015.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_760ac7624802ba2be179617dd4dd9ead">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Nestia V. Lloyd Diaries, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_9c11f15940147800f1be68639712ba29">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Christian Cleveland and Meghan Lyon, Dec. 2017</p>
      <p>Accessions described in this collection guide: 2015-0050</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_45741f602d9ffc32a8f1cf481d5274e4">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>Collection consists of three bound diaries kept by Nestia V. Lloyd for the years 1923,
        1924, and 1925. The early pages of the diaries include printed matter such as calendars,
        tips intended for women in the home (regarding cooking, cleaning, personal hygiene and
        health, fashion), London theaters (including Lloyd's notes about which shows she saw at
        which theaters), and notes. Lloyd used the diaries regularly and discussed her personal
        activities, gifts sent and received for various occasions, financial expenses and
        housekeeping, her work and schooling, her travels and activities through London and Wales,
        and family news.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Education</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Wales -- 20th century</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Young women -- England -- London</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">English diaries -- Women authors</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women -- History -- 20th century</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Diaries</genreform>
      <corpname role="rps" rules="dacs" source="naf">Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and
        Culture</corpname>
      <persname role="fmo" rules="dacs" source="naf">Baskin, Lisa Unger, former owner</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_07ec9f1f0fa62c1d542ee60fcc994fb4" level="item">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Volume 1</unittitle>
          <unitdate>1923</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_6cc91d122525a5fc15d81f88d86530ea" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_c7832c52c3dfcb8ea3bfdbe1c3cac20e">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The first volume of Lloyd's diary, which chronicles 1923, documents her life within the
            domicile. Each day, she writes about performing a variety of chores, from dusting entire
            rooms to washing all the silver in the house. Similarly, she accompanies her mother as
            she shops daily throughout London. Two of the destinations that they frequent are
            Kensington and West. Most of the purchases that they make revolve around food and are
            often times the ingredients for that night's dinner. Throughout the diary, Lloyd also
            indicates that she maintains a few correspondences over the year. She frequently writes
            to her friends Ellie Wills and Sytha. She also maintains a constant communication with a
            man named Russell. They talk on the telephone often, and she has him over for dinner a
            few times over the year. In April, Lloyd wrote about the Royal Wedding that took place
            between Prince Albert and Lady Elizabeth. In school, Lloyd is studying both French and
            Italian. Based on her accounts of each class, French is easier for her to learn, and
            there are times where she exclaims how well she is picking it up versus how poorly she
            is understanding Italian. Every week, Lloyd attends church with her mother, and
            sometimes her Auntie May accompanies them.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_8700b8b474d1dc0889bdf5dfef496f71" level="item">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Volume 2</unittitle>
          <unitdate>1924</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_fbec6a1eae10a6ef5fbe4d887dc8bc4f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_ed94e92a8666fcf538a0f49187749fd7">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The second volume of Lloyd's diary, which chronicles her 1924 year, indicates both a
            continued presence in the home but also her increasing independence. While she still
            goes shopping with her mother frequently, Lloyd also begins to do things without her
            mother's guidance and help. For example, midway through the year (around July), she
            began to go on daily walks with her sister to Colwyn Bay (Wales) without the company of
            her mom. Lloyd also picks up both the piano and the violin in her free time, and she
            becomes an avid reader. On many occasions, she would stay in bed until it was time for
            dinner because she was so invested in whatever book she was reading at the time. Lloyd
            also continued the dance lessons that she began the year before. She also appeared to
            increase her commitment to dance, as she began practicing multiple times per week
            without fail.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_35ae593b85038e5d037abc1e47112b3b" level="item">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Volume 3</unittitle>
          <unitdate>1925</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_25509b4dfef024e1c1b55dcd5184a9a2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_0a807755e27c9275c48df0b1104a275f">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The third volume of Lloyd's diary, which chronicles her 1925 year, again indicates her
            continued presence within the home as shown by the various chores that she performs
            daily. However, Lloyd also begins to learn how to type. On one particular day, she is
            ecstatic after passing one of her typing tests with flying colors after achieving a
            words-per-minute score of 33. On top of that, Lloyd begins attending weekly lectures
            about being ladylike; she learns about manners and how to carry herself. She continues
            to dance and play both the piano and violin, though does so less frequently and with
            less enthusiasm as she did in 1924.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
