<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/lowyben/">lowyben</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Benjamin Lowy photographs of Iraq, 2003-2008
          <num>RL.00825</num></titleproper>
        <author>Joanne Fairhurst</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>November 2012</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">004984312</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-07-19 15:34:33
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2014</date>
        <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported to
          Archivists Toolkit</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Benjamin Lowy photographs of Iraq</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname role="pht" source="ingest">Lowy, Benjamin, 1979-</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.00825</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">2 boxes</extent>
        <physfacet>32 items</physfacet>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="2003/2008" type="inclusive">2003-2008</unitdate>
      <physloc id="aspace_f8467cd48d00e5b8d92738c2783d1edf">For current information on the location
        of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
      <abstract id="aspace_4e8ee1bddb795be9af9854496a2e4655">The collection consists of thirty-two
        9x13 inch untitled digital color inkjet photographs taken by Benjamin Lowy, documenting the
        U.S. military presence in Iraq from 2003 to 2008. The prints are arranged in two series:
          <emph render="bold">Windows</emph> and <emph render="bold">Nightvision</emph>. Images in
        the Windows series were taken from the bulletproof windows of the armored Humvees in which
        Lowy spent most of his time while on missions in Iraq; they depict street scenes with Iraqi
        civilians, tanks, soldiers, checkpoints, military impoundments, street life, urban Iraqi
        culture, and a war-ravaged Iraqi landscape. Taken through U.S. military-issue night vision
        goggles, photographs in the Nightvision series reveal greenish images of late-night raids,
        prisoners and soldiers, landscapes, families, women, and street scenes. The images in this
        collection were published in 2011 as a photobook titled <title render="italic">Iraq |
          Perspectives</title>. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke
        University.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_46c104cad58cbe2993f2e9118834fdcc">Material in English </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_fcdd9caabede1eeb5eb79d30afc31729">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research. Images may only be used for educational, non-commercial
        purposes; any other use requires the photographer's permission.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
        research use.</p>
      <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_db80ff1f060b09616e0aa3d4d1a90f50">
      <head>Copyright Notice</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_d04c07c9bae62cda057805412f4ca2c5">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Benjamin Lowy photographs of Iraq, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_2cad76953b7195d7f8c458d3074c3dab">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Benjamin Lowy photographs of Iraq were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2011.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo id="aspace_77ea61b1db4c864189ab92911377ef02">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed and encoded by Joanne Fairhurst, November 2012.</p>
      <p>Accession(s) described in this finding aid: 2011-0180.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_45190531488bbcd8320f55576411d45c">
      <head>Biographical Note</head>
      <p>Documentary photographer Ben Lowy was born on June 4, 1979. After receiving his BFA from
        Washington University in St. Louis in 2002, Lowy began his career covering the Iraq War in
        2003. In addition to his coverage of Iraq, Lowy has worked in Darfur, Libya, Haiti,
        Afghanistan, and other countries. Lowy has received numerous awards for his work from World
        Press Photo, POYi, PDN, Communication Arts, American Photography, and the Society for
        Publication Design. Exhibitions of his work have been held at the Tate Modern, SF MOMA,
        Houston Center for Photography, Les Invalides (Paris), and Arles. In 2011, Lowy's <title
          type="simple" render="italic">Iraq | Perspectives</title> won the Duke University Center
        for Documentary Studies/Honickman First Book Prize in Photography by William Eggleston.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_a0f5a10b70ee8e77e544d209f4f341d8">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>The collection consists of thirty-two 9x13 inch untitled digital color inkjet photographs
        taken by Benjamin Lowy, documenting the U.S. military presence in Iraq from 2003 to 2008.
        The images were published in 2011 as a photo book, <title type="simple" render="italic">Iraq
          | Perspectives</title>.</p>
      <p>The prints are arranged in two series: Windows and Nightvision. Images in the Windows
        series, reproduced as sixteen 13x19 inch color digital inkjet prints, were taken from the
        bulletproof windows of the armored Humvees in which Lowy spent most of his time while on
        documentary missions in Iraq. The images include street scenes with Iraqi civilians, tanks,
        soldiers, checkpoints, military impoundments, and images documenting urban Iraqi culture,
        and a war-ravaged Iraqi landscape. Images in the Nightvision subseries, consisting of
        sixteen 13x19 inch color digital inkjet prints, were taken through U.S. military-issue night
        vision goggles, and reveal late-night raids, prisoners and soldiers, families, women, night
        landscapes, and street scenes. </p>
      <p>All the images were shot with a digital single lens reflex (DSLR) camera and printed on
        Epson Professional Paper. They are arranged in original order as received from the
        photographer.</p>
      <p>Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_be772ad02f14ff947b3de6c78fc98e5c">
      <head>Related Materials</head>
      <p>Exhibit (online): <title render="italic">Iraq | Perspectives: Photographs by Benjamin
          Lowy</title>, Duke University Libraries, 24 October-11 December, 2011.</p>
      <p>Book (see Duke University Libraries catalog): <title render="italic">Iraq, perspectives:
          photographs by Benjamin Lowy</title>, Durham, N.C. : Duke University Press : CDS Book,
        c2011</p>
      <p>Related collection: <extref xlink:type="simple"
          xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/iraqciviliansphotos/"
          >Photographs by Iraqi civilians, 2004 April-May</extref>, Rubenstein Library, Duke
        University.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <controlaccess>
      <geogname source="lcsh">United States. Army -- History -- Iraq War, 2003-2011</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Documentary Photography -- Iraq</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Pictorial works</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">War photography -- Iraq</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Iraq -- Pictorial works</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Iraq -- Social conditions</geogname>
      <genreform source="aat">Color photographs</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Inkjet prints</genreform>
      <persname source="ingest">Lowy, Benjamin, 1979-</persname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref14_kss" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Iraq | Perspectives I: Windows</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="2003/2008" type="inclusive">2003-2008</unitdate>
          <physdesc id="aspace_3a317d0bd10c28750c2608c414e5f965"><extent>16
            prints</extent></physdesc>
          <container id="aspace_ea4e1ca018a6dd4c60c64fd2030b3620" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_4f43e2c3132a6c5888b90dc4841b319e">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>This series, consisting of 16 color digital inkjet prints, stems from images taken from
            the bulletproof windows of the armored Humvees in which Lowy spent most of his time
            while on missions in Iraq. This perspective was necessary since Lowy was unable to tour
            the streets of Iraq without protection. The Humvee window, evidenced in each image of
            this subseries, came to represent for Lowy the barrier between the Americans and Iraqis.
            The images portray not only street scenes with Iraqi civilians, notably Iraqi women and
            children, but also tanks, soldiers, checkpoints, military impoundments, street life,
            urban Iraqi culture, and a war-ravaged Iraqi landscape.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref17_o84" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Iraq | Perspectives II: Nightvision</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="2003/2008" type="inclusive">2003-2008</unitdate>
          <physdesc id="aspace_33c7a92a51338c13d3393e8856adc3a4"><extent>16
            prints</extent></physdesc>
          <container id="aspace_c58d425608d5bc27aaf80b49af37b341" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >2</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_482cbfadf926b2fd0d67f59359ccc8d7">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>The images in this series, consisting of 16 color digital inkjet prints, were taken
            through U.S. military-issue night vision goggles, which Lowy attached to his DSLR camera
            with a combination of duct tape, dental floss and occasionally chewing gum. The night
            vision images, with an eerie greenish hue, reveal frightened civilians, abandoned
            streets, and U.S. soldiers. The images document the impact of war on Iraq. Dominant
            subjects include families, late-night raids on Iraqi dwellings, interactions between
            soldiers and prisoners, Iraqi landscapes, and street scenes.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
