<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/matlockrebecca/">matlockrebecca</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Rebecca B. Matlock photographs, 1980s-2015, bulk 1980s-2005
            <num>RL.11383</num></titleproper>
        <author>Paula Jeannet</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>September 2017</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph number: <num type="aleph">008012054</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-03-26 10:20:30
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>December 2017</date>
        <item>Addition of 25 photographs and small group of papers processed and described by Paula
          Jeannet Mangiafico.</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Rebecca B. Matlock photographs</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname rules="rda" source="local">Matlock, Rebecca B., 1928- </persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.11383</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">23 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">26 boxes</extent>
        <physfacet>approximately 975 items</physfacet>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1980/2015" type="inclusive">1980s-2015</unitdate>
      <unitdate normal="1980/2005" type="bulk">1980s-2005</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_9848b143ca021a0a3e23072d1f63e120">Collection of 848 color inkjet
        photographs taken by Rebecca Matlock while traveling and living in countries around the
        world, with a special focus on landscapes, churches and other buildings, people, and
        culture. Over half of the collection features images from the former Soviet Union during the
        Gorbachev administration (1980s-1990s), including Central Asia, the Republic of Buryatia,
        the Ukraine, and Moscow. Notable individuals include the Gorbachevs, Reagans, Bushes, and
        the Shevardnadzes, secretaries of state, politicians, and military officials. Other subjects
        include artists, writers, religious leaders, with one series given to dissident and
        scientist Andrei Sakharov. Other series include: the Republic of Georgia and Tbilisi during
        and after the civil war; the Czech Republic; the Middle East; the wall dividing Jerusalem;
        the fall of the Berlin Wall; and Peru. There are smaller groups from the Baltic States,
        France, Alaska, Hawaii, Japan, Hong Kong, and other places. An additional series has as its
        subject conductor and opera director Sarah Caldwell. There is also a series of abstract
        images titled Black and White in Color. Most of the prints in the collection were exhibited;
        thus there are roughly 100 printed items such as caption and title cards and
        fliers.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_34489a62d988a38cbeb86588f6783f2d">Materials in English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <arrangement id="aspace_95652d841534fbd4dbcdd633c9ed4ef7">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Arranged in the following series: Baltic States; Black and White in Color; Czech Republic;
        Far East; France; Germany: The Wall Came Down; The Middle East; Past and Present in Peru;
        Russia and Other Regions, divided into 11 sub-series; Sarah Caldwell; South and Central
        America; Special Places; United States; and Other Places. There is also a small series of
        papers.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <bioghist id="aspace_5fd68c3adae0931d8ea6d933fe1ff5e3">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Rebecca Matlock is a photographer, writer, supporter of the arts, and wife of former U.S.
        Ambassador to the former Soviet Union, Jack Matlock.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_8a46bc7fcfca085e45f938aa59a929fc">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research. Use is restricted to non-commercial, educational purposes;
        any other use requires written permission of the photographer.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_7dac1a425345fc57e7261c806dbb0353">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_ca63b697cd46fcc44192beb15dec69e3">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Rebecca Matlock photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_593658e2de4681561679a3e245131825">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Rebecca Matlock photographs, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_e4c9f4f7bfb84e44c66036477cc618d3">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Paula Jeannet and Rachel Fox, August 2017. Addition processed and described by
        Paula Jeannet, December 2017.</p>
      <p>Accession(s) described in this collection guide: 2017-0004, 2017-0175</p>
    </processinfo>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_d0009df61d6e8dbfd6a027ce46273ad7">
      <head>Related Materials</head>
      <p><archref><unittitle label="Collection">Jack and Rebecca Matlock Papers,
            1930s-2017</unittitle><repository label="Repository">Rubenstein Library, Duke
            University</repository>
        </archref></p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_57a0b7f1cc91cbbea91147b3386e5e6e">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>Collection of 848 color inkjet photographs taken by Rebecca Matlock while traveling and
        living in countries around the world, with a special focus on landscapes, churches and other
        buildings, and all aspects of society and culture. There are also approximately 100 printed
        items. Over half of the collection features images from the former Soviet Union during the
        Gorbachev administration (1980s-1990s), including Central Asia, the Republic of Buryatia,
        the Ukraine, and Moscow. Many notable individuals appear, including the Gorbachevs, Reagans,
        Bushes, Shevardnadzes, secretaries of state, and military officials. Other subjects of
        portraits include artists, writers, and religious leaders in the Soviet Union; one small
        series is given to dissident and scientist Andrei Sakharov. Other places and events include:
        the Republic of Georgia and Tbilisi during and after the civil war; the Czech Republic; the
        Middle East; the wall dividing Jerusalem; the fall of the Berlin Wall; and Peru. There are
        smaller series from the Baltic States, France, Alaska, Hawaii, Japan, Hong Kong, and other
        places. An additional series offers portraits of conductor and opera director Sarah
        Caldwell. There is also a series of abstract images. Most of the prints in the collection
        were exhibited in the U.S. and other places abroad; thus there are some printed materials
        related to exhibits and lectures. </p>
      <p>Matlock was especially interesteed in documenting the people she encountered in her
        travels, on the street as well as in restaurants, shopping districts, and at home. Following
        from her interest in architecture, the arts, and literature, many images have as their
        subjects artists, writers, editors, and dancers, as well as architecture, modern artwork and
        traditional crafts.</p>
      <p>The Russia and Other Regions series is significant for its often informal and intimate
        depictions of notable individuals associated with the Matlocks' activities as American
        ambassadors in Russia: these include Mikhail and Raisa Gorbachev, Ronald and Nancy Reagan,
        George H. W. and Barbara Bush, Eduard Sheverdnadze, along with several secretaries of state,
        career politicians, military officials, and religious leaders. Other subjects include
        artists, editors, writers, and scientists, with one small series devoted entirely to
        dissident and scientist Andrei Sakharov. </p>
      <p>Other notable foreign leaders appear in the Middle East series group entitled "Middle East
        Leaders," while they attended various meetings and conferences at which the Matlocks were
        present.</p>
      <p>The color prints fall into two size groups: 11x14 and 8x10 inches, with some variability.
        Almost all the larger prints are housed in thin white window mats and are typically inkjet
        or laser printed, some at a later date than when they were originally taken.</p>
      <p>Most of the prints in the collection were exhibited in the U.S. and abroad; thus, there is
        a small amount of print materials in the Papers Series related to exhibits and lectures,
        such as caption cards, title panels, and fliers as well as a Russian magazine, OGONET
        (1989), with an article about her photography, in Russian.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Ambassadors -- American -- Soviet Union</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Artists -- Soviet Union</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Authors, Soviet -- Portraits</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Civil war -- Georgia (Republic)</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Documentary Photography</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Glasnost</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Scientists -- Soviet Union -- Portraits</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women photographers -- United States</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Berlin Wall, Berlin, Germany, 1961-1989 -- Photographs</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Buri︠a︡tii︠a︡ (Russia) -- Photographs</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Czech Republic -- Photographs</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Georgia (Republic) -- Photographs</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Jerusalem -- Administrative and political divisions</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Middle East -- Politics and government -- 1979- </geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Moscow (Russia) -- Photographs</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Palestine -- Administrative and political divisions</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Peru -- Photographs</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">South America -- Photographs</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Soviet Union -- Churches -- Photographs</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Soviet Union -- Foreign relations -- United States</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Soviet Union -- Politics and government -- 1985-1991</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Soviet Union -- Photographs</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Soviet Union -- Religious life</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Soviet Union -- Social life and customs</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Spaso House (Moscow, Russia)</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Tbilisi (Georgia) -- Photographs</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Photographs</geogname>
      <genreform source="aat">Color photographs</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Digital prints</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Electronic documents</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Inkjet prints</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Photobooks</genreform>
      <persname authfilenumber="85320162" source="naf">Matlock, Jack F.</persname>
      <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Bush, Barbara, 1925- </persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Bush, George, 1924-2018</persname>
      <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Caldwell, Sarah, 1924-2006</persname>
      <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Gorbachev, Mikhail Sergeevich, 1931- </persname>
      <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Gorbacheva, Raisa Maksimovna, 1932-1999</persname>
      <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Reagan, Nancy, 1921-2016</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Reagan, Ronald</persname>
      <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Sakharov, Andreĭ, 1921-1989</persname>
      <persname rules="rda" source="naf">Shevardnadze, Ė. A. (Ėduard Amvrosievich),
        1928-2014</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_1ebbd4bb5c1029fc01dadebe942c3ba8" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
          <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">896
              items</extent><extent altrender="carrier">27 boxes</extent><physfacet>Approximately
              875 prints; one photobook; approximately 20 loose printed
            items.</physfacet></physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1980/2015" type="inclusive">1980s-2000s</unitdate>
          <physdesc id="aspace_97a614845ddba1fbc89ac66c2bf93143">The photographic prints come in two
            sizes: the majority are 11x14 inch prints housed in 16x20 inch window mats; the rest are
            unmatted smaller prints measuring approximately 8x10 to 11x14 inches, with some
            variations in size. All are color inkjet prints.</physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_d4a01f620be10b0701298a2eb0078125">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The color photographs forming this collection are arranged in fourteen series: Baltic
            States; Black and White in Color; Czech Republic; Far East; France; Germany: The Wall
            Came Down; The Middle East; Past and Present in Peru; Russia and Other Regions, divided
            into 11 sub-series; Sarah Caldwell; South and Central America, Special Places; United
            States; and Other Places, which includes images of the Antarctic, Australia, Bora Bora,
            Canada, the Galapagos, New Zealand, Samoa, and Tahiti, taken during cruises and tours. </p>
          <p>Many of the series titles derive from exhibits, and many prints bear caption cards. In
            addition, there are often large matted exhibit title cards at the beginning of each
            series. Most of the prints are undated and untitled, but approximate dates were conveyed
            by the photographer and are recorded for each series.</p>
          <p>As Rebecca Matlock engaged in the political and social responsibilities of a U.S.
            Ambassador's spouse and cultural affairs partner, she was often present at state
            dinners, meetings, and cultural events, many of which she organized at Spaso House, the
            U.S. Ambassador's residence, and elsewhere. With camera in hand, she captured portraits
            of notable leaders and associates: Mikhail and Raisa Gorbachev, Nancy and Ronald Reagan,
            George H.W. and Barbara Bush, Eduard Shevardnadze, George Schultz, Colin Powell, Howard
            Baker, James Baker, and many other politicians, religious and military leaders, and
            artists and writers in the countries the Matlocks visited.</p>
          <p>These photographs, usually informal and intimate in comparison to officially
            distributed White House and Tass Agency images, offer a rare glimpse into the personal
            and social lives of these individuals, and the often unusually relaxed gatherings and
            other events in the "glasnost" era.</p>
          <p>Other photographs were taken during family trips and tours to places in the United
            States and abroad; these images tend to focus on landscapes, people, and all aspects of
            culture, with a particular emphasis on local arts and crafts. Places in the U.S. are
            chiefly limited to Alaska and Hawaii, although there are other places in the U.S.A
            Buildings group, and a few images probably from Boston in the Sarah Caldwell series, and
            some U.S. locations, unidentified, in the Black and White in Color seres.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_7014ff25c52a79bf320b5f47b0af1bc0" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Black and White in Color</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">22
                prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1980/1984" type="inclusive">circa 1980-1984</unitdate>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_4f08fd63d6c3f8a7ff2237809a392cfc">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The title of the series derives from the title of Rebecca Matlock's first solo
              exhibit, in 1984. The 21 large color prints and one smaller print feature abstract
              patterns formed by contrasting light and dark tonalities, found in architectural
              details, human figures, and the natural world. The photographs were taken around the
              world in various locations. Two other items consist of exhibit title cards.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_c41bb35972a55322ce52fca31fa646fc" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Large prints</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_65a03f55b13bca6b1cd47401ad5e9630" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_9cbda8dd3a6c635e6ebf5f7f31f0a4ca" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Small prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                  items</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-11x14x3" id="aspace_1304b5a135a936b7308e4de1ff823517"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_dfac00da4331d9d99b2b8ddd5db7d7a6">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains 1 print and 2 title sheets.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_a43760667c4c85c694754242b15ef34d" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Baltic States</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                prints</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="2000/2000">circa 2000</unitdate>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_a072c700f3f5568d48cd443351a0c5ed">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>These images were taken on a cruise in the 2000s. One print is labeled "Blue Grotto,
              Italy," and two are of the Baltic Sea in Sweden.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_8b3732022acf0f7787f60f858266efb5" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Large prints</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_668a15a3dc4c484f63658fbf09669782" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_55253e6b74207f575a228aac5441061c" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Czech Republic</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">27
                prints</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1990/1999" type="inclusive">circa 1990s</unitdate>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_9873a741082dfcfceb58b086b473f756">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>This large series of photographs was taken in Prague and other urban locations.
              Images chiefly consist of public art - mostly sculptures - and portraits of citizens.
              There are also landscapes from rural areas. One photograph is a view of the monument
              to the Battle of Austerlitz, 1805, which took place in what is now the Czech Republic.
              Along with the 24 matted 11x14" prints there are three smaller loose prints.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_3414a1e2641a42d81a015b8e09997988" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Large prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">24
                  prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_0d8b1d6c0374cbbcb3bd369f29642348" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_f1c6bd0e898baee15200cf23a1ce984d" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Small prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-11x14x3" id="aspace_cf504b4554acee7dec81f9d0e2deda09"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">24</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_dd3142638dbd7b22d158587d7963cc0e" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Far East</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">37
                prints</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1980/2010" type="inclusive">circa 1980s-2000s</unitdate>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_597f89801235105492a6b5202f2ebb31">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The majority of these color photographs were taken sometime in the 1980s and 1990s in
              the Republic of Buryatia, a region of steppes in southeastern Russia bordered by Lake
              Baikal. They formed part of exhibits on the Far East and thus were retained as part of
              this original series. Many other images of Buryatia are in the Central Asia sub-group
              in the Russia and Other Regions series.</p>
            <p>The Buryatia photographs chiefly consist of street portraits of ordinary men, women,
              and school-aged children, with a few architectural and landscape studies, and scenes
              from such subjects as a horse race, a fashion show, and a wedding. Other photographs
              were taken in China, Japan, Hong Kong, South Korea, and unidentified locations.
              Twenty-one of the prints are smaller unmatted photographs and are also chiefly from
              Buryatia.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_445c4cc7caca065f6b7a66e9f33e1473" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Large prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_7c331a4691f2db438a50266dce742b50" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_20e3763af40ad1990a71b2d69713c818" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Small prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">21
                  prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">2 folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-11x14x3" id="aspace_532f690d303518f717a50c3b775d1e98"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">24</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ad12d3bc607111d34b0b33886b8b7f01" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Additional large prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc id="aspace_d53a037295ffd1db42036b4799e70542"><extent>4
                prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_76f95f2fe8744fd4176485cb8994f4f8"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">26</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_8d23ee19b7b72f661428696acea98d80">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>A later addition to the collection, the locations represented in these large prints
                include China, Japan, and South Korea.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_a94953cc28abddf171f1dcf397efb4ab" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>France</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4
                prints</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1989/1989">after 1989</unitdate>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_9e0bce366dfd711d8ce39656d27b2390">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Subjects of the three large prints are: an unidentified glass-fronted building; the
              glass pyramid by I.M. Pei at the Louvre in Paris, and the rhinoceros sculpture by
              Alfred Jacquemart, outside the Musee d'Orsay. There is also a smaller unmatted print
              of an unidentified sculpture.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_94216c781692ab83617dbb361d8768ed" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Large prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_9a570c25ba34905da59eebed02ca9d96" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_60038ec47c280a4d924c05604ef52ae5" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Small print</unittitle>
              <container altrender="Flat-11x14x3" id="aspace_a06e6cd589ce3288bb67682826f2c462"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">24</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_86971cb62bedb2ab15bccd416efe16dd" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Germany: The Wall Came Down</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12
                prints</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1990/1990">1990</unitdate>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_aa604a2aea0cac4943b1ae384e28991d">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Images relate to the fall of the Berlin Wall and were taken in 1990, before the
              official demolition of the Wall. They show citizens and tourists hammering at the
              wall, embracing each other, selling souvenirs, and standing or posing near the wall.
              There is also one image of the post-modernist Neue Staatsgalerie art museum in
              Stuttgart, which has as its subject an outdoor wall with a few stones deliberately
              removed.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_19e46e91b44cacea69ec44a19fd24636" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Large prints</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_0d943a8e7415c590b5ab287682b34c79" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_179926c04f37746467e2c5683c07cde0" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>The Middle East</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">24
                prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="2009/2009">2009</unitdate>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_84cb1f160f14d344346dc804d4ac75bf">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Divided into two groups based on exhibits: The Wall Isolating Jerusalem (10 prints);
              and Middle East Leaders (14 prints). Also includes a title card for the Wall series.
              Each group has a description section with more details.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_35b785705a57709933871b540e1094e7" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>The Wall Isolating Jerusalem (large prints)</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_49612c4d3aafccf757d8c9598276d41e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">4</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_fb33a459564755c9dc9f0b542acc834b">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>This body of work consists of photographs of the "Separation Wall" dividing East
                Jerusalem from the West Bank and other areas. It was begun in 2000 and never fully
                completed. The images often show graffiti on the wall, mosques and other buildings
                behind the wall, and long-range views of the wall; a few images show people walking
                nearby.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_fd042fedc2e38c461cd983d67f79dd92" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Middle East Leaders (large prints)</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">14
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_9e8205bad638b0036e61498e44035ab4" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">4</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_315723e31ba7acb3396d7698ef299d25">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Almost entirely portraits of leaders, men and women, from Egypt, Lebanon, Jordan,
                Syria, Israel, and Palestine, photographed in the Fall of 2009. Some were taken at
                meetings and dinners, and others seem to have been taken in private residences or
                houses. Names include Saad Al-Hariri (Lebanese Prime Minister); Michel Suleiman
                (President of Lebanon); Ahmed Maher al-Sayed (Egyptian Parliament); Naomi Chazan
                (member of Knesset, Israel); Hesham Youssef (League of Arab States, Egypt); Hussein
                Haider (Hezbollah, Lebanon); Khaled Meshaal or Mashal (Hamas, Syria); and Salaam
                Fayed (Prime Minister, Palestinian Authority).</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_89ca68c9b73d385f07c5f52e532b1253" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>The Past and Present in Peru</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">59
                prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">2 boxes</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="2013/2013">2013</unitdate>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_4a2127a6f08a1eb78cb4bb3418b12b3a">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Many of these photographs formed an exhibit entitled "The Past in the Present in
              Peru." Taken in 2013, they include landscapes from northern to southern Peru, scenes
              from rural villages, ruins such as those of Machu Picchu, aerial views of hilltop
              carvings, gardens in Lima, portraits of native inhabitants, and arts-related images,
              with a focus on sculptures, rug designs, wall paintings, and native crafts, especially
              pottery. There may be a few images from other South American countries included in
              this series. A later addition to the collection consists of photographs taken in other
              South and Central American countries around the same time.</p>
            <p>Most of the prints bear detailed captions. Some are identified as having been taken
              by Rebecca Matlock's son Joe as the family traveled together. Along with the 57 large
              matted prints, there are two smaller loose prints, and there are also a handful of
              panoramic photographs. </p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_85a291dccd34814280e422dbb697cdc2" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Large prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">23
                  prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_9594144a02c3c1c444119ed85a9e4611" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">5</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_da3ec9054dd0b217eb6d2d31c790fba8" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Large prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">34
                  prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_ee592d1ece320765de4da5e2d574a436" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">6</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_5fe8db95c548dadc283efdf2011755c0" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Small prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-11x14x3" id="aspace_8295b62e35d1f23ef602a4b887b05ad9"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">24</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_4189b72ae1d04d8ce05fd5896292acd5" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Russia and Other Regions</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">580
                prints</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1985/2000" type="inclusive">circa 1985-2000</unitdate>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_51fca2f624af8252ec0ca19ebd172042">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>This body of work is the largest by far in the collection, with 580 total prints, and
              is subdivided into the following groups titled after their exhibitions: Americans and
              Russians; Andrei Sakarov; At Spaso House; Central Asia and Buryatia; Chautauqua; Faces
              of Slavic Countries; Gorbachev and American Presidents; Gorbachev in Retirement;
              Landscapes, Buildings, and Other Scenes; Republic of Georgia and Tbilisi; and
              Trans-Caucasus (chiefly from Ukraine). There is also one folder with a later addition
              of two prints. Groups are described in further detail in each section.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_9649a6077a75b2f96c666f598600988d" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Americans and Russians</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">14
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_216bd1c80eb6010148c8fb38a5fbdead" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">7</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_c3ec806c3b1ffb6aeb24e6dc8d00a55d">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>These photographs document the gradual thawing in the 1980s of American-Soviet
                relations, which led to less strictures on contacts between individuals and groups
                from both countries. Notable individuals featured in the images include Prime
                Minister Shevardnadze with Ambassador Jack Matlock and Ambassador and politician
                Anatoly Dobrinin; Mrs. Helena O'Brien Schultz with Tereshkova, a museum director; a
                young American posing with her host Russian family; young Americans and Russians
                planting trees; Librarian of Congress James Billington with Kirgiz author Chingiz
                Aitmatov and a Kirgiz film director; David and Susan Eisenhower; writer Leonid
                Leonov; and many others. One photograph shows a Fourth of July celebration at a
                Russian dacha. There are also ten small prints with portraits of American general
                and former Secretary of State Colin Powell, ballerina Maya Plisetskaya, poet and
                writer Andrei Voznesenski with Jack Matlock, and Yehudi Menuhin with Andrei
                Sakharov.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_8b17dcf0364ffb75224938b5950cb898" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Andrei Sakharov</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">35
                  prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_772f6e4a2c9b4a39aad5b22e1eadb87e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">7</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_bf31db6955caf4a830a0913898f865a5">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Images of scientist and dissident Andrei Sakharov relaxing at Spaso House and at
                his dacha (summer home). Other people featured include Yehudi Menuhin with Sakharov
                at Spaso House, where they would draft a letter together to Gorbachev concerning
                human rights, and the writer Andrei Voznesenski. There are several images of the
                interiors at Spaso House, as well as interiors and the exterior of Sakharov's dacha,
                with some intimate close-ups of his boots, books, and other belongings.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_1fdf6340adc37588ba9aa9fc759f1beb" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>At Spaso House</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">38
                  prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_b9d408dcb351c8c20c184f2e3b584f9d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">8</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_ccc55d6669af57dd9e59e96bc97175d5">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>These photographs were taken at Spaso House, the neoclassical Moscow residence
                built in 1913, and which became the U.S. Ambassador's residence. Most of the
                photographs were taken in the 1980s, and portray the many visitors and events held
                at Spaso House, many of them arts-related. The majority are captioned.</p>
              <p>Individuals featured in the portraits include cellist Yo Yo Ma; pianist Van
                Cliburn; Katherine Graham of the <title render="italic">Washington Post</title>;
                David Rockefeller; Susan Eisenhower at a celebration of her wedding to physicist
                Roald Sagdeyev; entertainer Brooke Shields with Bob Hope; conductor Sarah Caldwell
                and composer Rodion Shchedrin; cellist and conductor Mstislav Rostropovich; members
                of the Harlem Chess Club; Native American artists; writers Akhmadulina and Aksyonov;
                and Leo Tolstoy's granddaughter. Political and military figures include Ambassador
                General Walters; Eduard Shevardnadze; Akhrameyer, a military advisor, with Jack
                Matlock; Richard Nixon; and Boris Yeltsin.</p>
              <p>Mixed with images of people are a few shots of interiors and meeting rooms at Spaso
                House; one shows several rows of Russian military hats on a coat rack. Other
                photographs taken at Spaso House are found in the Andrei Sakharov subseries.</p>
              <p>Several of the photographs in this series were taken by White House photographers,
                and are captioned as such; one is of President Ronald Reagan with Jack and Rebecca
                Matlock, during his 1988 visit to Moscow for the U.S./U.S.S.R. Summit.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d424bad91730523b09173ffe4ea14fd6" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Central Asia and Buryatia</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">42
                  prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">2 boxes</extent></physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_53a3674d2a6ae73d9591283a4bb7f8bf">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>The 42 photographs in this series were taken by Rebecca Matlock while traveling
                with a group across the steppes and high-altitude regions of Central Asia. There is
                a large group from the Republic of Buryatia. Many of the photographs feature
                portraits of adults and children, chiefly from villages and small towns; there is a
                portrait of a monk near Ulan Ude. There are many landscapes, including a scene from
                Listvyanka, on the shores of Lake Baikal, and other lake settings; buildings such as
                log homes and architectural details, traditional and modern arts and crafts; musical
                instruments; and a table set with traditional Buryatian foods. Other photographs
                taken in Buryatia are found in the Far East subseries, which formed a separate group
                of exhibit images.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c04 id="aspace_b78907f2040a2e2b1aa345c01ab12e42" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Large prints</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_74d6c4e541a5fa111584562447d2e4f0" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">9</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_903a98d58bef9a10fc51916d592c5f58" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Large prints</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_feebf15a129823cb9ab3c5592097b1bf" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">10</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_b208a54bd14e63d69b13d630497ceb97" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Chautauqua</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">27
                  prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_87aae65cea749e5be4777560f5dcadc1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">11</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_3fe01f220290aa045b4998281b0707c3">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>These images were taken at several Chautauqua meetings on Soviet-American
                relations, held jointly by the former Soviet Union and the United States. The
                Chautauqua locations were: New York, 1985, Latvia in 1986, in New York again in
                1987, Tbilisi in 1988, and in Pittsburgh in 1989. The majority of the images are
                from the 1988 meeting in Tbilisi. It is unclear if the New York images are from both
                1985 and 1987 or from only one date. </p>
              <p>The photographs were chiefly taken in the meeting rooms, banquet halls, and other
                spaces devoted to the gatherings; they feature attendees, speakers, religious
                dedications, and cultural entertainments put on for the benefit of the participants.
                Notable people among the USSR and US representatives include Jack Matlock; James
                Baker and his wife Susan Garrett Winston; Helena O'Brien, the wife of George
                Schultz; the Deputy Mayor of Tbilisi; Mr. and Mrs. Shevardnadze; Cosmonauts
                Valentina Tereshkova and Leonid Leonov; and Congressman Amo Houghton of N.Y. There
                are also 18 smaller prints of participants and panels.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_09049ac03ee02e137d4e5750f97ae606" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Faces of Slavic Countries</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">27
                  prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_f2ac9eb93dde249389fc76e371b7bbe2"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_cdfb8f565163479a59572c98cdfdee90">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>The images in this series are of the people Rebecca Matlock encountered in her
                travels across Eastern Europe and Central Asia. Most of the prints are uncaptioned.
                Informal portraits include women, children, and men, individually and in groups;
                there are editors, artists and writers, as well as workers and ordinary citizens.
                There is one image of the interior of a home.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_14bff030438b8939b002e7b84ccfde47" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Gorbachev and the American Presidents</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">37
                  prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate normal="1980/1995" type="inclusive">1980s-1990s</unitdate>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_62e04d62e920528a63c10ee249aeaa36"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_a548f5678e865d7c02cc4272d2d1ac5e">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Taken at large and small meetings, receptions, tours, and other official events in
                Russia, the Ukraine, and the White House, photographs in this series convey a point
                of view distinct from the official images by White House or TASS Agency
                photographers. A few formal group portraits are indeed from White House
                photographers and are labeled as such by Matlock. </p>
              <p>The prints were originally grouped for exhibits and the title posters are still in
                the collection: "The Reagans, The Bushes, and the Gorbachevs" and "The Reagans and
                Gorbachev." Notable people in addition to the Gorbachevs, Bushes, and Reagans,
                include poet Andrei Voznesensky with Nancy Reagan; Chief of Staff Howard Baker;
                Russian KGB director Vladimir Kryuchkov; Nancy Reagan with the son of Boris
                Pasternak at Peredelkino, the Pasternak's summer home (dacha); and Barbara Bush and
                Raisa Gorbachev cutting the ribbon on a "Make Way for Ducklings" sculpture in
                Moscow. There is also a photograph of President George H.W. Bush aboard Air Force
                One, recording his impressions of the meetings on a small dictation device.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ac6f3f39302a63e51ec10435aa015cea" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Gorbachev in Retirement</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_06b0ab0bf65a3fbd12fb1e54f3833c5a"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">14</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_a14dd1adfde3086cba3359e77f16ea60">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>These photographs relate to a period of time when Mikhail Gorbachev had stepped
                down from his role as leader of the former Soviet Union and began a new phase of
                life following the loss of his wife Raisa in 1999. Images show Gorbachev conversing
                with Jack Matlock and others at the World Political Forum (which he founded) in
                Stresa, Italy, attending a World Leaders Symposium in St. Petersburg, and receiving
                an honorary degree at the Univesity of Oklahoma. There is also a photograph of a
                modern portrait of Gorbachev on the U.S. Presidential yacht "Sequoia." Includes a
                photograph of President Bill Clinton speaking in support of the Raisa Gorbacheva
                Leukemia Foundation. All of the prints are captioned by the photographer. Includes a
                title panel.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_14f36efceb00981b8974d93c77d158a2" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Landscapes, Buildings, and other Scenes</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">72
                  prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">3.5 boxes</extent></physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_cb81d9f5822c041e7e319ba90213bb9a">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>This subseries begins with a general grouping chiefly featuring landscapes of
                Russia, the Urals, Crimea, and Tajikistan, and other places. There are snowy
                landscapes, images of bridges and houses, and lakes. then is further arranged into
                other small groups which have self-explanatory titles: Around Moscow; Art After
                Stalin; Buildings in the USSR; Churches in the USSR; Circus (the smallest with only
                several prints); and On Space, which depicts the Matlocks' visit to a Russian space
                complex where the space station Mir was being constructed (the workers in the images
                are mostly women). Most of the prints in this series are uncaptioned. Includes some
                title cards and panels, and one event poster for an Art After Stalin exhibit and
                lecture.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c04 id="aspace_ff74b8baf75091d3d5800dadf5ddaf69" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Landscapes</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">19
                    prints</extent></physdesc>
                <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_4adcd6cd14c0f33215a4d31353dd1def"
                  label="Mixed Materials" type="box">14</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_b34b7d8d81fd3108324bcfd82951dbf6" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Around Moscow</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                    prints</extent></physdesc>
                <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_339f6ff92535f17e983166e46b369bb1"
                  label="Mixed Materials" type="box">14</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_7a169b803e7778810c1e1ca1f9ddfd73" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Art After Stalin</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10
                    prints</extent></physdesc>
                <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_3edc1c80036dec0c750d2c1acef18e18"
                  label="Mixed Materials" type="box">15</container>
              </did>
              <scopecontent id="aspace_4192d029c071dba572b04f68a7b55e7c">
                <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                <p>Images feature artists, museum-goers, artwork in various media, and a children in
                  a classroom holding up their own artwork.</p>
              </scopecontent>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_dfae78f1bb6e13aacaf5479005f7ff0f" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Buildings in the USSR</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13
                    prints</extent></physdesc>
                <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_7ef24c5ddefbc15269b296411babb3dc"
                  label="Mixed Materials" type="box">15</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_62f3cedc5606396e9f96e42e46359be4" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Churches in the USSR</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">15
                    prints</extent></physdesc>
                <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_f3501ed94761ec62fbf7d9281705d673"
                  label="Mixed Materials" type="box">16</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_608b44081ed8b8c1a95807263171a98b" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Circus</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4
                    prints</extent></physdesc>
                <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_30947f949e163a95e6d1238bf6dc8991"
                  label="Mixed Materials" type="box">16</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_f2dd14186f9c5050782293bf690f942a" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Concerning Space</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8
                    prints</extent></physdesc>
                <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_e86e117691317775624ffad914dfe30c"
                  label="Mixed Materials" type="box">17</container>
              </did>
              <scopecontent id="aspace_93e5b24629a9946646775d3627ec84e8">
                <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                <p>During a tour of the Soviet Union's regions and cities, the Matlocks were given
                  clearance to visit the space complex where the Mir space station was being built.
                  In this unusual look behind the scenes in an otherwise tightly controlled area,
                  one can see women workers, the assembly hangars and other workrooms, and the
                  grounds of the complex, which include outdoor sculpture. The location of this
                  space complex is unknown, but it may be the Khrunichev State Research and
                  Production Space Center, or the S.P. Korolev complex north of Moscow.</p>
              </scopecontent>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_759cf8a7788f319b14473ea7022eec08" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Republic of Georgia and Tbilisi</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_c377a9a7cf1fc4b1e3f6540073ae20ac">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Like the Landscapes series, the large Republic of Georgia series is further divided
                into smaller groups whose titles from an original exhibit panel: Interactions with
                Americans During Glasnost; Churches and Countryside; Contemporary Leaders;
                Desperation During Civil War; Euphoria of the Postwar Period; and Tbilisi and Some
                of Its Residents. Images range widely, featuring rural landscapes; inhabitants and
                villages; city scenes from Tbilisi; and many types of buildings and dwellings,
                including churches and one Jewish synagogue. Images from Tbilisi chiefly focus on
                architectural details around the city, and marketplace scenes. </p>
              <p>Notable people featured in the Contemporary Leaders group include Eduard and Nanuli
                Shevardnadze, and several leaders of Parliament, one of whom was an author of the
                1995 Georgian Constitution.</p>
              <p>A large group of these photographs relates to the effects of the Georgian civil war
                from about 1988 to 1993. Images in this series include rural elderly, damage to land
                and buildings, markets, bread lines, and street vendors, and refugees from Abkhazia
                and scenes from the South Ossetian conflict (1989-1992).</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c04 id="aspace_551c7bea25b8dd5d55e59b1a2700a9a6" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Interactions with Americans During Glasnost</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7
                    prints</extent></physdesc>
                <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_327b07ff6d3a726d6ae5c640f9e4296d"
                  label="Mixed Materials" type="box">17</container>
              </did>
              <scopecontent id="aspace_c0b53218d92e60109925af56a4c99703">
                <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                <p>Includes portraits of individuals as well as groups of men and women, and a
                  phtoograph of a street poster in Georgian advertising an exhibit of Rebecca
                  Matlock's work.</p>
              </scopecontent>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_210622820aeec9d64e379b040e0ea3b4" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Churches and Countryside</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">18
                    prints</extent></physdesc>
                <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_1b5fc196c9b876d6d5e79b3a4d8d3e92"
                  label="Mixed Materials" type="box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_88e95b671c65cb5935084fdb10f89555" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Churches and Countryside (continued)</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8
                    prints</extent></physdesc>
                <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_91e3f9554f31877c43337a4b2064b8b7"
                  label="Mixed Materials" type="box">18</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_8a5b6e2196c76b25f5d91b4cf2bf8fd2" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Civil War</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">22
                    prints</extent></physdesc>
                <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_3a9852c8ae9ec9e36a8e0518b765a1c1"
                  label="Mixed Materials" type="box">18</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_e8ea869d2c9f03948c9606451a493ef6" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Contemporary Leaders</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8
                    prints</extent></physdesc>
                <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_fbfeb28763297bb72123ff32e85eb3f2"
                  label="Mixed Materials" type="box">19</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_9d6002887af5db893e569d3afba90e64" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Euphoria of the Post War Period</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8
                    prints</extent></physdesc>
                <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_58975a804d974c3f4926370999197f95"
                  label="Mixed Materials" type="box">19</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_b5e210fc8d9f148f86ec396eada16a0b" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Tbilisi and Some of its Residents</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">18
                    prints</extent></physdesc>
                <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_dd83b9f6924178b79a7308faa298ef26"
                  label="Mixed Materials" type="box">20</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_9b7d1449b3bdb8081b956ceb6b5a88fc" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Trans-Caucasus (Ukraine)</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_9c7a2fd62622e436f2e3416d78445ed1"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_e0dc50be721044e43778af8cb21796b1">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Chiefly uncaptioned images of a Russian ship, a ship's crew, and naval officials.
                There are also some images of outdoor sculptures. Chiefly from the Ukraine, but
                there may be other locations pictured.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_eda6a452c9d373260b2739c53cc5b0f9" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Russia and Other Regions: Small prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">95
                  prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-11x14x3" id="aspace_d26ed1a9b0e6fc34ead40c69e47d04dc"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_b5b1f958c87053b32b211d013542dffd">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Includes small prints, chiefly 8x11 inches or slightly larger, from these series:
                Americans and Russians; Andrei Sakharov; At Spaso House; Central Asia and Buryatia;
                Chautauqua; Faces of Slavic Countries; and Gorbachev and the American
                Presidents.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_e0d4a8a9d22a024d03e21b9773ccaa57" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Russia and Other Regions: Small prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">96
                  prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-11x14x3" id="aspace_32052e05da93d35da6632337aec1b7b3"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">25</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_13384c3a4a0376251b39d8203cfb1558">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>These small prints, chiefly 8x11 inches or slightly larger, consists of images from
                these sub-groups from the series Russia and Other Regions: Landscapes and Buildings;
                Republic of Georgia; and Trans-Caucasus.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_7ec26d63bdda37225bc802fe156f591d" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Additional large prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc id="aspace_43f7ae3410c1940a03bcf4e93ffe2a7c"><extent>2
                prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_6ab6a6c85d4cfab0ce0ce9bc8a5519fc"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">26</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_a59e9d2bd1dd53e07972492f0ce579cb">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>A later addition to the collection, these prints chiefly consist of landscapes,
                portraits, and official meetings. Locations are unidentified.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_0dcdbfb7a40301626c4467a3971a771a" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Sarah Caldwell</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">19
                prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="2000/2005" type="inclusive">circa 2000-2005</unitdate>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_4bb31ee592af36e10408f66b29ca3ec6">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>This collection of photographs is related to an autobiography of Boston-based
              conductor and opera director Sarah Caldwell. The book, titled <title render="italic"
                >Challenges: A memoir of my life in opera</title>, was based on a series of
              interviews conducted with Caldwell in the early 2000s by Rebecca Matlock, who
              eventually published the book in 2008 following Caldwell's death in 2006. </p>
            <p>Photographs in this series are uncaptioned, and chiefly show Sarah Caldwell attending
              events, posing with others, and at home. Some served as illustrations for the book.
              There are photographs of the interior and exterior of her Massachusetts house, several
              shots of unidentified buildings and architectural details, probably in Boston.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_9686723eeb81bf33bb64ab8841695a8c" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Large prints</unittitle>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_d5242ba9f7180d160703264246c9de15"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">21</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_2bc1e8c17286f7d7331e150509845f52" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Special Places - USA and Republic of Georgia</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">27
                prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1990/2013" type="inclusive">1990s-circa 2013</unitdate>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_150f0c05e19396807bae30b2e08b271b">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Forming part of an exhibit by Rebecca Matlock called "Special Places," these images
              chiefly from unidentified places in the United States focus on botanical settings with
              specimen trees and flowering plants, lakes, and outdoor sculptures. Includes 17 large
              prints from the USA series, and ten small prints, three of which are from the Republic
              of Georgia and seven from the USA series.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_0c164fae5131c5c91d2e9a9d26e7725c" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Large prints</unittitle>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_588d72d8b888d1823823d485175ba64f"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">22</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_5c26c3c247c07683f3cdd5a86d33d41e" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Small prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-11x14x3" id="aspace_387efb30ce917498c7bcc01e05d88da0"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">25</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_c06746cae2c209e02a3db6e9bccd457d" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>United States</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">35
                prints</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1990/2015" type="inclusive">1990s-2000s</unitdate>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_ab1dddaddfda889b6cd870073d96aaae">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Taken during family trips through the United States, these images chiefly depict
              landscapes, botanical settings, and wildlife, and buildings with significant
              architectural interest. The series is divided into three groups designated by the
              photographer: Alaska, Buildings, and Hawaii. There are seven small prints (all from
              the Buildings series), and 28 large prints. As with other series, some of these images
              formed part of exhibits. Other U.S.-related photographs can also be found in the
              "Special Places - USA" series, which formed a separate exhibit. There are also some
              U.S. locations in the series on Sarah Caldwell, most likely in Boston.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_b4eafb884c55ecacc6ddec49bf017e79" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Alaska</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_6bda743cced8e0f772fa70dfec1dba13"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">22</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_5ec8286e9046510b7d2a193b56129ed8" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Buildings</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">16
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_5ee59e21320cc8118cebd753e992358f"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">23</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_2b7b1ce6cdc8a483f38d9dc154ea4fbb" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Hawaii</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_7e3a12c1858eb683b6d2701ad287746e"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">23</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_413dee00b2554c08950055f9ce8ac4fc" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Small prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-11x14x3" id="aspace_dc9d91901486c6f55719d78a455cbc78"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">25</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_d004b750ec1c3ff73593a544f932b667">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Images are from the U.S. Buildings series.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d038c96295f1d6992765cc6936f0fee3" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Additional large prints: Alaska, Hawaii</unittitle>
              <physdesc id="aspace_c02bee3dff68e44a8685a32de471ee69"><extent>3
                prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_7d933be45e4a93db0357b937a5a8209e"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">26</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_da4400626a2f42cf914ea383db9346be">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>A later addition to the collection, these prints were also taken on touristic trips
                in the 2000s.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_05bb82b113747e14f38441dccf31268a" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Other Places</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">15
                prints</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="2000/2015" type="inclusive">2000s</unitdate>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_309e41486197a10e668501212e222196">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>The large prints come from Antarctica, Alaska, Australia, Bora Bora, Canada, the
              Galapagos Islands, New Zealand, Samoa, and Tahiti. The smaller prints come from
              unidentified locations; some may be from Japan.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_b5c2cc3cdf2fdf4373b6c4e2ca0a1419" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Large prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_1b3350b3c62cc00c2f850cf781323fa0"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">23</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_4c9ab6cdc8af81907c0236026c496fe2" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Small prints: unidentified locations</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5
                  prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-11x14x3" id="aspace_efa1c44f8567acc12e43e41a34ca02f2"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">25</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_03f0abcad8b72a5c62a1b367b75ebb13">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>These prints were originally from a folder titled "Miscellaneous countries,
                including Japan."</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_3f31a8c6c8bf7f21fca880d5173d98e5" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Additional large prints</unittitle>
              <physdesc id="aspace_8494841ece2741f5635bf49a05e4f177">2 folders; 8 prints</physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_76dbd13a38bb58cbe05183876db2ac4a"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">26</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_30db0a7cb6cc9b52e3bb46f1dfb37907">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>A later addition to the collection, the locations of these tourist travel prints
                include Antartica, Australia, Bora Bora, Canada, Galapagos, New Zealand, and
                Tahiti.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_23b862edcc53141e1ee975c6a492b277" level="series">
          <did>
            <unittitle>South and Central America</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7
                prints</extent><extent altrender="carrier">2 folders</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1990/2015" type="inclusive">1990s-2000s</unitdate>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_e98e9947f6bfd0e1c7809420d6d79186">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>A later addition to the collection, the prints in this series were chiefly taken on
              touristic trips to various locations in South and Central America sometime after the
              1990s. Portraits of individuals predominate, but there are also a few images of fauna
              (coatimundi) and vegetation. Captions indicate the photographs were taken in Chile,
              Costa Rica, Guatemala, Honduras, Mexico, and Nicaragua.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_6d4573c45b4b894367d93070c2b47fb5" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Large prints: Chile, Costa Rica</unittitle>
              <physdesc id="aspace_7d803da0416b8bd497f3b729f3219d30"><extent>3
                prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_d0b1c6e694e22e560783e04336870038"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">26</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a2c01bd9429f04a438453f25f911ecde" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Large prints: Guatemala, Honduras, Mexico, Nicaragua</unittitle>
              <physdesc id="aspace_0ca75856b271d7dad054728b6d788a64"><extent>4
                prints</extent></physdesc>
              <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_d33ce9bf0d1763e056b3e7e15d3e851c"
                label="Mixed Materials" type="box">26</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_5c661a1babaa63c7674fe4f58541a38e" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Other Papers</unittitle>
          <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">approximately
              84 items</extent></physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1981/2010" type="inclusive">1981-2010 and undated</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_b0fa32ff64202484a12a787f3dce5219">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series includes a Russian magazine with an article about Rebecca Matlock's
            photographic work; there is also a small group of loose caption cards separated from
            photographic exhibit prints; caption labels on printer sheets; and a few exhibit
            information sheets.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_d4c1fee65af5e717805c64ad4a9388d3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Exhibit-related materials</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1980/2010" type="inclusive">1980s-2000s</unitdate>
            <container altrender="Flat-11x14x3" id="aspace_607f6f9141ad45305ba3be1bb121f75b"
              label="Mixed Materials" type="box">25</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_cd42f750315d8c3eb8671eed3c6dc3df">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Small group of caption cards, title cards, and a few fliers related to exhibits and
              lectures.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_e3aadbf6661101bf9f46fc8cc21ce385" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Issue of <title render="italic">Ogonek</title> magazine with Russian-language
              article about Rebecca Matlock, 1989 July, no. 27</unittitle>
            <container altrender="Flat-16x20x3" id="aspace_8c97fe0f2bbb6731043ae9ca772339f4"
              label="Mixed Materials" type="box">26</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
