<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/mccollomthomasc/"
         >mccollomthomasc</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to A private journal kept by me... of a voyage to... the West Indies
               to New York and Cape Ann, 1865 Feb. 21-1889 Feb. 23 <num>RL.00865</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Alice Poffinberger; machine-readable finding aid created by: Noah
               Huffman</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">004168311</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 03:06:29
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>A private journal kept by me... of a voyage to... the West Indies to New York
            and Cape Ann</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">McCollom, Thomas C.</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00865</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1865/1889" type="inclusive">1865 Feb. 21-1889 Feb. 23</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_8f30a5e53e9a79940ee312772f26ba18">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_d352b0be1c51103eef90f52248dda2f8">Thomas C. McCollom was a resident of
            Cambridge, Mass., b. May 9, 1847. Collection comprises the journal (104 pgs.) McCollom
            maintained daily while voyaging to and from the West Indies, Feb 21-May 18, 1865, when
            he was between the ages of 17 and 18. The ship was the schooner D. L. Sturgis; with five
            crew members and its captain, Daniel Deasy. It appears McCollom undertook the journey
            for the improvement of his health, and the majority of his entries detailed the
            depression, homesickness, and boredom he experienced during the trip, "I can't tell why
            but I feel homesick and blue. I have such days now quite often though not so often as
            formerly. I shan't be sorry to get home I know. I don't know what to do with myself when
            I feel so. I find that writing home or in this journal is about as good a cure as
            anything. I feel better to express my feeling somehow if only to write them down here
            (pp. 25-26)." McCollom also described crew members' activities (including one man's
            drowning after an accident, p. 5), the weather and wind patterns, the difficulties of
            the Atlantic Ocean crossing and vagaries of the Caribbean Sea, and any birds and animals
            seen. He also identified any ships encountered, usually with their nationality,
            destination, and any cargo being transported.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_e732450e4e38a1100ca28f479c5bd067">Materials in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_129ed950a22585625c03ac2a55c3bccd">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_486cd314676d257b1b59aa76fe23b7fd">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_20d61b9df7269b1feb44aac27c4adf98">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>A private journal kept by me... of a voyage to... the West Indies to New York and Cape
            Ann, 1865 Feb. 21-1889 Feb. 23, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library,
            Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_24510cd0b8a2a558fc0a9c8d5fb2d0c3">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>Purchase, 2009</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_145e32e50196568ab1b82a327b272d28">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by: Alice Poffinberger, July 2010</p>
         <p>Encoded by: Noah Huffman, July 2010</p>
         <p>Accession(s) described in this finding aid: <num type="accession">2009-0134</num>
         </p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_bd2621bb3dbc446062c8f897820c1b2d">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Thomas C. McCollom was a resident of Cambridge, Mass., b. May 9, 1847.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_df7c5b1bc71e78873b8f9de8372a9da4">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Collection comprises the journal (104 pgs.) McCollom maintained daily while voyaging to
            and from the West Indies, Feb 21-May 18, 1865, when he was between the ages of 17 and
            18. The ship was the schooner D. L. Sturgis; with five crew members and its captain,
            Daniel Deasy. It appears McCollom undertook the journey for the improvement of his
            health, and the majority of his entries detailed the depression, homesickness, and
            boredom he experienced during the trip, "I can't tell why but I feel homesick and blue.
            I have such days now quite often though not so often as formerly. I shan't be sorry to
            get home I know. I don't know what to do with myself when I feel so. I find that writing
            home or in this journal is about as good a cure as anything. I feel better to express my
            feeling somehow if only to write them down here (pp. 25-26)." McCollom also described
            crew members' activities (including one man's drowning after an accident, p. 5), the
            weather and wind patterns, the difficulties of the Atlantic Ocean crossing and vagaries
            of the Caribbean Sea, and any birds and animals seen. He also identified any ships
            encountered, usually with their nationality, destination, and any cargo being
            transported.</p>
         <p>Other common topics included his attitudes regarding race and the inhabitants of each
            island; activity on the wharf and ship while in port, especially sales and purchases
            made; his excursions on each island, particularly for church services; and his growing
            participation as part of the crew, by writing up of invoices and bills, noting the
            loading of cargo, and eventually assisting with sails and repair of the ship. McCollom
            also mentioned his desire to hear about the end of the Civil War, and recorded his
            opinions about ships sailing under the Rebel flag (p. 59), Lincoln's death (p. 91), and
            the capture of Jefferson Davis (p. 97). The main ports the ship visited included
            "Kinston" (Kingston), Jamaica; Georgetown, Grand Cayman Island; and "Rattan" Island,
            Honduras. Other areas visited or mentioned at length included Port Royal, Jamaica; Utila
            Island; and New York City, where McCollom considered the highlights of his trip to be
            touring Central Park and listening to a sermon by Henry Ward Beecher. The item's final
            entry, dated Feb. 23, 1889, contained McCollom's comment after rediscovering the journal
            twenty-four years after the voyage.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Grand Cayman Island (Cayman Islands)</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Islas de la BahÍa (Honduras) -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Caribbean Sea -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Central Park (New York, N.Y.) -- History -- 19th century</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Jamaica -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Kingston (Jamaica) -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Port Royal (Jamaica) -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Voyages and travels -- History -- 19th century</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Utila Island (Honduras) -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Roatán (Honduras) -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Winds -- Atlantic Ocean</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Atlantic Ocean -- Navigation</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Seafaring life -- History -- 19th century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Travelers' writings</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Journals</genreform>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">West Indies -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <persname source="ingest">McCollom, Thomas C.</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">McCollom, Thomas C.</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Deasy, Daniel, Capt</persname>
         <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Beecher, Henry Ward</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">D. L. Sturgis (Schooner)</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_179" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>A private journal kept by me... of a voyage to... the West Indies to New
                  York and Cape Ann, 1865-1889</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_d20901e15aef245baa022b40fa3a38a8">
                  <extent>1 folder</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_f7b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Journal, 1865 Feb. 21-May 18, and 1889.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a26e2bf8c0016d73b274a848988bddc8" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="folder">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
