<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
         url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/mcfaddenjoshua/">mcfaddenjoshua</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Joshua Rashaad McFadden photographs, 2015-2016
                  <num>RL.11527</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Paula Jeannet</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>October 2017</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">008022231</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-11-01 16:22:46
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Joshua Rashaad McFadden photographs</unittitle>
         <origination label="source">
            <corpname role="rps" source="ingest">Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke
               University)</corpname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname role="pht" rules="rda" source="naf">McFadden, Joshua</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.11527</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent>
            <physfacet>20 prints</physfacet>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="2015/2016" type="inclusive">2015-2016</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_8e3a679ddaeda3531688f97480ca5e65">Collection consists of 20 13x19 inch
            color inkjet photographic collages featuring portraits of young African American men,
            taken by McFadden, paired with reproduction color portraits of their fathers when they
            were younger, and a handwritten personal narrative by each youth about what it means to
            be an African American man in the 21st century. There is also a print with McFadden and
            his father. Many of the fathers appear in military uniforms. Topics expressed in the
            personal narratives include stereotypes as well as new definitions of black masculinity;
            the construction of and attitudes towards race, gender, and sexuality; generational
            issues; and relationships with fathers. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary
            Arts at Duke University.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_64051f066893e603c9e68057d4791332">Material in
            English</langmaterial>
         <physdesc id="aspace_0079d2eec96e8c235828d46b2815141c">20 color photographic
            prints</physdesc>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_ab0e56d854bf2621286110fc31555788">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Joshua Rashaad McFadden, artist and author, is originally from Rochester, New York.
            During his undergraduate years at Elizabeth City State University in North Carolina, he
            began to make photographs as a fine art practice. McFadden attended Savannah College of
            Art and Design where he obtained his Master of Fine Art.</p>
         <p>In response to recent incidents of police brutality and the murders of African American
            men and women, McFadden created the photographic series "After Selma." Since its release
            in April 2015, McFadden was named one of the top emerging talents in the world by
            LensCulture and received the first place International Photography Award (IPA, 2015) for
            "After Selma." He won the first place IPA award again in 2016 for his series and book
               <title render="italic">Come to Selfhood</title>. </p>
         <p>McFadden has since been published in <title render="italic">EyesOpen Magazine, Slate
               Magazine</title>, and the <title render="italic">New York Times</title>. In 2017
            McFadden was recognized by <title render="italic">Time Magazine</title> as one of "12
            African American Photographers You Should Follow Right Now."</p>
         <p>McFadden is the winner of the 2017 Duke University Archive of Documentary Arts Award for
            Documentarians of Color.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_178539ffd862e8ddf5556e7db8956e3a">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research. Images may only be used for educational, non-commercial
            purposes; any other use requires the photographer's permission.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_0125a579851fe720ede7c763ddad316a">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_47ace37554c091b56047d5c9b5897d46">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The Joshua Rashaad McFadden photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare
            Book &amp; Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2017.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <phystech id="aspace_eb9f1dca236fac542ea1aac63aaa1d57">
         <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
         <p>The photographs in this collection were printed on Exhibition Fiber Epson photography
            paper using a Epson SureColor P9000 Commercial Edition Printer.</p>
      </phystech>
      <prefercite id="aspace_3a32fc2512837dd6a03bb640bd7fea1d">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Joshua Rashaad McFadden photographs, David M. Rubenstein Rare
            Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_79cd33204a2cbaeaeebe3ce14c21e2dd">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed and encoded by Paula Jeannet, October 2017.</p>
         <p>Accession(s) described in this collection guide: 2017-0137.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_0fe1e539655a018fcca7e978651f1b0e">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>Collection consists of 20 13x19 inch color inkjet photographic collages featuring
            portraits of young African American men, taken by McFadden, paired with reproduction
            color portraits of their fathers when they were younger, and handwritten personal
            narratives, one to three paragraphs long, by each youth about what it means to be an
            African American man in the 21st century. One print is of McFadden and his father, and
            includes a reproduction of his father's Selective Service card. </p>
         <p>Topics expressed in the personal narratives include stereotypes as well as new
            definitions of black masculinity; the construction of and attitudes of others as well as
            themselves towards race, gender, and sexuality; generational issues; and relationships
            with fathers. Many of the fathers served in the Armed Forces, and appear in their
            portraits in military uniforms.</p>
         <p>From the artist's statement: "How does one begin to challenge the misguided perceptions
            that decrease the quality of living for young African American men? Furthermore, how
            does the African American man position himself in a society that does not acknowledge
            his true identity? African American men and stories of their intersecting identities
            unrecognized in forums that allow these positive images to become a part of the dominant
            narrative of African American men. As a photographic artist, I chose to use contemporary
            portraiture, the vernacular image, qualitative data, and positioning to expose this
            narrative with Come to Selfhood." </p>
         <p>"Come to Selfhood explores African American male identity, masculinity, notions about
            the father figure, and the photographic archive by providing a frame of reference that
            visually articulates the diverse identities of young Black men. By delving into ideas of
            history, role models, and varied experiences, Come to Selfhood makes the previously
            invisible Black man, accurately and meaningfully visible."</p>
         <p>For this body of work, McFadden received the 2017 Duke University Archive of Documentary
            Arts Award for Documentarians of Color.</p>
         <p>Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American men -- Family relationships</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American men -- Portraits</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American men -- Psychology</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American men -- Social conditions</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American men -- Social life and customs</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American youth -- Attitudes</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American youth -- Personal narratives</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American youth -- Portraits</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Masculinity -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Racism -- United States</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Race relations</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">United States -- Social conditions -- 21st century</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Color photographs</genreform>
         <genreform source="aat">Digital prints</genreform>
         <genreform source="aat">Inkjet prints</genreform>
         <corpname role="rps" source="ingest">Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke
            University)</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_2d9d92e68ce9ade39ac5e7e73fd5a339" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Come to Selfhood</unittitle>
               <unitdate normal="2015/2016" type="inclusive">2015-2016</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_a0a6a84e82bd293532b0d8165e278ad8">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Series of 20 13x19 inch color inkjet prints by Joshua McFadden, organized in
                  original order as received by print number.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_984cf5f7ad66d7c6d197aff1d796fec1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Jamel Jones left, and his father, James Jones</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2015/2015">2015</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_5943c9ef3cebb9264d3cb81c8381b4fe" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0027af5e457ee94bfee966b15c6ed773"
                     parent="aspace_5943c9ef3cebb9264d3cb81c8381b4fe" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0001</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bdd9e3d9b377bee29940b5f6340ea29b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Wow. It'd probably be a combination of people and traits I find impressive. My
                     dad's super diligent, loving and one of the most intelligent people I know. My
                     uncle Pete's always involved in the community as a leader. And my granddad
                     Albert loved life and lived it to the fullest. He had this uncanny sharp
                     memory, able to pick up a conversation at the exact point you left it. It's
                     surprising when he had seven kids and loads of grandchildren that he could give
                     them all individual attention. I do have to thank my family for giving me a
                     clearer picture of being a man. </p>
                  <p>I identify as a black male. I don't see being black as a negative thing. For
                     me, I get to be a part of a rich legacy of struggle and triumph. I'm a part of
                     one of the most creative groups of people on the planet and a real leader of
                     change. I'm good with that. I'm not going to let others color the way I view
                     myself, my family and my history. </p>
                  <p>We're extraordinary individuals regardless (and in spite of) oppression.
                     Granted, if we weren't dealing with oppression, we could accomplish a lot more
                     in a shorter amount of time. We're a monolithic group, but I find more of us
                     tend to lead in our respective fields (art, science, psychology, etc.) with
                     great results.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_becf9f0550e6f1b43c0057b7cd21a3d7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Brittonius Lyle left, and his grandfather, Thomas E. Lyle</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2015/2015">2015</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_21404ee1b3fc47961ffd951362bc09b9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_26b5018d72ee7ee64cffe6f6fd620ee9"
                     parent="aspace_21404ee1b3fc47961ffd951362bc09b9" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0002</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5182c7fe310e20a41a99636fed52a159">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>As a black nerd, super heroes were my ideal figures that represent black male
                     masculinity. Given there were and still so few it really made it easier for me
                     to choose, specifically, John Stewart as the Green Lantern, Virgil Hawkins as
                     static. Both these men possess excellent qualities for young black males to
                     look up to strong, bold, brave, resourceful, level-headed, talented and role
                     models for their community. The fact that Static looked up to Green Lantern as
                     a role model for black super heroes was inspiring. These characters helped
                     shape me as a young black male today.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_a77050445691314892383d213e006ce9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Johnathan Marshall left, and his father, John Marshall</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_95fe3f9af3c125abdc65ca6eeefb0dff" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_bbe5ff1383a12c0d601deb4295a00c49"
                     parent="aspace_95fe3f9af3c125abdc65ca6eeefb0dff" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0003</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ba1d102c6274032f31bb3d5b0f884c54">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Human. Plain and simple. We cry, laugh, fight, create, love, sympathize, dream,
                     just live like the rest of the human race. </p>
                  <p>My granddad is that figure of masculinity for me. I watched him work day to
                     day, provide for our household and coach my uncles and cousins into adulthood.
                     He was reserved, funny and confident in his masculinity. </p>
                  <p>Positive self-talk, as well as setting goals, have always helped me ignore the
                     bullshit America has to offer black men. Finding my place outside of having to
                     rely on the dominant culture and relying on myself cements my positive
                     identity.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_fc3093813811a577d7b31b8fb73c83fc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Brian Lawrey left, and his father, James Lawrey</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_b4c594db648737729dd29e0140fc89b0" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e35b48c922f528046109b697659c1cc7"
                     parent="aspace_b4c594db648737729dd29e0140fc89b0" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0004</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fc538fda6e7f9e99d17bea12beb7e3b5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Masculinity as a black man is remaining genuine. Believing in your movements by
                     moving with a strong moral purity. Having an innocence at the core of wisdom
                     leading the male along his path and resonating his joy through action. A black
                     male in America is tougher. I personally do not like America due to it sticking
                     a target on my back. "America" is an adjunct of where I reside currently. I
                     have learned the "idea" of freedom in its constitution, yet I rely on my own
                     strength and history to create my freedom. America is a house to me as a black
                     male, not my home.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_daf82da5d7d4ccd403fbe08604742ce2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Cameron Goins left, and his father, Keith Goins</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_a98d1accadb118820b51aefffe7db6b7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_29e5b98269e4dece31fc24bc837b62c9"
                     parent="aspace_a98d1accadb118820b51aefffe7db6b7" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0005</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1a4f119f545ea5528b7983f4405768f1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>We're violent, we're ignorant, we're criminals, we're loud, we're aggressive,
                     we sell drugs, we trap. These perceptions impact me every day because as a
                     black male I am automatically stereotyped because of my skin as opposed to my
                     character. I am constantly judged due to the medias perception. They have given
                     me insight to how to bounce back and how to grow from experiences and turn the
                     negatives into life lessons.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_85f9601c62fb710c9bc8350734e23a9c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Christian Cody left, and his father, Ywahnos Cody</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_27c3459a18e675ee322b43ed7210f601" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7a34c67fdb3ad57a0cb46659a5b52990"
                     parent="aspace_27c3459a18e675ee322b43ed7210f601" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0006</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fc6f8f19d1f386bcc8e8cf547bc3968e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Andre 3000 came to mind first, so I'll use him as an example. I admire how he
                     exists within the Hip-hop world without selling himself to be the stereotypical
                     rap icon. He has a strong sense of self-expression undiluted by his
                     surroundings. I like when men aren't afraid to show themselves. To me black
                     masculinity is a liquid; loose and easily manipulated. It can take many forms.
                     I'd say that my own identity as a black male would be characterized by
                     intelligent, hardworking, and loving. That is who I am and what I have
                     experienced.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_4a6756f5b2e8147db1024c0832d69b4c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>David Chapman left, and his father, Earl Chapman</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_b0acd21115d310a9a8f1592db59183d4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b6702a92f5027b1fdb0cfb24f1cee71b"
                     parent="aspace_b0acd21115d310a9a8f1592db59183d4" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0007</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_52566ae705adb6a2e2467e7b6106dc69">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>No, because I identify myself as a black man. The subtle yet distinct change in
                     terminology from "male" to "men" makes all the difference between my physical
                     and spiritual being.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_4d55c4bab9c2453d797da875192c1410" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>David Williams left, and his father, David Williams</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_9afd885676eece7fabf49a90f3f887bf" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0c5b2d6346e13846c77844baf39b1307"
                     parent="aspace_9afd885676eece7fabf49a90f3f887bf" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0008</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9cdcf1b4ca5bb090f479b354abeca43f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>There is no Doubting my ethnicity. My skin is a smooth cocoa brown, my nose is
                     round and wide, my hair is curly and I am blessed with talents with only a
                     black man can have, and it brings me a greater sense of pride. My father, David
                     Williams, came from the poverty of Ocho Rios, Jamaica. Downfall in life was
                     women. He is a father of 6-7. But he works every day to make sure we were
                     always taken care of. He had one son. Thought me what to do as well as what I
                     shouldn't.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_68a67fa31621d9cc535ff4bfa0a4bfb6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Dravon McKinnie left, and his father, Leo McKinnie</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_46602d80ef53a4be3605231698b48574" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_9eaccdc8c07620acf4bae5cfd7792df0"
                     parent="aspace_46602d80ef53a4be3605231698b48574" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0009</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fe277478dd8b6bfd0d60de96c8394d16">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Sylvester, though not likely the idealized version of "black masculinity,"
                     Sylvester embodies what masculinity means to me. That means having the guts to
                     walk, talk and stand in your own truth despite what others think. A man of
                     color cannot develop a positive identity of himself unless those around him
                     uphold and maintain his self-worth.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_88bda14aae5a005c08cd0fd4e365d42c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Hasani Sahlehe left, and his father, Vernon Morgan</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_1cb18940699e93f22a3d02c70d44d28c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e62a45ac75f5c44f6ded10f99a89833a"
                     parent="aspace_1cb18940699e93f22a3d02c70d44d28c" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0010</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2f1241f01ca34606058c34fc0ecf4222">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>I thought that I had to be big, strong, athletic, tough. I tried to be all of
                     those things. I looked down on myself when I wasn't. I thought that others
                     would too.</p>
                  <p>When I was younger, I wanted to be Tupac or Bob Marley. That's where I got my
                     philosophy. Two great men but now I see the world differently. I still love
                     them both, but now I want to be Hasani. I've finally started to appreciate me
                     for me. </p>
                  <p>My experiences have made me who I am today. Unfortunately, those that are
                     traumatic seem to have the most impact on my character. Not feeling accepted
                     for who I was contributed to a desire in me to be accepted by all. I'm
                     beginning to become more comfortable with who I am. I am so happy that I am
                     able to become more and more like myself every day. It is still a struggle but
                     one thing I know is that I wouldn't want to be anyone other than myself.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_6d4995beaf4683dec9d8b44fb0669775" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ian Benboe, left, and his Father, Michael Nelson Benboe</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_41f46c61fe9398efb4e9f243a1bb27ab" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_aeffb18dbe46cd878be78486dbd946c4"
                     parent="aspace_41f46c61fe9398efb4e9f243a1bb27ab" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0011</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_faebf652973c5709044204c84e583983">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>They are still black men, which is something that can never be erased. Being
                     black comes with direct and indirect ties to the birth of the civilization we
                     reside in today. I used to deny my heritage, hoping to be more mixed and
                     diverse. Now, I fully embrace my ethnicity.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_e947b5a52b8215b8b58cce94498c5f45" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Jonathan Magee left, and his father, Willace Demetris Magee</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_fbfa01281a07aaf19b3f5a5a5dd88c11" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b8443ff560fca5aeaca571555bd6db86"
                     parent="aspace_fbfa01281a07aaf19b3f5a5a5dd88c11" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0012</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f04cecad690cb0980c8d992367e5e718">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Everything in my life has helped me create a mold for the man I am and the man
                     I want to be. Every trail brings new changes to my character. Every event
                     evolves the nature of my soul. If I could change one thing in my life good or
                     bad, I couldn't do it because every single thing has created who I am
                     today.</p>
                  <p>To me, the ideal figure that represents black male masculinity is my father.
                     All his life he has worked hard and pushed himself for his family and is always
                     teaching me new lessons on what it means to be a man.</p>
                  <p>Do not worry about other people. No matter what you do someone in the world is
                     going to hate you or what you have. So in the end, do not worry about it. Get
                     yours, and have faith in yourself.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_d63cf5498a027e63601557a0418042e5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Kamall Browne left, and his father, Venzil Rawle Browne</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_7f997b789f402831e3b6f14e0e79ad7b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_727b0b19ea176d639412a203070bfc34"
                     parent="aspace_7f997b789f402831e3b6f14e0e79ad7b" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0013</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c3d1e082e02c5609e21d600d91f5e3eb">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Only speak ebonics (slang) All grew up in poverty All have baby mothers All
                     have violent criminal backgrounds.</p>
                  <p>I watch people's first assumption of me disappear the second I speak.
                     Perceptions make people look at me like I'm dumb or illiterate. So many people
                     are surprised to hear how intellectual I am after taking the time to get to
                     know me.</p>
                  <p>My father is the ideal figure for black male masculinity. He works his ass off
                     just to provide for his family. He's been married for almost 25 years, had
                     three kids, and never cheated on my mother. He's the most passionate person I
                     know.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_b37f9c308a0be76c176f85c10d63aa5e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Lamarr Moore left, and his father, Larry Moore</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_9411ec4ee37b491fbea9c1ee9d1a23c4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_fe465ee396fa8e517cf1eaba912f04d3"
                     parent="aspace_9411ec4ee37b491fbea9c1ee9d1a23c4" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0014</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_30597d28c849176a22e03f709cc0b303">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>I was told by my father at a young age that I was a black man, and my life
                     would be harder because of it. I didn't understand that; I'm brown. Later I
                     understood that our world operates in symbols and labels. Just as I am not
                     literally black, white people are not white… Black is the label on our ethnic
                     and cultural background, and I am glad to be in it.</p>
                  <p>Role models played a very important role in my development. However, the
                     majority of my role models growing up were women. My father's actions lead me
                     to an understanding of the "provider". Whoever I have brought into my life, or
                     whoever is special in my life should be taken care of.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_bf96295dc1435a649047ea259ea55768" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Lindel Brown left, and his father, Medford Brown</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_b961431a9a25d3a24711305bed4ac310" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_ee4f5e3032e5f38a7ca47ad9e3f677a6"
                     parent="aspace_b961431a9a25d3a24711305bed4ac310" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0015</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c9776e64c0bef850929154e1f5ea5aa5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>In this photograph is a man of flaws like many of us, but who had great
                     intentions. This man, who is my father, has been a great man to his children in
                     teaching them the lessons that is necessary to live a decent life, more so to
                     be an even better person. I am blessed and happy that I can say I have a father
                     who loves and care for me and has been there when it mattered most.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_2769ee138288cdd8cf19ccbe4c8ae38b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Matt Cornwall left, and his father, David Alexander
                     Cornwall</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_64dcec8901f4ea4aa6569f21fa070a21" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0ba4ba19bcb144b80f9c9074998e6138"
                     parent="aspace_64dcec8901f4ea4aa6569f21fa070a21" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0016</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_98d87730fb69e9ee3a90a33cbeee29f5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>I don't truly believe there is an ideal figure of black male masculinity.
                     Manliness is a series of qualities that we categorize into a certain group. No
                     one can be 100% masculine though, it's impossible. If anything, the black male
                     who doesn't chase such ideals would ironically be an ideal figure. </p>
                  <p>Black masculinity is a phantom to me. I personally try to move towards it and I
                     can never fully grasp it. However, my parents are black and I'm comfortable
                     with the body I'm in right now, that's perfectly good enough for me.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_3538a40e8b0a73c7f8fb10ecc3d15d1b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reeyon Rouse left, and his Father, Larry Rouse</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_a873b884fb0fc8a137ba2c1d1878ea8f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_6be9209d3cbf2bd90be02e280dee78dd"
                     parent="aspace_a873b884fb0fc8a137ba2c1d1878ea8f" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0017</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9db913fade557bae59ccf78136002053">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>There are perceptions of men of color. Being scary, rude, disrespectful, mad
                     and always up to no good. It impacted me by making me try not to be any of the
                     things. I have had experiences where I have judged by my skin. It has opened my
                     eyes to what the world can be.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_62deb0050693ebf488818104ecd667ee" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Jeremiah Thompson left, and his father, Joseph Thompson,
                     Sr.</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_08a5799e8aa014c4e29cad09114a20d1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b082a3f6b76acca7bcb5bd213143abab"
                     parent="aspace_08a5799e8aa014c4e29cad09114a20d1" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0018</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_580a471c39add5b93146f081c2499748">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>I have been afraid to express my true identity in the past because as a gay
                     black man I could potentially be threatened, beat up, or killed. I've had
                     friends who've been jumped and harassed because of their identity. Not to say
                     I'm ashamed of who I am, but I have to protect myself. Being black is one
                     thing, but being black &amp; queer poses a different topic of discussion. This
                     has shaped me into not hiding who I am, &amp; understanding that representation
                     is important because you never know who you are helping by being you. No one
                     should live timid and afraid because of things they have no control over, such
                     as skin color and sexual orientation. It's also shaped me to be fearless &amp;
                     fight for true unity amongst the black community. Not talking about something
                     doesn't erase its existence.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_dc4919459245106f74591b662e566e9c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Devin Hughes left, and his father, Philip Hughes</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_fa3d94850b804ba8aa62e125f95ee3c5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_4a132b7db42ff231b2ed204ce0df77f1"
                     parent="aspace_fa3d94850b804ba8aa62e125f95ee3c5" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0019</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_001ee820b60d0662268c061cca51c5a9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Setting a good example for the younger generation is vital. Being a minority in
                     America isn't easy, having someone to look up to in a positive way can get you
                     far. Having a strong male role model in my life molded me into the independent
                     man I am today. I think being exposed to certain things at a young age shaped
                     me early. I knew better when faced with them later in life because of my
                     experience. Seeing negative things just makes me want more for myself.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_12e392e749b10ae0ab53670724faf4e0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Joshua Rashaad McFadden left, with his father, Craig McFadden, and
                     grandfather, Robert McFadden</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_2e0228e8b29e737690da98612a3d2a82" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7f084b0d9885176916b120e9e1fabfe7"
                     parent="aspace_2e0228e8b29e737690da98612a3d2a82" type="image"
                     >RL.11527-P-0020</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_054484b49f0c54a91e8178e7b80b8d4e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Positive role models played a major role in my development as a black man. They
                     provided inspiration, guidance, and knowledge. I learned so many things about
                     my history from them. Things that I wouldn't have learned in the school
                     systems. Growing-up with three brothers made it difficult to find my own
                     identity. My father and grandfather always encouraged me to be unique. My
                     mother did too. They also pushed me to get an education; they constantly told
                     me and my brothers how it important it was. Black people will continue to face
                     oppression in this country, but we must not let it stop us. We are powerful
                     beyond measure. Please make an effort to be a positive role model in someone's
                     life.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
