<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/mckeendurenfamily/"
      >mckeendurenfamily</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the McKeen-Duren family papers, 1720-1945 and undated, bulk 1855-1900
            <num>RL.00875</num></titleproper>
        <author>Paula Jeannet Mangiafico, Geraldine Degiron, Aaron Thornburg</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>March 2009</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">002209511</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-07-19 15:00:24
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2014</date>
        <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported to
          Archivists Toolkit</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>McKeen-Duren family papers</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <famname source="ingest">McKeen-Duren family</famname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.00875</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12.6 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">16 boxes; 1 oversize folder</extent>
        <physfacet>Approximately 3240 items</physfacet>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1720/1945" type="inclusive">1720-1945 and undated, bulk 1855-1900</unitdate>
      <physloc id="aspace_9312e4d88785571dbe46d7f1c58c9f3e">For current information on the location
        of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
      <abstract id="aspace_51310b71980ad761716c14726e0ee685">Collection documents in great detail
        the histories of the McKeen and Duren families, particularly of Silas, Phebe, and Philena
        McKeen. Topics of note documented through correpondence, diaries and journals, other peronal
        papers, printed material, and images include: religious thought and institutions in New
        England; the education of women and the careers of female educators; photography throughout
        the 19th century; the Civil War and its effects on New England society; westward migration
        patterns; social life in Massachusetts and Vermont; family relations in the 19th century;
        19th century New England women writers and their activities; and New England genealogy.
        There are also many clippings in the scrapbooks debating the abolition of slavery, many
        written by minister Silas McKeen. The photographs series is large and offers many fine
        examples of 19th century portraiture and photographic processes, including ambrotypes,
        cyanotypes, daguerreotypes, tintypes, albumen prints, postcards, and early gelatin silver
        and platinum prints. The majority are portraits but there are also interiors of family rooms
        and images of educational institutions, especially Abbott Female Academy in Andover,
        Massachusetts (now Abbot Academy), whose principal over several decades was Philena McKeen.
        Three photograph albums round out the photograph series.</abstract>
      <physdesc id="aspace_3018d52457e09c9ef63ec524407ce7c8"><extent>Approximately 3240
          items</extent></physdesc>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_a7dc174f001ca35aec67c77ea0b7d33e">Material in English </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_b1f84c42f4518d7887ca47226e869485">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
        research use.</p>
      <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_0bf6ac887a7541148af6c8897f3fcfa6">
      <head>Copyright Notice</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_8748dfb5130035cf16e489dd774a9912">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], McKeen-Duren family papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_79291806cd2fafeefe8d84b3ce9c2899">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The McKeen-Duren family papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library in 1973.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo id="aspace_19a042b961dc201d9be87005dff4f162">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Geraldine Degiron, Aaron Thornburg, January 2009.</p>
      <p>Accession(s) represented in this collection guide: two accessions from 1973.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_848a98903ff2731509d2353b797e3918">
      <head>Biographical Notes</head>
      <p>The McKeen family traces its history to James McKeen, a magistrate, who immigrated to
        America from Northern Ireland in the early eighteenth century (circa 1718) and was active in
        the settlement of what would come to be called Londonderry, New Hampshire. </p>
      <p><emph render="bold">James McKeen, 1666-1756</emph>
      </p>
      <p>Emigrated from Ireland to America in 1718. Settled in township of Londonderry, New
        Hampshire, circa 1719. Commissioned as magistrate in 1720.</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Silas McKeen, 1791-1877</emph>
      </p>
      <p>Great-grandson of James McKeen. Born in Corinth, Vermont. Married Phebe Fuller in 1816; she
        died in 1820. Children: Marianne, Serena, and Julia. Married Hannah Johnson in 1821.
        Children: Philena, Catherine, and George, and Phebe, his last child. Only two daughters
        survived into old age, Philena and Phebe. Second wife Hannah died in a carriage accident in
        1848. Married Sarah Parmelee, 1851. Congregational Minister of Bradford, Vermont
        (1814-1832?, 1842-1866). Born in South Corinth, Vermont, and died in Bradford. Ordained,
        1815. M.A., Dartmouth, 1822. Called to be pastor in Belfast, Maine, 1832. Called once more
        to Bradford, 1842-1866. Received D.D. from Dartmouth, 1861. Wrote many pieces for the <title
          type="simple" render="italic">The Vermont Chronicle</title>, <title type="simple"
          render="italic">The Bradford Vt.</title>, <title type="simple" render="italic">The New
          Englander</title>, and <title type="simple" render="italic">The Green Mountains
          Freeman</title>, including memorial pieces, obituaries, and articles and published letters
        on temperance, and defending the abolition of slavery (1830s-1850s). Wrote <title
          type="simple" render="italic">A Scriptural Argument in Favor of Withdrawing Fellowship
          From Churches and And Ecclesiastical Bodies Tolerating Slaveholding Among Them</title>
        (New York: American and Foreign Anti-Slavery Society, 1848).</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Serena McKeen Duren, 1819-1862</emph>
      </p>
      <p>Daughter of Silas McKeen and Phebe Fuller McKeen. Married Rev. Charles Duren, 1841. Two
        daughters, Marianne and Elizabeth, died in childhood. Mother of Charles McKeen Duren
        (1842-1934).</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Philena McKeen, 1822-1898</emph>
      </p>
      <p>Daughter of Silas McKeen and Hannah Johnson McKeen. Helped to establish Abbot Academy
        (sister institution of Phillips Academy), Andover, Massachusetts, and served as principal
        for 33 years. Co-author with her sister Phebe of <title type="simple" render="italic">Annals
          of Fifty Years: A History of Abbot Academy, Andover, Mass., 1829-1879</title> (1880).</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Phebe Fuller McKeen, 1831-1880</emph>
      </p>
      <p>Daughter of Silas and Hannah McKeen. Long-time teacher at Abbot Academy. Author of numerous
        published writings including several book-length works: <title type="simple" render="italic"
          > Thornton Hall</title> (1872); <title type="simple" render="italic"> Theodora</title>
        (1875, entitled <title type="simple" render="italic">Theodora Cameron</title> when published
        in the United Kingdom circa 1878); <title type="simple" render="italic">The Little Mother
          and her Christmas</title> (1876); <title type="simple" render="italic">Annals of Fifty
          Years: A History of Abbot Academy, Andover, Mass., 1829-1879</title> (1880, coauthored
        with her sister, Philena); and <title type="simple" render="italic">Sketch of the Early Life
          of Joseph Hardy Neesima</title> (1890, published posthumously). Published many short
        pieces under the pseudonym Jenny Bradford.</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Charles McKeen Duren, 1842-1934</emph>
      </p>
      <p>Grandson of Silas McKeen and son of Serena McKeen Duren and Rev. Charles Duren. Moved from
        New England to Iowa after the Civil War. Married Gertrude Whiting. Children: Alice Serena
        (Fanny?) and Mabel. Began successful career in banking in Iowa and worked to establish
        banking services in underserved areas.</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Note</emph>
      </p>
      <p>More information on Silas McKeen family members can be found in Silas McKeen's book, <title
          type="simple" render="italic">A History of Bradford, Vermont</title> (digitized and
        availabled online). Also, additional biographical information on the McKeen, Fuller, and
        Duren families and related individuals, as well as further details on the photographic
        components of this collection, are available in the Rubenstein Library; please contact
        Research Services for assistance. Finally, the numerous genealogical documents in this
        collection can be consulted.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_6bb54af9c04e3c8bac5d70ecc5343ef7">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>the histories of the McKeen and Duren families, particularly of Silas, Phebe, and Philena
        McKeen. Topics of note documented through correpondence, diaries and journals, other peronal
        papers, printed material, and images include: religious thought and institutions in New
        England; the education of women and the careers of female educators; photography throughout
        the 19th century; the Civil War and its effects on New England society; westward migration
        patterns; social life in Massachusetts and Vermont; family relations in the 19th century;
        19th century New England women writers and their activities; tourism in 19th century
        England, Scotland, Switzerland, and Egypt; and New England genealogy. There are also many
        clippings in the scrapbooks debating the abolition of slavery, many written by minister
        Silas McKeen. </p>
      <p>The bulk of the manuscript material is housed in the <emph render="bold">Correspondence
          Series</emph>, which chiefly consists of exchanges between members of the McKeen-Duren
        families. The earliest correspondence originates from New England, the McKeen family having
        been established in the area by brothers James, William, and Samuel McKeen, who emigrated
        from Ireland in the early 18th century. Beginning around 1823, letters exchanged between
        Silas McKeen and the father of Serena McKeen (she married Charles Duren) appear. A
        significant later portion of the correspondence was written by Silas to his son Charles, who
        served as a Union soldier during the Civil War. The family's exchanges then began to stretch
        westward during a period in which Philena and Phebe McKeen taught at the Western Female
        Seminary, Oxford, Ohio, and when Charles McKeen Duren moved to Iowa following the Civil War.
        Prominent topics in the letters from the latter half of the 19th century include Phebe and
        Philena's literary and publishing activities; education in New England and the Midwest; the
        Civil War and its effect on New England citizens; and routine family topics such as health,
        religion and morality, and social activities. There are very probably references to the
        abolition movement and slavery: the McKeens, Silas in particular, were outspoken
        abolitionists.</p>
      <p>A rich variety of written communication is found in the <emph render="bold">Writings
          Series</emph>, divided into two subseries, Manuscripts and Volumes. The Manuscripts
        subseries contains handwritten copies of a variety of types of writings by members of the
        McKeen-Duren families. The Volumes subseries contains often unattributed handwritten drafts
        and notes on fictional pieces; essays, probably written by Phebe or Philena; and sermons,
        most likely written by Silas McKeen. There may be material related to Silas McKeen's
        writings on slavery.</p>
      <p>The collection is notable for its extensive <emph render="bold">Photographs Series</emph>.
        Almost all photographic formats across the 19th century can be found here, including many
        albumen prints, chiefly in the form of cartes-de-visite and cabinet cards; cyanotypes; cased
        and uncased ambrotypes and daguerreotypes; and tintypes. Also present are gelatin silver and
        platinum prints. The series is divided into four subseries: Albums, Cased Images, Oversize
        Prints, and Prints. One family member, perhaps Phebe, was reportedly an amateur
        photographer, but direct evidence of this remains to be discovered. Interior photographs of
        the family home show multitudes of photographs hung on the wall. Subjects in the
        collection's images include family members from babyhood to old age, family friends, travel
        in England, Europe, and the Middle East, pets, and horses. Other families portrayed in the
        photographs include Page, Deming (?), Grovenor, and Dunlevy. There are only a few landscapes
        but there are images of Abbot Academy buildings, grounds, and students with their teachers
        (Andover, Massachusetts). Some of the photographic items, particularly the cased images, are
        fragile and should be handled with care.</p>
      <p>The <emph render="bold">Diaries and Scrapbooks Series</emph> contains many personal
        journals and diaries, spanning the years 1804-1900, and scrapbooks, circa 1838-1902. The
        diaries are quite detailed and were chiefly written by the female members in the McKeen
        family; topics revolve around family health problems, visitors and travel, readings, the
        weather, and emotional or religious experiences. There may be passing references to slavery;
        there is one reference to a prominent abolitionist, later imprisoned, who visited the McKeen
        house. The scrapbooks house pasted-in clippings pertaining to family members, and many
        published short pieces written by Silas, Phebe, and Philena McKeen. There are also
        handwritten extracts of letters, as well as prescriptive pieces and poems, and a series of
        pages from Civil War periodicals. There are quite a few clippings in the scrapbooks on
        slavery and abolitionism, as well as references to issues pertaining to statehood; many of
        the anti-slavery pieces published in New England serials were written by Silas McKeen from
        the 1830s to the 1850s. The clippings folder in the Printed Material Series contains similar
        loose items.</p>
      <p>The <emph render="bold">Financial Papers Series</emph> contains notifications of
        contributions to missionary institutions, receipts for good and services, society
        memberships, and subscriptions. A number of ledgers, some in bound volumes, are also found
        here.</p>
      <p>The <emph render="bold">Genealogy Series</emph> contains extensive handwritten accounts and
        notes originating from the early 19th century, documenting the ancestry of the McKeen-Duren
        families and related branches, as well as two hand-written bound volumes containing detailed
        genealogies of the Duren, Gould, Prichard, and Freeman families. There are also a few
        printed materials, including obituaries and memorial pieces.</p>
      <p>The <emph render="bold">Legal Papers</emph> files contain the earliest documents in the
        collection (1720). Items include land grants and deed transfers, inheritance inventories,
        loan notices, service contracts, wills and will abstracts, writs of indenture or
        apprenticeship, powers of attorney, and other documents.</p>
      <p>An assortment of printed items, clippings, and ephemera pertaining to members of the
        McKeen-Duren families can be found in the <emph render="bold">Printed Materials
          Series</emph>, including invitations, event programs, announcements, obituaries and
        memorial pieces, short story reprints, copies of a course curriculum, a copy of the Abbot
        Academy journal, cards, and other assorted materials, including a hand-drawn map, perhaps
        the local vicinity where one of the families lived, found in the ephemera folder.</p>
      <p>A folder of <emph render="bold">Oversize Material</emph> housing diplomas awarded to
        members of the McKeen-Duren families completes the collection. </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Abolitionists -- Vermont</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Antislavery movements -- United States -- History</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Education -- United States -- History -- 19th century</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Photography -- United States -- History -- 19th century</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Portrait photography -- United States -- 19th century</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Slavery -- Religious aspects</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Slavery -- United States -- Public Opinion</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Education -- United States -- History -- 19th
        century</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women educators -- United States -- 19th century</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Iowa -- Social life and customs</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Massachusetts -- Social life and customs -- 19th century</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">New England -- Social life and customs -- 19th century</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Social
        aspects</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Vermont -- Social life and customs -- 19th century</geogname>
      <genreform source="aat">Albumen prints</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Ambrotypes</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Cabinet photographs</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Cartes-de-visite</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Cyanotypes</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Daguerreotypes (photographs)</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Diaries</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Gelatin silver prints</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Journals</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Photograph albums</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Platinum prints</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Tintypes (prints)</genreform>
      <persname source="ingest">McKeen, Phebe F. (Phebe Fuller), 1831-1880</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">McKeen, Philena, 1822-1898</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">McKeen, Silas, 1791-1877</persname>
      <corpname rules="aacr" source="lcnaf">Abbot Academy</corpname>
      <famname source="ingest">Duren family</famname>
      <persname source="ingest">Duren, Charles McKeen, 1842-1934</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">McKeen Duren, Serena, 1819-1862</persname>
      <famname source="ingest">McKeen family</famname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref12_mr2" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence, 1816-1934 and undated</unittitle>
          <physdesc id="aspace_0bd1e48bb1740d58cce160faa5c80126"><extent>7.5
            boxes</extent></physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_f6f9ebda8296b0b3682b2dd183cae179">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>This series starts off with a single folder of birthday "Certificates," letters written
            from Silas McKeen, Charles Duren, and Charles McKeen Duren to their children giving
            thanks and a description of the child on the occasion of his or her birthday. A
            significant portion of the correspondence falls during the United States Civil War
            period, 1861-1865 (17 folders); they were written mainly by Silas McKeen to his son
            Charles, who served in the Union Army. Exchanges from this period express the senders'
            thoughts on contemporary events and are sometimes written on stationery supporting the
            Union cause, and include passing references to slavery. A number of letters pertain to
            or are written by Freeman Duren, a family member who served in the 13th Regiment,
            Massachusetts Volunteers. There are very probably many more references to the abolition
            movement and slavery in the correspondence - the McKeens, Silas in particular, were
            abolitionists. Following the Civil War, the bulk of the correspondence generally belongs
            to members of the Duren family in Iowa, and refer to family matters, health and
            sickness, honors received by family members, and business. Themes of note include the
            teaching and education administration career of Philena McKeen, who was Principal of
            Abbot Academy, Andover, Massachusetts for 33 years (1859-1892). The literary career of
            Phebe McKeen, sister of Philena and a teacher at Abbot Academy, is also a notable topic
            of correspondences in the collection. From 1859 a number of the exchanges relate to
            Phebe's contributions to serial publications and several book-length works: <title
              type="simple" render="italic"> Thornton Hall</title> (1872), <title type="simple"
              render="italic"> Theodora</title> (1875, entitled <title type="simple" render="italic"
              >Theodora Cameron</title> when published in the United Kingdom circa 1878), <title
              type="simple" render="italic">The Little Mother and her Christmas</title> (1876),
              <title type="simple" render="italic">Annals of Fifty Years: A History of Abbot
              Academy, Andover, Mass., 1829-1879</title> (1880, coauthored with her sister,
            Philena), and <title type="simple" render="italic">Sketch of the Early Life of Joseph
              Hardy Neesima</title> (1890, published posthumously). A letter of particular note sent
            to Philena McKeen in March of 1892 is from the widow of Joseph Hardy Neesima, the first
            Japanese person to receive a degree from a western college, Amherst College, and founder
            of what would become Doshisha University in Kyoto, Japan; in it she thanks Philena for
            sending a copy of the book that Phebe McKeen had written about Joseph Hardy Neesima.
            Another letter of note comes from Harriet Beecher Stowe (1892 May 5), sent along with an
            autographed copy of <title type="simple" render="italic">Uncle Tom's Cabin</title> for a
            new library/reading room that was constructed at Abbot Academy. Two letters, the first
            from an unidentified writer addressed to Miss McKeen (1890 Nov. 3) and the second from
            the widow of Joseph Hardy Neesima include cartes-de-visite photographs.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref14_o96" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Certificates and correspondence, 1816-1859</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_843bfb4bf2b9c3504aa848dba08c4f4e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref15_lwx" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1860-1864</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_5ae75b122291e5124c282e334cc4412b" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref16_0ye" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1864-1869</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_ec4ccde636cef1544ec9bcf8419ec4fc" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref17_il7" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1870-1873</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_c444ccad3fee9d8feda366bee60cfae1" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref18_y71" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1873-1877</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_42c75d61d8f7abd2298777eed2fee585" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref19_ajh" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1877-1880</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_44e59067b007a5190852f45199515bb4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref20_og3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1880-1897</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_4e8e67a2cafb79526711283048ee13c8" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">7</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref21_mfa" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1898-1934 and undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_3f7187436cbaf51cbb9e9e689d1246db" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref23_9om" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Diaries and Scrapbooks, 1804-1906 and undated</unittitle>
          <physdesc id="aspace_688adf74068300eca3d0d4e7cf65a1af"><extent>2.5
            boxes</extent></physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_440344d0cc26c08c637fe14e513b94dc">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>Comprised of 19 volumes of varying sizes. The diaries and journals, described more
            fully below, were kept by various individuals in the McKeen family, mostly women, and
            span the years from 1804-1898; most are quite detailed. Names in brackets are tentative
            identifications extrapolated from context or handwriting; names without brackets are
            taken from the items themselves.</p>
          <p>The scrapbooks house many clippings pertaining to family deaths or honors, publications
            written by family members, and other events relating to the McKeen-Duren families. In
            the scrapbooks probably kept by Silas McKeen from the 1830s through the 1850s, there are
            a number of clippings regarding abolitionism, slavery, and various political events
            relating to statehood, the Dred Scott Decision, and other national issues preceding the
            Civil War. </p>
          <p>Series materials are arranged in rough chronological order.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref25_igl" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal, 1804-1806, [possibly Elizabeth Freeman Duren]</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_57110249312ff4af88eaa14bb4ee9f09" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_9347981545ca58d804ad71bb5e4af745">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Writer mainly expresses religious sentiments and interior experiences of
              unworthiness, guilt, and redemption; few personal names are mentioned.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref27_mwc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle><title render="doublequote">Memo of ministerial service of Silas
                McKeen,</title> 1815-1821, 1873, 1877</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_d69c0c9ee9d3d899d8141878099b9451" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_71f07c528fff78c5b0ac8f5d4e39486d">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Memoranda documenting Silas McKeen's ministerial service; includes 1877 postscript
              regarding the monument erected to Silas after his death.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref29_q04" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle><title render="doublequote">Sermon and topic book,</title>
              1842-1845</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_6550855dd87589b0b1354758eb54b8de" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_8a59f5518f22abb3663ac0558b0f8271">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Silas McKeen's record of sermons and topics preached.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref31_lkr" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Quotidiana, GWM", 1848</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_d3e4e062c399869223691186ab95ca09" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_55592304e426b1ec89d3dc12bf622e42">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Diary, 1848, possibly written by George Whitefield McKeen, died in 1850 at age of 27.
              Comments on many events, education, and family routines, including visits by friends.
              Inscription on flyleaf reads "Marianne McKeen, 1840" - George's sister, died in 1845,
              age 23. Clipping on stereoscopic photography, 1855, Alfred Southworth, laid in
              back.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref33_r3f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Diary, 1851 Jan.-1854 Mar.</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_39a46ab75219cfed9cc94e5c6a6775e0" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_eca21819ed9694178afcf337c50bbfc9">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Title page reads, "Index Rerum," G. W. McKeen, Dartmouth College, Oct. 1843 N. H.,"
              but first pages cut. Diary, 1851-1854, begins on page marked "29," entries written by
              a woman, possibly Serena, George's sister, as it mentions Philena and Phebe in the
              third person. Postscript from 1853 may be by a different hand, as it speaks of "our
              dear" Serena's illness after June 1851. Comments on page 40 that antislavery "martyr"
              Capt. [W?alker], came to dine; had been imprisoned and was evidently supported by the
              McKeens.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref35_v5e" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Diary of Eliza M. McCane, Western Female Seminary, Oxford, Ohio, 1858
              April-July</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_a1cbfa47ace04d6709b1d1733c612141" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_aaa0b6dd80d802a0fb77f3308cb92108">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Seems to have been a teacher at the seminary. Mentions Phebe McKeen, missionary
              training and visits by missionaries, missionary work among Native Americans, and
              various school events and festivities.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref37_nv4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Diary [Phebe McKeen], Waitsfield, Vermont, 1852 May-1862 July</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_65a2a7d173527f01eac6c5674e9d90d1" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_a11de57d18741fb9539bcfba067d0fd3">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>The writer, Phebe McKeen, expresses many religious sentiments and practices much
              self-examination; entries also mention visits of family and friends, outings, the
              weather, and readings. The diary dwells at length on her sister Serena, who at the
              time was an invalid and died in 1862. Clipping about Civil War Vermont soldier laid
              in, also several religious notes.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref39_pha" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Diary, Serena M. Duren, 1861 Jan.-1861 Dec.</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_cba57b88cb5388d220aac3ddef96fbf2" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_ac031bfd9f5790fb26e447323c7d551f">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Small almanac diary which begins with the funeral for her daughter, Lizzie, who died
              at 14. Brief entries which follow note the weather, her own health and the sickness
              and death of others, outings, and visits. Small list of expenditures in back.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref41_0e6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Diary, Serena M. Duren, 1862 Jan.-1862 May 5</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_3e47f0846eeb4d5bbd063aec9b339264" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_da69b9a26af1e5be123eb1e3f2011005">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Small almanac diary continues as above, with frequent mentions of ill health, daily
              weather, visits, and infrequent outings. Serena Duren died at age 43, July 1862.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref43_6t7" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Diaries, Silas McKeen, 1863 May 19-Dec. 9; 1864 Jan.-Dec.</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_42bbe9b71b905e541c316c9df787c90d" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_28d35186f138c96d9e58b183ece52719">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Small almanac diary for 1863 sewn to a larger farmer's almanac for 1864. The 1863
              diary begins in May with a trip to Lowell (Vt.); subsequent entries are brief and
              chiefly note the comings and goings of family members, especially his children, his
              own church-related activities, and trips out of town. There are lists of addresses on
              the last few pages. The 1864 almanac's memoranda, which chiefly record Silas' travels,
              are even more brief.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref45_o2y" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Travel diaries, P. McKeen [Philena], Andover, Mass., <title
                render="doublequote">Trip from the river St. Lawrence with Capt. Holmes and Miss
                Carrie and Mr. Edmund Holmes in 1867</title>[followed by trip to Adirondacks, 1869],
              July 19-Aug. 19, 1869 July 30-Aug.</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_471ee714c706521853f5d2b03198c2dc" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">9</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_8a2ec8c6f37dc243ff27bf2ac6001bd1">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Diary of pleasure trip down the St. Lawrence in summer 1867. Sketches, packing list,
              names and addresses, and expenses on last pages. Two dried plants laid in. Also
              includes notes on a trip to Adirondacks in August 1869. These trips were turned by
              Philena into published travel pieces pasted into a scrapbook in this collection.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref47_09f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Travel diary, Philena McKeen, Andover Mass., summer 1889</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_3fac62cb7fa668ac27faed51c873eeae" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">9</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_46ebbb990e79e922d686dd02359baafe">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Trip to England and Switzerland with Charles, her brother, and one other woman.
              Almost certainly related to photo album from same geographical locations - see the
              Photographic Materials Series, as well as to published travel pieces appearing in a
              scrapbook in this collection. Currency conversions and detailed expenses included.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref49_0m2" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal [Phebe McKeen], Andover, Mass., circa 1870s (many pages
              cut)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_6ba3fb3cf5a61e52fcb7c1aef509807a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">9</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_efe2826b804c8916ef36b369dda9e0ac">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>A researcher has tentatively identified the handwriting in this journal to be Phebe
              McKeen's, and going by the student names, also notes that the timeframe appears to be
              circa 1870s.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref50_66f" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Scrapbooks, 1838-1900s</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref51_ysw" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Two scrapbooks, 1840s-1892</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_23965c3e6770f72b3c43526186663364" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">9</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_91e22aa42665297a58b6faa7ac4d82e6">
              <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
              <p>Contain much genealogical and biographical information regarding the McKeen family,
                including lengthy biographies of Serena and Marianne McKeen as well as extracts of
                letters describing the demise of various female individuals in the family, including
                the death of Silas McKeen's first wife in a carriage accident.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref53_n3e" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Five scrapbooks, 1838-1900s</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_01eca11aac14224d6f5bab49ac7cd048" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">10</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_365a951bec2aa1d2eadec2bda209a925">
              <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
              <p>A large scrapbook contains a lengthy series of published exchanges from 1838-1840
                on slavery, apparently initiated by Silas McKeen, addressing church members in
                Mississippi. In the same scrapbook there are many published extracts from <title
                  type="simple" render="italic">The Christian Banner</title> written under the
                pseudonym "Jenny Bradford," who has been identified as Phebe McKeen. Some travel
                pieces are signed by Philena, and clearly pertain to travels which are also
                documented in her diaries in this collection. Many of the writings by Bradford also
                appear in a Civil War-era newsletter published by the Tract Society of Boston, and
                these pages are pasted into the same scrapbook. A second large scrapbook, from the
                1860s and 1870s, contains a handwritten chronology of military and civil events
                during the Civil War, and a handwritten transcription of President Lincoln's last
                inaugural address, March 4, 1865. Other scrapbooks also contain clippings on
                slavery, the Dred Scott Decision, and events concerning statehood and slavery, as
                well as many poems, prescriptive anecdotes, temperance pieces, and other writings by
                the McKeen family and other authors. One scrapbook contains a pasted-in confederate
                bill for ten cents, issued in Charleston, S.C. in 1861. The latest date in these
                scrapbooks appears to be 1902.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref56_n7u" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Papers, 1821-1890 and undated</unittitle>
          <physdesc id="aspace_2ef1ea7fec21bfe2bfc95c48d9e62974"><extent>2
            folders</extent></physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_5bca440397938a84adbbb8acf29b56ba">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>The first of the two folders comprising this series houses a variety of materials,
            including certificates announcing professional qualifications; reciepts for cemetary
            bequest, church assessments, contributions to missionary institutions, good and
            services, society membership, and subscriptions; a calling card from Miss Dix, and a
            three-page ledger of monies received. The second folder contains three bound volumes: a
            memorandum of bonds and obligations in the care of Rev. S. McKeen, 1874; an account
            ledger pertaining to publication of a book by Silas McKeen, 1875; and an account of
            expenses of Miss Philena McKeen on behalf of Abbot Academy, 1886.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref58_4gg" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Financial materials</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_b448ad7f290843b3cbd1c03afebe0dc4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">10</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref60_22q" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Genealogy, 1839-1945 and undated</unittitle>
          <physdesc id="aspace_ddd5e654b30f819cdd81758b6a90b3d4"><extent>5
            folders</extent></physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_6118d0f94d2f5c1b5ef4a3cb4dc13de2">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>This series contains handwritten accounts and notes pertaining to the ancestry of the
            McKeen-Duren families and related branches. Printed materials, usually in the form of
            obituaries and memorials, also appear in the series. Two hand-written bound volumes
            contain detailed genealogies of the names of Duren, Gould, Prichard, and Freeman.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref62_o77" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Genealogy files</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_d0f485d053788d19ccfcaae69458fa5f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref64_hed" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Legal Papers, 1720-1938 and undated</unittitle>
          <physdesc id="aspace_36afb5667d5c9b818223386fc7b47da0"><extent>2
            folders</extent></physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_b9ff02e3e0e544954652fca77a076465">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>This small group of materials comprises legal documents relating to the McKeen-Duren
            families beginning from 1720 and continuing into the twentieth century, among which are
            land grants and deed transfers, wills, writs of indenture/apprenticeship, powers of
            attorney, inheritance inventories, loan notices, and service contracts.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref66_6dw" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Legal Papers files</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_5e1c942ddb8e7101cccd0d5eefa7be3e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref68_kug" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Photographs, 1841-1928 and undated</unittitle>
          <physdesc id="aspace_462981db6af195e80a9d54031bbd2ce0"><extent>5 boxes</extent></physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_9423330169eabff3f66e0b2e8ee3d4da">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>Arranged by type of material into four subseries: Photograph Albums, Cased Images,
            Oversize Prints, and Photographic Prints.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict id="aspace_856cacc210ec5cce04a6e21e8dffdb1d">
          <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
          <p>[Note: Some of these photographic materials and cases are fragile and should be handled
            with extreme care. Please use gloves for unsleeved items.]</p>
        </userestrict>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref70_ek9" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Photograph Albums, 1889, 1895 and undated</unittitle>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_22d75413ea7056bb7bf918e3e886dda9">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Three albums, almost certainly related to Philena's trips to England, Scotland,
              Switzerland, and other places. Philena then wrote travel pieces on these experiences,
              and these writings are pasted into scrapbooks in this collection.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref71_cli" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Souvenir album, 1895 (M. Duren)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_9f8388571f7a34ee3e009e19d02b1558" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">11</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_3a1e6ecb32fb03056e2cba1258297d1d">
              <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
              <p>Documents travels in England, Scotland, and probably Italy.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref73_l96" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Edinburgh, 1899 (C. M. Duren)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_3f5148d99c0fb646acbccb7fe41a3226" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">11</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_e74b5be068bdad00cc52fbcddb1b74ce">
              <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
              <p>Contains many loose prints.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref75_e43" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Album, late 19th century (G. W. Duren)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_9631626983d4c6ec6fdaceaabe27985e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">11</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_82b4dff369a060401bd2c102216f3607">
              <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
              <p>Contains many loose prints of artwork and tourist locales in England and
                Switzerland; the first print in the album is of a seated woman, and is captioned as
                being taken in Turkey.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref78_qky" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Cased Images, circa 1841-circa 1860 and undated</unittitle>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_cd425feb2785968890e9cf3dac96780b">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>15 ambrotype and 22 daguerreotype portraits of McKeen-Duren family members and
              friends. Many cases are fragile - please handle with care. Gloves should be used.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref79_lb6" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Ambrotypes</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_e75ac24b7ef62dc246f57a6e3c857ba5" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">12</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref80_1kh" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Daguerreotypes</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_9dbf3a7e08ee1294d1daa4f8c48a4719" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">13</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref82_kxc" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Oversize Prints, 1883-1895, and undated</unittitle>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_2e545aec40d36dc82c06aec35e95e2c3">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Sixteen interior photographs of different buildings of Abbot Academy, one exterior
              photograph of "Maple Walk," presumably on the Academy campus, and prints of three
              different classes of students at the Academy (1893-1895).</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref83_yr6" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Student class portraits, 1893, 1894, and 1895</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_d4a8737a432ceb03242d997a3e6e8383" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref84_mbk" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Unidentified (building??), undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_617c69a3a95ae03a5d9ce218c1ff4073" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref85_jnh" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Sunset Lodge, undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_e6ca6a27964cc9301ae2208eb9d28968" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref86_s9h" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Draper Hall, undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_a7f8ae0cde04f9256a88d4407057964e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref87_t5d" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Smith Hall, undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_4e238838297a83d85ee7bd019be78616" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref88_eh0" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Maple Walk, undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_b3046b3d93f2ee4743b08ad87123757a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref90_bej" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Photographic Prints, 1862-1928, and undated</unittitle>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_dc1f783052c57229e24efa3551b242a9">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Approximately 160 portraits of individuals, groups, and animals. The majority of
              these are albumen prints, usually mounted, of members of the McKeen-Duren families,
              and almost all are captioned with names and dates. Images for each individual are
              housed in separate folders. Folders also exist for the Deming, Dunlevy, and Grovenor
              families, for family pets and other animals, and for unidentified individuals, as well
              as various identified individuals. There are also 38 photographs of Egyptian monuments
              and archeological sites.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref91_b07" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Animals and unidentified people, 1899, 1910, and undated [2
                postcards]</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_d0c216af0a220fcd043c1feb3841ccde" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref92_vbz" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Deming (?) family, 1862 and undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_a7d9cdc02086ca37b538dcd27b75fade" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref93_ps6" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Dunlevy family, 1876 and undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_b3159ad298dfb432acb588865709e252" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref94_scg" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Grovenor family, undated (c. 1870?)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_f98534b8dfe5138f25e57d903094341f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref95_6h9" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Jesse Page family, undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_fc8f80072a1933250d35c56403b3345f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref96_vy7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Fanny Duren, 1876, 1877, 1885, 1888-1890, and undated [2
                tintypes]</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_074f3f40f94d1586cee68d2cf7452683" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref97_xmv" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Fanny Duren, 1894-1899 and undated [5 cyanotypes]</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_ea1975c7280d91ce27b31d486e046720" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref98_dta" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Fanny Duren, 1900, 1904, 1913, 1914, 1921, and undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_1742ddd42754fa6cd9d3df432a0fb6de" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref99_ns3" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Mabel Duren, 1874, 1877, 1883, 1887, 1889, 1891-1895, and
                undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_41eb1a2002f4146a628e1be8282eb2fe" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref100_rav" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Mabel Duren, 1896-1898 and undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_45b9ae73560914433962a65f31e4befd" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref101_e6p" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Alice Serena Duren and Charles and James Duren, 1873, 1874, and
                undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_8c82af7219dd067b6130e963a73b15e6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref102_adj" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Gertrude Eliza Whiting Duren, 1871, 1882, 1887, 1894, 1913, and undated [3
                tintypes]</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_3abcdd711242c9a67378c837c0372c60" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref103_s3j" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Charles McKeen Duren, 1887, 1888, and undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_6392fc556ef68d73034fd2a7f08d0d52" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref104_zx0" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Charles McKeen Duren, 1896, 1901, 1920, 1928, and undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_485e9e68764b67850ee371920474f814" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref105_vvr" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Phebe Fuller McKeen, undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_e29a553c2f3ce0886d05fa29df778d67" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref106_gnq" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Serena McKeen Duren, Charles Duren, and Lizzie Duren, 1850, 1862, and
                undated [1 tintype]</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_358f9059f064a278f4f7bc7cb8739eaf" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref107_usd" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Silas McKeen and Philena McKeen, 1877 and undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_c6170dcc4786a913d0a6c7156e5688c7" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref108_y36" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>William G. Duren, Emma Duren, and Mary F. Duren, 1869, 1873, 1874, 1898,
                1899, 1908, and undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_bc89fb4cec4207c199b5a1fa528bf703" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref109_2ng" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Elnathan Freeman Duren, Anna Butler Duren, and Freeman Hyde Duren, 1863,
                1869, 1897, 1898, and undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_614c295b23c26d5bf23adbd0a44bfaee" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref110_y0g" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Various individuals, identified, 1857, 1868, 1881, and undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_06e28f32254c43ae8bd50b1bbbf213c7" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref111_v2r" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Egypt, undated</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_829815263f025f2e3238e2399c43d1f4" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref115_z0o" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Printed Material, 1839-1894 and undated</unittitle>
          <physdesc id="aspace_17de18288ab8340292ea1ca81749f377"><extent>3
            folders</extent></physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_06a7be7419a94042ed30c49f734de9bc">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>First folder contains an assortment of printed materials, including invitations, event
            programs, announcements, obituaries and memorial pieces, short story reprints, course
            curricula, the Abbot Academy journal (including an obituary for Phebe Fuller McKeen), a
            boarding house business card, and a list of saloon passengers on a 1889 steamship
            passage. A single folder of newspaper clippings (1859-1882) comprises obituaries,
            historical pieces focusing on individuals or groups of people; contains a number of
            travel, local interest, and other short articles written by Phebe or Philena McKeen,
            sometimes under a pseudonym. The ephemera folder contains a variety of materials (1839,
            1884-1898) including a certificate announcing completion of study at the Theological
            Seminary, Bangor, Maine, by Charles Duren; a receipt for a framed portrait of Phebe; a
            list of letters sent to Europe; a number of wedding announcements and calling cards; a
            list of household items with names penciled next to them; and a sketch of the road from
            Bradford to Vershire, Vermont, annotated with traveling directions, "for Philena and
            Phebe, 1865."</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref117_xn9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Printed material, clippings, and ephemera folders</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_6bb229b7cfa3328671c7df4b599d7b13" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">16</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref119_6uo" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Writings, 1816-1899 and undated</unittitle>
          <physdesc id="aspace_cd3c289aab8661d141eb5989f4ace5af"><extent>14
            folders</extent></physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_66868753fd105343ec9cb7852f0f888e">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>Divided into two subseries, Manuscripts and Volumes. Manuscript folders of this series
            (10 folders) contain handwritten copies of short stories and essays, manuscripts, burial
            services, sermons, speeches, reports, themes for pedagogical purposes, in rough
            chronological order ranging from 1816 to 1899, with two folders of undated materials.
            Volumes in the series (5 volumes in 4 folders) contain unattributed handwritten drafts
            and notes on fictional pieces, essays or texts, most likely written by Phebe. The author
            of the manuscript sermons is most probably Silas. There may be material in this series
            related to Silas' anti-slavery writings published in book form and in periodicals prior
            to the U.S. Civil War.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref121_55k" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Writings files</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_fc548f905c67774d461a7ad32cc103cc" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">16</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref123_wtr" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Oversize Material, 1833-1857</unittitle>
          <physdesc id="aspace_eebfe17ffdafe719628a38600d9f92c7"><extent>1
            folder</extent></physdesc>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref125_j1z" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Diplomas</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_68d2f28f698424e9891fa43d2154583a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">Sec. A OV4</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref126_kxo" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>George W. McKeen, Dartmouth (1847)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_94cd1d187709627ad7473428b23d5350" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">Sec. A OV4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref127_y81" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Carol Duren, MA, Bowdoin, Maine (1841)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_590bed9eb70e4714a75df13434d10d6c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">Sec. A OV4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref128_tck" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Marianne McKeen, South Berwick Female Seminary (1835)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_452c2edd569d6331d1608e709c544aa4" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">Sec. A OV4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref129_e1f" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Carol Duren, BA, Bowdoin, Maine (1833)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_b939ab2f5d78082d7a254972c3fff18f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">Sec. A OV4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref130_2o5" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Catherine McKeen, MA, Harrodsburg Female College (1852)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_7a42252901962bb2d01b9fb6c20ed5e6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">Sec. A OV4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref131_ta6" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Genealogy</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_a15ef94d448dbaec98c50e01c5dc4f9c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">Sec. A OV4</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_d712537ce6948ec9b6b6d63212a79000">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Family tree "For Charles Duren," pen and ink. Tag says Eldora, Iowa, 1934 but signed
              by artist Dec. 1857.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
