<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/murphyelizawright/"
         >murphyelizawright</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Eliza Wright Murphy Papers, 1847-1927 <num>RL.00922</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Library Staff; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Meghan Lyon</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000842387</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 03:55:55
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Eliza Wright Murphy papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Murphy, Eliza Wright</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00922</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.2 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1847/1927" type="inclusive">1847-1927</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_84b975dbbd5131f90d83244abbd935e7">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_ad957b0dc07565b8b368fd228da835e7">Teacher, from Atkinson, N.C. The
            papers of Eliza Wright Murphy consist of correspondence, poems, school essays, receipts,
            printed material, reports, and photographs. Most of these items are the personal papers
            of Eliza and her brothers: Edwin Edgar Murphy (1874-1914), John Gerald Murphy (b. 1872),
            Paul Percy Murphy (b. 1878), Isaac Wright Murphy, and C.C. Murphy, referred to as
            "Neil." Also includes material concerning the Arran-on-Black River Literary and
            Historical Society in Wilmington, N.C., including programs, minutes, memos, and reports,
            and the Presbyterian Mission Hospital in Kiangyin, China. The correspondence consists of
            several hundred letters to Eliza and her brothers from friends and relatives in North
            Carolina, South Carolina, and Florida. News about local events and the correspondent's
            personal life are the chief subjects discussed. Correspondents outside of the immediate
            family included members of the Vidal and Wright families.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_ce04394242a6cfdf4377ff1114fca0d6">
            <extent>950 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_ae488034c273e48da2bc9d507d9b4fe8">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_be867735adea4709f9680f53948b68c8">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_8690cc15c7924f1c1e74212e461420b5">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_f138d5dca0a26f165ace5b6694d61580">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Eliza Wright Murphy Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_3da73b46ebe37e3ff9979457132ec73f">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Eliza Wright Murphy Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1955-1956.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_97ec9eca4a89808aa7c5e2b4b0bed06e">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library Staff, 1989</p>
         <p>Encoded by Meghan Lyon, May 2011</p>
         <p>Materials may not have been ordered and described beyond their original condition.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_fa3bde067849df3130b7067f2215795a">
         <head>Biographical and Historical Note</head>
         <p>Elizabeth Wright Murphy, daughter of John Henry and Elizabeth Catherine Murphy, was born
            during the 1860s or 1870s in Atkinson, N.C., where she continued to live for most of her
            life. Eliza graduated from Salem Female Academy in Salem, N.C., in 1895, and soon
            thereafter moved to Miccosukee, Fla., to teach at an unidentified school. In 1899 Eliza
            moved back to Atkinson; it appears that her career as a teacher did not continue
            afterwards. Eliza never married.</p>
         <p>Eliza had five brothers: Edwin Edgar (1874-1914), John Gerald (b. 1872), Paul Percy (b.
            1878), Isaac Wright, and C.C. Murphy, referred to as "Neil."</p>
         <p>Edwin Edgar Murphy, a merchant and farmer, was involved in a number of business
            enterprises and by 1905 was operating a general store in Atkinson, N.C. John Gerald
            Murphy, a physician, attended medical school at the University of Louisville and
            returned to North Carolina to practice medicine at Kenansville (1902-1907) and
            Wilmington (1908-?); he also served as president of the Arran-on-Black River Literary
            and Historical Society from 1920 to 1922. Paul Percy Murphy, a textile company
            executive, was employed by Wilmington Cotton Mills, Lowell Cotton Mills, Peerless
            Manufacturing Co., and other firms. Isaac Wright Murphy and Neil Murphy, both
            businessmen, eventually established a firm in Greensboro, N.C., which sold stoves,
            heaters, and cooking utensils. All of the Murphys appear to have been devoted
            Presbyterians.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_e9e0928381474c60e4bae2face039118">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The papers of Eliza Wright Murphy span the years 1873 to 1927 and consist of
            correspondence, poems, school essays, receipts, printed material, reports, and
            photographs. Most of these items are the personal papers of Eliza and her brothers;
            about 30 items, however, concern the Arran-on-Black River Literary and Historical
            Society or the Presbyterian Church. The correspondence forms the bulk of the
            collection.</p>
         <p>The correspondence consists of several hundred letters to Eliza (circa 60%), and, from
            the 1890s to 1927, to her brothers (circa 40%), from friends and relatives living in
            North Carolina, South Carolina, Florida, and elsewhere; very few of the letters are
            addressed to Eliza's parents. News about local events and the correspondent's personal
            life are the chief subjects discussed. Correspondents outside of the immediate family
            include Eliza's uncle J.C. Wright and other relatives in Coharie, N.C.; John W. Vidal,
            Adolphe L. Vidal and other cousins in Gainesville, Fla.; and Elizabeth Janet Black, or
            "Bessie," also a cousin, who lived in Raleigh, Lumber Bridge, and elsewhere in North
            Carolina before finally settling in Ivanhoe. Bessie's letters include a limited
            discussion of her teaching career, and, after 1919, her work for the Arran-on-Black
            River Literary and Historical Society as its secretary.</p>
         <p>Eliza and her brothers also wrote frequently to each other. From 1898 to 1901, there are
            letters from John, Edwin, and Paul while they attended the University of North Carolina
            at Chapel Hill, Isaac while he attended Oak Ridge Institute in Oak Ridge, N.C., and, to
            a lesser extent, from Neil while a student at Massey Business College in Richmond, Va.
            These letters concern student life at their respective schools, Isaac's volunteer work
            for the Y.M.C.A., and the usual family matters such as inquiries as to one's health,
            church, and social activities. Although Eliza's brothers pursued several different
            careers, very few of their letters discuss their professional and business activities;
            instead, the focus of their letters is on family news and social activities.</p>
         <p>The Writings series (14 items) consist of short poems and school essays (1 p.) written
            by Eliza during childhood and early adolescence. The Legal and Financial Papers (40
            items) consist of receipts, and undated tax list for the Black River section of Pender
            Co., N.C., and an undated contract for the distillation of grain. The Miscellaneous
            Papers (25 items) include two grade reports, one each for Edwin Edgar Murphy and John G.
            Murphy from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, concert programs, a
            mimeographed copy entitled "Constitution, By-Laws, and Minutes of an Educational
            Association in Cleveland County organized about 1860," and three photographs (circa
            1890s) of five women, one of whom may be Eliza.</p>
         <p>The first category (15 items) in the Tropical Series concerns the Arran-on-Black River
            Literary and Historical Society. Incorporated in 1919, its chief purpose was to collect
            and publish materials documenting the heritage of Scottish emigrants from the island of
            Arran, off the west coast of Scotland, who settled in the Black River section of Eastern
            North Carolina. Included are programs, minutes, memos, and reports dating from 1919 to
            1923. Letters concerning this society are located in the correspondence from 1919
            onward.</p>
         <p>The second category (12 items) concerns the Presbyterian Church, especially its foreign
            missions. Included is a manual of the First Presbyterian Church of Wilmington, N.C.
            (1904); newsletters from the Foreign Missions Executive Committee (1908-1910); and a
            handwritten report (1913) on the hospital fund campaign, submitted by Eliza Murphy to
            the Wilmington Presbytery, for the mission in Kiangyin, China. </p>
         <p>This collection best documents a young woman growing up in North Carolina during the
            late 19th and early 20th centuries, as well as her relationships with her brothers and
            the relations among the brothers themselves, separate from her. Other aspects documented
            include student life in college, teaching, a family's support of the Presbyterian
            Church, missionary activities in China, and the Arran-on-Black River Literary and
            Historical Society.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Florida -- Social life and customs</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">South Carolina -- Social life and customs</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Wilmington (N.C.) -- Social life and customs</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Presbyterians -- North Carolina</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina -- Social life and customs</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Presbyterian Church -- Missions</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Correspondence</subject>
         <famname source="ingest">Murphy family</famname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Kiangyin Hospital (Kiangyin, China)</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Arran-on-Black River Literary and Historical Society (Wilmington,
            N.C.)</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Murphy, Elizabeth Wright</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Murphy, Eliza Wright</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Murphy, Edwin Edgar, 1874-1914</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Murphy, C.C.</persname>
         <famname source="ingest">Vidal family</famname>
         <persname source="ingest">Murphy, Paul Percy, b. 1878</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Murphy, John Gerald, b. 1872</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Murphy, Isaac Wright</persname>
         <famname source="ingest">Wright family</famname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_nma" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Papers, 1847-1927</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_f257b3a4ef87e31767d27a14545515ad">
                  <extent>3 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_n53" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a2265d573ce95c640daae25e4d6c03fe">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Chiefly letters to Eliza and, from 1890s onward, to her brothers, from friends
                     and relatives living in N.C., S.C., Fla., and elsewhere. News about local
                     events and the correspondent's personal life are the chief subjects discussed.
                     Eliza and her brothers also wrote frequently to each other. Arranged
                     chronologically.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref15_x65" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>1873-1901</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_9a63d2e06917152f349496168b2c1113" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref16_cva" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>1902-1905</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_212670668026d12d05ade12c74158b0b" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref17_a87" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>1906-1927 and undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_fa3966e15a191d57089d516558f4e159" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_a6c" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Writings, 1880</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref20_p6o" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Short poems and school essays</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_b584d4cfdf88d58309f1c3032039a531" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_aii" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Legal and financial papers, 1847-1912</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref22_svr" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Undated tax list for Black River section of Pender Co.,
                        N.C.</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_e7c706b18fa35058ee85f71e7d99435a" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref23_dt3" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Undated contract for distillation of grain</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_127200facb1879ae84e9fbaaf4e8a4cb" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref24_l11" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Receipts</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_ec92d76bae109b36e0037158cc46d1d7" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_246" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous papers</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref26_9j4" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Grade reports, concert programs, printed material, and three
                        photographs of five women</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_8aa24c4917fee211065f836710b42d91" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_yja" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Topical Series</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref28_yrz" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Arran-on-Black River Literary and Historical Society,
                        1919-1923</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_27ee78ac8108b1a3cf72c5830399ac04" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_7e0d780bfc6a10f4189f95a73f4350ee">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>Programs, minutes, memos, and reports documenting this organization's
                        purpose.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref30_okt" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Presbyterian Church, 1904-1913</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_31702a4f870ecdb3bb1c86011c8d00a3" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_adaf2f3ea50fc15b837604886eebfd48">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>Mostly materials relating to foreign missions, especially the Kiangyin
                        Mission Hospital in China.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
