<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/noyesbalch/">noyesbalch</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Noyes-Balch Family Papers, 1854-1957 and undated.
            <num>RL.10176</num></titleproper>
        <author>Alice Poffinberger</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>October 2014</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">005857472</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-12-09 09:28:02
          -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Noyes-Balch family papers</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname rules="aacr" source="local">Noyes, Catharine P. (Catharine Porter),
          1838-1924</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.10176</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.6 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">4 boxes</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1854/1957" type="inclusive">1854-1957 and undated</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_52613cc5079138ef7dc8ab120460cda7">The Noyes and Balch families resided
        primarily in Jamaica Plain, Massachusetts. Collection comprises correspondence, including
        136 letters (603 pages); 3 diaries; a photograph album and loose photographs, as well as a
        wooden box in which the family stored letters from Catharine Porter Noyes. The collection
        centers around Catharine, who detailed her experiences while teaching newly freed slaves at
        plantations on the Sea Islands of South Carolina, from 1863-1864 and 1869-1870. There are
        also family letters written to Catharine, 1860-1892, especially from her sister, Ellen
        (Nellie); Ellen's husband, F. V. “Frank” Balch; and her cousin, Mary, who taught with Ellen
        in South Carolina, among others family members. Another set of letters were written by Ellen
        to Frank while he served as secretary to U. S. Senator and abolitionist Charles Sumner
        (R-Ma) in 1864 in Washington, D.C.; and by artist Emily E. Balch to Richard Noyes Stone. The
        collection also contains a diary maintained by a 12-year-old girl, probably Ravella Balch,
        and there are two diaries maintained by Emily E. Balch in 1929. There is a photograph album
        containing 32 black-and-white photographs of Noyes and Balch family members, as well as
        family friends. There are also loose black-and-white photographs, dated 1877-1957. Acquired
        as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture, and as part of the
        John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and
        Culture.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_9329888aef8b1defa1ca0537eec5b863">Materials in English</langmaterial>
      <physloc id="aspace_5ab9c2cc244037d674591b8b7183d1c8">For current information on the location
        of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
    </did>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_c6e2623edfbf78dbd884f7e90e71818e">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>Collection comprises correspondence, including 136 letters (603 pages); 3 diaries; a
        photograph album and loose photographs, as well as a wooden box in which the family stored
        letters from Catharine Porter Noyes. The collection centers around Catharine, who detailed
        her experiences while teaching newly freed slaves at plantations on the Sea Islands of South
        Carolina, from 1863-1864 and 1869-1870. She described the challenges of her teaching
        situation, social events and celebrations, local attitudes about freed blacks and her
        teaching them, black funeral and religious practices, and general conditions on the islands.
        She included her hand-drawn maps of the area, indicating its relation to the mainland. In
        addition to these letters from the Sea Islands, there are letters Catharine wrote while she
        was in Illinois and at the family home in Jamaica Plain, Mass., before she made her trip
        South (1854-1863). There are also family letters written to Catharine, 1860-1892, especially
        from her sister, Ellen (Nellie); Ellen's husband, F. V. “Frank” Balch; and her cousin, Mary,
        who taught with Ellen in South Carolina, among others family members. Another set of letters
        were written by Ellen to Frank while he served as secretary to U. S. Senator and
        abolitionist Charles Sumner (R-Ma) in 1864 in Washington, D.C.; and by artist Emily E. Balch
        to Richard Noyes Stone.</p>
      <p>The collection also contains a diary maintained by a 12-year-old girl, probably Ravella
        Balch, and there are two diaries maintained by Emily E. Balch in 1929. Common topics in all
        the letters include family news, health matters, visiting, travel plans, reading, lectures
        and church services attendance, theater performances, and pastimes. The photograph album
        contains 32 black-and-white photographs of Noyes and Balch family members, as well as family
        friends. There are 31 cartes-de-visite and one tintype; two of the cartes-de-visite have
        been hand-painted. The majority of the photographs are labeled, several in ink in a later
        hand. In addition to the photograph album, there are 17 loose black-and-white photographs,
        dated 1877-1957, including 4 cartes-de-visite, 6 tintypes, and 2 photo postcards. </p>
      <p>Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture, and as part
        of the John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and
        Culture.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_3f0a3b87b6898325027ba4233fb4b22f">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Organized into the following series: Correspondence; Diaries; and Photographs, photo
        postcards, and photograph album.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <processinfo id="aspace_a97efd039b18a797e3385a27baefdff2">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by: Alice Poffinberger, October, 2014</p>
      <p>Accessions described in this finding aid: 2013-0099, 2013-0214</p>
    </processinfo>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_3687975692aeadca29661e5be2bcd6e9">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Noyes-Balch Family Papers, 1854-1957 and undated, were received by the David M.
        Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library as a purchase in May 2013 and gift in December
        2013.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_fcee2e54ca8ca83d498ea04bbe1a39c7">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Noyes-Balch Family Papers, 1854-1957 and undated, David M.
        Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <userestrict id="aspace_815aeaf84f5c57a0a716fb5d2ddfd9b4">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_123e11ab6426367e1f6dcba5efae8669">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for
        research use.</p>
      <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <bioghist id="aspace_ceb90a88a0ee0ef3a0e5d1a65814fcda">
      <head>Historical note</head>
      <p>The Noyes and Balch families resided primarily in Jamaica Plain, Massachusetts.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Sea Islands</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- South Carolina</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Freedmen -- Sea Islands</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Freedmen -- South Carolina</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Freedmen -- Education -- Sea Islands</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Freedmen -- Education -- South Carolina.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Girls -- Diaries</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Diaries</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Teachers -- South Carolina -- Correspondence</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Women teachers -- United States -- Correspondence</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Sea Islands -- Maps</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Sea Islands -- History</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Sea Islands -- Social life and customs</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Sea Islands -- Religious life and customs.</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">South Carolina -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
      <genreform source="aat">Diaries</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Photograph albums</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Cartes-de-visite photographs (card photographs)</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Tintypes (prints)</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs</genreform>
      <famname role="cre" rules="aacr" source="local">Balch family</famname>
      <famname role="cre" rules="aacr" source="local">Noyes family</famname>
      <persname rules="aacr" source="local">Noyes, Catharine P. (Catharine Porter),
        1838-1924</persname>
      <corpname role="rps" rules="dacs" source="naf">Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and
        Culture</corpname>
      <corpname role="rps" source="ingest">John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and
        African American History and Culture</corpname>
      <persname rules="rda" source="local">Balch, F. V. (Francis Vergnies), 1839-1848</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref12_op9" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
          <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9
              folders</extent></physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1854/1936" type="inclusive">1854-1936 and undated</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_7d944e28922453d43f26d23277765714">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The correspondence series contains 136 letters (603 pages) primarily written between
            1863-1892 by Catharine Porter Noyes, her sister Ellen (Nellie) Noyes Balch, and Ellen's
            husband F. V. (Frances Vergines, known as "Frank") Balch, along with a few by other
            family members. Another writer, Catharine's cousin Mary, joined her as a teacher of
            freed slaves in South Carolina. Includes letters written in 1933 by artist Emily E.
            Balch to Richard Noyes Stone.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="aspace_7a1ee046ad13c8ee630f5716409e7ed1">
          <head>Arrangement</head>
          <p>Arranged chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref15_vlq" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Catharine Porter Noyes, Outgoing correspondence</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1854-1870 </unitdate>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_f9c36a45769ec8f4b34a98bd5b1c08bb">
            <head>Scope and contents</head>
            <p>Catharine Porter Noyes served as a teacher of newly freed slaves at plantations on
              the Sea Islands of South Carolina, from 1863-1864 and 1869-1870. In this subseries of
              letters written to family members, she described the challenges of her teaching
              situation, social events and celebrations, local attitudes about freed blacks and her
              teaching them, black funeral and religious practices, and general conditions on the
              islands. She included her hand-drawn maps of the area, indicating its relation to the
              mainland. In addition to the letters from the Sea Islands, there are letters Catharine
              wrote while she was in Illinois and at the family home in Jamaica Plain, Mass., before
              she made her trip South (1854-1863).</p>
            <p>The family stored these letters written by Catharine in a wooden box (Box 3),
              separate from the other correspondence in the collection.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref17_g07" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Illinois, Jamaica Plain and first trip to St. Helena’s Island</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1854-1864</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_1270c8dd0d27db852f67a70b5133a91b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_f12b87e3d6a0e566dfe32a3d703cf5b9">
              <head>Scope and contents</head>
              <p>Subseries includes Catharine’s letters written between 1862 and 1864. Letters from
                1862 were written while she lived in Illinois. She wrote of secret societies active
                locally, including the Knights of the Golden Circle, and noted general poverty, the
                transport of Rebel prisoners, and participation by her Uncle in the battle at Fort
                Donelson. She also reported having stayed a week to help a family fighting 12 cases
                of measles among its children. In addition, she remarked on the general abuse of the
                English language and “the Rules” she witnessed. Later Catharine returned to Jamaica
                Plain, and topics in her letters included family matters, visits, travel, lectures
                she attended, and poetry she learned, as well as her reading habits.</p>
              <p>In her initial letters written from St. Helena’s Island (1863-1864) where she
                served as a teacher to newly freed slaves, Catharine mentioned a steamboat pleasure
                party that was disrupted by sudden and severe cold. She and several others were
                forced to take shelter a home of one of her black students. She added that two
                children and one other black woman eventually died from exposure.</p>
              <p>Catharine went on to describe her teaching situation at Hope Place, where the
                length of her contract and the amount of her pay were both indefinite. As for her
                students, who included both adults and children, she had difficulty teaching even
                the basics because their vocabulary was so meager, but she eventually attempted to
                teach them both poetry and some German. She pointed out that students did not have a
                high opinion of her handwriting, and they struggled with their own writing and
                creating mathematical symbols. Maintaining discipline in her school room was a
                constant topic in Catharine’s letters, and attendance was irregular, but the
                students showed pride in their learning by hosting frequent public performances for
                recitation. Catharine visited a school at Pine Grove convened by a mulatto, whose
                students were mulatto children. Catharine also attended the nearby black church,
                described the “praise houses” used for worship, and stated her intention to learn
                the songs the blacks sang. Near the end of her initial stay, one of her students
                caused an angry upheaval in the entire community by making up and attributing to
                Catharine unfavorable opinions about the living habits and scattered relationships
                of the former slaves (1 April 1864).</p>
              <p>She reported that the former slaves’ opinions of their former master were
                favorable. By all accounts master Captain John was kind: “he did not have any
                [illegible] and never let anyone whip his slaves but himself he always counted the
                strokes and they never minded his whippings, but Mrs. Tripp seems to have been very
                cruel…” (10? Dec. 1863) </p>
              <p>In Jan 1864, Catharine outlined a plan by Federal troops to sell nearby plantations
                in 20-acre lots to any resident, black or white, for 20 cents an acre. She added
                that the black men did not wish to risk being bloodied by outsiders for making such
                a purchase, so they were unlikely to take advantage of the offer. Other letter
                topics included weather (in comparison to that of Massachusetts), the prevalence of
                rats and snakes, a local hunting accident, and her waiting a shipment of belongings
                via a schooner facing heavy winds that could prove a problem for the cargo.
                Catharine spent her free time reading, riding, and playing games such as euchre.</p>
              <p>Includes Catharine’s two, hand-drawn maps of the local islands that also outline
                their relationship to the mainland.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref19_jvk" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Second Trip to St. Helena’s Island</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1869-1870</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_b9b2608e28fb313c719dab59f902457f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_e21e41e2abe41c36a78b4f239ce1b03c">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Catharine’s letter topics included local opinions about freed blacks and the fact
                that some white visitors looked down on her for her teaching the freedmen. Also, she
                noted that one local black male who was apprehended for wrongdoing was widely
                believed to be innocent. There was often illness and death on the plantation, and
                she described her sense of discomfort while attending funerals for blacks, because
                she was unfamiliar with their funeral customs.</p>
              <p>Holiday celebrations were a main focus of these letters. She listed who was invited
                to Thanksgiving dinner, then provided detailed plans for an extensive Christmas
                Festival that featured extensive amounts of food plus more than 800 hand-made
                individual items for distribution. Catharine noted that one woman assisting her
                wanted to give gifts only to the most deserving rather than to the most needy and
                Catharine was forced to intervene, if only to watch that sizing was appropriate for
                clothing items. Other topics involved clothes and dressmaking orders, gardening,
                family news, and invitations and visiting. One visiting flutist forced her to play a
                flute, despite her dislike of music and unwillingness to take up any instrument.</p>
              <p>Catharine provided brief descriptions of what transpired in her classroom, where
                she taught reading and proper manners. She also described her class favorite and
                mentioned a female student who was planning a wedding and being very coy with hints
                about the identity of the groom.</p>
              <p>She recorded the excitement in the local community because a railroad terminus was
                being planned nearby, and discussed the shipments of items she desired, and mail in
                general. In final letters she outlined a quarrel between black porters over
                transporting her baggage and pointed out how glad everyone is to see people
                returning from the North. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref34_iq7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Wooden box the family used to store Catharine Porter Noyes’
                letters</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1860s</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_c3d3f81f2262e43a3895d9e819303b22" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref22_ucn" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Catharine Porter Noyes, Incoming correspondence</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1860-1892 </unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_67ae494ae6084ee94b1b33b5380d1b5d" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_0c8107e4de4b022964a460f6ab622537">
            <head>Scope and contents</head>
            <p>Subseries contains primarily family letters to Catharine written by F. V. [Frances
              Vergnies] “Frank” Balch; Catharine’s sister and Frank’s wife, Ellen (Nellie); and
              their cousin, Mary, who joined Catharine on St. Helena’s Island as a teacher. The
              letters contained family news, along with travel and visiting plans, and notes on
              health and sickness. They also often mentioned special events and pastimes,
              particularly reading, theater attendance, and churchgoing. A few letters from
              Catharine’s aunts questioned whether she was prepared to teach in South Carolina.
              Includes two letters written by two of Catharine’s students at St. Helena’s (1865 and
              undated). There is also a receipt for the church pew at Trinity Church, West Newton,
              Mass.</p>
            <p>In 1861, Frank wrote from Camp Dubois where he was stationed, to point out that he
              could not carry into battle both a musket and Catharine’s crossbow she offered to lend
              him. Topics in his later letters included a neighborhood woman who was taken to the
              Taunton Lunatic Asylum, his hatred of author Alexandre Dumas’ writing, his thoughts
              after reading Sense and Sensibility, and and the illness and death of his first child,
              Catharine. Frank also described his family’s trip to England, including a visit to
              Winchester Cathedral, followed by a voyage on the Baltic.</p>
            <p>Ellen wrote of slippers she was making for Frank as a gift, and reported that their
              father’s personal letters were going astray and his rheumatism was worse. She also
              occasionally and abruptly mentioned war news and events in the Western theater, e.g.,
              “McClellan is beginning to hold up his end at last, isn’t he?” She quizzed Catharine
              about her trip South and the conditions there, then recorded her own trip to
              Washington, D.C., to visit their father in Feb. 1864. She went on to outline her
              activities in the capital, including her attendance at several White House receptions,
              with a description of Mrs. Lincoln’s dress and Mr. Lincoln’s “handshake in passing,”
              along with their plans to attend as many Shakespearean performances by Edwin Both as
              possible. She noted with bemusement that their father created a fire escape from a
              rope and pulley for their use in their building, and that they tested it. Like her
              husband, Nellie’s letters also traced the illness of her first child, Catharine, who
              was eventually cared for by a respected black nurse from Fredericksburg, but later
              died.</p>
            <p>Cousin Mary wrote to Catharine regarding her classes and their mutual acquaintances,
              along with her upcoming marriage and a wedding gift of books. </p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref24_mud" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Ellen M. [Noyes] Balch letters</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1864 June-July</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_f0ac230d03a321ba2f08a60ca9de8bf7" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_7ad708a22d8f0cccb1b7b3d5362eaeb7">
            <head>Scope and contents</head>
            <p>In these letters, Ellen (Nellie) M. [Noyes] Balch wrote to her attorney husband, F.
              V. [Frances Vergnies] “Frank” Balch, while he served as secretary to U. S. Senator and
              abolitionist Charles Sumner (R-Ma.). She recorded serious health concerns for those
              around her. For instance, Catharine Noyes was recovering from wounds she received when
              the hoop of her skirts became entangled and she was dragged during a wagon accident,
              and an unidentified “Henry” was wounded during a Civil War battle and then suffered a
              raid on his ambulance. Also, Frank’s mother had three teeth pulled. Ellen herself was
              preparing for, then convalescing following, childbirth. She also noted events in the
              neighborhood, including her abolition fight with a neighbor and a woman who was
              deserted by her “intemperate” husband who took even the couples’ bed. Remarkably,
              Ellen recorded several dreams she had of her husband during sleep. She had constant
              fears of a raid on Washington, D.C., and urged her husband to practice good self-care
              so that he would not become ill. In a final letter, Ellen reproved herself for losing
              a button that fell off a gift from her husband, and for not admitting it to him
              sooner. The letters included the doctor’s telegram following the birth of their first
              child on June 14, as well as an excerpted manuscript short story about a family. At
              one point Nellie mentioned in the letters that family friend Henry Wadsworth
              Longfellow stopped by the house, but she did not go on to describe the visit.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref26_e7h" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Noyes-Balch family letters</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1855-1884 and undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_60d469d0854fb568bdd6e896cf3f7350" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_06f118e4ad6aff0556a3303e9ff1f553">
            <head>Scope and contents</head>
            <p>The subseries contains primarily family letters. Topics included illness in the
              family, including description of the use of brandy as an enema, as well as travel
              plans for trips to Charleston, S.C., and Washington, D.C., before the Civil War.
              Included two letters (1863) from William Little requesting permission to marry
              Catharine Porter Noyes; he was not encouraged by Catharine’s father. There was also a
              professional letter (1864) to F. V. Balch that requested him to investigate possible
              military appropriations to Dr. Morton for his discovery of ether as an anesthetic
              agent, along with a congratulatory letter to Ellen M. Noyes regarding her
              engagement.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref28_c9j" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Richard Noyes Stone letters</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1933, 1936 </unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_6afa6acafe6b7b5017794b6952e68a54" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_0b1eec917f3531839b7960f7544b1938">
            <head>Scope and contents</head>
            <p>This subseries contains two love letters to Richard Noyes Stone from Emily E. Balch,
              along with the official announcement of Stone’s wedding to Louise Magill.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref31_jyf" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous letter fragments and envelopes</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1861, 1875 and undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_5e33449f65b496f93e19e4b613e65b2e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_8918797bbdf4a3a9dba4ac5a2ecc1d2e">
            <head>Scope and content</head>
            <p>There are 27 letter fragments and envelopes, including letters to Ellen (Nellie) M.
              [Noyes] Balch describing the death of her (grand?) mother, as well as a letter from
              “Maria” regarding illnesses and deaths of babies in the family.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref13_k9d" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Diaries</unittitle>
          <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2
              folders</extent></physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1855/1929" type="inclusive">1855, 1929</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_ae5de9a3fbaf76c8faee508f72d2c5ba">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The diary dated 1855 was maintained by a young girl about age 12. She mentioned her
            sister, Ellie, and (Aunt or Cousin?) Catharine Porter Noyes, so it is possible the diary
            belonged to Ravella Balch. Catharine later practiced her handwriting in the volume.
            Topics included a wagon accident, travel to visit friends and family, play time, reading
            habits, school, as well as the forgery of her father’s name by an unidentified man who
            later escaped to California. She also noted a visit by a biologist, whose experiments
            she served as an assistant.</p>
          <p>Emily E. Balch was an artist, and maintained two diaries in October and December 1929,
            where she documented her creation of an art studio in her home; the status of and
            reception for her art works, visiting friends in various hospitals; attending a funeral,
            along with teas, luncheons, wedding receptions, museum exhibitions and other
            entertainments. She also noted her visits to family members and brief vacations, as well
            as her preparations for the Christmas season. Notably absent from her writing is any
            mention of the stock market crash that year or its impact on her family.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref41_b8b" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Ravella Balch? diary</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1855</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_94b2b3cc5f6eaf7facbb7a7807a93102" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref42_sze" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Emily E. Balch diaries</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1929</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e15573db4c024d67711a8eef2d0e3951" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref14_2y4" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Photographs, photo postcards, and photograph album</unittitle>
          <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">49
              photographs</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 folder plus one photograph
              album</extent></physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1860/1957" type="inclusive">1860s-1957 and undated</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_1de90e8d26ccff8264d3025726812e44">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series contains a photograph album, loose photographs, cartes-de-visite, tintypes,
            and photo postcards. The photograph album contains 32 black-and-white photographs of
            Noyes and Balch family members, as well as family friends. There are 31 cartes-de-visite
            and one tintype; two of the cartes-de-visite have been hand-painted. The majority of the
            photographs are labeled, several in ink, in a later hand. Separate from the album, there
            are 17 loose black-and-white photographs, dated 1877-1957, including 4 cartes-de-visite,
            6 tintypes, and 2 photo postcards.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref35_xsg" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Photographs and photo postcards</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1860s-1957</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3ca4269030baa7c04cf55142935ee01f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_ae98304c5327c9ae58ff2b3169eaef7f">
            <head>Scope and contents</head>
            <p>there are 17 loose black-and-white photographs, dated 1877-1957, including 4
              cartes-de-visite, 6 tintypes, and 2 photo postcards. Photographs were labeled by
              family members, as follows: Group photograph of F.V.B., Susan Clark, Alice George
              [illegible], M.C.B., on piazza at [Cohasset?]; Pamela Balch, age 13 years, May 1957;
              Mary Simkhovitch with [Sle]pha and Helen; [Elizabeth?] Pye; Ebbie Noyes; Alice Stone
              Blackwell, daughter of Lucy Stone, wife of Henry Brown Blackwell; Katharine Allen,
              Andrews Allen; C.P. Noyes, Grandpa F.V. Noyes, E. M. Noyes, Elizabeth Balch (Mrs. F.
              V. Noyes) [Emily E. Balch]; Mrs. F. V. Balch, A. L. Balch, F. N. Balch; [Illegible];
              Balch House (postcard)</p>
            <list type="ordered">
              <head>Photographs and photo postcards labeled</head>
              <item>Group photograph: F.V.B., Susan Clark, Alice George [illegible], M.C.B., on
                piazza at [Cohasset?]</item>
              <item>Pamela Balch, age 13 years, May 1957</item>
              <item>Mary Simkhovitch with [Sle]pha and Helen</item>
              <item>[Elizabeth?] Pye</item>
              <item>Ebbie Noyes</item>
              <item>Alice Stone Blackwell, daughter of Lucy Stone. Wife of Henry Brown
                Blackwell</item>
              <item>Katharine Allen, Andrews Allen</item>
              <item>C.P. Noyes, Grandpa F.V. Noyes, E. M. Noyes, Elizabeth Balch (Mrs. F. V. Noyes)
                [Emily E. Balch]</item>
              <item>Mrs. F. V. Balch, A. L. Balch, F. N. Balch</item>
              <item>[Illegible]</item>
              <item>Balch House (photo postcard)</item>
            </list>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref37_3ah" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Photograph album</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1860s-1890s</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_26ded5c1fb063f171393c246783d501f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_0aa52ee812b7c2dd7a86d12424ea2e42">
            <head>Scope and contents</head>
            <p>The photograph album contains 32 black-and-white photographs of Noyes and Balch
              family members, as well as family friends. There are 31 cartes-de-visite and one
              tintype; two of the cartes-de-visite have been hand-painted. The majority of the
              photographs are labeled, several in ink, in a later hand.</p>
            <list type="ordered">
              <head>Handwritten captions for individuals photographed</head>
              <item>F.V. Noyes 1864</item>
              <item>Agnes Y. Balch “Cousin Agnes”</item>
              <item>Ellen M. Noyes</item>
              <item>A.L.B.</item>
              <item>[photograph slot empty] Grandpa &amp; Grandson, Ellen M. Noyes, C. P.
                Noyes</item>
              <item>Grandma Noyes Balch</item>
              <item>Aunt Agnes</item>
              <item>Mr. Sweat [Swett]</item>
              <item>Uncle Leonard [Nottingla]</item>
              <item>Aunt Katie Lambert</item>
              <item>Mr. W. F. Allen, American educator</item>
              <item>Annie Wing</item>
              <item>Aunt Katie Lambert</item>
              <item>A.L.B. &amp; E.G.B hand tinted</item>
              <item>A.L.B. hand tinted</item>
              <item>A. L. Balch</item>
              <item>Ann L. Balch</item>
              <item>Elizabeth Balch</item>
              <item>Ellie, Ellen Maria Noyes </item>
              <item>F.N.B.</item>
              <item>F.N.B.</item>
              <item>Alice</item>
              <item>Bobbie, Alice’s dog</item>
              <item>[Alice?]</item>
              <item>M.C.B.</item>
              <item>Mabel Morse Lee</item>
              <item>Mabel Morse, daughter of inventor of Morse code</item>
              <item>Helen Cheever</item>
              <item>Helen Cheever, daughter or wife of minister George Barrell Cheever</item>
              <item>Kate Wendell, daughter of Barret Wendell?</item>
              <item>Cora Bowditch</item>
              <item>Vladimir S[im]khouvld</item>
              <item>Mary S[im]khouvld</item>
            </list>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
