<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="https://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/oaaaslidelibrary/"
      >oaaaslidelibrary</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Outdoor Advertising Association of America Slide Library,
          1891-2000 and undated <num>RL.00965</num></titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: Lisa C. Chandek-Stark and Lynn Pritcher. Thank you to Stephen Freitas
          of the Outdoor Advertising Association of America and James Fraser of Fairleigh Dickinson
          University for background information used in description of the collection.
          Machine-readable finding aid created by: Lisa C. Chandek-Stark. Additions processed by
          Richard Collier, 2017.</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>Sept. 2017</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003121546</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-05-18 09:19:51
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2014</date>
        <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported to
          Archivists Toolkit</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date>2017</date>
        <item>Additions processed.</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Outdoor Advertising Association of America Slide Library</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <corpname source="ingest">Outdoor Advertising Association of America</corpname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="source">
        <corpname source="naf">John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising &amp; Marketing
          History</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.00965</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">51.0 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1891/2000" type="inclusive">1891-2000 and undated</unitdate>
      <physloc id="aspace_c319469baefc460bb26d5d686e0a3d45">For current information on the location
        of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_3abee2b41b5473287e47a597f422e10f">English.</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/r3k64bd3m"
      xlink:role="ddr-collection-object" xlink:show="new"
      xlink:title="Resource of Outdoor Advertising Descriptions (ROAD)"
      xpointer="ark:/87924/r3k64bd3m"/>
    <altformavail id="aspace_4c5d6f5e0f99200c15a2c9141e93d7be">
      <head>Existence and Location of Copies note</head>
      <p>Some items from this collection have been digitized and described in: <extref
          xlink:href="https://repository.duke.edu/dc/outdooradvertising">Resource of Outdoor
          Advertising Descriptions (ROAD)</extref></p>
    </altformavail>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_b0e14feb13d23a50e135e8e5863c8445">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_dfe188a224637439cc24f49bce808b79">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_08fe00f9954e481205a273e7fa8a78f0">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Outdoor Advertising Association of America Slide Library, David
        M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_77d343586b746f18f72320b76aa5f594">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Outdoor Advertising Association of America Slide Library was transferred to the David
        M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library from Fairleigh Dickinson University in
        1996.</p>
      <p>Processing of this collection was supported by the National Endowment for the
        Humanities.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo id="aspace_6deb7476b41bdb4c353d77b5983e0f0f">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>There was already some arrangement to the collection when it came to Duke University, and
        this is reflected in the choice of series maintained. The <title type="simple" render="bold"
          >Topical Series,</title> Subseries II, was created at Duke out of the many slides that
        arrived unsorted. Product categories in this subseries are those used by the industry
        itself. A few subgroups within <title type="simple" render="bold">Topical Series,</title>
        Subseries I are labeled <emph render="doublequote">Miscellaneous.</emph> Some of these
        miscellaneous groups are extensive and should not be overlooked in a comprehensive
        search.</p>
      <p>The collection contains a few negatives and loose transparencies, especially in the <title
          type="simple" render="bold">Award Nominees Series.</title> These were sleeved and
        interfiled with the slides. Information from most of the slides in the collection was
        entered into the <title type="simple" render="bold">Resource for Outdoor Advertising
          Description (ROAD)</title> database (available in early 2003). An "SL" number was assigned
        to an individual slide and placed on the slide itself, while also being used as the database
        record number. Certain letter combinations are restricted to certain series, but they do not
        necessarily <emph render="italic">match</emph> the first letter of a corresponding series or
        subseries. Approximate dates found on slides were usually included in the database, but many
        dates could not be confirmed. Gaps were left in some slide sleeves to show divisions between
        groups of slides that originally were banded or boxed together. Older boxlists with old
        notebook designations may also be found in this repository. Old slide notebook designations
        were maintained on the new slide sleeves and in the <title type="simple" render="bold"
          >ROAD</title> database. Box number prefixes (e.g. CH, TP) indicate particular series
        except in the case of the small series at the end of the collection, all placed together in
        boxes labeled "TT1" and "TT2."</p>
      <p>Processed by Lisa C. Chandek-Stark and Lynn Pritcher.</p>
      <p>Completed April 2002</p>
      <p>Encoded by Lisa C. Chandek-Stark</p>
    </processinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_103d8f523236407b868c0f4528758bca">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>The Outdoor Advertising Association of America Slide Library was created by officials in
        the Outdoor Advertising Association of America ( OAAA) and member organizations. OAAA is the
        primary professional and trade association representing the outdoor advertising industry,
        and was founded to promote outdoor advertising interests in the U.S. OAAA members own and
        operate billboards, street furniture, transit, or other outdoor advertising displays.
        Members also include service providers to the industry, users of the outdoor medium and
        others supporting its goals.</p>
      <chronlist>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1891</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event><corpname>OAAA</corpname> was founded as the <corpname>Associated Bill Posters'
                Association of the US and Canada (ABPA)</corpname>.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1901</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event><subject>Outdoor advertising company </subject><corpname>Foster and
                Kleiser</corpname> opened for business in Portland and Seattle; the company later
              was known as Patrick Media, then Eller, then Clear Channel.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1906</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event><corpname>ABPA</corpname> changed its name to <corpname>Associated Bill Posters
                and Distributors of the United States and Canada.</corpname></event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>ca. 1910</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Association set national standards for <subject>outdoor advertising</subject> and
              established the numbers of panels to be sold in each market.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1912</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Association changed its name to the <corpname>Poster Advertising Association,
                Inc. (PAA).</corpname></event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1912-1913</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event><corpname>PAA</corpname> established an Education Committee to encourage
                <subject>public service advertising</subject> donations.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1916</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The National Outdoor Advertising Bureau was formed to inspect showings and to
              conduct the outdoor advertising portion of ad agency business.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1920</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The Art Directors Club was organized, establishing standards for commercial arts
              through competitions and the identification of categories of <subject>commercial
                art.</subject></event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1925</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event><corpname>PAA</corpname> and the <corpname>Painted Outdoor Advertising
                Association</corpname> merged to become <corpname>OAAA.</corpname> The Fulton Group
              and the Cusack Co. combined to become the <corpname>General Outdoor Advertising
                Company.</corpname></event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1930</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event><subject>First National Contest and Exhibit of Outdoor Advertising Art</subject>
              was held under the auspices of the Outdoor Advertising Department of the Advertising
              Council of the Chicago Association of Commerce.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1941-1942</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event><corpname>Advertising Council</corpname> (initially, during WWII, the War
              Advertising Council) founded as a non-profit organization to coordinate selected
                <subject>public service campaigns.</subject></event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1946</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Raymond <subject>Loewy poster panel</subject> adopted as new 24-sheet structure
              for billboards.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1962</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The first modern <subject>"multivision" painted bulletin</subject> displayed in
              Sacramento, Calif. Triangular sections permitted display of three different designs on
              a single unit.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1990s</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Digital technology affected creation of advertising designs and display. Painted
              boards were replaced by computer-generated formats.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
      </chronlist>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_b70a279fe9fd8da82458d8b9a77b1aa1">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>The <title type="simple" render="bold">Outdoor Advertising Association of America Slide
          Library</title> spans the years <unitdate normal="1891/2000" era="ce" calendar="gregorian"
          type="inclusive">1891 through the 2000s,</unitdate> with the bulk of the collection
        originating in the <unitdate normal="1950/1959" era="ce" calendar="gregorian"
          type="inclusive">1950s</unitdate> and later. The collection documents over a hundred years
        of outdoor advertising primarily in the United States, plus some international campaigns
        from several other continents. The <title type="simple" render="bold">Slide Library</title>
        is a large collection, almost entirely comprised of slides of billboards, exhibiting a grand
        range of graphic artistry, advertising campaigns, and marketing strategies. A smaller group
        of images supports the ad collection with views of artwork, billboard construction and other
        related images. In addition to over 62,000 slides, there are a few early glass slides, as
        well as transparencies, a small number of paper files, and six audiocassettes accompanying
        slide presentations. Many images were submitted by outdoor advertising companies over a
        number of years to the Outdoor Advertising Association of America (OAAA) as entries in
        annual national competitions to determine the best poster designs. The OAAA currently
        sponsors the OBIE Awards, which were preceded by awards programs under various names and
        sponsorships starting in the early 1930s. The award is modeled after the ancient Egyptian
        obelisk, considered by many the earliest form of outdoor advertising. Indeed much of the
        collection can be seen as evidence of this awards program although only the <title
          type="simple" render="bold">Award Nominees Series</title> contains slides labeled as such.
        Other slides probably were transferred to OAAA when companies cleaned out their back files,
        though the precise sources of many items are unknown. The slides were maintained at OAAA
        primarily as a large supply of creative examples for member companies. Researchers
        interested in the following subjects may find the <title type="simple" render="bold">Outdoor
          Advertising Association of America Slide Library</title> especially helpful: the outdoor
        advertising medium itself, advertising awards, advertising design, billboard construction,
        and commercial art, as well as the many outdoor advertising companies, advertisers, and
        advertising campaigns represented.</p>
      <p>The images, designed to attract mass audiences, depict part of American society's history -
        a history of consumer attitudes and desires. The collection is therefore a valuable tool in
        formulating not only a pictorial development of the outdoor advertising industry but of
        societal norms and opinions. The ads speak to the creativity of artists and designers, but
        they also convey a rich story of how these creators saw society at large, especially in the
        United States. Perhaps more importantly, ads reveal how corporations and designers felt
        America <emph render="italic">wanted to see itself.</emph> Such visual richness underlies
        the primary goals of selling goods and services and promoting ideas for the public good.
        There are thousands of product advertisements but also many public service ads, political
        issue ads, and even Happy Birthday greetings in the collection. Billboards are one direct
        link from corporate America, various interest groups, and their advertising specialists
          <emph render="italic">to</emph> consumers; and a succinct one-sided conversation designed
        to spur them to action. </p>
      <p>In contrast to other types of advertising, outdoor ads were designed with the fast-moving
        traveler in mind. The collection documents well the evolution of the billboard's attempt to
        reach those on the move, especially drivers. With careful thought to what would quickly
        provoke interest, advertisers presented a huge range of thought from text-free images of
        abstract artwork to direct discourse (e.g. Vote for Nixon). Because posters were displayed
        for only limited time periods, and because their physical size makes them impractical to
        store, photography is the primary method of capturing billboard images. Most billboard
        photos - whether print or slide - were created to document the work of the company which
        posted them for their business use. </p>
      <p>Within the <title type="simple" render="bold">Slide Library,</title> the creative output of
        many outdoor advertising companies is documented, although particular creators of many of
        the ads are unknown. Foster and Kleiser is well represented in the collection. Other
        companies named in the collection include Naegele, Pacific, Turner, Eller, Donnelly,
        Columbus, General Outdoor, Patrick, Gannett, Lamar, United, and many others. Thousands of
        national campaigns are represented, but many local ads are present as well. Outdoor formats
        range from 19th century posters to <emph render="doublequote">multi-vision</emph> boards
        that automatically change views with the use of three-sided boards. Most images are of
        actual billboards, posters, and other outdoor advertising formats in the field, while a
        sizable portion are just images of the ad design itself with a plain background. There are
        some slides of stock posters (<emph render="doublequote">Your brand name here</emph>) and
        other forms of outdoor advertising such as bus cards, street furniture, and truck side
        advertising. The vast majority of the advertisements are in English. </p>
      <p>The first three series make up the bulk of the collection: the <title type="simple"
          render="bold">Award Nominees Series,</title> the <title type="simple" render="bold"
          >Chronological Series,</title> and the <title type="simple" render="bold">Topical
          Series</title> (by far the largest of the three). These series are made up almost
        completely of slides showing advertisements, usually in billboard format. All series are
        described further within the container list. The only other series with a sizable number of
        advertisements is the <title type="simple" render="bold">International Posters
          Series.</title> This is where the largest concentration of international ads is found,
        although there are a few scattered within the other main series. Ads may also be found
        scattered throughout the <title type="simple" render="bold">Presentations and Presentation
          Slides Series.</title>
      </p>
      <p>Several additional small series contain images of related content, providing support and
        context to the advertisements. These include the <title type="simple" render="bold"
          >Construction and Creation Series,</title> the <title type="simple" render="bold">Artwork
          Series,</title> the <title type="simple" render="bold">Street Scenes and Approaches
          Series,</title> and the <title type="simple" render="bold">Other Outdoor Advertising
          Related Images Series.</title> The <title type="simple" render="bold">Presentations and
          Presentation Slides Series</title> adds insight by showing some of the internal
        conversation between directors and trainees, advertisers and advertising creators, and more. </p>
      <p>The most direct route to locate any identified ad is through the <title type="simple"
          render="bold">Resource for Outdoor Advertising Description (ROAD)</title> database,
        available in early 2003. Information about most slides in the collection has been added to
        this database. Researchers will be able to search for specific attributes of ads such as
        brand or company name, product type, and headline, as well as other types of information
        including slide number, date, collection name, image type, image color, outdoor advertising
        type, and special notes. Many database records also contain a searchable field with the
        outdoor advertising company's name (posting company), a field indicating if the billboard is
        in a rural or urban setting, information on the presence of women, children, ethnic
        individuals, or famous people in the ad, and the billboard's geographic location. Various
        slide series were entered into the database differently. Multiple searches may be required
        for comprehensive searching. For more information, consult Research Services Staff
        (special-collections@duke.edu).</p>
      <p>For more contextual information, use this collection in conjunction with the Outdoor
        Advertising Association of America Records, especially that collection's Physical Structure
        Series, and Photographs, Slides, and Negatives Series. Closely related collections in the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library include the John Brennan Outdoor
        Advertising Survey Reports, the John Paver Papers, the John Browning Papers, the Duplex
        Advertising Co. Records, the H.E. Fisk Collection of War Effort Mobilization Campaigns, the
        Outdoor Advertising Association of America Records, the Outdoor Advertising Poster Design
        Collection, the Garrett Orr Papers, the R.C. Maxwell Company Records, the Howard Scott
        Papers, and the Strobridge Lithographing Company Advertisements.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_c737c76b9f621b5e3be950092c2b7279">
      <head>Category Descriptions for Topical Series - Subseries II</head>
      <p>Though seemingly well-defined on paper, the fluidity of these categories becomes obvious
        when facing thousands of diverse and often vague advertisements. If an initial search in one
        category does not bear fruit, try a related category. The best way to find any particular
        advertisement is via the <title type="simple" render="bold">ROAD</title> database, available
        in early 2003. In cases where more than one product was featured in an ad, usually the most
        prominent item dictated category placement. </p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Amusement and Entertainment</emph>
      </p>
      <p>This category includes ads for the following:</p>
      <p><emph render="italic">Bars, Casinos, Concerts, Country Clubs, Live productions (e.g.
          theater), Lotteries, Museums, Motion pictures, Movies, Night clubs, Race tracks, Sporting
          events, Teams (sports), Theaters, Theme parks, Venues (concert or event venues),
          Zoos.</emph>
      </p>
      <p>Generally, advertisements for hotels, resorts, national parks, and whole geographic areas
        ("See Florida!") as tourist destinations were placed in Transportation and Travel (T and T),
        but there is overlap with T and T. Look in both categories for a comprehensive search.
        Products in the Amusement and Entertainment category are generally final destinations, as
        opposed to means of travel. Most television show advertisements were placed in the Media
        category since the network was most often a prominent part of the advertisement, but some
        may also be found here. Most recordings can be found in the Consumer Goods and Services
        category.</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Apparel</emph>
      </p>
      <p>This category includes ads for the following:</p>
      <p><emph render="italic">Clothing brands, Fashion accessories, Footwear (shoes),
          Jewelry</emph>
      </p>
      <p>If searching for a particular apparel brand name, search this category along with "Retail,"
        as it was often difficult to tell if a name on a billboard referred to a brand of clothing
        or an entire clothing store. Zippers were usually placed in the Consumer Goods category. Ads
        for watches may be found in Apparel or Consumer Goods and Services.</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Automotive</emph>
      </p>
      <p>This category includes ads for the following:</p>
      <p><emph render="italic">Auto parts, Auto parts stores, Auto service, Auto dealers, Auto
          leasing, Auto manufacturers, Motor oil, Motorcycles, Motorcycle products, RVs, Tires,
          Tractors</emph>
      </p>
      <p>This category includes advertisements for almost anything related to cars, except gasoline.
        Auto parts stores are usually included here, not under Retail. Gasoline and gas stations
        were placed under Transportation and Travel (T and T). Ads showing both motor oil and
        gasoline (and/or car service) were put in the category of the item most prominent. A search
        for all gas stations should be completed in both this category and T and T. Often an ad
        advertised both car products and gasoline, or just the brand name was presented (Texaco -
        provides oil, gas, and car service). Sometimes it was unclear whether an ad was for an
        automotive or a household radiator and so both the Automotive and Consumer Goods and
        Services categories should be checked for those items. To search for a particular car
        dealer, look through subgroups of that dealer?s manufacturer within this category.</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Beverages</emph>
      </p>
      <p>This category includes ads for the following:</p>
      <p><emph render="italic">Alcoholic beverages, Non-alcoholic beverages</emph>
      </p>
      <p>This category includes ads for alcoholic and non-alcoholic beverages including mixers,
        coffee, buttermilk, and milk. Evaporated milk is most often found in the Food and
        Restaurants category. For a comprehensive search of all beverages, also check the Food and
        Restaurants category.</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Business and Technology</emph>
      </p>
      <p>This category includes ads for the following:</p>
      <p><emph render="italic">Agricultural products, Armed forces, Banks, Builders, Business to
          business services, Computers, Credit cards, Financial service organizations, Freight
          services, Government organizations, Health care, Insurance, Manufacturing equipment,
          Office products, Office space, Real estate, Schools, Software, Telecommunications,
          Telemarketing firms, Utilities </emph>
      </p>
      <p>General office supplies usually went into the Consumer Goods and Services category.
        Flooring and wallpaper (as well as other items used both by builders and average consumers)
        should be searched both in this category and in Consumer Goods and Services. Ads for
        lotteries can usually be found within the Amusement and Entertainment category. Car dealer
        financing is usually found in the Automotive category. Outdoor advertising is usually found
        in the Media category. Many ads featuring major appliances are without a brand name - these
        are probably for a utility company and were placed here. For this reason, however, some
        utility-sponsored ads may also be found in the Consumer Goods category. Search both this
        category and Consumer Goods for animal feed. Government-sponsored ads can be found in this
        category but if sponsorship was questionable, ads may have been put into Public Service,
        Consumer Goods, or some other category according to the nature of the ad. This category
        contains the largest variety of materials. Check other categories to complete a
        comprehensive search. Schools were sometimes put into the Public Services category as a
        non-profit and sometimes placed here.</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Consumer Goods and Services</emph>
      </p>
      <p>This category includes ads for the following:</p>
      <p><emph render="italic">Appliances, Books, Cemeteries, Dry cleaners, Electronics, Florists,
          Furniture, Gum, Gyms and Health clubs, Funeral services, Health and Beauty products, Hobby
          and craft items, Household products, Office supplies, Over-the-counter medicines, Pet food
          and supplies, Recordings (albums, CDs), Repair services, Sporting goods, Tobacco products,
          Toys and games, Undertakers, Vitamins </emph>
      </p>
      <p>Household products include zippers, most flooring, and wallpaper. Office supplies were
        placed here but other office products are in Business and Technology. Services were also
        placed here including funeral homes, and dry cleaners. Cable Service ads can usually be
        found in the Media category. Search for watches in this and the Apparel category. Cars,
        motor oil, car-related products, RVs, and motorcycles can be found mostly in the Automotive
        category. Gasoline can be found in the Transportation and Travel category. Sometimes it was
        unclear whether an ad was for an automotive or a household radiator and so both the
        Automotive and Consumer Goods and Services categories should be checked for those items.</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Food and Restaurants</emph>
      </p>
      <p>This category includes ads for the following:</p>
      <p><emph render="italic">Candy, Confectionery, Food, Food services, Ingredients, Prepared
          foods, Produce</emph>
      </p>
      <p>Gum, pet food, and tobacco products were most often placed in Consumer Goods and Services,
        although some may still be found here. Beverages, including coffee and milk, can usually be
        found in their own Beverages category. Grocery store and supermarket ads are usually found
        within the Retail category.</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Media</emph>
      </p>
      <p>This category includes ads for the following:</p>
      <p><emph render="italic">Advertising, Cable television, Direct mail, Internet services,
          Magazines, Newspapers, Outdoor advertising, Radio stations, Television stations, Yellow
          Pages </emph>
      </p>
      <p>Ads for recordings (albums, CDs, etc.) and books were usually placed in the Consumer Goods
        and Services category.</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Public Service</emph>
      </p>
      <p>This category includes advertising created for a charitable cause or by a non-profit
        organization. Government organizations are normally listed under Business and Technology,
        but government sponsorship of an ad was often difficult to discern. Check this category and
        Business and Technology for a more comprehensive search. Political campaign and issue ads
        can usually be found here. Some Public Service-type ads were actually placed under the
        sponsor?s usual category, if the sponsor?s name was an obvious part of the ad. For instance
        an ad saying <emph render="doublequote">Don't Drink and Drive, courtesy of Fred's
          Funerals</emph> may have been placed under Consumer Goods and Services. Schools were
        sometimes put into the Public Service category as a non-profit and sometimes placed in
        Business and Technology.</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Retail </emph>
      </p>
      <p>This category includes ads for the following:</p>
      <p><emph render="italic">Convenience stores, Department stores, Discount stores, Drug stores,
          Grocery stores, Malls, Pet stores, Other Retail stores, Shopping centers, Variety
          stores</emph>
      </p>
      <p>Some ads featuring clothing lines may have been placed here by mistake since it was often
        difficult to tell whether a name referred to the clothing brand or a store name. Some of
        these ads also feature an individual product or products carried by the retail store. If the
        item seemed prominent in the ad, the slide may have been indexed under Consumer Goods or
        Food and Restaurants. For auto parts store ads, search this category as well as the
        Automotive category.</p>
      <p><emph render="bold">Transportation and Travel</emph>
      </p>
      <p>This category includes ads for the following:</p>
      <p><emph render="italic">Airlines, Bus lines, Cruise ships, Gasoline, Gasoline stations,
          Hotels, National parks, Public transportation, Resorts, Trains, Travel/Tourism
          services</emph>
      </p>
      <p>Since gas stations but not car service are included in this category, search both this and
        the Automotive category for an ad featuring a company that sold gas and provided auto
        service. This category also overlaps a great deal with the Amusement and Entertainment
        category - search both categories for a comprehensive search.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <controlaccess>
      <genreform source="ingest">Billboards</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Transparencies</genreform>
      <subject source="lcsh">Advertising, Public service -- United States</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Audiocassettes</genreform>
      <subject source="lcsh">Advertising -- History</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Advertising -- Brand name products</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Advertising, Outdoor -- Awards -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Advertising layout and typography</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Advertising, Outdoor -- Posters</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Advertising, Outdoor -- Design and construction</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Advertising -- Posters</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Advertising, Outdoor -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Commercial art -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">OBIE awards</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Commercial art</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Commercial art -- Awards -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Billboards -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Brand name products -- Marketing</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Advertising -- Awards</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Billboards -- Design and construction</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Slides (photographs)</genreform>
      <subject source="lcsh">Signs and signboards</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Posters -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Posters -- Design</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Poster, American -- 20th century -- United States</subject>
      <corpname source="ingest">Outdoor Advertising Association of America</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Foster and Kleiser Company</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Advertising Council</corpname>
      <corpname role="fmo" source="naf">John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising &amp;
        Marketing History</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">General Outdoor Advertising Co</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref15_lhj" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Award Nominees Series, 1965-1968, 1983-1987 and undated</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_29ec592e76429dbcf5c9371f1dcd08dc">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>These slides (labeled with "SLA" prefix) were submitted to the Outdoor Advertising
            Association of America (OAAA) specifically as nominees for the national award program,
            most recently known as the OBIE awards. Member companies and advertisers submitted what
            they felt to be their best work for this national competition. The first National
            Contest and Exhibit of Outdoor Advertising Art was presented by the Outdoor Advertising
            Department of the Ad Council of the Chicago Association of Commerce in 1930. Later,
            sponsorship appears to have been provided by the Art Directors Club of Chicago, and
            perhaps other industry organizations. The Institute of Outdoor Advertising (IOA) was
            involved starting in 1965 until its merger with the OAAA, which continues "the OBIE"
            awards competition today. The OBIE award is patterned from the ancient Egyptian <emph
              render="doublequote">obelisk,</emph> considered by many to be the earliest form of
            outdoor advertising. Award categories varied by year but early groupings often included
            Posters, Painted Bulletins, Campaigns, and Public Service (Kerwin H. Fulton medal
            award). Later, the number of categories grew to include emerging formats such as transit
            advertising and product type categories. </p>
          <p> The competition has been known by a variety of names in the collection including the
              <title type="simple" render="doublequote">National Competition,</title> the <title
              type="simple" render="doublequote">Outdoor Advertising Competition,</title> and later,
            the <title type="simple" render="doublequote">OBIEs.</title> Winners were published in a
            serial, issued also under several different names: <title type="simple" render="italic"
              >Advertising Outdoors,</title><title type="simple" render="italic">100 Best
              Posters,</title><title type="simple" render="italic">Poster Annual,</title><title
              type="simple" render="italic">Outdoor Annual,</title><title type="simple"
              render="italic">National Competition of Outdoor Advertising Art, </title><title
              type="simple" render="italic">Outdoor Advertising Competition,</title> and <title
              type="simple" render="italic">OBIE Awards</title> (consult Duke's online catalog).
            These publications indicate that ads posted in one calendar year were usually eligible
            for the award presented the following year (recent winners can be found on OAAA's
            website: www.oaaa.org). Unfortunately, labeling within the collection and publications
            was unclear as to whether a specified year is a posting date or an award year. Years
            given in the list below are taken from original slide sleeves and containers. For more
            information on national outdoor advertising awards, consult the publications listed
            above, the online catalog, and Rubenstein Library Research Services Staff.</p>
          <p>While a sizable series, only a relatively small portion of many decades of national
            competition nominees are represented here. It has not been determined with certainty
            whether the outdoor industry sponsored any awards from 1973 to 1982, but the OBIE award
            was not awarded during that time. This may explain most of the gap in slides from 1969
            through 1982. Some transparencies also are included in this series. Labeled yellow slips
            were found attached to original slide sleeves, perhaps referring to slides removed at
            one point. Information on these slips was transferred to acid-free paper and clipped to
            the new archival sleeve. Some images are marked as being winners in a particular
            category, but most slides or sleeves have no such marking. Old notebook designations
            (A-1, A-2...) were maintained on the slide sleeves. Old notebooks were listed in the
            preliminary boxlist as follows: A-1: 33rd-35th National Competition (1965-1967); A-2:
            1984; A-3: 1984; A-4: 1985; A-5: 1985; A-6: 1986; A-7: 1986; A-8: 1986; A-9: 1987; A-10:
            1987; A-11: 1987; A-12: Various Designs and Awards. Hard copies of old boxlists may be
            found in this repository's inventory drawers.</p>
          <p>Slides are arranged by award competition dates and were numbered in that order, all
            with the prefix "SLA." In this series only, slides inserted after most had already been
            numbered were assigned a number with an alphabetical suffix so all slides following
            would not have to be renumbered.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <altformavail id="aspace_7858a41cb45ec90e051e066c8c363651">
          <head>Online Items</head>
          <p>Some items from this collection have been digitized and described in: <extref
              xlink:href="https://repository.duke.edu/dc/outdooradvertising">Resource of Outdoor
              Advertising Descriptions (ROAD)</extref></p>
        </altformavail>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref16_mmm" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1965: 33rd National Competition of Outdoor Advertising Art</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_081e87c8487bc442321026c3a19d2038" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">AW1</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref17_3l5" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLA0001-SLA0086</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_f79fcba18d157933288031fcaecc3773" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">AW1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref18_s91" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1966: 34th National Competition of Outdoor Advertising Art</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref19_sfk" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLA0087-SLA0164</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_4bd46f809c4de461238306e3fb1988f2" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">AW1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref20_x5h" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1967: 35th National Competition of Outdoor Advertising Art</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref21_xz6" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLA0165-SLA0261</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_f25fb1aaff52caa400e355704d9d084e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">AW1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref22_5wp" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1968: 36th Outdoor Advertising Competition</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref23_81t" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLA0262-SLA0277</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_fe7b57d2699da61ab306897de93de770" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">AW1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref24_ovd" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1983/84: OBIE Award Competition</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref25_5ag" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLA0278-SLA0327</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_c15c01a3c8efbc0988ce55bdccf5b57d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">AW1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref26_dhz" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1983/84: OBIE Award Competition</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_c67fb2f2b50d1c6e3dbdd1cba6c0e2e6" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">AW2</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref27_7bx" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLA0328-SLA0824(A-J)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_b5823c742cf135e161815b2c3af3167b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">AW2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref28_5o3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1985: OBIE Award Competition</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_31a67200375d0f710be33965d3988df4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">AW3</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref29_blo" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLA0825-SLA1469</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_f6a176b0f5e4eee527fbf229d2ffa563" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">AW3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref30_4n6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1985: OBIE Award Competition</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_daf7ec9198f62adb36e2d98181b73f52" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">AW4</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref31_uxg" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLA1470-SLA1524</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_a3ba682d5fbc5ac7af483675238e57aa" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">AW4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref32_pxs" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1985/86: OBIE Award Competition</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref33_8q2" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLA1525-SLA2046</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_ee9e92ef7fd3a3b98312634c9c0c8c8f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">AW4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref34_q83" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1985/86: OBIE Award Competition</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_d9a75f4c081b9d8468991578f4658ec3" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">AW5</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref35_m4v" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLA2047-SLA2545(A-L)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_3a00796995c8f39fab1459db454ab25f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">AW5</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref36_v8y" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1986/87: OBIE Award Competition</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref37_0n1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLA2546-SLA2677</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_4926e6e7be2c9cdd185c30ddd36d0b67" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">AW5</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref38_75d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1986/87: OBIE Award Competition</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_a2eb0aac487ee27dc7ffac34a2cacd7f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">AW6</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref39_683" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLA2678-SLA3279(A-L)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_6ad0e008fe16868ada4efa3e1bb3987c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">AW6</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref40_54e" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1986/87: OBIE Award Competition</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_1b9662c59b00413f1f10f30443f280cf" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">AW7</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref41_whb" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLA3280-SLA3575</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_2046b69d99bbf60ef61ba2625fe7b5d0" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">AW7</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref42_jo0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous Nominees</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref43_8db" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLA3576-SLA3975</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_d28260fa0ff72c31551ba47c323b8c8e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">AW7</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref46_r8f" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Chronological Series, 1891-1994 and undated</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_be93c21f1f110f3798f42da16536dcc0">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>The Chronological Series slides ("SLD" and "SLG" slides) are roughly in chronological
            order within each box. The earlier images have a higher concentration of poster
            advertisements as opposed to billboards. The series is almost completely made up of
            advertisement slides, but there are also some street scenes and a few other slides that
            could be tied to a specific era.<lb/><lb/></p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref47_u4a" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1891-1950</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_c951f5c3952c6076e229d1a6bb4ae25f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH1</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref48_1ct" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLD0001-SLD0740</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_2a1b8819fd86c2be36402acf8bebceb8" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref49_6bk" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1946-1957</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_3ca97a0c464296a800f1e79732ea6e63" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH2</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref50_qp1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLD0741-SLD1420</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_6983ed3159d8b4c84e1358c401b6f060" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref51_xbt" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1950-1960s</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_f2ec4a8b1dcb310fb93147f71b1524d3" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH3</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref52_ig0" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLD1421-SLD2100</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_455d1140a8ca000e54d4f29120948850" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref53_93z" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1951-1956</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_4e37c3829c8cc6729df5aa81704774bb" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH4</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref54_ia0" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLD2101-SLD2860</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_738ef5d1d2b582430507436d37f8dc2e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref55_fbh" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1951-1960</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_9be46df37a896f44ecaf45ace45ca094" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH5</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref56_2lj" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLD2861-SLD3660</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_49a4862a08fe32a7124bcda08f6d0931" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH5</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref57_q0b" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1952-1960</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_819ca624a248e39348d8d3bd1aebc6a2" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH6</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref58_raf" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLD3661-SLD4520</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_a77d25564fed42d9e227c66c569feb04" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH6</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref59_q2c" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1955-1962</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_b58f9666b5287e01ff584f9e2da7b092" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH7</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref60_4f7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLD4521-SLD5440</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_5b9cf2dab5668f59a3393a385f21b757" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH7</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref61_6ey" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1950-1962</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_34b43eaf8699a28f117f9e2620c97972" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH8</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref62_l2a" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLD5441-SLD6240</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_e4e49530b9d8b9d075d5088ebc9e7506" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH8</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref63_uv1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1960-1963</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_c50e55fa41ba20b67d36f60141160058" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH9</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref64_k81" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLD6241-SLD7080</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_9c7b5b9c4519e04a29bf8d1ff7a75cfd" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH9</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref65_l3o" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1961-1963</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_3bc713bdd9e816b47be4d5b2ea7e704d" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH10</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref66_brc" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLD7081-SLD7780</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_f0537396037f9ee38c2a250535b3f41b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref67_et8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1959-1963</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_b497b20419224092ff3877719452f14e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH11</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref68_v38" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLD7781-SLD8620</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_c2a93504bcfef1f4b95d5dbd013873bf" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref69_zkn" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1961-1964</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_a7caa9ad25a5a144effbb879ec76e9c2" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH12</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref70_c4a" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLD8621-SLD9460</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_748dc40d24bee230adde9a02315c37b3" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH12</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref71_7zt" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1964</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_a4d25639db37d72e5356f0e3f636d03a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH13</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref72_b75" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLD9461-SLD9999</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_1e8ac3599e241ce7a893b3593583edd9" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH13</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref73_uvi" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLG0001-SLG0281</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_52d2aaf2aeab86d99c8130226bdcbfc1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH13</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref74_ekl" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1964-1965</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_b21e23db38709b7f835c81f94e5043e7" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH14</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref75_jqu" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLG0282-SLG1096</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_5476f2aecf7030e90d5621d0b354d093" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref76_owo" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1965-1970</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_420a8d2fd4dd83ffd12d8a22a5f47ccd" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH15</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref77_48q" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLG1097-SLG1777</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_0840cf6cf7ea787e5d9c363bd7176781" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref78_7lb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1965-1970</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_1a04f8c89e36de329d1d5e34c9dd70e4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH16</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref79_vm9" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLG1781-SLG2520</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_3c201f69857da1d32eb892ab27c49fda" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH16</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref80_zsq" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1966-1984(no slides for the date span 1976-1983)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_2f6e656e68f2926b1f4e9cb89183b6a9" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH17</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref81_dov" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLG2521-SLG3380</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_d81d5adab0112bc72ee3838bddfdce59" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH17</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref82_lta" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1971-1989(no slides for the date span 1986-1988)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_06f30e783cc972679d47057f4963b9a3" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH18</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref83_ym7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLG3381-SLG4160</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_b63718e98a35634e5b274d8c415d70b0" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH18</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref84_5n4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1981-1987</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_9fe1f8d3f33fda3fa338951cbb962c8c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH19</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref85_12v" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLG4161-SLG4860</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_581e2d390e5bb9742848dc9683f81d15" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH19</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref86_izg" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1987-1988</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_36054ef7ccbfce8e5dacef548f099da7" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH20</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref87_mh8" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLG4861-SLG5520</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_309a3bfdeb48fa567d16548396cd80ba" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH20</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref88_kc9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1988-1989</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_fb405277c724ca883d64d85e9feffee6" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH21</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref89_3dq" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLG5521-SLG6400</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_0cad93499b1b5d9e4aa65cb4bb80e336" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH21</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref90_1zj" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1989-1990</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_400227ac31065bde32229273cc9e32b0" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH22</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref91_c4m" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLG6401-SLG7300</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_47ae26e696bd239dfcca8651a51b72e9" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH22</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref92_bwf" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1990-1992</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_ebee215c60cbf207a0ace05c82f69262" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH23</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref93_z49" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLG7301-SLG8280</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_838e159b9a8c308ab1663250a72a80ad" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH23</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref94_5z1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1992-1993</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_84a09b712c212ceda0ac742027e23a74" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH24</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref95_16x" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLG8281-SLG9180</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_adb16baf0ea2cc0817933e4507555005" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH24</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref96_vd8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1993-1994</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_a5b726f0c3125d2b0920cf3fd4ee6102" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">CH25</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref97_jba" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLG9181-SLG9880</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_b51ac43e5f9b81a29f7b8719c20e3f2c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">CH25</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref99_wwd" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Topical Series, undated</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_b87880fe41899802d0f2214374139b41">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>The Topical Series is the largest group of advertisement slides in the collection and
            is organized by product or service type. It has been maintained in two separate but
            similar subseries, the second being the larger of the two. To provide meaningful
            organizational categories for sometimes vague products, issues, and services, each
            category within each subseries is in effect one of three things, (1) a product type
            (food, cars, etc.), (2) a sponsoring organization (armed forces, liquor stores, etc.),
            or (3) an ad type (public service, political ads, etc.). Read through the entire list to
            target a search before browsing through boxes. Advertisements are often arranged into
            subgroups and then alphabetically by brand name within the groups listed below. For the
            second subseries, see category descriptions appended to this document before searching.
            A large percentage of the slides are undated but range from at least <unitdate
              normal="1940/1988" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" type="inclusive">1940 through
              1988.</unitdate> There are probably earlier images in this series as well that could
            not be dated precisely.<lb/><lb/></p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref100_11t" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Subseries I</unittitle>
          </did>
          <arrangement id="aspace_deb11455760fc041ef756d1de1530ca0">
            <head>Arrangement note</head>
            <p>The first subseries (Subseries I, "SLP" and "SLQ" slides) is roughly organized into
              groups according to product types listed below. Some of the <emph render="doublequote"
                >Miscellaneous</emph> groupings are extensive and should be consulted in a
              comprehensive search. These slides have been maintained in their original order.
              Topics may appear in more than one box.</p>
          </arrangement>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref101_r8j" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLP0001-SLP0740</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_abed9d6f2c4238cc06c04a153bb3e049" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP1</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref102_php" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>US Armed Forces</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_e486bccfd7017afe3a223f7d0878e731" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP1</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref103_ypa" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Boys Scouts</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_dbd86189b0a6dbe9e548c76049ca6504" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP1</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref104_ora" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Ad Council, Public Service</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_ee1bb30ff91b3c230e6788ff35b39a23" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP1</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref105_954" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Alcoholic Beverages (non-beer)</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_42578aba3b9222cc1b913140044e2feb" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP1</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref106_c20" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLP0741-SLP1540</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_8a30ee55c1e71fd54437ed2a327a83ea" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP2</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref107_wng" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Alcoholic Beverages (non-beer) <emph render="italic"
                  >continued</emph></unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_a372c6c1bedb6840caafa645a49434e5" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP2</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref108_5f9" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Liquor Stores</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_ebae4b1ff083ebae477311f106c6bf86" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP2</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref109_bgy" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Beer (roughly in alphabetical order by brand name)</unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref110_on1" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>A-Falstaff</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_cfb481c85b86d473aa050f4580a6e6cd" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP2</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref111_sot" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLP1541-SLP2360</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_6f03a81c9fd17ddf171d94e761219ae3" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP3</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref112_e2o" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Beer <emph render="italic"> continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref113_u5x" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Falstaff - Pearl</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ef110dcfa255c66db4856b6f78bea742" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP3</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref114_g9l" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLP2361-SLP3140</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_42c05314d0fc4b9759e3bdbfdd969b43" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP4</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref115_pn9" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Beer <emph render="italic"> continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref116_2dw" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Pearl - Wiedemann's</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_98bdd4ef971dfd0681d980da2ca1125b" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP4</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref117_9pe" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous brands</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a40c8e5139e4da26dc2fde3c0862489c" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP4</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref118_4lu" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLP3141-SLP3840</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_be2ce9fe7834ab074addf96c8a819765" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP5</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref119_xra" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Beer <emph render="italic"> continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref120_ty3" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous brands</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_303d141b2defd4de59c91d1f300583d5" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP5</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref121_psv" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Alcoholic Beverages (non-beer)</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_5da0c1fc5dc178586cae7fdb42d9f502" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP5</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref122_6y3" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Automotive/Motorcycles (roughly in alphabetical order by
                  manufacturer/dealer)</unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref123_mc4" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>American Motors - Ford</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c2c7f7b24399ca544337cb15b028e1bd" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP5</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref124_lf1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLP3841-SLP4600</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_769a600fd3c056985bdc127db1d9fff6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP6</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref125_pna" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Automotive/Motorcycles <emph render="italic">
                  continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref126_9vn" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Ford - Honda</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_606b69211d110d76fe3c48d38bb5a9ab" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP6</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref127_61t" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a8cc92fb739efb112dd0051b1daad45b" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP6</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref128_rng" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Hyundai - Yugo</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_40d1f84809c6a8c8d8b1f117325b4cc2" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP6</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref129_pa9" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_88eac42009d08dbdc0bbff6c77fc6c0e" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP6</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref130_ssg" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLP4601-SLP5180</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_33c22c46e19fe9fe92da03e940c50018" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP7</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref131_uax" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Automotive/Motorcycles <emph render="italic">continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref132_x58" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Car Parts and Service</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f88d76ff26c0d367507a185f6a93b178" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP7</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref133_i39" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Tires</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8ac06448b6cde159180966a032908e87" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP7</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref134_kop" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Car Parts</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8d338485839b03c80e2ffac2ae5cf147" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP7</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref135_afx" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Car Rental</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1c6bbaab683317a8f62bcc3fce24ed3c" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP7</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref136_k2p" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Financial Services (primarily banks/insurance roughly in alphabetical
                  order)</unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref137_xa1" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Ahmanson Mortgage - First National Bank</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f99b39d1bf1de7bbe5f9e9b03cf6bd6d" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP7</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref138_dzm" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLP5181-SLP5780</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_cb9232d57788ac97646ac3ba901b2ce9" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP8</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref139_ndu" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Financial Services <emph render="italic"> continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref140_zgb" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>First National Bank - Pittsburgh National</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_991a80e57a166d5564592d4a8698822f" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP8</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref141_k52" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Watertown - Zions</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b3991cb859c13469753821120c241ec9" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP8</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref142_02m" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Pittsburgh National - Zions</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f131c4afb1f7d3b2984c9981c02ecbce" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP8</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref143_uyq" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Credit Cards</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_474176498de2948ee2326e5b38720ada" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP8</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref144_ul9" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous financial</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_49799fa17004efe8e238ee764b478c11" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP8</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref145_ihx" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Non-alcoholic Beverages (esp. soft drinks including mixers; roughly in
                  alphabetical order)</unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref146_mmi" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>AandW - Coca-Cola</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_726d5d962e2640a4fe9f216ca67438dd" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP8</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref147_t62" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLP5781-SLP6460</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_265d7c7cbc71ee7b1fa721249ef0a3b8" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP9</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref148_px7" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Non-alcoholic Beverages <emph render="italic"
                  >continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref149_tj7" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Coca-Cola - 7-Up</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_59aa8918952c23b88539cf411ff91553" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP9</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref150_iye" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3b1cb2176e40639f4b12ac15aa0b0421" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP9</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref151_oee" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Juice and Coffee</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_7d2005b5c1ad79fd30b2be42ba660759" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP9</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref152_w0e" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Tobacco (primarily cigarettes roughly in alphabetical order)</unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref153_7ty" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Basic - Kent</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e145d00b054bf9cee33d89f9197069b1" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP9</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref154_sh9" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLP6461-SLP7080</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_ab9c7152a2cbc9871248620d00d0f668" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP10</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref155_y26" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Tobacco <emph render="italic">continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref156_kkx" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Kent - Winston</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0b21046ae3031989b19ca363576cba56" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP10</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref157_vku" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Amusement Parks/Farms</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_5bbf12380257ee52c13c4927e3fb4b38" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP10</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref158_55h" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Books</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_10905cdec933776696fa012d6754804e" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP10</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref159_e2m" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Miscellaneous (especially products pertaining to entertainment including
                  publications, gasoline, casinos, electronics, retail, alcohol, books, record
                  albums, television shows, celebrity/concert appearances, movies, mouthwash,
                  circuses, fairs, miniature golf, lottery, magazines, museums, and
                  symphonies)</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_6e4d6bee7576be479d06904112ec0f70" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP10</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref160_xn9" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Newspapers</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_e15ce647b5d39947c61c33a025d9f682" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP10</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref161_jrf" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Pet Shops</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_dc309db6e2cd59aab2e767f18146be42" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP10</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref162_wfe" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Animal Parks/Exhibits</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_952f20bf6ce967d568add8fc31edbc2b" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP10</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref163_yfy" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Sporting Goods, Events, and Teams</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_39d7d4a4e6d7bd0bb67a68a9af7c8389" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP10</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref164_yh6" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Playhouses, Studios, and Zoos</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_6ec08c501f8ad0c234fb23179bcfe16a" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP10</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref165_r76" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Movies</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_a8f27dbd10d987ebdf3e7d94f18e2298" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP10</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref166_ksz" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Radio and Television Stations/Shows</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_92d31240ca8c0eb8e7fbdfc8e6fd18a4" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP10</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref167_n6w" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLP7081-SLP7700</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_3c0e6df55cd779e38347165eb591c0b6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP11</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref168_fy6" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Radio and Television Stations/Shows <emph render="italic"
                    >continued</emph></unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_7cfdaab7362e67a51d15a9ea756fc7c8" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP11</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref169_4uh" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Pet/Animal Feed</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_ba7f1c4681a1295c9a9560c22815d1b3" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP11</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref170_s3w" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Food</unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref171_32j" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Bakery Items</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a8b83df435de0377eb9135e9f4ba5fe5" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP11</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref172_hf1" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Bread</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_251b80a21d0a44f332776d133c1c4247" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP11</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref173_2ms" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Butter</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b5cb7657f4767276eb165f14147d1923" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP11</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref174_zp7" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Buttermilk</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9c91e7f2851dfc64aedfb3c1dccb8520" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP11</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref175_n8l" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Candy, Snacks, and Gum</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6e1c429380f99a74c97d778d649974e4" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP11</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref176_gqq" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLP7701-SLP8320</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_62aab3fbe007fba40013756ece1a8db2" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP12</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref177_zqu" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Food <emph render="italic">continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref178_sal" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Candy, Snacks, and Gum</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2257262dc36b86d57c7c5dc674fce341" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP12</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref179_ws9" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Cereal and Breakfast Foods</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0f146f69d7e8729beff81d8b1ea360d9" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP12</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref180_r80" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Cheese Products</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e068371743dffe02629fabc08e63e852" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP12</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref181_msm" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Eggs</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3a583aab8d8717b18ea6881981496d28" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP12</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref182_mv2" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Flour</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e3fd2c2d3dc78ecdb8aa091f803c12ca" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP12</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref183_2x0" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Fruit</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_25fa55c816f5799b17cba608b2860e3f" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP12</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref184_c00" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Ice Cream and Popsicles</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_25b399e313d8e2d8f88194b8821c8428" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP12</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref185_a6t" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Jelly and Baby Food</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ef29b06e072fd242fb322aedb64b17f2" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP12</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref186_ne8" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Ketchup (catsup)</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e2926d17a71946090dcca767d284ec30" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP12</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref187_thh" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Margarine</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e03553f4ade011ad383d05df0e8dad31" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP12</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref188_pir" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Mayonnaise</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_55aa9d87b631b23d62174674f6040efb" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP12</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref189_dgl" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Meat, Fish Products, and Rice</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_87a10a5c9f53799584b7f159040fee03" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP12</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref190_vl9" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLP8321-SLP9040</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_26166b493c339a5bf6d50814b34fa641" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP13</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref191_5y7" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Food <emph render="italic">continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref192_axh" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Meat, Fish Products, and Rice</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_51688a3894ab63b99acffe5061d4373f" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP13</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref193_zwj" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Milk/Dairy Products</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_75ea2f99989ba16d360f25651eb21ec2" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP13</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref194_4oh" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Mustard</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fc68bf95b977ec02e5c2d45777903b38" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP13</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref195_cw7" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Nuts</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_995b786c844af64d3cc49a0adf8152b9" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP13</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref196_969" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Peanut butter</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_204eb6bd07ee45ffcb4807bb53a233b1" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP13</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref197_fgh" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Pickles</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e23c3f08fba56c94b07cc0d8ceeadc0a" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP13</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref198_8xb" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Potato Chips, Crackers, and Snack Foods</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a58ad841844da7c7084fe69c903b27de" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP13</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref199_pjr" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Salad Dressing</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e594e82fcfdaa668bab5e8c752e59239" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP13</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref200_rt1" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Potato Chips</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fca35e5cdbe67d0ee95f905f74c7bdd5" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP13</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref201_g02" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Salt</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8613e80723ca7877251d677f65f1f69f" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP13</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref202_p99" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Sour Cream</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5c98bd698827fd1de561b2f8f81cf7c9" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP13</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref203_cir" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Sugar</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_614f7d90291f3d28dbfdc46135d6760c" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP13</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref204_4vq" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLP9041-SLP9660</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_61396db429e64cb6edac9b5f228dc691" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP14</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref205_ek4" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Food <emph render="italic">continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref206_jxq" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Sugar</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c64f6e4259b6343094743122a8940630" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP14</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref207_y3b" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Vegetables</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8633b6e2e4f64f96485a83306b466886" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP14</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref208_7f8" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Jell-O Products</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ced57e717f5a51ad75f82588d1a99251" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP14</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref209_att" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Heinz Products</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_21731655a3e40a26db2f209cb384c175" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP14</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref210_cmb" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Shortening</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_308d6d266e26f8ca72f497b2505094e3" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP14</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref211_sne" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_41e7d76ad3b0374a7fe48951ae233d0d" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP14</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref212_wln" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Aluminum Foil</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_7b7ff4f78b068f877abc6259d138622d" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP14</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref213_ody" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Gasoline and Automotive (primarily gasoline/oil; roughly alphabetical by
                  brand; includes some auto parts and service)</unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref214_ezt" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Amoco - Hancock</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_cff5bb88d3bec2eaf5778f698ac5d552" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP14</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref215_gnv" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLP9661-SLP9999</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_061b0a3fb7375b308bcafa69103ec54f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP15</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref216_1me" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Gasoline and Automotive <emph render="italic"
                  >continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref217_8dp" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Hancock - Shell</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_7e31d479e58d3a3902ad86d7f926536c" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP15</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref218_6vq" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLQ0001-SLQ0300</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref219_785" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Gasoline and Automotive <emph render="italic"
                  >continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref220_fhe" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Shell - Signal</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b5661f33b9a3f4297ca8fc78ef5bf971" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP15</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref221_mbx" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLQ0301-SLQ1000</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_72ef376a8f7411701e278f99517afc38" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP16</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref222_3rp" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Gasoline and Automotive <emph render="italic"
                  >continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref223_5nl" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Shell - Union 76 (includes Standard/Chevron)</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d52390046d52cf74da8ff9abb2733f91" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP16</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref224_6gg" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_61edbf734a052e31262dedfdb6c4b32a" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP16</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref225_7p7" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Pain and Cold Medicine</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_4927473ce334492d8b2dc540db0aa719" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP16</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref226_nat" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Oral/Personal Hygiene</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_0c65bbc1ca24e2935bf2b5787216dbc0" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP16</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref227_0c4" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Eyewear</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_fb6c3e5eb131f744ac6e498d2ffe9e7d" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP16</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref228_szc" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Hair and Skin Products</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_fd36eb904536211da96a8599795de13d" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP16</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref229_i7s" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Dental and Medical</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_4ec1040fe40b1175692830f6103bb788" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP16</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref230_1bh" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Miscellaneous Personal Products and Retail (Includes medicines, bath,
                  health, and beauty products, pharmacies, beauty salons, and sunscreen)</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_e3eb32261fe035023e2915de9d5dee89" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP16</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref231_x56" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLQ1001-SLQ1620</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_c46da8a45bf41f008eae4799552fc324" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP17</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref232_nsh" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Miscellaneous Personal Products and Retail <emph render="italic"
                    >continued</emph></unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_d0591b4b9d9391bdea23126009f2a851" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref233_b6b" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Restaurants (roughly alphabetical)</unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref234_hzh" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Acapulco - Der Wienerschnitzel</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_cfc0b4c6a3dc108597c70a605ea545fa" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP17</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref235_qpv" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Ice Cream Shops</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_91673b8127502261973f68530db662a3" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP17</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref236_6ty" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Allenhurst - Zim's</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a909f80c0abf05c4c5efa069eefb6d6c" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP17</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref237_gqe" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Apparel, Apparel Stores and other Retail (roughly alphabetical; includes
                  some watches, cosmetics, electronics, shopping centers, and other department store
                  consumer goods purchases)</unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref238_a0d" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Anell's - Robinson's</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_db491c9f05f2f9678b210a9e9e81b69a" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP17</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref239_kmk" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLQ1621-SLQ2320</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_3d0e09791d9eff916d99f5b46f8f5204" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP18</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref240_47f" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Apparel, Apparel Stores, and other Retail <emph render="italic"
                    >continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref241_231" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Robinson's - Zayre</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_85d037ecb5fa65f1089f3a0e30603d51" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP18</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref242_1i3" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2c494b55d22df0284c986956b2f2a67a" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP18</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref243_3wm" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Footwear</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b1d9b799b2185bfdd44e7a15c52a7fdc" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP18</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref244_g5t" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_136edbb8eb66ac111d3098e25e378ee8" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP18</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref245_nxj" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Grocery Stores (roughly in alphabetical order)</unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref246_wqt" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>AG Stores - Winn Dixie</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c97f8d58f263ddb90376c30757532576" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP18</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref247_p4o" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Airlines (roughly in alphabetical order)</unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref248_etg" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Alaska Airlines - Western Airlines</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2c3e1b9d8354dad4acd4b4096b283136" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP18</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref249_y55" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLQ2321-SLQ2980</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_48b2b4a8df466962c38d1f030e69adc6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP19</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref250_5uc" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Airlines <emph render="italic">continued</emph></unittitle>
              </did>
              <c05 id="aspace_ref251_397" level="file">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Western Airlines - World Airways</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f8b0093831cf48aa7c97267d5690c8ee" label="Mixed Materials"
                    type="box">TP19</container>
                </did>
              </c05>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref252_kq6" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Transportation and Travel (Includes public transportation, bicycles,
                  mopeds, travel agencies, cruises, vacation destinations, commerce/convention
                  destinations, resorts, miscellaneous attractions, and shopping
                  centers)</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_ebc02f24573b796b49c7c71a2b80ad23" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP19</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref253_nws" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Hotels</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_5f22a5e850b30b7c95e756effdaa1501" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP19</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref254_p43" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Moving and Storage</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_44df48b487f1afbdcc93387c340829e9" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP19</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref255_x3n" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Utility Companies (often ads featuring appliances)</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_8d62d6f7081ee0f0b6a785c2b2b3af6f" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP19</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref256_3o5" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Heating and Air Conditioning</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_5584e70d0711fdad3da6aa0ceda7d28d" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP19</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref257_yuf" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Electronics and Appliances</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_08b12e19305a26c2102f51a53480089a" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP19</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref258_1eh" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Photographic Equipment</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_417e798bd77ec5c55235bd88c6f179e3" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP19</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref259_9td" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Laundry Detergent and Dry Cleaning</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_ce795affee46203e1cd468f8bd86b8a2" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP19</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref260_0gv" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Household Cleaners</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_56522bad8d9c5f15e8ee075ce11e2670" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP19</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref261_v8q" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Hosiery, Footwear, and Apparel</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_b5cb983cddfb8c1e4027593df821b610" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP19</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref262_f6t" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Florists</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_0c09ea4878c9cf46608eccf278e35a01" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP19</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref263_2k8" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>SLQ2981-SLQ3597</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_c8de7dcc82d7458bc48831ecd71d1d3d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP20</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref264_9sb" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Florists <emph render="italic">continued</emph></unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_ddd2c0b6ebec5f4c511f1c09c57711bb" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP20</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref265_0v5" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Construction and Home Improvement (Includes building materials, floor and
                  wall coverings, decorators, furniture stores, and mattresses)</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_fc5c72d7ea551762e2971aaec845b088" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP20</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref266_3qp" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Insurance</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_cd9bd2ca8877a6a11cd4fb46c9dbcf0d" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP20</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref267_ka5" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Lawn Care</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_692a5626d575d9342d6ad26b51119d7a" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP20</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref268_kn9" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Metals (Includes Aluminum, Steel Buildings)</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_99b587d4cd60f3690d23110cb97c1d82" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP20</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref269_fda" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Data Processing and Printers</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_a67e53079c915dc97f9140aa993a3dc9" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP20</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref270_5c2" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Paper Products (Includes napkins, tissues, wax paper, and toilet
                  tissue)</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_0c6be0df8e8266b6fe9360a2fa1f8abd" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP20</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref271_zuv" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Paint</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_38e0bc5fc54865be7eebe42769581ebe" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP20</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref272_zy2" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Plumbing</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_e02417de10eea00f355c815cab3a2d1f" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP20</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref273_zab" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Political Ads</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_baa71af0a9bb7927e88f260c404ad823" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP20</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref274_rtq" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Real Estate</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_c2c55268fe12ecb6ab854d1b7b2521af" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP20</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref275_yf4" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Campers</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_9c8528b7b1af8892454e9a946cf8d967" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP20</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref276_wjp" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Miscellaneous (Includes massage school, zippers, and trading
                  stamps)</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_da15dfea10437026cf4996af02ed453d" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP20</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref277_a50" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Yellow Pages</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_266dce1a4b512487c3e85eb81e86a960" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP20</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref279_ld9" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Subseries II</unittitle>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_caab29c005ff2a17905a7cf55f3f6c04">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>These slides were grouped into industry standard categories. Please see category
              descriptions at the end of this document to facilitate your search. Often, like
              materials are further grouped within these categories. For ads where identity of the
              product was unclear, a small <title type="simple" render="doublequote">Product
                Unclear</title> category was created at the end of this subseries. This subseries
              contains slide numbers with the following prefixes: SLS, SLT, SLU, SLV, SLW, SLX, SLY,
              SLZ, SLJ, SLK, and SLL.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref280_toe" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Apparel</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_6d993b4456b09638772936bdc2bcfed9" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP21</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref281_0v9" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLS0001-SLS0274</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_43b6da8c408ed3bf6a521f9fcecae0c1" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP21</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref282_dm5" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Retail</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref283_wrt" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLS0275-SLS0693</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_802b99ee12d95d4a7d30c0e385bc8259" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP21</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref284_bul" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Retail</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_37d794e969e1d6c70481f1401ce305a5" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP22</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref285_70r" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLS0694-SLS1353</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_885d797f4f92f4839608b8356e3309f3" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP22</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref286_bvf" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Retail</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_9ad516239a22200edf5cc0392ad29a04" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP23</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref287_4md" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLS1354-SLS1413</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_73ad8bc5395ceaf56839a67602c93a82" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP23</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref288_ul7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Retail / Apparel</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref289_ewy" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLS1414-SLS1649</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_49fc9f68353d54ed7d3dcecdc88b9aa0" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP23</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref290_g3a" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Business and Technology</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref291_qcd" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLT0001-SLT0280</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_92b84431baf10fde7ec0faa7d2af08c4" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP23</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref292_lhy" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Business and Technology</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_ba0449becaabbee8dc232b0b0ce1c6ea" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP24</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref293_x2v" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLT0281-SLT0980</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_76059b347fcfe743d65d34985a7c0081" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP24</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref294_zuq" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Business and Technology</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_c89f516df3f511bd9bb587b362648f89" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP25</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref295_qmo" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLT0981-SLT1640</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_3df7428f3479238582a7196f7b373e5f" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP25</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref296_hdy" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Business and Technology</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_1d593a8cb899e902e9f98816ed2eaaa2" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP26</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref297_1jf" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLT1641-SLT2340</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_2f6384cfc60e923fb811bd9cb0dca335" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP26</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref298_3bj" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Business and Technology</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_2f478fca9dbcd2493da78d0ece4f9e1d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP27</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref299_rl1" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLT2341-SLT2754</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_c79ae900a8787809568462b57c326aaa" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP27</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref300_ku3" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Amusement and Entertainment</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref301_f0n" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLU0001-SLU0140</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_e1d4ed861a1f44f68fe75704f035c3cb" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP27</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref302_kd3" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Amusement and Entertainment</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_9435a4d2b906b17e8ad1750d2e404ead" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP28</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref303_ckj" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLU0141-SLU0820</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_53c662d29835c1eb0415161c1ad6d7fa" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP28</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref304_ui1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Transportation and Travel</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_24888ca56dbf60eb9f62242bceb77156" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP29</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref305_rne" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLV0001-SLV0500</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_5e6fc0aadaf55dacbf76880b46b0bc63" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP29</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref306_lke" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Transportation and Travel</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_3ce9f184b59a4105553d6f5412bc58fb" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP30</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref307_n0f" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLV0501-SLV1200</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_e0aa6c1bea73478a5d71edd8f9b2040c" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP30</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref308_5gk" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Transportation and Travel</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_4b2d97a0e157b43caa7700b97dfe1f6b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP31</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref309_2cj" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLV1201-SLV1526</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_a937b1a74efb53461b8e5a2c15f0e689" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP31</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref310_p4j" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automotive</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref311_4uk" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLW0001-SLW0280</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_7942aa1f649254a0d87389651ad25b11" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP31</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref312_tgu" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automotive</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_41ff902846228faaa19a36c451bf6092" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP32</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref313_2bn" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLW0281-SLW0980</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_b1a7e11adda2a4a94f05674d9711ccca" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP32</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref314_702" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automotive</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_7e48555ed85f5b6a685b2ae9e7e675ae" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP33</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref315_8jj" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLW0981-SLW1620</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_6893f3bada54a85151e037049100923d" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP33</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref316_2w1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automotive</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_b9817531f724eecc387032f1eb67d36e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP34</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref317_44a" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLW1621-SLW1845</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_f085847dedc77157c5f40d70ad942b75" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP34</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref318_s2e" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Consumer Goods and Services</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref319_6nm" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLX0001-SLX0380</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_c5286d28782de9ceaf4e32ba893aa3bb" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP34</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref320_ipr" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Consumer Goods and Services</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_0cb0fece4fa34e4786de5d8a8a9241d5" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP35</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref321_6yp" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLX0381-SLX1020</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_0ffa9eb9634c98294b66bb040240183f" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP35</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref322_d48" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Consumer Goods and Services</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_d1d3c71659496340d24e1a70d28fed27" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP36</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref323_73m" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLX1021-SLX1660</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_a766bf309000f1927a08a909dec00e9e" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP36</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref324_718" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Consumer Goods and Services</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_60fd6b23c66350bf6b283ff50be4c0d8" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP37</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref325_00j" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLX1661-SLX2072</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_0082c30f558090a06231da4256766aad" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP37</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref326_dey" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Beverages</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref327_1sw" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLY0001-SLY0080</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_dd2dfb19ad4d7c3a2153c5ded10ceeee" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP37</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref328_1e3" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Beverages</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_dfcbe5ff24dd7b254a0020fd9ab9b14d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP38</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref329_c2d" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLY0081-SLY0560</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_5908eadd1f0e56dc2f5fa59f727dd140" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP38</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref330_1yq" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Beverages</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_3decb4262d8268a8bbd6aae822557e8a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP39</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref331_ph0" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLY0561-SLY1020</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_ff5ac2ad89fef2df95ae0fef5d22802a" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP39</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref332_09w" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Beverages</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_83878c259104c7c881d6e763e7a9d5bf" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP40</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref333_t5p" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLY1021-SLY1427</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_422c000b7de51a9ff4d0a7fa24098fb7" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP40</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref334_m8r" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Beverages</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_0ccbe330d5188328d3d3fa2dffb401c0" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP41</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref335_f42" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLY1428-SLY1947</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_6cd3a0314292f9148ba23db84582cf33" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP41</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref336_iym" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Beverages</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_2073b766f33ccc17846e276e5873fa4e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP42</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref337_o7n" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLY1948-SLY2467</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_5e6ca647acebd64b9d193d10d72e2094" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP42</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref338_wg7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Beverages</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_0b45374218544f2f262563d0c9ff7331" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP43</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref339_sn7" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLY2468-SLY2967</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_02777f56689481451868d40ca48cc13a" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP43</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref340_86u" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Beverages</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_9ec8db253983bcbc8ddbadeb9954cdf1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP44</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref341_7rk" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLY2968-SLY3332</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_33bb6e3990a5f03f67d4572f5d0bbf21" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP44</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref342_2zq" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food and Restaurants</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref343_bnw" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLZ0001-SLZ0100</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_0f6361a85738bd295af9a4a630ac4e69" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP44</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref344_wf0" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food and Restaurants</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_afb6e69ae11ee39b7c89ce0b137e6e5e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP45</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref345_d8g" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLZ0101-SLZ0720</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_abf33f8e8699ae95af8508da51e3fc4e" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP45</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref346_6vn" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food and Restaurants</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_63b0589a19c5e6a88522247891fee936" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP46</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref347_c6a" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLZ0721-SLZ1375</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_575d1e45dc79a771016bc5ce3c8eff40" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP46</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref348_3ie" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Public Service</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_f4a69794879614b7535bff8b68a619ae" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP47</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref349_jhy" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLJ0001-SLJ0544</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_9f73f5bbaa56d79d2f52d8b94ef1e663" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP47</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref350_jyt" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_fb5c7b17e449403cf646c86e090c453f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP48</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref351_491" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLK0001-SLK0660</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_0eb6dbd26dc3d896dbd2e285dbb819e4" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP48</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref352_lon" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_769adb5b12418829a4a43183faa54ff4" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">TP49</container>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref353_04v" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLK0661-SLK1113</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_a65af28b01c85633e490f2d3ac00208c" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP49</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref354_lpa" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Product Unclear</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04 id="aspace_ref355_bwo" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>SLL0001-SLL0117</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_788e16fc72a127eeb1de3c15f0826fe7" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">TP49</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref358_u9p" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>International Posters Series, 1925-1983, bulk mid-late 1960s, especially
            1969</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_01f980a653b15450eded62e32952f8a2">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>Presumably, some of the ads in this series ("SLM" slides) were submitted for an
            International category of the OBIE awards program, a category added in more recent
            years. They are often in a smaller poster format to accommodate larger pedestrian
            audiences abroad. Some products featured include alcoholic beverages, concerts, cheese,
            travel, London transportation, beverages, museum exhibitions, festivals, ice cream,
            newspapers, and the Moscow Olympics. The slides are arranged by slide number.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <altformavail id="aspace_e919bcd65d8da987384a4eaef9b57cfe">
          <head>Existence and Location of Copies note</head>
          <p>Some items from this series have been digitized and described in: <extref
              xlink:href="https://repository.duke.edu/dc/outdooradvertising">Resource of Outdoor
              Advertising Descriptions (ROAD)</extref></p>
        </altformavail>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref359_vvj" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>SLM0001-SLM0621</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_6cbf05b889b3f8433027b1dbcea553f9" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">TT1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref363_mzo" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Construction and Creation Series, 1950s-1980s and undated</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_0fa6cc4e54f89f337e751ec3aa19532c">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>This small series ("SLE" slides) provides perhaps the most context for the creative
            process. More than just the finished product, these slide images show ads at every stage
            of creation from idea boards to finishing touches. Most slides show images of people
            working on billboards, but there are also graphics showing billboard dimensions or
            various billboard types, photo images of workrooms, workers at worktables, workers with
            equipment doing actual construction, cranes hanging large billboard segments, photos of
            props used to put together an image, shots of billboards at various stages of
            completion, close shots of trim pieces, and more. The slides are arranged by slide
            number.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <altformavail id="aspace_c663ad4a8708129d155ed46caf8435b5">
          <head>Online Items</head>
          <p>Some items from this collection have been digitized and described in: <extref
              xlink:href="https://repository.duke.edu/dc/outdooradvertising">Resource of Outdoor
              Advertising Descriptions (ROAD)</extref></p>
        </altformavail>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref364_e62" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>SLE0001-SLE0135</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_6d6b144bb77ec6a7afeb414b8e2446fc" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">TT2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref367_bi0" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Artwork Series, 1956-1973 and undated</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_781cfe0d0b8e52cee2512d16ff82a13d">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>This series contains slide images of original artwork ("SLF" slides), usually not in
            any advertisement format. Artwork was sometimes submitted to OAAA as part of the OBIE
            Awards program. Many of these slides are labeled with the artist's name such as graphic
            artist and painter, Luis Gordillo. Other names found in this part of the collection
            include Eric Lanneau, Luis Perez Minguez, T. Mixta, Boix, A. Heras, E. Borduas, Robert
            Burns, F.C.B. Cadell, R. McG. Coventry, G.D. Davison, John Duncan, Crawhall, George
            Henry, J.W. Herald, Hornel, Leslie Hunter, W.Y. MacGregor, J.Q. Pringle, Claude Breeze,
            Ivan Eyre, Alex Coville, and Opura Benazon. Slides are arranged by slide number.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <altformavail id="aspace_6eeec62e9d11e20b6220b402d0237033">
          <head>Online Items</head>
          <p>Some items from this collection have been digitized and described in: <extref
              xlink:href="https://repository.duke.edu/dc/outdooradvertising">Resource of Outdoor
              Advertising Descriptions (ROAD)</extref></p>
        </altformavail>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref368_y9x" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>SLF0001-SLF0208</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_b3913015a1689a36252b7d3664bbe770" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">TT2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref371_o44" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Street Scenes and Approaches Series, 1930s-1980s and undated</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_22c5ab14b57bf332df27db2b7d226771">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>This series ("SLH" slides) contains slides with images of street scenes, often showing
            long approaches to billboard sites. There are examples of outdoor advertising present,
            but views are from a distance. These images were used in planning and preparation for
            construction or to show sites to prospective clients. This series reveals the most
            outdoor context of time and place for the advertising. While most shots in other series
            are close-ups of billboards, these photo images almost always show a wider scene. Slides
            are arranged by slide number.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref372_2i2" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>SLH0001-0131</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_6bfdca51f57921f925eb21e2dbcc7352" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">TT2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref374_lmc" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Other Outdoor Advertising Related Images Series, ca. 1910-1985 and
            undated</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_075eeb097eefaf59c794772b3428f104">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>This small series ("SLN" slides) contains slides with images that did not easily fit
            into other categories. It includes slides of the 1975 Miss America and other campaigns
            designed to test or prove how well people could remember information from the outdoor
            medium. Various pieces of art are included, as well as a mock-up of a <title
              type="simple" render="italic">Signs of the Times</title> publication cover;
            photographs related to a consumer survey; group portraits from industry meetings, some
            from as early as the 1910s; print advertisements; and portraits of advertising
            executives including Burr Robbins. Slides are arranged by slide number.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref375_f5i" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>SLN0001-SLN0091</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_832afa9fb0bf5166009272a22762bd11" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">TT2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref377_6dg" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Presentations and Presentation Slides Series, 1960s-1980s and
            undated</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_5a14713ae48b38ff03d7c4cd9fbed5ed">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>This series contains slides organized for individual presentations, several with
            scripts included. The presentations at the start of the series are the most complete. As
            the list continues, the presentations become less complete (e.g. lacking slides,
            transcripts, etc.), until only loose slides from presentations are present. The intact
            presentations at the start of the series were created for a variety of audiences by
            outdoor executives often as training devices or sales tools for prospective clients. A
            number of the presentations were put together by the Institute of Outdoor Advertising,
            the marketing arm of the industry. The scripts and slides provide a mix of information
            not found in other series, including an introduction to the medium, comparisons to other
            advertising media, and history of the industry.</p>
          <p>Included are some historical images from the early days of outdoor advertising, but the
            series mostly contains mid to late 20th century images including billboard construction;
            shots of the creative process; labeled charts indicating the standard billboard sizes;
            statistics on cost, reach, frequency, and readership; and much more information about
            the medium in general. Though not indexed in the <title type="simple" render="bold"
              >ROAD</title> database, there are many images of outdoor advertising used as examples
            in the presentations. Some slides relate to specific companies or campaigns such as
            Kraft, specific markets such as Birmingham, or certain product types such as insurance
            or magazines. Many of the loose slides are grouped into at least partial presentations.
            Three of the scripted presentations have audiocassette recordings included in box PR13.
            There are duplicate slides in some presentations and so presumably, many were created
            and used in various presentations according to the need at the time. For database
            control purposes, individual "SLB" numbers were assigned to whole presentations.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <altformavail id="aspace_072eb98844c20328ef79b1145fbd0b14">
          <head>Online Items</head>
          <p>Some items from this collection have been digitized and described in: <extref
              xlink:href="https://repository.duke.edu/dc/outdooradvertising">Resource of Outdoor
              Advertising Descriptions (ROAD)</extref></p>
        </altformavail>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref378_9dq" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Presentations:</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_2df9fbec8a0677685da103ff508fd416" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">PR1</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref379_qat" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Outdoor Goes to College (SLB0001)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_7a7e7a4056625de8270d85c40e6d1c4f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_9b395aeef2a2134a35b96da2f9bd851e">
              <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
              <p>Audio recording of script included in box PR13.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref381_3np" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>It Pays to be Creative (Institute of Outdoor Advertising [IOA])
                (SLB0002)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_211030baaaa2220d8b5d7fd0a94a8a24" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_4e94969a0ced8cd2a1365aaee87e62b0">
              <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
              <p>This presentation is aimed at new creative directors and discusses among other
                things what makes a good design and how to sell it. Audio recording of script
                included in box PR13.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref383_wtt" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media Insurance (IOA) (SLB0003)</unittitle>
              <physdesc id="aspace_4b77d6088fe046486f9d05cfef0db8df"
                label="General Physical Description note"><extent>3 folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_3d421a62ff2dd905422f1e3ab0b20825" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_8816d27251703073a7b6abbd388973d4">
              <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
              <p>This presentation seems designed to sell the medium to potential advertisers. Audio
                recording of script included in box PR13.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref386_2te" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Profiles of Outdoor Advertising Readers (Outdoor Advertising Incorporated
                [OAI]) (SLB0004)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_c80e503efc3cc77e67beba5db91da95f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref387_rmm" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Working Women (Donnelly Adv.) (SLB0005)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_d92c5c063fb3aceea09bb9addb086038" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref388_4om" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Be It Ever So Humble, There?s No Place Like Out-of-Home (IOA)
                (SLB0006)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_77db2094bb84a24746e6526a76552c03" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref389_v2f" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>A Presentation on Geometrics (Center for Advertising Services, 1976)
                (SLB0007)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_7c884166d59d8ad9cc6bb38545b12d31" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref390_cyk" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Dialogue Presentation (IOA) (SLB0008)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_af39a1358d38f5a49504a92ab66e5f63" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref391_fp7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>The Giant (IOA) (SLB0009)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_703a59019826402391bb967a2e3469bd" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref392_kg1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Outdoor for Retailers (SLB0010)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_91893d859318f01917d21a81575273cc" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref393_1zl" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Kraft (SLB0011)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_d36d995f15296cc876848af040008c0a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref394_9sb" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Common Sense (SLB0012)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_0dcb779aa4b0f18b99d6ba1ef0e6459b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref395_768" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>What?s New Under the Sun (SLB0013)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_641e8d3729c8f16f5b632156a20d517a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref396_8rf" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Miss America ( IOA, [1975?]) (SLB0014)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_76e85396b15b4c81bd4a2f5f044776bd" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR3</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_c11a01736f210faeeac0818cb78df781">
              <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
              <p>This presentation features slides of a campaign that tested awareness. The industry
                used ads with Miss America's name (Shirley Cothran) and subsequent testing as proof
                of outdoor advertising effectiveness.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref398_juw" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>IOA Membership (IOA) (SLB0015)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_c7a0d29dd754d15b3972748e7bff36f0" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref399_tqg" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Inflation (IOA) (SLB0016)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_4574edef5f19e86fc94cd55ffc35b803" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref400_6d8" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Target Group Index (SLB0017)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_ef60889bb33adba176de1477a34e3686" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref401_73g" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Best Painted Bulletin Displays - Master General Foods and duplicates (IOA)
                (SLB0018)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_fd5f336b0cc4d9a5c85820741582df28" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref402_9mr" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Cole Creative Presentation (SLB0019)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_e5161a493592aa9f4636dab38d848d40" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref403_qzy" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Garrett Orr Presentation (SLB0020)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_dba2e5550701591dc67801c16bcc0378" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref404_783" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Take a Look at Birmingham (SLB0021)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_77a9d10ae2ae4f584680a4c4016786b3" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref405_3qn" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Planning an Outdoor Program, Outdoor Seminar, Toronto, Ontario, 10/16/65
                (SLB0022)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_334a39d2a0591d9e92cf738eb9a61cb5" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref406_665" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Presentation to Food Market Institute, 3/25/78 (SLB0023)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_7eaf4baf31aa21ae84f6ccffc0dbf533" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref407_zer" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Outdoor for Passenger Cars (SLB0024)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_1a8f8f9933cdb57a8d35434b6e2d549d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref408_del" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Wall-Dog Era and Story of Outdoor Advertising (scripts only)
                (SLB0025)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_0261a064858813d913c4afbfd271ec0f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref409_i0m" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Various Presentations (SLB0026 and SLB0027)</unittitle>
              <physdesc id="aspace_d76af38d528016f8c2fb7e509f0209e8"
                label="General Physical Description note"><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_2ef0563092ff5b5e8fab183935f4d232" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref411_atc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous presentation slides</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_e95fb02f9361d7d6ba69946a8b953de3" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">PR5</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref412_94h" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous presentation slides</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_7b3f9a5da75012ec5d0839858f764cb2" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">PR6</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref413_4uj" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous presentation slides</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_480580c42af1f12fd6eb09f5a4265dc8" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">PR7</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref414_2xz" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous presentation slides</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_84e89a0a09490ed3034e76896ab9e6e3" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">PR8</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref415_4a0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous presentation slides</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_de3332afe8e838f52bc6a2b122eb5c2c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">PR9</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref416_3di" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous presentation slides</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_cd2e0d7881ae55ac9e4e50755f737ef0" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">PR10</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref417_zyb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous presentation slides</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_979c595cb5acdb0f6dcb3d2a87c6d615" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">PR11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref418_49w" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Glass Presentation Slides</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_95edf3c7c4ef3904c8beecd4c1441cf4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">PR12</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_5947789dda654ed0d8f74f5a0dbbbdeb">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>These slides are encased in glass. Most appear to be a part of a presentation by
              Outdoor Advertising Incorporated including images of ads for 7-Up and Budweiser
              (Anheuser Busch). There is also a wide variety of street signs, spectaculars, and
              other signs.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref420_6lg" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Presentation Scripts on Audiocassette (master and use copies):</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_2a6c5518e9996e0063f211091342fffc" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">PR13</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref421_hfy" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Outdoor Goes to College</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_f03b6a884d379fb926b6e92801cbbbc0" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR13</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref422_a0s" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>It Pays to be Creative, F and K (IOA)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_9a4684adfc957f3e078675d86153ce9a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR13</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref423_7oc" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media Insurance, F and K (IOA)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_58562e418acdd796374717963a326895" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">PR13</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_bc8d9953a3347f08f13538d285029434" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Additions Run 1</unittitle>
          <unitid>1</unitid>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1960-2000 and undated</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_133733685239a47770af022bf43498f5" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Awards</unittitle>
            <unitid>1</unitid>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1986-2000</unitdate>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_b243c14e2f8eb79e1fc78d3095b84011" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Merit winners</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1999</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_199d269c405784b0970b01755e854553" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_e01f05667386d846abc72fe33e705a20" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1986 Obies</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1986</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d74c544192f60714e8054da676042f1f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_c253feb849ef0999984c09d7c8631696" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1990 Obie finalists</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1990</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_b8d88e3253d89b2f44c7f83515616773">4 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_da632a379c0d5ed7a5fdbe95c8958002" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_f46d348e0f51dd1b4765f216e1f4204b" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1994-1995 Obies</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1994-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_34b6fc98b4c161babb2b8ad3b33e3e0a">5 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_1d49403453fb332e7a2faff70d996977" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_4856ff23db9b80c7e866b4df3e97a1f6" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1994-1995 Obies</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1994-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_6ef7d978b3012d6d20459179975b0593">7 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_bfc8ab8e0e3328c849516929c5cc903b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_2c3fdab620d813c559d71d121e625b6c" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1995 Obies--Ballots</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1995</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_20c7231cff10c4af1cd08cc265faf89e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_fd8228c4af2c3a011430856aa7cfd4f1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1995 Obies--Entries (forms)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1995</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_ca90ebd99895d96bdd467e8f1117d891" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_e8c5106cd7802f7c4f86b9fa20a69a5f" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1995 Obies--Entries (forms)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_0469c7b960d8d803e8e36f586c2c54fb">20 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_9542f9a653813407e92eb8d13f633ee6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ad846781fde8d15906ff77d8901188ec" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1995 Obies--Finalists</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1995</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_2202f1ce85e5835ef8bd606ae9b4bec4" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a7ede75b59202269e8702d294d442d32" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1995 Obies--Winners</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_4c32d2c8453b6527d02a900f1c5f7f65">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_65ce718e833200497899c88c129c7d7a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_dabab7f080b52921ccd532deab57e5fe" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1996 Obies--Entries--Campaign</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1996</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_62b492827fc4a24d98e5676a11cb6a5f">6 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_1812e85f317682db22798659fdedadf6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a00fa513674cbf642ebd75ff5dbc8f95" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1996 Obies--Entries--Campaign</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1996</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_a51595b8ab408c1fc11870bcdf29d05f">6 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_f88c01c58e46402b7b7e707eb13df239" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD5</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_8079563a5be0ec15dcfc3a59f32b51b3" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1996 Obies--Entries--Single execution</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1996</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_9c65946ed4323f9243e3388389b6c899">6 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_b69408f05a175873a44cafabf20ae3cc" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD5</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_90bfd77e00cc84eea3b25ba41508fee9" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1996 Obies--Entries--Single execution</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1996</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_9da7121bb259d63141a52a7b62dbbd77">11 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_ee2e075ed039b4ef14c45457db8b0e97" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD6</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_8dc0d78c87ebcd06edcd5b49b7fd195e" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1996 Obies--Entries--Sample entry forms</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1996</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_310939943802f9205ff85b82af7e5326" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD6</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_11f7bd2f4be4cd4c472968ff96a67198" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1996 Obies--Finalists</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1996</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_1f2190553e51bd4d50c011c8edcef0fb">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_0e7d90e8ed2822717dd136569ec08a2a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD6</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_db67331667805e8497fe53bdf47dafcd" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1996 Obies--Finalists</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1996</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_d7fbde7062b5d582ab3ee311ac7a2743">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_f6508711c06357ac372be3d5ff285eb4" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD7</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_4a9e35863910ea16a0234f27fbeef959" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1997 Obies--Entries--International Out-of-Home</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1997</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_80d7a5b6873463d992923f9be4824471">4 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_508ee71560157f648c349ce26ef7e139" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD7</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_eec8109694247fb2f3376073bc52d394" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1997 Obies--Finalists</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1997</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_ee385891efcd815538dc00eb9a6454d1">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_b2480688dfae145f95c92ed4b6e9e88d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD7</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a769fc00c9598c50780c40cf42ff6fa3" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1997 Obies--Miscellaneous slides</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1997</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_f68c48e3bfc4c922a2b0f69f93a7e98a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD7</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_df96947fbb81d1726c2e505bd1394b2a" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1998 Obies--Entries--International Out-of-Home</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1998</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_b67c09f53dac4a6e64d6d179a451c207">13 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_0e2c08efdc4df45054130da7dc314730" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD8</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_7a12fed421c86694995ced472e725b77" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1998 Obies--Finalists</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1998</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_20228e567aa652c8633010f6c870462a">4 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_2614c46345d9438521baa8cce20e82f2" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD9</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d7e704dfc74734ea5f0bd4e513b2dbdf" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1998 Obies--Hall of Fame (Levi's)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1998</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_873ee2b15fd1b4b0388bac077c7c96d1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD9</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_6a82fb06eafe621d7e3a1180595683e4" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1998 Obies--Winners (plus Ad Age Best)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1998</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_98b5bcfbc8ea6f4f41bc52005d314f01" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD9</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_4b94078ec8b7dc9586b36cbd5b135798" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1998 Obies--Winners and finalists</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1998</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_7402e9c82ce69eb81563f27344f2b96b">5 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_1c5cf23b8a0d81fd90461ef289724b81" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD9</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_9a6557a47e46dfc4c1b444c89af50c41" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1999 Obies--0001 through 0567</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1999</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_ad6394028f823678c89f6913107005c7">8 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_ec15136fbc1096b00d72e3b4af9f5173" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_367833247122febd75087f742ce865f9" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1999 Obies--0568 through 1118</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1999</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_8c8944c8fe9f2fae28764365d465aabe">9 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_329878c45c5c9783b98bc17943386583" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_86ea06e38cd79725818f9d841237da93" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1999 Obies--Winners</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1999</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_40b5d82e7b589bb6cc5e838b563a88a0" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_1ac8c0b8b42ba46f648b0760eacde0a4" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>2000 Obies--0001 through 0492</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">2000</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_9b7011087aad197753876a2abb0a6071">10 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_d7019f7c839257344e81b8f771872828" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD12</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a1b0914da3be171e9b223ffecf5ce173" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>2000 Obies--0493 through 1026</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">2000</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_aaddd7d60bb6d6793efd5f26e688fbc5">12 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_e847c9381ce7265020d99c588312bdc1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD13</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_00eefe49aa760d9cbd3848d8af89c68a" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Other finalists</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1999</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_4880927bde1f4f476e6af33959ba8063" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD13</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_94dcec2b40f7f6f85d2bbc6e9f6eebfe" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Presentations and curated slide collections</unittitle>
            <unitid>2</unitid>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1970-1997 and undated</unitdate>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_34d67abb4496f2e108df741113e21068" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Brand Building (text and slides)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1997</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_f6e6288a6931c33735c1e24fe5c3763a">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_17823978017a562364ac3bfcba9f36a0" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_6b0fe87ce9196a6fa01eae563e56dc0a" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>The Competitive Edge</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_3c524d64d395264cb4f93295136b6976" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_7b2c9b1dde9b81ffd1ac5fc4725a2deb" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Cosmetics</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_481f33854428d86398bf0486329bc270" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_62be02d478628056ee529d07f4929224" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Curated slides</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_50f260afe49c6f30fd7a7c76848bdda7">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_ec8ac47b225c5425aa5ee2ff357c8031" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD14</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_28810d4031d302d7595068544be33508">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>[Business, Media, Fashion, Beverages, OAAA, Consumer goods, International,
                Automotive, Entertainment, Travel, Public Service]</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_9f2638f87322f13a8f464dadaa3dd49a" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>ESOA</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_2e0be53c7d6f1c16db66af77a2125f90" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a2d94ba4118648a99cc294f72e1c46f1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>"Fleege" [Robert A. Fleege and Partners?]</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_ea3903e45c607de1bd318a7c81e720f7" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_22ad79435d07b5416f78f1b263130276" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Historical Outdoor Creative 1800-1970</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1970</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_7f1706110f89f871c671a52609b3d2d2">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_b29f52978e31d389078378d8f64d3740" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_555daa086acdd1fd58bb3081144c9a95" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Mixed Media Marriages II</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_bfa9cb2e28153c0a0f167c0651ee9d61" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ba7ea770480cb1af72bbd2557ad05a17" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Outdoor Goes to College</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_de22a73555b48e0d901ad3d574f498c3" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_113dc79dbbcbf1694d1a0e286d84baee" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Retail</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_3679a2d3fed8a7aaacf0561398846b31" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d6f777c6812243d4e14a0975fa86e549" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Scenic outdoor slides</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_abf0976d87d6938a6c5d60263c59c5bb" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_f9f330d75ab78e208c96e173055f5c27" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Slides for Nancy Odenthal (OAAA Creative Library)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_c6f4cb9ae47058979a6564acc2917348" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_6b2963a45989793a8152d1e76e51a851" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>T4 Fashion; T5 Healthcare</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_e9e12b9f019a23d1006580caa3db3671" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_b2799eae593f8a124346298a3ff470f7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>T6 Media</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_3824a5780ff9b6e8919f58158857de08" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_fbc425f923bb353565580dbb1ffa1898" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>T7 Restaurants; T8 Travel</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_5697c55d783d207702af4bf113613cc8" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_302c194f375e33973f9a5767b37cab24" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>T9 International English; T10 Public Service; T11 International
                non-English</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_c3116db4a9de7189b674b85807ac1fbd" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a0387c8b6fb4ee7cbfe04d72651bf094" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous slides, mostly Eller</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_7534ede208df95fe0c3d46ff9e0a1ed1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_80ed7a0f5848f6e07e57c2eb20a43be7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous presentation slides</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_4714a39151354a47d9a9df21a6e02567">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_24a2001585086799bce35a3f58028b45" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_806f2f69b455dbd076ba288093ec0366" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Product categories</unittitle>
            <unitid>3</unitid>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1974-1996</unitdate>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_97d8693c754f6e9686e8e8d5ad15b0d8" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Apparel and accessories</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1983-1995</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_20f3ad244b0cc9a0db744942cba570e0" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a747fb429dbb0d23b2ae885ad3d3b313" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Apparel and accessories</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1983-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_ec28f4014944caec6a65682760fe3cd6">8 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_9f383ecf95d5b64511c49c055e03cdab" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD16</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_e2052f2c2ec22bf7c02124c8333bbf6c" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Apparel and accessories--Apparel NEC-Berlei</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_42ed37cc67a961c586bebec304e55d7f">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_fd502c6cdb5ad0940cfe6b34fc590719" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD16</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d1c6d4fc68651e8ccd8738b942a3e902" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Apparel and accessories--Camp Beverly Hills-Gap</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-1993</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_0bbe6338a9cb1c3b9e61aaa67c6a0975" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD17</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_9d1fd09dd5a9c026d5ad8177538a5a4e" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automotive--Notebook 1: American</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1994-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_9990313704d30ef9e924fc729d2c3198">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_c575435a8c50c040bb34df237525b933" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD17</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_426535a0fdd968baee9d7c4c9f2e4e08" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automotive--Notebook 2: T110-T117</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1983-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_57e047744e3d14fef57a6c9765116a5b">5 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_7f9960fa6ab7f42b6f7994bb35200f9d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD17</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ae3954ad3a1980f74b56466bcc3a81fb" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automotive--Notebook 3: T114-T131</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1993</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_2af86561b5453f935a6df0dad0a001af">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_764f224d56a708cce335c0a31c24de31" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD17</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_abb1b6bde66dd061574b995e02fe3434" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automotive--Notebook 3: T114-T131</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1993</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_f40101ba6d1fecf59b842100ee6924eb">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_b3b391f5b0214bd4e91860a3f1d1248e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD18</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_9f33d632b951f97a951392c0d49059da" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automotive--Notebook 4: T117-T151</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_de8bfcef2b2a3cf446e0f8cce4b3f634">5 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_4a14fce5700cdb4bb705068ee522a8e3" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD18</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_c0741f391e3a5899dc48c14456cec538" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automotive--Notebook 5: Acura to Dodge</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1987</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_792f196137f5f11ec52f5e1318f1a26d">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_1237a6a7563323ead455d9610a467da4" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD18</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_23278193462eaf87eb1663992e58b5a4" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automotive--Notebook 5: Dodge to Lexus</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1980-1993</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_a6ea02537122cf6b4a9219c9ed0e09e5">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_2a8cbc4bbc201865d4b7b6dad815aef0" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD19</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_0316a3b54abddae73f21faf6e47bcdab" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Business/Finance--Notebook 1: B430-B450</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-1996</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_24736d5933f4f496dfe146be6f5286b7">5 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_9d16989d87b23216e30a1501ce50434e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD19</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_0b5700dbf9d651711abab734dbfae4c5" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Business/Finance--Notebook 2: B120 (Financial products and
                services)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-1996</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_ca90a0131f6ea6e567bc41bfab8cc480">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_2e8030a8652cc7cdd4f8ae0ed7aab383" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD19</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_da5058e073749b730bcb7ee48f2cf446" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Business/Finance--Notebook 2: B120 (Financial products and
                services)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-1996</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_b53818085bae78e7f7f86d885bde54c5">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_135af0c5ffe830df9cab2e09d390a9ab" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD20</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_c81c461590743c8bc01cb9f94b251e8b" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Communications</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1994-1995</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_4f0b0e5882ba8026e50c8807d3221a77" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD20</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_09b5e768d49fd268045686b920bae97f" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Drugs, toiletries and fitness</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1984-1994</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_754cc16c566f704a07fd47ab0159ead2">4 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_611566d6416fa872a451864d6895a6d3" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD20</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_149bcd42f7ca16243c6200339b97ca0a" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Education: Schools, camps, seminars</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1986-1993</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_502e264bee05c195b1997439344403a4" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD20</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ae4906af88db9c871fe891979a338f03" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Entertainment and amusement: Notebook 1: Motion pictures</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1989-1996</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_66da2065050857b904e6cf3331d3b9d8">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_7a32dbe60e375cde7e257ef2cb0bcf4f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD21</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_88a78c98562ea91c8686999446187f06" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Entertainment and amusement: Notebook 2: Zoos, museums, participatory,
                sporting events</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1983-1996</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_381777530d751030072ec48c434f4c5f">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_568bc39fb69bd2b0542d9d11bdcbfc3f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD21</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_2da51a3fc81b9dcbf52af303e845ec96" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Entertainment and amusement: Notebook 3: Zoos, museums, participatory,
                sporting events</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1986-1996</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_b66e9303dc4e8ab7f3a3cb343f9040e7">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_0ed04c195c7ef3eeaafd720f3b0de028" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD21</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_f4f873bc5f62812cae09390ae3d03789" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Entertainment and amusement: Notebook 3: Zoos, museums, participatory,
                sporting events</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1986-1996</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_0b7b607e539529e3bc52cf847b3ac365" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD22</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_9866d7f6990d68bf7c0ef8f161387e9e" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Entertainment and amusement: Notebook 4: Zoos, museums, participatory,
                sporting events</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1983-1993</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_83c646299df8f94b87de2393a9ac3d03">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_46a825dfff51431f68c9a3b9c86b5f49" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD22</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_247bd47e2510440c2cb7218a0f672091" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Entertainment and amusement: Notebook 5: Zoos, museums, participatory,
                sporting events</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1983-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_cc5611802a958f10c6ca14d83447a4a9">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_d27d94ad23455d595e169d7d9b2edf49" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD22</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a0a64e420e1f1d7bbb8418b18b6beef8" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Fast Food</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1987-1996</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_72d41e43176091c80a4f0e0a9c5139c9">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_e1bbd7612f1b8f3422da5479d602120e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD22</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_5632948386d1940f0ec289b0b94563cd" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Fast Food</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1987-1996</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_6de8e383faeb13415a08e8dd99d1075a">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_62400686ccd358a59802a3f2e8966d08" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD23</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_81f8d8bdf25bc8bc3d0a1151e1df9ee4" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food and beverages--Alcoholic</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1993</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_cff44987d66396fd8bc5783cb406d353">6 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_86ac0d975fcc1926a08389b26a8697c6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD23</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_fa0ecfbec7699fc2b9970941cc051f66" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food and beverages--Notebook 1: Beer and ale</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-1993</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_2a8461432d9457fd1f88085140b61dd1">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_b8663cf0f4b34c747485de4291cf7275" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD23</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_41e039f5a8b40cfad018ccacf98ec8b8" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food and beverages--Notebook 1: Beer and ale, vodka</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-1993</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_55c3031c72628c26abf88ac55d0d120d">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_a137e285a222c2e8912094f326226b90" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD24</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_14efd4ce444847bf9e725296f10d0f81" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food and beverages--Notebook 2: Coffee, tea, fruit drinks, carbonated
                drinks</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1993</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_504df814b82e8f165ed34639db372bb6">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_c700439a48444b371e034f9ffc84ea94" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD24</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_8a661f5f4da3a0f1af5c5f6dfa6498ee" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food and beverages--Notebook 3: Coffee, tea, fruit drinks, carbonated
                drinks, bottled water</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1986-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_370bc5a0d46d2e18a1d7b7330475f504">4 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_e385198e875d667358b0d9f1eac92dcb" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD24</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_6b0173d968b080baf09e843b38bb37b6" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food and beverages--Notebook 1: F600-F720, Beer and ale,
                whiskey</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1982-1994</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_ca7afa05715f89ba4c3a29792b1ef41b">5 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_17cc7567fcacbb0ca5aa4d76218e8a6c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD25</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_0aabf073c1fd5f165fa584d70c8ce315" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food and beverages--Notebook 2: F610, Beer and ale, alcoholic
                beverages</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1984-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_2640e3c1ea42cac4903d6dd1a541cd38">4 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_685b7a23d1cce1e01bfdb53b10154e01" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD25</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_15aecfeca5e8a5626842e950236c8380" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food and beverages--Notebook 2: F610, Beer and ale, alcoholic
                beverages</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1984-1995</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_e653dd0f5dfc797e7ea672c04a3ba5e5" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD26</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_66f75d655c3618d8cd3f6861104bf908" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food products--Notebook 1</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1984-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_222c51c94dd871f6151977910e076ff2">5 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_729105bb0e47466b64059c6c4d67a811" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD26</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_e0dad1e98ffc621a1b3261208ba4ad75" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food products--Notebook 2</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1983-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_edf2045b16252602bd89d398255b4d3b">4 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_6dbcba544223b726b90480852fa4b119" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD26</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_589e738708f908d59caa71a6b769a439" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food products--Notebook 2</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1983-1995</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_825088ec2a12583d43247b090ad1d83c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD27</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_4f848b9110f28a16587749e6a68763b1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food products--Notebook 1: Candy, snacks, soft drinks</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-1993</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_b399fc36dc808db6675bbc8bf853aa15">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_4eb291313b55ca7165a3799ea85a78b7" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD27</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_c4f08b059eb7214a2ca39ec217b88a39" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Food products--Notebook 1: F120-F340</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1992</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_a30ab693d83e87aa7c28af842201974e">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_1622115f27bbaec0d09a4023c717db9e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD27</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_b2650fbbc1c914954ee15641eac4899e" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>General consumer goods--Sporting goods, ski equipment, pet
                supplies</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1976-1991</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_6b61958dcb9bf3c274bc173068800b5e">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_feb06c80519ceca4d8f0a9bab9c073c0" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD27</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_9da182fcba9e769f1c6bc39a49cefb29" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Healthcare</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1986-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_537e4e704d2136721e548e9a2567398e">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_479dc5d182c3f17ed37f488cce541bee" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD27</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_9663a5966e95569351737c0ba842e98d" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Healthcare</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1986-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_e0b8e79a40e862108240d3da209782df">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_c1dbd9f615f6ee57f1a27f2e0d65a8f7" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD28</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_de2cefe24ec4239529375165c6ea3fc1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Notebook 1: Television, cable, radio</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1990</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_98e47559fafe1139091129801dba7a28">5 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_006e22118a37c0af28832810e44399fa" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD28</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_33ace0dc746bded5b099c566f7209dd2" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Notebook 2: Television, cable, radio</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1989-1994</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_b2eccb2eb41cb186f892a8a17e939dbe">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_50d515d32daec4234f947c10ee33b41c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD28</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_14f8e21098981cea60beceee94ff0bbc" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Notebook 2: Television, cable, radio</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1989-1994</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_37df0be3e7a2c983b06bf189093d095e">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_e4c189d3b20ab66da617b060183d8212" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD29</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_e6f05da6afeab534f46f7a7c99cd1833" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Notebook 3: Print media (except books), radio</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1989-1994</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_fff569aff616d1b8f82436c04863cb4a">7 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_f3d10d94bdef1aa2c65ac97f2e45dfd8" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD29</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_911d241834c8a753a42127959531d5c3" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Notebook 4: Print media (except books), radio,
                television</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1984-1995</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_3791dd1e80499e4d3ff65c14beb1769c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD29</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a9c095830dd14b98b988899ed797bcd2" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Notebook 4: Print media (except books), radio,
                television</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1984-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_4dd042f00bf3ac85940b20283e07a5b9">5 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_eb31eb3ba94d902a0670f6874ecc0581" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD30</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_8091784435689565adf5ce44e20e745d" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Restaurants--G300-G320</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1982-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_fb4a9407cce175bb62ab12cc9e3c4841">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_bd4554f8737b6dbec0f424a7caf8718a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD30</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ab008408cbdb2313f9a8851e400fc406" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Restaurants--G300-G320</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1988</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_b818a62dda623e9f63bc3a98649f206b">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_78bf228a8c15f9aac6e3e6a6f815781e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD30</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_fa41742fbed1449d76a7e0c1bfa14ddf" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Restaurants--G300-G320</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1988</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_e39cd6b2098df3c533647ebd32e05b1b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD31</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_0c188eb10bed56d9b164a7a22f1fb686" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Retail stores--Notebook 1: Apparel, jewelry, department</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1993</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_d3f0a66d1648da48865228cf0e0f49bf">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_132426035414658c101777c5734fbd43" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD31</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_5748d1d6f50110d2b9fed9cd252d6fd0" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Retail stores--Notebook 2: Apparel and department, Robinson's</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-1986</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_12f495bf02660845c6655eca26941d91">5 folderss</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_28f792b4683a18c5ebf2266211fe98c8" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD31</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a7bdd00de3cc4962084c3ca6487c7b9b" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Retail stores: Department stores--Notebook 1: V410
                apparel-department</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1986-1994</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_cda073d689d197e35bdbe6eb9482131f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD31</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_df782c58f705351b48758ae1d11b2b12" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Retail stores: Department stores--Notebook 1: V410
                apparel-department</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1986-1994</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_4a9362e9e5bd80359c733f38b728c355">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_429a297827423c85cbca4b6e882fb9c6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD32</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ac31d07aa06b181f601d66ff015b6df6" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Retail stores: Department stores--Notebook 1: miiscellaneous-department;
                V540 food and beverage</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-1994</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_0c2a67cc95a1228e4e44c2b8a6d1a268">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_c62518dfc7c75d633329e0652d00a164" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD32</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_bef7fbbf291a67afc3aaa19cb31646ad" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Retail stores--Notebook 1: V410-V620: stores and shopping malls</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1982-1992</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_a4d17b6b5eeec29c338ce1770325c5c6">4 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_d255054edf89dcb0080946fa47e5d37a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD32</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ffd1d81fe968735503af05a606f3b989" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Retail stores--Notebook 1: V341-V620: stores and shopping malls</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1982-1992</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_d06b44c67f031e3edcff44012ff17867">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_5b12e05d2ce07efacb8eeacab309d18a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD33</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_26947b2077202f811c55cb16014facef" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Tobacco: cigarettes, tobacco and smoking accessories</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-1994</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_90a7acab8a00485d07670656653f63a3">4 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_8b7b9e4370faf34159cc1388775e4a53" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD33</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_0dda6a3e818b5ab95f34ae699bf9d849" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Transportation and travel--Notebook 1: Airlines, public
                transportation</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1974-1993</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_6f0d95e32da4836befd27a1d93b4ae5d">4 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_0a9542af67a7e2529103f607eb8c32ed" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD33</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_3bf8709f33fada28fccd8ce8a8b0d4a8" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Transportation and travel--Notebook 1: Public transportation, resorts,
                travel accomodations</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1974-1993</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_f4e0be14ad94aa1da0b3685c8720acdc" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD34</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_dc6c4ce5ab27eb568ed0dd8145561ee5" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Transportation and travel--Notebook 2: Public transportation, resorts,
                travel accomodations</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1984-1994</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_62276a4b7580027be8a7e12c92cf62a4">5 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_9418a85a2c284acb0166794185f8c2c4" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD34</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_94e3bdb447da47f96c74c4f2025e515f" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Transportation and travel--Notebook 1: T420-T430; resorts, travel
                accomodations</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1982-1993</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_e43db1a85bf6dd8803ec1c25d3470ea2">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_482998f67d158583a4092cf81edac9c9" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD34</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_f2836e50ebd16e405d182ea3a9be04fe" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Transportation and travel--Notebook 1: T420-T430; resorts, travel
                accomodations</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1982-1993</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_15e3c67f52874bf666932bf204e0f9f8">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_d3f9586a9f2834ea8dd8fb6edce8447c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD35</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_5916c9f1390841525d27eb8c4309caa7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Unsorted and duplicate slides</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1980-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_83400f42c48a0af353c720816e935c99">8 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_64732e8a5080ce5f4c0bac84a633671f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD35</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_2d8cc0edd332968ab1215816889e2aa0" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Unsorted and duplicate slides</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1980-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_4ce276e5de54cd310cda7b35e6fefcb8">13 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_6d4092d14838a2a767bb68df4ee5de65" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD36</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_1ff3a616fbbe14650fdef92b554e47ed" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Unsorted and duplicate slides</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1980-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_4b47b31556141c8db976462c05e3de94">11 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_a8cc4219e5e445f2afa6a4e3aaa19353" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD37</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d33bca90f693479ebd7dfca5d9760828" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Unsorted and duplicate slides</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1980-1995</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_81f3169115bbcebdfa1ea2619f28f480">4 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_d2826f304a8e665bfb565a0f01f23a4c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD38</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ece0b0033568cd2e4d859745cc25b3a0" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Eller Media/Foster &amp; Kleiser Slides</unittitle>
            <unitid>4</unitid>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1960-1986</unitdate>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_fafbb65d2f66d988e657f0bb90d32029" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1986</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_8ad0907120f13dc84adeda8968ae63b3">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_ec64083f626eec191fc976d2e9c94f09" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_04e865668afd1a3544dea070aaeddd7a" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Audi</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1983</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_5b8e677fa4d334efccbbd2bdab9a7a9a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_8adfa49a1b8e6c186eb547dbd9603b02" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Buick</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1970-1981</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_8819839b590c501685c53fd0abdeb389">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_16710a2776ad8674f056f5a1cbc8d81f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_73e45c4feed68e1e78ac36f3480b03af" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Cadillac</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1975</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d0490b90470094220e2ec5efe5a9a1b8" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_68ad5e4bc4e06927eb02f6de3d9f2991" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Chevrolet</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1970-1983</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_0ba50917cc6c02cec840aa787bfba957">4 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_17013b7725c217ab106d272d87d40139" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_3305829f25371b1334caeaa8bebe6a01" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Chrysler/Dodge/Plymouth</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1970-1984</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_ad9d29e90029ad2174b218598ead2b8e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_648a4c4563d06a2b1a1b885b7f9ec8ba" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Datsun/Nissan</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1984</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_f0bb037636aecab9337a0336c8d39964" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_0183ab78799461a655a79b2c4d7f6530" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Ford</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1973-1986</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_d6db84a16b8ed4af3de3efe3440e0a63">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_24367c732ff05b443c8c5f736e859f36" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_4cbff28c7a80e1bbbc1989c9a2cbff09" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Honda</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1974-1983</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_b6d3f11ce4286382d465388b6ee8428d">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_d67e9d446fe77a7174b904fadc6ce878" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_e7c4cf5b03e6e152b3559bb2fafdeb89" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Jaguar</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1981-1984</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_e1313d85e0be9168f18c236cbd68aee3" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_348eba4e4af2638aa1955f50def83467" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Lincoln-Mercury</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1980-1983</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_0dcfc0867c30c8afc562a744208ff933" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_1a3facac1c0420bdd68fa2a13d85698e" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Mazda</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1983</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d3a9c4e1abc12b06907e5823d888f903" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_f59032a3d736c965289a9330a84a906d" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Peugeot, Renault</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1972-1978</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_8ead2621376bc1a32e33a286f8b6f9aa" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_c6e4aa9daa96af0b276d25e17b85c258" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Pontiac</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1976-1977</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_a980d47d84a7da9b45104fdc4dd98718" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_341f0851602d4821f34e712dfda71f82" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Subaru, Suzuki</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1985</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_bed3d6237b0d891c126757f326abdf65" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_71b565f903213f2bd507dc64a13766ee" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Toyota</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1970-1985</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d772c95fe7811eba12a4406a94dfb07f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_aeb9054f4fcff79a1abe19948e8dc096" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Volkswagen</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1984</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_a8e8fec9a13bb13878692d0eeedd4721">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_907e084d2cc46cf304261b113df86db4" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_b56a158b73db99ccd3209772aa6fd5f9" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Dealerships</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1968-1984</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_ba1cdd94f3f18ffacad000ca6ba72a99">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_0f58e48d489e35ca0e014dffa90f0eec" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_8dd16f6fc34dea152b2bf68bd69d3e15" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Oil and Gas</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1965-1974</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_a36d3f1cbcd197a7f065e0dff00ab387" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_c3644f37d6957b62b74be63f0682d74b" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Oil and Gas--Chevron/Standard</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1962-1969</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_f2e668c59bfb4df6d6f4d185f5103a38" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_c09139c5798808638869d12dd73f105f" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Oil and Gas--Douglas</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1966-1967</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_24e0fed3f180d9c72c4302172b3d747d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_763a7e8e257e122d8394dd4b50cb0db8" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Oil and Gas--Enco/Exxon</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1972</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_259676b392706d7fb895d33673921d8e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_3dbaf3ac2b29334f8cf966eab95b662c" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Oil and Gas--Gulf</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1972</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_9ec9d3f7ca326244507f50cb4bcc236c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_0b9cbd019b8e821b5b7d3375b0785aa5" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Oil and Gas--Texaco</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1970</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_484d19c52728f14338640a98a574f1f0" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_31ecfa80f6ac14257495c0455c7e61ed" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Oil and Gas--Union 76</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1963-1969</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_62b889a962971d085afe0864941fa427" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ce853d7668af773cff32bf1fc42b6f12" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Parts and Supplies</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1986</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_e608263572548b33a27020d96a27b0c3" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a86fed17fe2a8d29a76adfdbceea47a1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Automobiles--Trucks and Motorcycles</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1984</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_928ad31a8b27178a7ac307002b27ccda" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_bef534bbeaff295d844437e1401c0c95" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Banks and Savings &amp; Loan</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1982</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_1a9fc7a1d4fe8b014366f6b572c38bda">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_e596832c811075c4a5c4ff1e2bb28fd7" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_66998cffb483484b1909964dedff2a16" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Banks and Savings &amp; Loan--Union Bank</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1961-1977</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_ba9305793f9d559c6e68efd79c08b215" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_9c511a2ca0332acd5e56cd44192fa132" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Banks and Savings &amp; Loan--Wells Fargo</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1965-1971</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_de014a38e1c89a3029ea174a8c4f58ce" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_5dee6b9be6ef625d58660256fed0eb00" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Beverages</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1972-1979</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_ec9594410160b311f97352bfcaac2fd1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_e8efc90c565ca4cc14412a74b7510f96" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Beverages--Beer</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_c4d0c7991d1b9229a71fe5c85971943a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_3f99647e126458eb861815d87ef4d0e2" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Beverages--Coffee</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1966-1977</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d31b409208d6b1b491c0ca06dcc9636d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_97a3831dc30471afc2e3954f92075721" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Building Supplies/Contractors</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1965-1984</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_6d769a8c14ae652c39f6bf1e6ad14760" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_4c1408b0db70d6481d0fc9febf95fcde" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Building Supplies/Contractors--Lakewood Pipe</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1972</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_7de566d822471346473a477ce77e00c2" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_8367ee4de2c033cd5bd98702a60a2a8f" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Cigarettes</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_bb127665dfb88b3a4ae39a513bad354c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_3da2d359ba5b16eafe995cdbc461198c" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Cigarettes--L&amp;M</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1974-1975</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_47e41bec4f8cbed48d02dd9b513d4763" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_eee0dbf1cf5b001a9648c0f157045528" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Cigarettes--Marlboro</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1972-1977</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_286b229892c882beef8406b84afde9b6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_4ca9a7c8601e39f34ee655e386185546" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Cigarettes--Salem/Camel/Real</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1980</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_7c69aa1a6735e0626738f150750bc676">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_aad5460cb1a2edcee452c333c413312e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d073f9cc4a9f7b16e260b555472acf8f" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Cigarettes--Winston</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1972-1976</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_e92f7869df26e3b8920df6f51a182bc1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_5b5dad1b1c8fee4236eaf124a347a1d4" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Department Stores, Shopping Centers</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1964-1986</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_3182c9725d32b9a6694151a7ff3b1906" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_49f08916c5fb330b69bc20568c2c547e" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Department Stores, Shopping Centers--Anell's</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1966-1971</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_e77d911ee226ff9ca9b84180063c0f93" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_568f875730c0ee066d1b7208a55f0d4c" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Department Stores, Shopping Centers--Inland Center</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_6dc35d2894d9c653d075a4b9aff3279a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_3d686183a782dee3d420e6f05276d8c1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Department Stores, Shopping Centers--Mission Valley</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1963-1969</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_17e325183d7fa326665449b08795244b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_e4e1b10501e8036408c47062bc5d1b9e" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Department Stores, Shopping Centers--Montgomery Ward</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1970-1977</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_3b5ea534d7d025228a87b530cd98cc76" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_b590354e8b233d70c45c5c3ee1b97554" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Department Stores, Shopping Centers--Ohrbach's</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1961-1968</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_2ac3432ff0e6309661d3fe4fc256e471" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_0e6ac58b688138d2a07c574776b43380" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Department Stores, Shopping Centers--Topanga Plaza</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1966-1968</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_f29130360966dcf4f0d0628bb5b8590c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_54d1cfb6ac748cf10851451e51f4b248" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Electronics/Televisions</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1964-1978</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_b45ddacfdd355d80774c1b2dfe755cc6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a9dc1629cef9cb6ff17c5363dcaf5f2f" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Foods</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1981-1984</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_74b8db23895b2f90715d14bc7a9d9fa9" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_01173b6f04ef60f8e503290cfb4c9d62" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Household Goods</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1963-1986</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_ec4f5ccd00c9c0ce7a1e53a8576980b7" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_3e3dccfb25f23f3523e2cf3fd5376fb4" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Household Goods--Payne</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1972</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_4144a54ff2f94ac41c56cc67b808863b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a620f1696fc75b66bfd909b883880b4f" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Insurance</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1981-1985</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_b935ce23351ce71ba2f53c55aba4d7a6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_fd724a02a9771cfbcdce192cba33d7f2" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Kitchen and Laundry</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1963-1976</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_af307bc4d60b7abc0dd966108e403414" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_6ab4503bcfc5e3a81dcf9a7f2d27cb88" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Lawn and Garden/Agriculture</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1972-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_dba77f31c30fac8adb47520cff88a2cc" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ecac58070f94c7e3230c508544ca42db" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Liquor</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1978</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_311d6b0fb517113906b8cad7d9e51563" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_762280626be7ce95d32cdf169594882d" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Liquor--Scotch</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1965-1975</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_c8f0b87f1294ab4419e8840282dea094" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_4aef01bf668ef7086e0c728ea248b19d" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Liquor--Scotch--White Horse</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1968-1974</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_f2a450869ac4e9823b156aecaf3ab3d6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_b8124cb7447b5a238d95f5809b8d6834" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Liquor--Tequila/Mexcal</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1974-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_0ec46f236aba2b39aefd36f210556be6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_331051a17deba8a49598c0593d4ac406" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Liquor--Tequila/Mexcal--Arandas, Jose Cuervo, Olmeca</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1973-1979</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_53ce4d3f433eec28e71972cfeb66703f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_79ada1181f1266a756e23682d39ec3fc" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Liquor--Tequila/Mexcal--Puerto Vallarta</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1981</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_778a635533c625416a0414bfa42336e4" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_2264362f7c6fa8a6f71b5e8f49e09057" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Liquor--Tequila/Mexcal--Valido Fresa</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1975</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_07be405c3c724a3e5a910fb1e8a24bf9" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_093417350011acb3b42da72bf5b1de1e" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Liquor--Vodka</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1981</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_c945ca16d2141b370760164c2d22033b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_35fe1bb472c8b85a488293e026d4c80c" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Liquor--Vodka--Kamchatka</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1975</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_25d145769ebe2b1d27603187a163307e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ac81b7be81f91b561d3550d50b31d2a8" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Liquor--Vodka--Smirnoff</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1968-1983</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_2c7842b3cbfbb700f6b358c4e0c699ec" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_472c1f28241a10f0cbe625dd555825ee" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Liquor--Vodka--Stolichnaya</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_2f57692c75787b63a967fc9b791e7fe6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_0e417c8ea45a7a7e1f3379b49659f2e7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Liquor--Vodka--Wolfschmidt</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1980</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_61096efa5b732b6480f5af272f789bc1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_62633aae344a852527c687a8ec619432" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Liquor--Whiskey (U.S. and Canadian)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1980</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_4e248ef47ce96a892d8c5d0aa37f60a3" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_4eeb90afb97ea01a29de003969f1a99c" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Liquor--Whiskey (U.S. and Canadian)--Canadian Club</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1976-1978</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_c9a9f049b5ab5b70d6e117bd1e205219" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_c19329afe82f04eb455c84a35c572951" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Liquor--Whiskey (U.S. and Canadian)--Seagrams</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1964-1976</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_c53f55f23c47de5930186b04411a40e3" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD39</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d08afa62409bff02a9c12d5d04897ef2" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Print</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1978-1983</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_f2b5e3e4314b9e4c72beec05c358d9c7" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_8bb76df233afb855e26d353d0a8e8444" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Radio</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1960-1984</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_c4d64e6a5721e0239b0a072a56f5051b">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_9fe8b07528d6d9463ac6449abfdeff3c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_4395c6fcbf47553ba2dbf3bf09cfd97e" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Radio--KABC</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1975</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d3dd5a9c2bab11a222ff7e8fa989bc91" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_aecbb463e7b7a70e775fd6b08b46968d" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Radio--KBIG</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1979</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_7237452c9d1b8f783b725997beb91863" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_dd288a88fbe7a4d6099348072fdea8bf" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Radio--KFI</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1963-1979</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_0505727fbb251fcfbd8476441a77bf14" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_cc443088bb143487134c2f438dc62e38" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Radio--KLAC</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1970</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_ff7b189b128b520d7c76c37011c7c483" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_1efcfb4f3ba08c2c8f760e01579d087c" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Radio--KMPC</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1980</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_b10d4a6dd0a16c62102632ec26a8d240" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_52b75e1d0da7bf2eb641a6aa0805224b" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Radio--KNX</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1968-1981</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_78a9b9d6c5edec57e971b89eb2a2847e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_8107bc9f645c45e031f421ad0b466756" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Radio--KPOL</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1977</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_82ff87b2f9d55cfff8f49e629f5b0837" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_f193ae9746d0ed6ddb6744b6154e5d8c" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Radio--KSON</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1979</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_c7f9963a7637c57da94a337c7b3e58e1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_f4977750c161d03ac3b0842417b4c18c" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Radio--XTRA</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1966-1978</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_ba25ed708fbba68769bbcdf32657bbae" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d192d9ea70c3e3f984353c8444f9093a" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Media--Television</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1978-1984</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_039d1e6b086161ce365dc4b517096f05" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_28f7daf320dfd232b39a645e0ef468b2" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1973-1978</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_c99e07d419a1c7044e0ef2ebed2aaa5a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_f16e9275481ae6496dba09470aeaa2b7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Mortuaries</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1962-1984</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_c48d9c4fff6a7f49acd0e88c1663d586" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_00dc7f290d0d425689f51367d1235d9f" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Mortuaries--Inglewood</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1964-1981</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_55c15b7c256abb4ff76a51073c3b69af" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_be867ae5b9870cd765f0ec1caed6976b" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Mortuaries--Rose Hills</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_8dfd0269743049bba1ecc854fd5ca624" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_72ee8db863e89161db70fe854e589679" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Public Service</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_6b6ca012d2e29cc65ed859e908e5728d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ea8cbb2deea0d85d93e7cf4fa8f0fd79" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Public Service--Crime and Safety</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_f5232e64e208e6d8acc9cbd4eb46e43a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_493b4d7d4800f2e3b25c778881804720" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Public Service--Education</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1981</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_98e1400bd0cd2b8e3a753b91db2bf078" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_c42ea638201d2511f8f17b6c2c2c2554" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Public Service--Environment/Conservation</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1981</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_2ec6277e4f950a3d6ed3e33e5115c9f0">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_9484e363390e3b0d9cb64e41730433e1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_e9749a8e5e03f61564f8a8184d1c711e" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Public Service--Eyes and Ears Foundation</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1977</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_15774d29d91b59093664af92d78dfa5e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_df85364629120ddfa79510ca789d4cf9" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Public Service--Health and Medical</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1973-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_469591b42f4b4572996f1900fcbce37e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_6e94d587ad4b75b7a4c1696a1fb33e59" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Public Service--Municipal</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1972-0982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_6850c50e54865281cf2123f9809e3aa9" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_3a2d7ec840a39299df6909192f986ba1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Public Service--Religion</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1973-1981</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d255d593a17551cfdc550319449c5439" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_06b639e5ca154f79c928393082f05613" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Public Service--Youth</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_70e746ce3df4ac9afbe5379282014ed2" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_027603548c3f3480c3bed6c57740f3d1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Public Utility--Electric</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1966-1978</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d7c60fcd999e35bdc60773f8e420b302" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_341169470ad146a4e52510d8ee875e6e" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Public Utility--Gas</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1964-1979</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d28cdd25b0f88a3a207a0b1d4572c96f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a8a8b78ae1007c25718528004e01c5db" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Real Estate</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1979</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_5a10bda14d78aafbeb54eff851cfebc9" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_cae4e1d60fd87adeb855658b46eeaea3" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Restaurants</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1983</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_ca6bf92cd135aa21807237aaabd943cc">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_1df57b4d1d0e857cb17db1410592b961" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ad57e49199a3d921edd252e4374448b1" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Restaurants--Jack-in-the-Box</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1973-1977</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_b138aafb2b77d4cecfcd647171e04f4d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_af67fa04fe9fdee3c250fd068c27b167" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Restaurants--McDonald's</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_bc08fb69c614d51d566ea5319f528422" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_b9ab1c251fec0d6821605c325b0073d0" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Restaurants--Winchell's</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1981-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_b9a3be4089e62aafa3f7af8657f38c0c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_5e0500db93a528eb0653698bbbe931b2" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Retail</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1973-1986</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d231a8a0fe0197d2b182877b920a051e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_3cf9dbae1687a998a608c19153f93378" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Telephone Service--General Telephone (GTE)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1974</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_2ea13760f84c1ab9a400c30b08de1662" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_096cf0fe610128e7bc8b8e85bec63036" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Telephone Service--Pacific Telephone (PacTel)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1964-1974</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_f5f3ee8fd11f7cc2da9ca78a8b453402" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_840b13947b7a6401ad352502dee7da59" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Telephone Service--Yellow Pages</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1981</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_3356bf03c6200cbdbe8f902ccafc5eba" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_6281d16a47da06df464198da52e13d5b" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1979</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_bfd5ffe9f4839ff80fae16efe86bacfc" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_7496ae6d19c818a30d473c4098370793" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Airlines</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1983</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_c4e46a5eaf274cf58ae7264874912ccb" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_0e88e63ab99ae0740f289ce8e7174aa0" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Airlines--Air California</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1981</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_263716d0b38aee60b1330a8e98520d2c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_adfbff17b4e7380ec9dc5376c078163d" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Airlines--Air Canada</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1971</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_b16c2bb4e4a1a4ddacecb2b3c16a21e4" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_c1b6c2c0270b3821e066ddd692769f94" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Airlines--Alaska Airlines</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1981</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_7c4188e388e4528e8ccbc69b47b1dbbb" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_c00b66e0130f490136dbc2e8221188bd" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Airlines--American</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1982</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_772f979e2207d2e4f79bbd09f5e4fa35">2 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_50e0dc8ea04d5039e5f004820a6a5c43" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_7e8e9924dc644f12d6f4c9772e901fd3" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Airlines--BOAC/British Air</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1980</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_e5fdc11f9c7d7d8d1917707701c4fd57" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_320351e41e5d06fa65899561b8fe9c2d" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Airlines--Continental</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_6ddefa0b25796e159fb6fd2f2e081eb8" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_7e5d07344077898db44d368073e6233d" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Airlines--National</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1970-1976</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_c33748d28fe6020b32698bc6abfbb4df" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_c8231a43d4a74e8d8e39221f5a5405ce" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Airlines--Republic/Hughes</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1971-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d7b4eea3b877a9cc0cf82a482d382783" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_00da04545e2dd4c001ee4379a4bbfbeb" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Airlines--Western</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1967-1981</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_0965be723d8964856eef11c7e6620632" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_0662e8f19a01a33b65c0330866e00c37" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Bus</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1973</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_5aae1be72a7a73b62042cc5860db264b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_cb3da86c2f386d2c0add6806c258eff5" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--California</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1972-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_4209140df27c1fe881e854f30e019256" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_9e4d41a28294e28866d34ed2b2553f05" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Cruise Lines</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1968-1976</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_55655d10a8786bc993f76ce6d6611555" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_82281cd7647342e500cc05cfb5944aa9" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Entertainment</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1964-1983</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_6856a64883fe9864808ba2a91c95c6ed">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_5564b18eb967c26d1a595c17bc4ef888" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_743ebe675aaac8a875928de2e4be384b" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Hotels</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1983</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_df5d79d4ed104772c557186a66f130e6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_1b45c112ebddad39a42a7ac23afa28d7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Las Vegas</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1972-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_94cf07c92a09d9bf4e18861c20a4671d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_5b473c3ea5ad2b3da12796a96cb37b9b" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Nevada</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1976-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d72c68435a257b88036cf4516ecc86f6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_7087c63b3131815a53fafeaf92478116" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Palm Springs (Calif.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1976-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_8f7c98bee454ba2ad7f36784ce83ae26" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_216541a57cdb9c321e8ad14783129af5" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Railroads</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1969-1976</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_18bd96df025f47736dde9c9fa91bf62d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_620bf80b755ec01fd989b90f746e5688" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Railroads--Amtrak</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1973</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_eb5da19f80d11362a2225472a4930e7b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_f79bee80e765fb82e7b24ed46fc4a543" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Travel--Utah</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_0d05281111cc4f0bbf8a2a5e8ae59c8f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">ADD40</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
