<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/painemarygorham/"
         >painemarygorham</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Mary Gorham Paine Diary, 1879-1884 and undated
                  <num>RL.00989</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Danielle Moore; machine-readable finding aid created by: Danielle
               Moore</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003851431</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 05:41:23
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Mary Gorham Paine Diary</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Paine, Mary Gorham</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.00989</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1879/1884" type="inclusive">1879-1884 and undated</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_f11d4989601742c4caadf326cc2cd2ca">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_57aa83bba068e404a3afcdb85b86b551">Mary Gorham Paine (b. 1843) of
            Yarmouth, Massachusetts, was married to Eben W. Paine (1835-1904) of Brewster,
            Massachusetts, a merchant ship captain in the trade between Boston and Zanzibar. They
            had one son, Allan Thatcher Paine (b. 1882). The collection consists of a single diary
            kept by Mary Gorham Paine as she traveled twice by ship from Boston to islands near
            Madagascar. Forty-six manuscript pages provide both a day-by-day account of her trip
            aboard the Sarah Hobart to Nossi-Be (present day Nosy Be) from December 25, 1879 to May
            4, 1880, and a three-page, mid-journey synopsis of the passage with her young son to
            Reunion Island, begun on December 13, 1883. As is made clear by the text, the intent of
            both voyages was to join her husband who was probably located in Zanzibar at the time.
            Newspaper clippings chiefly concerned with literary topics, news and issues relating to
            Africa, and obituaries for her husband and others are pasted into 18 pages following the
            narrative portion of the diary together with a photograph of a man and another of a
            baby, most likely her husband and son. The diary as a whole provides some insight into
            the life of a sea captain's wife and a description of long-distance ocean travel aboard
            a barque such as the Sarah Hobart.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_37415be7bb0c97f5f7b3f9929fbaef90">
            <extent>1 Item</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_bcfea46b2d012e96cb766e3993337644">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_2a10ba410c1029c81b4f8746af095a59">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_a3b8296140e303d294d792c23d59d684">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_21c107fbafc6a0e89a67ef7be659ebb4">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Mary Gorham Paine Diary, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_d2171f22a41a228be5f6e6db2fde9821">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Mary Gorham Paine Diary was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2007.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_ddb1c476f32d4bd55b0b6bf70b422e2e">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Danielle Moore, September 2010</p>
         <p>Encoded by Danielle Moore, September 2010</p>
         <p>Accession 2007-0113 is described in this finding aid.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_316dedb4af57073dfc94205149159b19">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Mary Gorham Paine was born on March 2, 1843, in Yarmouth, Massachusetts, to Captain
            Thacher Gorham (1806-1874) and Dinah Hall Bray (1807-1856). She married Captain Eben W.
            Paine (1835-1904) of Brewster, Massachusetts, and had one son, Allen Thatcher Paine,
            born on April 29, 1882. Her husband, who commanded merchant ships in the trade between
            Boston and Zanzibar, resided in Zanzibar as agent for the Ropes &amp; Co. shipping firm
            for several years, presumably during the time this diary was written. After retirement,
            he farmed cranberries and later served as Brewster's town clerk, treasurer, and director
            of the Barnstable County Mutual Fire Insurance Company.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_5d28626244f531a04c795d0179a43cf8">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The collection consists of a single diary kept by Mary Gorham Paine as she traveled
            twice by ship from Boston to islands near Madagascar. Forty-six manuscript pages provide
            both a day-by-day account of her trip aboard the <title type="simple" render="italic"
               >Sarah Hobart</title> to Nossi-Be (present day Nosy Be) from December 25, 1879 to May
            4, 1880, and a three-page, mid-journey synopsis of the passage with her young son,
            Allan, to Reunion Island, begun on December 13, 1883. As is made clear by the text, the
            intent of both voyages was to join her husband, Captain Eben W. Paine, who was probably
            located in Zanzibar at the time. Newspaper clippings chiefly concerned with literary
            topics, news and issues relating to Africa, and obituaries for her husband and others
            are pasted into 18 pages following the narrative portion of the diary together with a
            photograph of a man and another of a baby, most likely her husband and son. The
            clippings lack an indication of the year and source except for the <title type="simple"
               render="doublequote">Literary Leaves</title> articles which are from the <title
               type="simple" render="italic">Boston Journal</title>.</p>
         <p>The diary provides some insight into the life of a sea captain's wife and a description
            of long-distance ocean travel aboard a barque such as the <title type="simple"
               render="italic">Sarah Hobart</title>. Paine initially suffered from sea-sickness, but
            once recovered, occupied herself with sewing, reading, washing, and baking, as well as
            socializing and playing cards and Parcheesi with fellow travelers. She often mentioned
            the activities of her primary companions, Mrs. Crocker and the ship's Captain, who
            sometimes cooked special meals for his female passengers and was often engaged in
            washing clothing himself. In addition, Paine unfailingly commented on the weather, foods
            served at meals, number of miles traveled, number of days at sea, and types of ships
            sighted. On April 18th, after nearly four months at sea, the ship made port at Tamatave,
            Madagascar (present day Toamasina). Paine mentioned little about the six days spent
            ashore and continued with the diary only until arrival at Nossi-Be. The summary
            description of the second journey centers mainly on Paine's concern with her 20-month
            old son's well-being and activities aboard ship, her own struggle with sea-sickness and
            feelings of inadequacy in managing her son, and her appreciation for the assistance of
            Mrs. Hill and the ship's Captain in caring for him. The final update to the narrative
            was added on February 4th, 1884, while still en route to their first stop, Reunion
            Island.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Ocean travel -- History -- 19th century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Ship captains’ spouses -- Massachusetts -- History -- 19th
            century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women travelers -- History -- 19th century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women travelers -- Diaries</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Indian Ocean -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Atlantic Ocean -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <genreform source="aat">Diaries</genreform>
         <persname source="ingest">Paine, Mary Gorham</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Paine, Mary Gorham</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_p35" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Mary Gorham Paine Diary, 1879-1884 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_fe6a1eb6b5a68b0b2c4aceb0971d1e85">
                  <extent>1 folder</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_ly8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Mary Gorham Paine diary, 1879-1884 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_01125ce42ff3ac4e5941d9064a770e28" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="folder">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
