<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
         url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/pattersonsamuel/"
         >pattersonsamuel</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Samuel Finley Patterson Papers, 1792-1939 and undated
                  <num>RL.01002</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Library staff; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Paula Jeannet and Matthew Warren</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2014</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000868104</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-11-01 16:17:32
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Samuel Finley Patterson papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Patterson, Samuel Finley, 1799-1874</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01002</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1792/1939" type="inclusive">1792-1939 and undated</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_e0ec78a4b4d439e39adcec5bea4430c5">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_d4c03910b12690f8f13f8acaabaeef52">Samuel Patterson (1799-1874) was a
            farmer, Indian commissioner, Justice of the Peace in Caldwell County, railroad official,
            and state legislator from Winston-Salem, North Carolina. Collection consists primarily
            of personal and business papers of Samuel Patterson, his family, and the Graham family,
            of North Carolina, Virginia, and Tennessee. The papers pertain to North Carolina
            railroads, legislative and politics in North Carolina, sale of Cherokee lands,
            mercantile affairs, the education of children, and other topics. Correspondents include
            C. B. Aycock, K. P. Battle, W. J. Bingham, Edward W. Bok, Locke Craig, Josephus Daniels,
            Dorothea L. Dix, John Haywood, William H. Haywood, Edwin Mims, John Charles McNeill,
            William Norwood, Henry J. Stockard, C. Alphonso Smith, Zebulon B. Vance, and Henry Van
            Dyke. Correspondence from the Civil War and Reconstruction periods discusses
            abolitionism, slavery, supplies to Confederate soldiers, refugees, prices, military
            affairs and leaders, the establishment of a school for African Americans, and refers to
            the dislike of the policies of Jefferson Davis and Judah P. Benjamin. The papers of Lucy
            Bramlette Patterson relate to her travels through Europe and Mexico in the 1880s, her
            literary and extensive political interests, and family matters.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_2aeb5183756405d780ab980076db6ea7">
            <extent>Approx. 2,167 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_574707df60601f48878f276ce136ee68">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_eb163c1c404b6f1fe2f428eae788ebb6">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_fe5cd3e4742dad2a455dc6e85880db18">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_4443c7da4799fa5c0c09e6d6ed0eff46">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Samuel Finley Patterson papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_6bbed38c602321651ed5b47d6b72bbc0">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Samuel Finley Patterson papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library as a gift in 1949, with additions received from 1950 to
            1960.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_5ae28aaac24483eec9640d558c05a7f5">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library staff</p>
         <p>Encoded by Paula Jeannet and Matthew Warren, June 2014</p>
         <p>Accession(s) described in this finding aid: from 1949 to 1960</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_f8a2e8f818db5190a931ac537fba0890">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Samuel Finley Patterson was a clerk of the N.C. Senate, 1835, treasurer of N.C.,
            1835-1837, president of Raleigh and Gaston Railroad, 1840-1845, chairman of the Caldwell
            County Court of Pleas and Quarter Sessions, 1845-1868, member of the N.C. Senate, 1846,
            1848, 1864, member of the N.C. House of Commons,1854, member of the N.C. State
            Convention, 1866, Indian commissioner, 1839, Brigadier and Major General of the N.C.
            State Militia, Justice of the Peace in Caldwell County, N.C, trustee of the University
            of N.C., and farmer.</p>
         <p>Lucy Bramlette Patterson, daughter of General William Houston Patterson, was born in
            Tennessee, the home of her mother's family, but spent the greater part of her unmarried
            life in Philadelphia, the home of the Patterson family. In 1888, she married Jesse
            Lindsay Patterson, grandson of Samuel Finley Patterson and son of Rufus Lenoir Patterson
            (1830-1879) and Mary Louisa (Morehead) Patterson (1830-1862). She had traveled
            extensively in this country, Mexico, and Europe before her marriage. With literary
            interests and some ability herself, she made her home, "Bramlette" in Winston, a kind of
            center for literary activity in North Carolina from 1888 until 1919 when she became
            interested in Serbian War Relief and national Republican politics. The greater part of
            her own literary works consisted of a page in the <title type="simple" render="italic"
               >Progressive Farmer</title> from approximately 1904 to 1918, relating the pleasures
            of country life. Lucy Patterson was a graduate of Salem College, 1882; founder and first
            president of the North Carolina Federation of Women's Clubs; president of the N.C.
            Historical Society; Republican nominee for Congress in 1922; and Republican National
            Committee Woman from North Carolina.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_2a3ed26b4466c2e85eff4667d3c9bf1e">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The collection comprises the personal and business correspondence and other papers of
            Samuel Finley Patterson (1799-1874), state legislator and president of the Raleigh and
            Gaston Railroad, and of Lucy Bramlette Patterson (1865-1942), wife of Jesse Lindsay
            Patterson, Samuel Finley Patterson's grandson. There are also papers of Samuel
            Patterson's son, Rufus Lenoir Patterson (1830-1879), and of his granddaughter, Caroline
            Finley Patterson. Early papers include the business records and daybooks of Hugh Graham
            concerning mercantile affairs, the purchase of land warrants, and the panic of 1819;
            letters of William Norwood (1767-1842) dealing with family matters and his election as a
            judge; letters of the Jones family, related through the wife of Samuel Finley Patterson,
            pertaining to family affairs; and life in 1823 at Salem Academy (Salem, North Carolina),
            in 1835 at the University of North Carolina, and in 1840 at Yale College; and letters
            from Edmund Jones Henry and James Edward Henry regarding farming in Spartanburg, South
            Carolina, and a temperance convention there in 1843.</p>
         <p>The papers of Samuel Finley Patterson give information of Revolutionary land claims;
            sale of Cherokee lands; the Raleigh and Gaston Railroad; Cincinnati (Ohio) in 1819;
            South Carolina politics, including nullification and support for the Van Buren
            administration; the Bank of the United States; the Whig Party in North Carolina and
            Virginia; Patterson's activities as a member of the North Carolina legislature; student
            life at the University of North Carolina in 1849 and 1867, and at the University of
            Virginia; Charlottesville (Virginia), in 1869; and Rufus T. Patterson's cotton and paper
            factories. </p>
         <p>Correspondence from the Civil War and Reconstruction periods discusses abolitionism,
            slavery, supplies to Confederate soldiers, refugees, prices, military affairs and
            leaders, the establishment of a school for African Americans, dislike of the policies of
            Jefferson Davis and Judah P. Benjamin, the Good Templars of Hillsborough (North
            Carolina), the emancipation of Louisiana from radical rule; and the threat to eliminate
            state funding for the support of the University of North Carolina.</p>
         <p>The papers of Lucy Bramlette Patterson include her diploma from Salem Female College;
            letters written while she was traveling in Mexico and Europe during the 1880s; letters
            from prominent persons in response to invitations to speak at Salem Female College;
            information on the Patterson Cup awarded annually for the best literary production in
            North Carolina; letters from a few North Carolina literary figures correspondence
            regarding the location of the Daniel Boone Trail; papers relative to Mrs. Patterson's
            service with Kolo Serbski Sestara in caring for the orphans of Serbian soldiers; a few
            items relating to the visit of Queen Marie of Rumania to the United States; clippings of
            Lucy Bramlette (Patterson) Patterson's contributions to the <title type="simple"
               render="italic">Progressive Farmer</title>, Raleigh, North Carolina; and an account
            of "The Groves," the home of Willie Jones. </p>
         <p>Other materials include a list of pledges by women of Caldwell County, North Carolina,
            in 1862 for construction of an ironclad gunboat; broadsides advertising the Charlotte
            Female Institute, Charlotte (North Carolina), Gaston High School, Dallas (North
            Carolina), O. P. Fitzgerald's <title type="simple" render="italic">Home Newspaper and
               Educational Journal</title>, Hubert H. Bancroft's <title type="simple"
               render="italic">History of California and the Pacific States</title>, and a forestry
            conference to be held at Montreat (North Carolina). Other printed materials include a
            program of performances at the Opera House in Winston (North Carolina) in 1882;
            broadside announcing the inauguration of Governor Zebulon B. Vance in 1877; bulletin of
            St. Mary's School, Raleigh (North Carolina); printed speech of John K. Kuttrell entitled
            "Who is Responsible for Chinese Immigration." </p>
         <p>There are several items in the collection relating to the Bolijack family, including an
            account book, 1855-1869, of William A. Bolijack with entries for a sawmill and for trade
            in barrels of lime, and an agreement, 1842, between John W. Smith and Bolijack for use
            of a patented sawmill on Town Fork of the Dan River in Stokes County. </p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Political activity -- North Carolina</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Europe -- Description and travel -- 19th century</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina -- History</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Education -- Southern States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Family life -- Southern States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Railroads -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women in politics</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Southern States -- Commerce</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Virginia -- History</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Tennessee -- History</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Cherokee Indians -- North Carolina -- History</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Daybooks</genreform>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Mexico -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1775-1865</geogname>
         <famname rules="dacs" source="ingest">Graham family</famname>
         <persname source="ingest">Patterson, Lindsay, Mrs., 1865-1942</persname>
         <famname source="ingest">Patterson family</famname>
         <persname source="ingest">Patterson, Samuel Finley, 1799-1874</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_wvq" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Samuel Finley Patterson papers, 1792-1939 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_8e99691357247c0f11af59a499a74d13">
                  <extent>15 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_y3i" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1792-1829</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_3650ca014b302278533042dc0c2c0f5d">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_6b93455abdd07686402b2c5fe3785734" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_kwt" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1830-1845</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_595cc0551146a378ff6d29bcf27f8ac6">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_bad8ce73d537d8a8b962ef371f9d1585" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_i5s" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1845-1856</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_cfa91ed9c11ed410a4e60a0c2bdbd1db">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_4006f5ca3f47aa17a9d9b5857e812130" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_uuk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Receipts and correspondence, 1856-1858</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b2790053e4f41f60978c794570f404a2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_ceo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1858-1866</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_bc48ab97bd7ab36a08c5704feafb1df0">
                     <extent>3 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_1fdc0efe181eef9f81eed7901cce866c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_n1k" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1866-1873</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_41344e846ef20cfb4260b39118a2c5cb">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_28bb6c45b03762a57e69c68295c1ff90" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_m1r" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1873-1878</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_35df90542de857ae3f962f448f817398">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_ccd97d0082e9423479fda949009d209a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_in2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1878-1881</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_773a0180476c8ad0b5100d902f2af35c">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_27614303a58b83549f27cb5e4b72ace2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_o5t" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1881-1882</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_26ee79028550100251858e8d45920ce5">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_68802afa0e56efd5207a7858e501f14c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_8hs" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1883-1903</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_12aaa96c73f1c5db758e8ea0d8e7dd04">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_00e74083bfe7ac0e2620e19c699d40ce" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref33_qv4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1903-1939</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_9fffccb927ae1bb430e7bda0bc76ef00">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_fc7c8bd0400306cc569e63a076b2ff21" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">10</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_h35" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0a743807126dd8eb661cb5f4a3ca1d75" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref36_rk9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Draft of history book, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5e1950229ee8af77b903b44e80ac8837" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref37_1qp" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Assorted writings, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c2f622f4331b81c7144675eec0ce6b0a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref38_sj5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, clippings, assorted writings, undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_efcfc0095aa6e1226be95d31a2fda53e">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_93b015692f89955908fe520afd4dc6fd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref40_l7x" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, assorted writings, undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_ee280c9c8183430ddf91bfe044d8cbc3">
                     <extent>8 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_81a31002eb05033f4e685c742f97dca1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref42_p8x" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Scrapbooks and notebooks, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0b9fbc53cd1948ba5313b6b353ba864b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_oha" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Scrapbooks and notebooks, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8e921d9a350ef586407c7a6ee5454617" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">15</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
