<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/peruvian/">peruvian</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Peruvian Collection, 1583-1892 <num>RL.01017</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Finding aid prepared by Processed by: Jesus Leyte-Vidal, William R. Erwin, Jr.,
               and Erma Paden Whittington; machine-readable finding aid created by: Stephen Douglas
               Miller</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000868091</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 06:19:17
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Peruvian collection</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Odriozola, Manuel de, 1804-1889</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01017</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1583/1892" type="inclusive">1583-1892</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_69ac2e88f5672b9c3d2c818171786c5e">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <physdesc id="aspace_fb6587635bf6e6fd2b2916f6419104fd">
            <extent>circa 47 Items; 21 Volumes</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <abstract id="aspace_ba055baf2b3426cf2a49757d2d4a00cb">Collection contains papers relating
            to Peru, roughly falling into three groups centering around commerce and industry,
            literary activities, and religious and social history. Includes papers (1786-1787)
            containing information on the mining of mercury; poems of Juan de Valle y Caviedes in
            17th century script; poems by Antonio de Solís; one volume of Documentos históricos,
            collected by Manuel de Odriozola; three Documentos literarios from contemporary
            publications, among them a compilation of the papers of Peruvian viceroys and others
            (1580-1818); a paper relating to witchcraft and idolatry in Peru; papers (1772-1773) of
            the Provincial Council at Lima, containing the core of the debate within the Catholic
            Church on the modernization of learning which Charles III attempted to foist upon the
            empire; a copy of the proceso of Mariano Tupac Amaro; and material relating to politics
            and the industrial development of Peru and neighboring countries during the 19th
            century.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_5cab5747c2e79112e96675f512413b2f">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_d14d262089035e198224448cb063e439">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information please consult the section on copyright in the Regulations and
            Procedures of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_443e3e0a0e1554ecf5a91f9f2894f0c2">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Peruvian Collection, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_f6facd1029bbb9d120a0ffcfb8c6179e">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The materials in the Peruvian Collection were acquired by Duke University from 1933 to
            1948.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_56c549ba81bfbc0873bd2cf6886d47ec">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by: Jesus Leyte-Vidal, William R. Erwin, Jr., and Erma Paden Whittington</p>
         <p>Completed 1984</p>
         <p>Encoded by Stephen Douglas Miller</p>
         <p>Updated for subject access by Alice Poffinberger, October 2014.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_642df903200d25d941247a549c53eea0">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>This collection of heterogeneous material, generally relating to the colonial period of
            Peru, falls roughly into three groups centering around commerce and industry, literary
            activity, and religious and social history. Several manuscripts in the first group
            contain information on the mining of mercury, 1786-1787. Literary materials include the
            poems of Caviedes in the seventeenth century script useful for correcting errors in the
            copies published by Ricardo Palma; a copy of iconoclastic and mysterious poems by
            Antonio de Solís; one cuaderno of the <emph render="underline">Documentos
               históricos</emph> collected by Manuel de Odriozola; and three <emph
               render="underline">Documentos literarios</emph> from contemporary publications. Among
            the Items relating to religion and social history are a compilation of the papers of
            Peruvian viceroys and others, 1580-1818; an <emph render="underline">expediente</emph>
            concerning witchcraft and idolatry in Peru; original papers on the modernization of
            learning which Charles III attempted to impose upon the empire; copy of the proceso of
            Mariano Tupac Amaru; and a booklet, 1794, describing the founding and development of
            Quito, Ecuador.</p>
         <p>Some of these Items, formerly the property of Manuel de Odriozola, the Peruvian literary
            historian who brought together this collection, are listed in the <title render="italic"
               type="simple">Cátalogo de la Biblioteca Peruana Propiedad de Dn. Francisco Perez de
               Velasco</title> (Lima, 1918). Rubén Vargas Ugarte, S. J., describes some of these
            manuscripts in <title render="italic" type="simple">Manuscritos Peruanos en las
               Bibliotecas de América</title> (Buenos Aires, 1945, pp. 230-243) which is volume IV
            of his <title render="italic" type="simple">Biblioteca Peruana</title> (Lima, 1935- ).
            John Tate Lanning, James B. Duke Professor of History, also mentioned these manuscripts
            in his article "The Hispanic Collection" published in <title render="italic"
               type="simple">Gnomon, Essays for the Dedication of the William R. Perkins
               Library</title> (Duke Unlversity, April 15 and 16, 1970).</p>
         <p>This guide to the collection is the result of extensive recataloging in which, for the
            first time, considerable attention has been given to analyzing the content of the
            manuscripts. The descriptions of many of the manuscripts have been enlarged, and, in
            some cases, author and title information has been changed or refined. Many entries have
            been added to the card catalog based upon these new descriptions. Copies of these cards
            have been included in this guide in order to provide additional means of access to the
            contents of the collection.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Spain -- Colonies -- America -- Administration</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Quito (Ecuador) -- History</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Peru -- History -- Sources</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Peru -- History -- 1829-1919</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Peru -- Intellectual life</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Perú -- History -- 1548-1820</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Peru -- Commerce</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Witchcraft -- Perú</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Viceroys -- South America</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Peruvian literature.</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Mercury mines and mining -- Perú</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Idolatry -- Perú</subject>
         <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Palma, Ricardo</persname>
         <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Solís, Antonio de</persname>
         <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">Valle y Caviedes, Juan del</persname>
         <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">Catholic Church -- Peru.</corpname>
         <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Tupac Amaru, Mariano</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Odriozola, Manuel de, 1804-1889</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref10_bmt" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Peruvian collection</unittitle>
               <unitdate normal="1583/1892" type="inclusive">1583-1892</unitdate>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref143_eu4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Guide to the collection</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1472661be41980a9eec08de560d48f0c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref11_pai" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Eguidio a su amigo. Diálogo. La Naturaleza, y Hijo. Libro 2º de Mangeto
                     ? f. 236.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_483deeb669728ab193ac90f099165f67" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_750d714a1482c4e0e1509892d3cd8092"
                     parent="aspace_483deeb669728ab193ac90f099165f67" type="ms">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_62958c9128cfcdaf2d7d0fd40ef09674">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>n. p., n. d. 50 folios.</p>
                  <p>A hypothetical dialogue between nature and her son.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref13_lw5" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Montero Bolaños de los Reyes, Francisco Xavier. Papeles que pertenecen
                     a Francisco Xavier Montero Bolaños de los Reyes.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_144c9819f63c3d9b0bf58a0ebd99a029" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0a4764f75939bb3a01afbe8268166741"
                     parent="aspace_144c9819f63c3d9b0bf58a0ebd99a029" type="ms">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7f20b1fe36cf25598406a8c657afce27">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Caracas, 1765-1770. 72 pages.</p>
                  <p>Petition, auto, and testimonials concerning the purity of race (limpieza de
                     sangre) of Francisco Montero Bolaños de los Reyes. Caracas, 1765-1770.</p>
                  <p>The purity of race (limpieza de sangre) was documented by testimonials
                     demonstrating that the person was not a descendant of Moors, Jews, heretics, or
                     penitenciados (persons punished by the Inquisition). This documentation was a
                     prerequisite in Spain and its colonies in order to be admitted into a
                     corporation, school or university, to practice a profession, or a trade, and to
                     get married. A law of May 16, 1865, abolished this requirement for marriage and
                     for admission into the public service, and it was definitively abolished by the
                     27th article of the 1869 Constitution, and the 15th article of the 1876
                     Constitution (in force).</p>
                  <p>This manuscript is an important source for the study of social or economic
                     discrimination against racial or ethnic groups in Spain and its colonies till
                     the end of the XIX century.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_v2c" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Libro manual de entrada, salida y existencia de los azogues que sa
                     hallan en los almacenes de ellos desde el l. de Enero de 1787 haste fin de
                     Diciembre de el. Por Francisco Angel Bravo de Rueda.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5254bb36157fda31bcd2e305697db348" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_9413802518c62abf852498d4afde9f71"
                     parent="aspace_5254bb36157fda31bcd2e305697db348" type="ms">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e8255f2f62d851f2f84473d295273ad1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>1787. 19 folios.</p>
                  <p>This original manuscript is an important source of information on mercury
                     production in the Huancavelica Dept. and in the province of Huarochiri, Peru.
                     Information about the dates of arrival and departure from the warehouses, the
                     weight, value, geographical source, and name of owners or shippers of the
                     mercury are specified. Reports appear throughout the year, and a summary of
                     figures for the year is given.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_7dz" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Peru (Viceroyalty). Expediente concerning witchcraft and idolatry in
                     Peru.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f2ff5ed8529d6db39562ad7f3cd17c4f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b24209cc1b0169a59985565ad2ce5b27"
                     parent="aspace_f2ff5ed8529d6db39562ad7f3cd17c4f" type="ms">4</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_888a49db1477fba8a72b5ba83db88110">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>1700. 188 folios.</p>
                  <p>This <emph render="underline">expediente</emph> contains two royal <emph
                        render="underline">cédulas</emph> issued by Charles III and Charles IV,
                     kings of Spain and the Indies. One <emph render="underline">cédula</emph> was
                     issued on June 25, 1783, at Aranjuéz, and the other, on Oct. 9, 1789, at San
                     Lorenzo del Real. In both <emph render="underline">cédulas</emph>, the Bishop
                     of Trujillo in Peru, Don Baltasar J. Martinez Compañón, is ordered not to
                     relent on his work of converting the Indians into the Christian faith. This
                        <emph render="underline">expediente</emph> also contains an edict of the
                     Bishop and correspondence between him and others under his jurisdiction in
                     relation to the same matter (ff. 1-10). This manuscript is notable because most
                     of its contents are the original records of a trial for witchcraft and idolatry
                     conducted against Salvador Bautista, Nicolás Bautista, Julián Bautista,
                     Margarita Chuquipul (Salvador's wife), Petrona Huilca (Nicolás's wife), and
                     María Paysic. Juán de Roxas, priest and vicar of the <emph render="underline"
                        >Doctrina</emph> of Atún Luya, was the acting judge and Blas de la Encidna
                     was the acting notary (ff. 11-188). The trial began on Feb. 28, 1789, and the
                     last record dated was July 9, 1790. It took place at the <emph
                        render="underline">asiento</emph> of San Juán de Lamúd, but the defendants
                     were from San Pedro de Cuemal. Between March 3 and May 11, 1789, 55 witnesses
                     were examined; they were relatives and neighbors of the defendants and almost
                     all of them certified their depositions (ff. 15-120). Confessions were taken
                     from the defendants (ff. 120-150), and the prosecution and the defense
                     presented their petitions (ff. 151-156). The sentence was pronounced on June 3,
                     1789 (ff. 157-158). The Royal Justice sentenced Salvador and Nicolás Bautista
                     and Maria Paysíc to be whipped through the streets over a packsaddle, with a
                     coronet on their heads and their backs naked. Petrona Huilca, Margarita
                     Chuquipul, and Julián Bautista were sentenced to be feathered, to wear a
                     coronet on their heads, and to serve as shield-bearers of the other offenders,
                     their punishment being left to the discretion of the executioner. While the
                     sentence was publicly performed, all the idols and instruments used by the
                     defendants in their rites were thrown into a bonfire. Immediately they were
                     expatriated to the Province of Caxamarca, confined to a house of correction in
                     perpetuity, and obliged to do hard work with rations but without salary for a
                     landowner who would provide them with the necessary prisons until their death.
                     Their houses were demolished and exorcised, and great crosses were placed on
                     the lots and on the caves, rocks, and temples they had used for their
                     rites.</p>
                  <p>The expediente includes the estimates of the cost of the trial (f. 165), the
                     inventory, valuation, and the sale by public auction of the properties of
                     Salvador and Nicolás Bautista (ff. 166-184), as well as the accounts of the
                     trustees, with credits and debits (ff. 185-188).</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_87x" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Perú (Viceroyalty). Testironio de los autos seguidos contra Mariano
                     Túpac Amaro y Andrés Mendigure sobre atribuirseles la reincidencia en la
                     revelidn Año de 1783. Real Sala del Crimen. Escribano de Cámara, Don Clemente
                     Castellanos, 1780-1783.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_35e065044f4b9a590dfcd6138e22f50c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e1841741004867d115e29575608009e7"
                     parent="aspace_35e065044f4b9a590dfcd6138e22f50c" type="ms">5</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8a1436ac05146da606c2a26e3b417eee">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú, 1780-1783. 372 folios.</p>
                  <p>Typescript from the original in a volume of <emph render="underline"
                        >Manuscritos varios</emph> desposited in the <emph render="underline"
                        >Archivo Nacional del Perú</emph>, containing testimonies on the trial for
                     relapse into rebellion, against Mariano Tupac Amaru and Andrés Mendigure, son
                     and nephew of José Gabriel Túpac Amaru, leader of the Indian insurrection
                     against the Spaniards in Perú during 1780-1781. These testimonies are not a
                     complete record of the trial. They are divided into six <emph
                        render="underline">cuadernos</emph> and one <emph render="underline"
                        >expediente</emph> with a total of 372 consecutive folios. The half title is
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">Rebelión de Túpac Amaro.</title> Tomo.
                     I. The <emph render="underline">cuadernos</emph> contain correspondence between
                     the Viceroy Agustín Jaureaui, the Bishop of Cuzco, members of the Túpac Amaru
                     family, and other civilian, military and religious dignataries, in relation to
                     the Túpac Amaru Insurrection. The <emph render="underline">cuadernos</emph>
                     also contain depositions of witnesses on the trial against Mariano Túpac Amaru
                     and Andrés Mendigure. The <emph render="underline">expediente</emph> contains
                     the claims of José Antonio Escale, <emph render="underline">Relator de la Real
                        Sala del Crimen</emph>, and Clemente Castellanos, <emph render="underline"
                        >Escribano</emph> of the same court, requesting to be paid for their work on
                     the trial against Mariano Túpac Amaru and Andrés Mendigure. Túpac Amaru and
                     Mendigure were sentenced to expartiation in Spain, the first died during the
                     trip, and Mendigure perished in a shipwreck off the coast of Portugal. For
                     further information see: <bibref>
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">La rebelión de Túpac Amaru</title> by
                        Daniel Valcárcel Esparza, <imprint>Mexico, <date calendar="gregorian"
                              era="ce">1947</date>
                        </imprint> (p. 167-168).</bibref>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_7yr" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Documentos reservados en los Autos Criminales contra Mariano Túpac
                     Amaro y Andrés Mendigure sobre reincidencias y posteriores excesos cometidos de
                     resultas de la nueva sublevación acaesida en los altos de Marcapata Provincia
                     de Quispicanchi.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3ad0537aaba36a4139d6dc0c2c329d9b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_ecb2a6f484f2d3cc4f928280f255f6c4"
                     parent="aspace_3ad0537aaba36a4139d6dc0c2c329d9b" type="ms">5A</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_296fa2b08e4d65f913312f19d6649d77">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima Perú, 1780-1783. 364 p., 249-333 p.</p>
                  <p>Typewritten copy from the original in a volume of manuscript documents
                     deposited in the Biblioteca y Archivo Nacional, Lima, Perú. Bound in a book
                     entitled <title render="doublequote" type="simple">Rebelión de Tupac Amaru,
                        Tomo II</title> (313 folios).</p>
                  <p>These confidential documents contain correspondence between the Viceroy Agustín
                     Jauregui, and some members of the Túpac Amaru family, and also with military,
                     ecclesiastical and civilian dignataries. Included are also other records of the
                     trial against Mariano Túpac Amaru and Andrés Mendigures. It is a valuable
                     source of information for researchers interested in the study of the Túpac
                     Amaru insurrection in Perú.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_ecr" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Documentos reservados en los autos criminales contra Mariano Túpac
                     Amaro y Andrés Mendigure sobre reincidencia y posteriores excesos cometidos de
                     resultas de la nueva sublevación acaesida en los altos de Marcapata Provincia
                     de Quispicanchi. Tomo segundo.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ddf8cf3155d0fc4e7cc7921074fc51c0" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_cc463fbdb53b6420097ab942e8dc0e07"
                     parent="aspace_ddf8cf3155d0fc4e7cc7921074fc51c0" type="ms">5B</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_623fdcd3b7103344d802d2c04656ebde">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>n. p. Typescript, n. d. 178 folios.</p>
                  <p>This volume is an incomplete typescript copy of MS. No. 5 containing only
                     information as far as page 305 of MS. No. 5A.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_2km" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Memorias relatives a la sublevación del Casique de Tunga-Suca José
                     Gabriel Tupac-Amaro su consecuencias y fin de este estraordinario suceso cuyo
                     acaecimiento empezó el año de 1780</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1b7699c73fff28d361e0a534f1bd8a4d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_9478929dcd34fd1e5ca8040b0b2a9398"
                     parent="aspace_1b7699c73fff28d361e0a534f1bd8a4d" type="ms">5C</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_522945e76fa86a4be87fccdf334cb7c9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú, 1780. [1], 173 p.</p>
                  <p>Negative microfilm of typed copy in the Bancroft Library, University of
                     California, Berkeley.</p>
                  <p>Motives or reasons of the insurrection of the Indians of high Perú under the
                     leadership of Don José Gabriel Túpac-Amaru Casique de Tunga-Suca.</p>
                  <p>Transferred to Newspapers and Microfilms Department.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_g07" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Pizarro, Gonzalo (1502-1548), et al. Transcripts of a collection of 19
                     letters, 1547-1548, written during the rebellion of Gonzalo Pizarro in Perú
                     (1546-1548).</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f2689e6a4fc591247b7b1ccd8717d416" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d79e9e4a752e2e67edacc33c021c0f6d"
                     parent="aspace_f2689e6a4fc591247b7b1ccd8717d416" type="ms">6</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3442efb2b94a7cb1943872a2d47f630e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>v. p., 1547-1548. Pages 378-505.</p>
                  <p>Transcripts of a collection of 19 letters, 1547-1548, written during the
                     rebellion of Gonzalo Pizarro in Perú (1546-1548) by Pedro de la Gasca
                     (1493-1567), Gonzalo Pizarro (1502-1548), Philip II (1527-1598) as Prince,
                     Lorenzo de Albana (d. 1571), and Diego Cepeda (d. 1550). These letters were
                     transcribed in a very legible hand and are related to Gonzalo Pizarro's
                     rebellion that ended with his defeat and execution as a traitor to King Charles
                     V by Pedro de la Gasca at Xaquixaguana, Perú, on April 10, 1548.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_qq2" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Odriozola, Manuel de (1804-1889). Colección de poesías modernas.
                     Recogidas por Manuel de Odriozola. Cuaderno 5º. Principiado en Lima el 1º. de
                     Marzo de 1849 y concluido en la Hacienda de la Mejorada en Huancayo, Abril,
                     Domingo 19 de 1857. 101ff., [2] ff. indice.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_00622a42a02f8152ed51345741f82149" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0d7f10f56957edda121449feee7bf041"
                     parent="aspace_00622a42a02f8152ed51345741f82149" type="ms">7</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_88d5062fd4caa164c52e2a14740d9b8e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Perú, 1849-1857. 103 folios.</p>
                  <p>Selections of poetry assembled by Odriozola consisting chiefly of sonnets,
                     several lyrics, and some burlesque forms. This volume includes: a sonnet of the
                     Spanish poet Francisco de Miranda y Vengóa (d. 1857); some poems published by
                        <emph render="underline">El Comercio</emph> (1845) and signed by Z.,
                     apparently the pseudonym of the Peruvian poet Felipe de Pardo y Aliaga
                     (1806-1868); a short story published by <emph render="underline">La
                        Bolsa</emph> (1841) and written by Manuel Ascencio Segura (1805-1871),
                     another Peruvian author; a poem of the famous Colombian poet Rafael Pombo
                     (1833-1912) published at Lima by <emph render="underline">El Heraldo</emph> on
                     Jan. 5, 1856, under the pseudonym Edda, and some other poems written by unknown
                     writers.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_3lt" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Odriozola, Manuel de (1804-1889). Copias de varies poesías. Cuaderno l
                     ro. año de 1837.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d8663c0f350743bf36fbf7e5d86834ec" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7f604abd323d0777afd94f5cc6de7b0e"
                     parent="aspace_d8663c0f350743bf36fbf7e5d86834ec" type="ms">7A</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f50d9de8e8ad18facfd2318bfe37cf1d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Perú, 1837. 56 ff., [1] f., index.</p>
                  <p>This volume also includes: some poems of Felipe Pardo Aliaga (1806-1868); a
                     short poem adapted to music ( <emph render="underline">letrilla</emph>) written
                     by Manuel Ascencio Segura (1805-1871); a ballad by an anonymous author; and a
                     poem of José Joaquín Larriva (1780-1832).</p>
                  <p>Manuscript 7a does not have Odriozola's name on it. It is attributed to him by
                     Perez de Velasco in his <title render="italic" type="simple">Catalogo de la
                        Biblioteca Peruana</title> (p. 141). In addition, the handwriting of No. 7a
                     is similiar to that in No. 7 and in other manuscripts that have Odriozola's
                     name as their compiler.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref33_efj" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Odriozola, Manuel de (1804-1889). Cartas de Heloysa y Abelardo. ff.
                     1-23. Added t. p.: Poesías antiguas y modernas. Cuaderno 4º. Principiado en el
                     año de 1837 y concluido en 22 de Marzo de 1840.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a74e0fb4362d57c80676c572a3de3a7e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
                  <container id="aspace_9148fcba12b3775fa8ab1ade4a964d8e"
                     parent="aspace_a74e0fb4362d57c80676c572a3de3a7e" type="ms">7B</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_67e567fd56c74b6b31a85474cbf125ad">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Perú. ff. 24-54, [1] f., index.</p>
                  <p>The majority of the poems in this volume were transcribed from the initial
                     issues of <title render="italic" type="simple">El Mercurio Peruano</title>
                     (1791). Included are copies of <emph render="underline">décimas</emph> (a
                     Spanish stanza consisting of ten verses of eight syllables), one <emph
                        render="underline">octava</emph> (a poetical composition of eight lines of
                     eleven syllables) written by the Peruvian poet F. M. Miranda at Trujillo, Perú,
                     in Feb., 1836, letters between Heloise and Abelard, and a few poetical works by
                     unknown writers.</p>
                  <p>Manuscript 7b does not have Odriozola's name on it. It is attributed to him by
                     Perez de Velasco in his <title render="italic" type="simple">Catalogo de la
                        Biblioteca Peruana</title> (p. 141). In addition, the handwriting of No. 7b
                     is similar to that in No. 7 and in other manuscripts that have Odriozola's name
                     as their compiler.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_icn" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Fein, John M. Una Versión Desconocida de un Poema de Pombo.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a3ad0cecf1cd0acf7ee458e324202eb9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b899500a15fabb1c453e924a3e152c28"
                     parent="aspace_a3ad0cecf1cd0acf7ee458e324202eb9" type="ms">7C</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_277b9ea3590eb096e2f0432b959fc33f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Medellín, Colombia, 1953. 1 p.</p>
                  <p>Newspaper article by Dr. Fein in <title render="italic" type="simple">El
                        Colombiano,</title>
                     <title render="doublequote" type="simple">Suplemento</title> (May 3, 1953), on
                     one of the poems in MS. No. 7 of the Peruvian Collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref37_ucz" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Perú (Viceroyalty). Documentos inéditos.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1e4e23937ab99c6f7cd6d71d794a81cc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
                  <container id="aspace_c5f74d6837b790cbda00d98ce25332b5"
                     parent="aspace_1e4e23937ab99c6f7cd6d71d794a81cc" type="ms">8</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0a613507dd7d74db45cf79eef7ffb3e5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>v. p., 1580-1818. 4 p., 182 folios.</p>
                  <p>Typewritten table of contents of the 31 manuscript documents bound in this
                     volume. 4 p.</p>
                  <p>The manuscripts are listed below in the order of appearance in this volume.
                     Each manuscript has its own pagination, if any.</p>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <item>1. Act siqned Oct. 24, 1580, by Viceroy Francisco de Toledo appointing
                        Diego de Valero Corregidor of the Valley of Ica and its District, and
                        commissioning Antonio Vadillo to take residence there. It is followed by the
                        testimony of the oath given by Valero at Chincha on Nov. 13 of the same
                        year. The appointment was limited to one year with a salary of 600 pesos.
                        ff. 119-122.</item>
                     <item>2. Questionnaire. Questions that the Judge of Residence of the Villa de
                        Santa and its Partido, Diego G. de Ocampo, will ask the witnesses giving
                        deposition on the secret information against Francisco de Mendieta who has
                        been Corregidor of that Partido and against his officers and ministers.
                        Followed by instructions and ordinances for Corregidores signed by Viceroy
                        Francisco de Toledo May 30, 1580. Followed by a testimonial that the
                        instructions and ordinances were seen by the Justice and Regiment of the
                        City of the Kings (Lima) July 1, 1580. And a testimonial that was also read
                        to the Caciques and Principales of the town of Nuestra Señora del Rosario de
                        Guarmey Aug. 15, 1580, translated by the Indian Antonio de Guamán. ff.
                        24-68.</item>
                     <item>3. Ordinances for Corregidores given at Seville on June 9, 1500, by King
                        Ferdinand and Queen Isabella and enforced in Perú and signed by Viceroy
                        Francisco de Toledo at the appointment of Gabriel de la Reguera as
                        Corregidor of the city of León de Huánuco. ff. 1-24, [12] ff. undated</item>
                     <item>4. Act signed by Viceroy Garcia Hurtado de Mendoza on March 8, 1590,
                        ordering the payment to surgeon Francisco Velázquez de Chavez from the funds
                        of the community of the Repartimiento de Mama for the medical care given to
                        the Indians during the epidemic of that region. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>5. Royal Cédula signed at Madrid on Dec. 5, 1603, by King Philip III
                        commanding the Viceroy of Peru, Gaspar de Zuñiga Azevedo y Fonseca, Conde de
                        Monterrey, to execute the order given to his predecessor, Viceroy Luis de
                        Velasco, Marqués de Salinas, in relation to providing the needs of four
                        Jesuit missionaries, residents in Santa Cruz de la Sierra. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>6. Decree signed by Viceroy Juán de Mendoza y Luna, Marqués de Montes
                        Claros, on July 12, 1615, granting a loan of 8500 pesos to Gaspar Rodriguez
                        de Castro from the funds paid by the Indians to the community. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>7. Royal Cédula signed at San Lorenzo on Aug. 27, 1617, by King Philip
                        III confirming the Encomienda de Indios granted by the Viceroy of Peru, Juán
                        de Mendoza y Luna, Marqués de Montes Claros, to Diego Peñalosa y Briceño for
                        two generations, on condition that he contribute one-third of his profits to
                        the royal funds of the city of Lima. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>8. Act by the Royal Audiencia of Lima presided over by and signed by
                        Viceroy Luis Geronimo Fernandez de Cabrera y Bobadilla, Conde de Chinchón,
                        on Sept. 6, 1633, granting loans of 374 pesos from the funds of the Indians
                        of the Repartimiento de Lunaguana to Alonso de Torres Romero and to Luis
                        Sánchez de Garro for the payment of their tribute from one-third of San Juan
                        that year. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>9. Instructions signed by Viceroy Pedro de Toledo y Leiva, Marqués de
                        Mancera, on Nov. 6, 1643, for the deposition of accounts and Residencia to
                        be given by Pedro de Valladares, recently appointed Corregidor of the City
                        of Piura. ff. 1-24</item>
                     <item>10. Act signed by Viceroy Pedro de Toledo y Leiva, Marqués de Mancera, on
                        Aug. 17, 1644, commanding the Administrator of funds of the Censo de Indios
                        de Lima to deliver to the Fiscal Protector de Naturales the amount of pesos
                        written in the adjunct certificate. f. 29</item>
                     <item>11. Ordinances signed by Viceroy Pedro de Toledo y Leiva, Marqués de
                        Mancera, on Aug. 27, 1644, directing Geronimo de Palma y Mayorga to observe
                        and execute them while performing his duties as Justicia Mayor of the
                        Province of Condesuyos. ff. 9-46.</item>
                     <item>12. Royal Cédula signed by King Charles II at Buen Retiro on Feb. 12,
                        1677, addressed to the Viceroy and to the members of the Royal Audiencia of
                        Lima reminding them about the oath of secrecy and confidentiality to observe
                        while performing their duties. Followed by the testimony that the Cédula was
                        read during the May 16, 1678, meeting of the Real Acuerdo. 2 ff.</item>
                     <item>13. Letter signed by Queen Mariana at Madrid on Dec., 1665, addressed to
                        the Archbishop of Lima requesting a donation for the Spanish government that
                        was in dire economic straits. The last four lines were handwritten by the
                        Queen who was the wife of King Philip IV and the mother of King Charles II.
                        f. 324.</item>
                     <item>14. Letter of Censure signed by the Archbishop of Lima, Pedro de
                        Villagómez, on Dec. 29, 1659, demanding the return of a sequestered slave. 1
                        f.</item>
                     <item>15. Letter of Censure signed by the members of the Cabildo Eclesiástico
                        Metropolitano de Lima on March 18, 1672, asking for the return of 3,000
                        pesos taken from the home of Simón Vaez Enriquez. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>16. Decree signed by Viceroy Melchor de Navarra y Rocafull, Duque de la
                        Palata, on July 19, 1689, granting a loan of 5,000 pesos from the funds of
                        Caja de Censos to the funds of la Comunidad to repair damages at the
                        Cathedral of Lima caused by the 1685 earthquake. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>17. Order of payment of the Real Audiencia de Lima presided over and
                        signed by Viceroy Melchor de Navarra y Rocafull, Duque de la Palata, on
                        Sept. 1, 1688, ordering the Caja de Censos to pay 125 pesos to the lawyer
                        Francisco de Rojas y Acevedo for his services to that institution during 6
                        months. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>18. Letter of Censure signed by the Archbishop of Lima, Melchor de Liñán
                        y Cisneros, on June 10, 1694, demanding the return of a sequestered black
                        slave to her owner, Fabián de Viñas y Coca. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>19. A decree signed by the Archbishop of Lima, Melchor de Liñán y
                        Cisneros, on March 23, 1691. Archbishop Cisneros was Viceroy of Perú from
                        1678 to 1681 when he was replaced at the viceroyalty by the Duque de la
                        Palata, but he remained in Lima as Archbishop and as a member of the Royal
                        Council. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>20. Royal Cédula signed by King Philip V at Madrid on Feb. 19, 1714,
                        demanding the Real Audiencia de Lima to see that the Juzgado de Bienes de
                        Difuntos delivers all the properties that belonged to Fr. Pablo de
                        Villanueva as ordered by the royal cédula. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>21. Seven letters signed by Viceroy José de Armendáriz, Marqués de
                        Castelfuerte, addressed to the Corregidor de Canas y Canches, Miguel de
                        Santistevan, between June, 1724, and July, 1732. 7 ff.</item>
                     <item>22. Royal Cédula signed by King Charles III at Aranjuéz on May 20, 1768,
                        commanding the Tribunal de Cuentas (Court of Accounts) not to charge the
                        Corregidores with Derecho de Tiras (cost of courts) for the arrangement of
                        their accounts. 2 ff.</item>
                     <item>23. Act signed by Viceroy José de Armendáriz, Marqués de Castelfuerte, on
                        Feb. 8, 1726, appointing Antonio de Luna Castañón to receive the testimonies
                        on the trial against Antonio de Ugarte. ff. 121-122.</item>
                     <item>24. Official letter signed by Viceroy Teodoro de Croix on March 27, 1789,
                        addressed to the Real Tribunal de Minería in relation to the awarding of a
                        mine. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>25. Edict signed by the Archbishop of Lima, Juán Domingo González de la
                        Reguera, about a chaplaincy ( capellanía) founded by Francisco Girón
                        Cabezas. Dated Aug. 27, 1789. 2 ff.</item>
                     <item>26. Official letter signed by Viceroy Francisco Gil y Lemus on March 18,
                        1791, addressed to the Real Acuerdo in relation to the tariff of duties on
                        some sequestered lands. f. 39.</item>
                     <item>27. Official letter signed by Viceroy Ambrosio O' Higgins, Marqués de
                        Osorno, on April 27, 1799, addressed to the Regente de la Real Audiencia de
                        Lima in relation to a judicial formality in the trial of the Conde de Fuente
                        González against the Marqués de Zelada de la Fuente. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>28. Order signed by Viceroy José Fernando de Abascal y Sousa, Marqués de
                        la Concordia, on Aug. 14, 1807, addressed to the Oydór Decano de la Real
                        Audiencia de Lima, in relation to the collection of papers related to a
                        decree of the same date. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>29. Official letter signed by Viceroy Joaquín de la Pezuela y Sanchez,
                        Marqués de Vilumá, on May 10, 1818, requesting from the Indendente of
                        Huamanga a list of all the military chiefs and officers under his command in
                        that territory. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>30. Official letter signed by the General en Jefe del Ejercito del Alto
                        Perú, José de la Serna, on Oct. 20, 1818, addressed to the Presidente del
                        Cuzco ordering the construction of equipment for the army as soon as
                        possible. 1 f.</item>
                     <item>31. Royal Cédula signed by King Ferdinand VII on Oct...., 1818, granting
                        the Reales Beneficios to the Province of Cuzco and giving the title of
                        Fidelísima to its capital, the city of Cuzco. 2 ff.</item>
                  </list>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref41_ta2" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Libro de la Razon de Salidas correspondientes a la Contaduria Pral. de
                     los Efectos que se Registran el las Embarcaciones que Salen pare los Reynos de
                     España y Otros Puertos de Esta Mar del Sur en el presente Año de
                     1774.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_bee33cecc9f1a7d153b38384c56492be" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f582683b9fb20a1cecbf5fc6a05a0a8f"
                     parent="aspace_bee33cecc9f1a7d153b38384c56492be" type="ms">9</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_362a74fdad300a6cefd57e2f7ac75436">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Callao, Perú, 1774. 91 pages.</p>
                  <p>This original manuscript is a register of goods exported in ships from the port
                     of Callao, Perú, to Spain and other ports of the Southern Sea during 1774.
                     Names of the owners or shippers of the goods, dates of registration, names of
                     the ships, descriptions of the goods, ports of destination, names of the
                     persons to whom the goods are sent, numbers of the invoices and the value of
                     the goods are specified. The first pages include an index by the first name of
                     the shippers. On the last two pages of the volume there is a summary of the
                     invoices included in this book with an estimate of the value of the goods. This
                     manuscript is an important source of information on commerce and shipping in
                     Perú during 1774.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_dda" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Monzón, Pascual Antonio Data de Penas de Camara, su Rezor. Gral. Dn.
                     Pasqual Anto. Monzon. Año de 1777. Data de los Pesos que voy pagando en Virtud
                     de Decretos del Superior Govierno y demas Tribunales a Saver. Desde 1º. de
                     Agosto de 1777. Penas de Camara. Gastos de Justicia.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a6a62a553545103b1c8c09df2ec59abe" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
                  <container id="aspace_eef5f6b3cf0e990fa42d5bdd537da220"
                     parent="aspace_a6a62a553545103b1c8c09df2ec59abe" type="ms">10</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3a0780aa2b3b6a15f133be21ce8e9c1d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, 1777-1779. 15 folios.</p>
                  <p>Account book of the payments that D. Pasqual Antonio Monzon made from the funds
                     of <emph render="underline">Penas de Cámara</emph> to cover the <emph
                        render="underline">Gastos de Justicia</emph>. <emph render="underline">Penas
                        de Cámara</emph> were the pecuniary penalties or fines imposed by the judges
                     and the courts. These funds were deposited in the Royal Treasury. <emph
                        render="underline">Gastos de Justicia</emph> were the expenditures incurred
                     by the different activities of the Administration of Justice and were paid from
                     the funds of the <emph render="underline">Penas de Cámara</emph>.</p>
                  <p>This original manuscript includes the names of the persons who received the
                     payments for services to assist the Administration of Justice and the decrees
                     and sentences that ordered the payments. The records date between Aug., 1777,
                     and Nov., 1779, at Lima, Perú.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref45_8h5" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Florez, Tomás. Prontuario de capellanías fundadas en el
                     Perú.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_24403759003869dad145d05f5e27e42f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a1ded546a0e6758dee4b329914c6f1c4"
                     parent="aspace_24403759003869dad145d05f5e27e42f" type="ms">11</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d1a0916a80c166127c86e20faf24723d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Perú, 1564-1718. Bound, 1821. [19], 283 folios.</p>
                  <p>This volume contains résumés of <emph render="underline">capellanías</emph> in
                     Perú examined since 1680, the year in which the Licenciado Don Francisco de
                     Xauregui was appointed <emph render="underline">Visitador de
                     Capellanías</emph>. The <emph render="underline">capellanía</emph>, or
                     chaplaincy, was capital, the interest of which was required by Spanish law for
                     the support of an ecclesiastic whose duties were to celebrate masses and to
                     perform other pious obligations. The résumés include information about the
                     nature, purposes, and duties imposed by the founders of the <emph
                        render="underline">capellanías</emph>, the persons that possessed them in
                     full right or on an interim basis, and the patrons responsible for the
                     appointments. The <emph render="underline">capellanías</emph> described in this
                        <emph render="underline">prontuario</emph> were founded between 1564 (f.
                     120) and 1683 (f. 211). Notations added to the original résumés date as late as
                     1718 (f. 231).</p>
                  <p>One of the common watermarks on the paper resembles watermarks illustrated in
                     Edward Heawood, <bibref>
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">Watermarks Mainly of the 17th and 18th
                           Centuries</title>
                        <imprint>(Hilversum, Holland, <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">
                              1957)</date>
                        </imprint>, Pl. 114-119.</bibref> These watermarks date between 1665 and
                     1766, and it is reasonable to assume that this paper was manufactured and used
                     during this period.</p>
                  <p>The dates of the <emph render="underline">capellanías</emph> and the notations
                     about them and the dating of the watermarks all indicate that the documents
                     bound in this volume date from the late 17th century and early 18th
                     century.</p>
                  <p>This volume was ordered to be bound in 1821 by Presbitero Tomás Florez, <emph
                        render="underline">Archivero de la Curia Eclesiastica and Colector del
                        Donativo Eclesiastico Voluntario</emph>. This event was apparently provoked
                     by changes in the Spanish law that prohibited the foundation of new <emph
                        render="underline">capellanías</emph> and ordered the incorporation of their
                     properties to the government treasury during 1820 and 1821. This legislation
                     was cancelled in 1823.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_ycj" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Convenio celebrado entre los generales de los ejércitos titulados
                     nacional y del gobierno de Chile, Mayo 3, 1814.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_40aeac8946595b43bca4e1a12466fb73" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
                  <container id="aspace_ae6221f7cf6d8f9ff1a01a5df67d9edf"
                     parent="aspace_40aeac8946595b43bca4e1a12466fb73" type="ms">12</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_722978cce14fcecdbc88cb479d79d500">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lircay River, near Talca, Chile. Copy, ca. 1814. 3 pages.</p>
                  <p>The agreement was reached the 3rd of May, 1814, on the banks of the Lircay
                     River near the city of Talca. It was signed by the general in chief of the
                     national army, Brigadier Gabino Gainza and the principal chiefs of the army of
                     the government of Chile, Generals Bernardo O'Higgins and Juan Mackenna. In this
                     agreement Chile offered to send deputies to the Cortes as its representatives,
                     and as an integral part of the Spanish monarchy; to recognize Ferdinand VII as
                     its monarch, and the Regency that approved the Junta of Chile, that will act as
                     interior government with all its power and faculties. Chile would have free
                     commerce with the allied and the neutral nations, especially with Great
                     Britain. The royalist army would evacuate Chilean territory, ending the
                     hostilities; and properties confiscated after February of 1810 would be
                     restored.</p>
                  <p>Don José Abascal, Viceroy of Perú, disapproved the agreement and sent to Chile
                     another expedition in July, 1814, that undertook the campaign that ended with
                     the Battle of Rancagua, retaining Chile under Spanish domain till 1824.</p>
                  <p>The paper on which the agreement is written was made in Capellades, Catalonia,
                     Spain, by the Almirall family who produced paper there for a long period of
                     time. Three examples of their work are illustrated and discussed in Oriol Valls
                     I Subirà, <bibref>
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">Paper and Watermarks in
                           Catalonia</title>
                        <imprint>
                           <geogname>(Amsterdam, </geogname>
                           <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1970)</date>
                        </imprint>, Vol. I, plates 2-3, and Vol. II, p. 238.</bibref> All the
                     examples date during 1804-1824, and those of 1807 and 1809 most closely
                     resemble the watermarks on the manuscript. These facts suggest that the paper
                     on which this copy of the agreement is written and the copy itself are
                     reasonably contemporary with the signing of the agreement in 1814. This copy of
                     the agreement differs from the one published in the second volume of <title
                        render="italic" type="simple">Archivo de don Bernardo O'Higgins</title>
                     (Santiago de Chile, 1947), pp. 156-159. Some words are missing, and others are
                     written with misspellings common in South America during that period, for
                     example the signatures of O'Higgins and Mackenna.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref49_hgw" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Lambayeque. Peru (Dept.) Descripcion geografica, demostrativa y
                     evidente de la ciudad de Lambayeque su cituacion y estencion. Numero de pueblos
                     y havitantes de todo su partido sur cabildos y tribunales, edificios; segun la
                     razon estadistica que se pide, y en que abraza su enumeracion el estado
                     politico y militar el economico civil y eclesiastieo de este
                     partido.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_af2bd7cfa0c79b16a4100981c48976bb" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
                  <container id="aspace_da37ccdddcb45de833db9fc9823f92ee"
                     parent="aspace_af2bd7cfa0c79b16a4100981c48976bb" type="ms">13</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e270b24e708f51802b9378e53c0d63bc">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>n.p., ca. 1821-1822. [94] pages.</p>
                  <p>This manuscript was written to be delivered into the hands of José de San
                     Martin, as is stated in its first page. It is a geographic description of the
                     Department of Lambayeque, Perú. It includes information on towns, population,
                     courts, buildings, and describes the political, military, and ecelesiastieal
                     organizations together with the eeonomie conditions of the department.</p>
                  <p>San Martin proclaimed the independence of Perú on July 28, 1821, assuming the
                     title of <emph render="doublequote">Protector</emph>. He held the protectorship
                     and military command until September, 1822, when he resigned and relinguished
                     power to the new Peruvian Congress. These facts suggest that this description
                     was written during the period of the protectorship and is either an original or
                     a copy contemporary with the years 1821-1822.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref51_vme" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Apuntamientos de novedades</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_052400185d602f4dbb649e635936a549" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
                  <container id="aspace_54afb7233f3f41143953341d1ec00c7e"
                     parent="aspace_052400185d602f4dbb649e635936a549" type="ms">14</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_590a5f65d0d64c5f90bc09b41d4c21c7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>v. p., 1700-1702. Folios 372-378.</p>
                  <p>Manuscripts concerned with the succession of Charles II, King of Spain, by
                     Philip V, Madrid, March 20, 1702, ff. 372-373. News received at the Port of
                     Buenos Aires from San Gabriel Island, signed by Bartolomé Montellano, n. d., f.
                     374. Copies of two letters from the Governor of Havana addressed to General
                     Mascarau, dated on April 29, and on May 6, 1700, ff. 375-376. Two additional
                     reports related to the same period, n. d., ff. 377-378.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref53_pkq" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Viage que hicieron á Manoa los RR. PP. Fray Manuel Gil, Comisionado de
                     las Misiones Seráficas, Fray Valentín Arrieta Misionero Apostolico y Francisco
                     de Josef, Guardian actual del Colegio Fide de Santa Rosa de Opoca. año de
                     1767.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a4c4a6c6085ddd197a8391689af3f78e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d31f05c9fdb316a563ef8ae11d980d2e"
                     parent="aspace_a4c4a6c6085ddd197a8391689af3f78e" type="ms">15</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8f9dc80cb05110c6244139774292f083">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>n.p. copy, ca. 1767. [6] folios.</p>
                  <p>Fr. Manuel Gil was the leader of this Franciscan missionary expedition to Manoa
                     in El Dorado territory where the Indians were revolting during the year 1767.
                     He had a name similar to the eminent Jesuit mathematician and physicist Manuel
                     Gervasio Gil (1745-1807), who, according to information from <bibref>
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">Enciclopedia Universal
                           Ilustrada</title>
                        <imprint>(Espasa-Calpe, S.A., <geogname>Madrid, </geogname>
                           <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1925)</date>
                        </imprint> Vol. XXVI, p. 34,</bibref> was at Río de la Plata and was
                     expelled together with other Jesuits to Italy during 1767. Considering the
                     distance between Lima and Río de la Plata and the fact that one was a
                     Franciscan and the other a Jesuit, it is difficult to believe that it was the
                     same person. The information about the Indians' revolt in Manoa and the
                     difficulties suffered by the members of the missionary expedition, including a
                     list of the missionaries and Christian Indians killed during the revolt make
                     this manuscript copy an important one (see folio [6]).</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref55_ma0" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Pérignon, Dominique Catherine de (1754-1818). Memoria presentada por el
                     Embajador de Francia al Excmo. Sr. Príncipe de la Paz. Madrid, 25 de Abril de
                     1797.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_596923bfbfee0f9707f656f9220e0d3b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
                  <container id="aspace_998e5ef941d0e0f71c28a6342574f53a"
                     parent="aspace_596923bfbfee0f9707f656f9220e0d3b" type="ms">16</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fd192575127960b563ffa99f57581b64">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Madrid, Spain, 1797. Copy, [2] folios.</p>
                  <p>Manuscript copy of the memorandum sent to Manuel Godoy (1767-1851), Prince of
                     the Peace, and Prime Minister of Spain, on April 25, 1797, by Dominique
                     Catherine de Pérignon (1754-1818), French Ambassador in Spain. Contains an
                     inquiry relative to a naval engagement between English and Spanish warships,
                     and expresses the opinion of the French Directory censuring the conduct of the
                     Spanish warships for not fighting the English warships during that naval
                     engagement, and requesting the punishment of those responsible.</p>
                  <p>Followed by: Diario de Montevideo, containing news gathered from ships that put
                     in at the Port of Montevideo from June 30 to July 11, 1797. Includes
                     information about the more important events in Europe and in other Spanish
                     colonies during the previous months, with a report about the ships arriving at
                     and departing from that port during those days.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref57_p63" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Andrade, Marcos de. Copia de los inventarios de las alhajas de esta
                     Santa Iglesia Metropolitana de los Reyes. 20 de enero de 1797.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_853312721d9c56120775c1d1ae43e303" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
                  <container id="aspace_74610bfda1e75ce3a46e9b32b3b5697d"
                     parent="aspace_853312721d9c56120775c1d1ae43e303" type="ms">17</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e7e5653ee07ad192674d574508bbab2d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú, 1797. [11] folios.</p>
                  <p>Manuscript copy of the inventories of the church property in the Santa Iglesia
                     Metropolitana de los Reyes at Lima, Perú, on Jan. 20, 1797. It includes: sacred
                     vestments, engraved silver, relics, linen, images, bells, books of anthems,
                     precious stones set in gold or silver, and goods and ornaments of the chapels
                     of Santa Ana and Santa Isabel in that church. There is a note at the end
                     explaining that the inventory of the goods and ornaments of the altar of
                     Nuestra Señora de la Antigua is not included because they are the property of
                     the University of San Marcos. The University uses that altar to deliver the
                     major degrees in public ceremony. The inventories were finished on Jan. 20,
                     1797, and signed by Marcos de Andrade.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref59_krf" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Perú. Ministerio de Hacienda Cuaderno 2º de oficios y consultas que
                     empezó a correr el año de 1825.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6c3d2041714416c5b25ffa2c22d89681" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7bd2f7291aa6b62efb461abfb7810973"
                     parent="aspace_6c3d2041714416c5b25ffa2c22d89681" type="ms">18</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_581d8e8106705ccf04e2d4371f408dd7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú, 1825-1826. 35 folios.</p>
                  <p>This original manuscript is a memorandum book of the General Treasury of the
                     Ministry of Finance of Perú. It contains copies of: official letters, proposals
                     from the General Treasury to the Minister of Finance related to state
                     properties ordering their sequestration from the tenants for not paying the
                     rent, a report of the salaries of the staff of the General Treasury, and other
                     proposals related to business to be solved by that ministry between April 22,
                     1825, and January 17, 1826.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref61_daq" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Alvarez Morán, Antonio. Libro de cuentas correspondiente a la general
                     que el albacea lleva con la testamentaría del finado D. Antonio Alvarez Morán
                     desde 4 de Julio de 1820.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_975d6806f6822e215bb71bd208d92b21" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
                  <container id="aspace_05aaeaad8887f30b9f9b73bda4d55b76"
                     parent="aspace_975d6806f6822e215bb71bd208d92b21" type="ms">19</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fe7a2f89847a8d966d0a24192d093833">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú, 1820-1823. 21 folios.</p>
                  <p>This original manuscript is one of the account books of the general account of
                     the testamentary execution of the estate of the late Don Antonio Alvarez Morán,
                     carried out by the testamentary executor Don Francisco Valerio Gassols. This
                     volume includes different accounts: one for the amount received according to
                     the inventory; one for the amount collected from rents and sales; and another
                     account for the value of the jewels, slaves, engraved silver, furniture,
                     vehicles for transporting persons or goods, and animals in the possession of
                     the widow. At the end is a list of the goods that were in the possession of the
                     testamentary executor including the amount of 29,815 pesos and 4 1/2 reales
                     given as a stipend for his labor on March 31, 1823. It is followed by a list of
                     the debts of the estate of the late Don Antonion Alvarez Morán.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref63_89z" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Solís y Rivadeneyra, Antonio de, 1610-1686. Obras líricas de Don
                     Antonio de Solís.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0bef697213b68c17cb0f369ae218a23c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
                  <container id="aspace_db543024e704c2d09dab622fe331b06e"
                     parent="aspace_0bef697213b68c17cb0f369ae218a23c" type="ms">20</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d1b0015cf219a7743b08c978431b2fc1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Copy, n. d. 94 pages</p>
                  <p>The undated original of this typescript is contained in a volume of <emph
                        render="underline">Manuscritos varios</emph> at the Archivo Nacional del
                     Perú. There are 104 poems written in serveral forms, including sonnets and
                     ballads.</p>
                  <p>Solís, a Spanish dramatist and historian, studied law at Salamanca, and in 1654
                     was appointed Secretary of State as well as Private Secretary to Philip IV of
                     Spain. Later he obtained the lucrative post of Chronicler of the Indies. His
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">Historia de la Conquista de
                        Méjico,</title> deservedly ranks as a Spanish prose classic. It was
                     published in 1684; an English translation by Townshend appeared in 1724.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref65_u7t" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>San Román, Miguel de, Pres. Perú. (1802-1863) Mensaje del Presidente de
                     la República al Congreso Extraordinario de 1863.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a88d145e38970e8afe90206ca4b45c6f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d05d57d58dc7545d0c4056be8a9d7ee1"
                     parent="aspace_a88d145e38970e8afe90206ca4b45c6f" type="ms">21</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6b4dd7a31dfad4b796dbd65a1d4a206d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú, Feb. 5, 1863. 3 pages.</p>
                  <p>Typewritten copy of the message sent to the Extraordinary Congress of 1863 by
                     Miguel de San Román, President of Perú, together with the budget proposal
                     submitted to that Congress for its approval on Feb. 5, 1863. President San
                     Román died on April 3, 1863, less than two months after the date of this
                     message.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref67_c3n" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Castilla, Ramón, Pres. Perú (1797-1867) Discurso del Presidente de la
                     República, al cerrar las sesiones del Congreso Extraordinario de
                     1850.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_baf3381991c3e29144c567cdafd7b58d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
                  <container id="aspace_9efb69191521699e026f2fe3e8065fb8"
                     parent="aspace_baf3381991c3e29144c567cdafd7b58d" type="ms">22</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9d37a39061336a4726827543e374d53e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú, March 26, 1850. 24 pages.</p>
                  <p>Manuscript copy of the speech delivered by Ramón Castilla, President of Perú,
                     to the last session of the 1850 Extraordinary Congress, on March 26 of the same
                     year. It is a report of his government in the last five years (1845-1850), and
                     an acknowledgement to the Congress of its collaboration. After Perú became a
                     Republic in 1820, Castilla was the first president to complete his first term
                     in government without an insurrection against him. He is considered by
                     historians the most influential political figure in Perú during the 19th
                     century.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref69_bs0" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Zevallos, Mariano H. Mensaje de S. E. el Primer Vice-Presidente de la
                     República.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d3c3cac8b656f6e55205735777455bf2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
                  <container id="aspace_2c8df92ec718852faadcf52b325784da"
                     parent="aspace_d3c3cac8b656f6e55205735777455bf2" type="ms">23</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c5591d839476887c8094b45c144b9341">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú, July 28, 1872. 4 pages.</p>
                  <p>Typewritten copy of the message sent to the Congress by Mariano H. Zevallos,
                     First Vice-President of Perú, when by constitutional mandate he became
                     President of Perú following the assassination of President José Balta Montero
                     (1814-1872). President Balta was murdered on July 26, 1872, one week before the
                     end of his term of office.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref71_ak3" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Valle y Caviedes, Juán del, 1652-1692. Caviedes. Colección de sus
                     poesías.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_964f485ce41686aded54705e9fc0f4b0" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d6dcdd353492fa77730264e079f2a39c"
                     parent="aspace_964f485ce41686aded54705e9fc0f4b0" type="ms">24</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2216645b7223e1a9865e97208143d789">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Siglo XVII. 289 ff.</p>
                  <p>Juán del Valle y Caviedes was the first satirical poet in Perú.</p>
                  <p>According to the typed memorandum of F. Pérez de Velasco, dated Lima, March 26,
                     1908, that is in the front of this volume, Ricardo Palma brought out a later
                     edition of the poetry of Juán del Valle y Caviedes based on a manuscript copy
                     from the library of Cipriano Coronel Zegarra. The manuscript copy, here in the
                     Peruvian Collection, written at the second half of the 17th century, of the
                     poems of Caviedes was very useful for correcting errors in the copies published
                     by Ricardo Palma. It includes more than sixty unpublished sonnets and many
                     other unedited poems of Caviedes. Copies of his poems are preceded by an
                     incomplete poem of an unknown author. The table of contents is incomplete, but
                     there are two typed copies that include all the titles of the poems in the
                     manuscript.</p>
                  <p>According to a bibliographical note of the Peruvian literary historian Rubén
                     Vargas Ugarte on page xxi of vol. I of his collection <title render="italic"
                        type="simple">Clasicos Peruanos</title> entitled <bibref>
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">Obras de Don Juán del Valle y
                           Caviedes</title>
                        <imprint>
                           <geogname>(Lima, </geogname>
                           <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1947)</date>
                        </imprint>
                     </bibref>, this is the oldest ant complete manuscript consulted, and he used it
                     as a guide for the compilation of the complete works of the poet. The
                     watermarks on the paper resemble watermarks illustrated in Edward Heawood, <bibref>
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">Watermarks Mainly of the 17th and 18th
                           Centuries</title>
                        <imprint>(Hilversum, Holland, 1975)</imprint>, Pl. 114-119</bibref>, used on
                     paper manufactured between 1665 and 1766, and it is reasonable to assume, as
                     Pérez de Velasco did in his typed memorandum, that this manuscript was written
                     at the end of the 17th century.</p>
                  <p>Caviedes, known as the riverbank poet, (el poeta de la ribera), revealed in his
                     poems a profound rancor against physicians, but his ingenuous and burlesque
                     versification was simple and unaffected, without any trace of " gongorismo," a
                     lofty style of writing commonly used by poets during that period.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref73_nj8" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Lima (Ecclesiastical Province) Council, 1772. Pareceres que se hen dado
                     sobre los puntos pertenecientes al actual Concilio Provincial celebrado en esta
                     ciudad de los Reyes del Perú.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b7181f212ce4633dfdebe1ade0c6a0a1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">10</container>
                  <container id="aspace_195f0313e379852766a36430efa99bef"
                     parent="aspace_b7181f212ce4633dfdebe1ade0c6a0a1" type="ms">25</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_69a2361d355a5164422718b6ef08387c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Años de 1772 a 1773. 1014 pages.</p>
                  <p>The <emph render="underline">Concilio Provincial</emph> is an assembly of the
                     clergy of an ecclesiastical province gathered to deliberate upon points of
                     doctrine and discipline of the Catholic religion. The decisions approved by
                     these councils are an important source of canon law in the Catholic Church.
                     This manuscript of more than 1,000 pages contains 49 opinions handed down by
                     the consultants that participated in the <emph render="underline">Concilio
                        Provincial</emph> that took place in Lima, Perú, during 1772-1773. This was
                     the last <emph render="underline">Concilio</emph> that took place in Lima under
                     the Spanish rule. The Archbishopric of Lima was highly interested in obtaining
                     this manuscript from the owners of the Pérez de Velasco collection to whom they
                     made a very substantial offer. This manuscript is an excellent source of
                     information for researchers interested in the study of the history of the
                     Catholic Church in Spanish America, and of the treatment given to the Indians
                     by the Catholic Church during the colonial period.</p>
                  <p>The record of proceedings and resolutions of this <emph render="underline"
                        >Concilio</emph> were published by Rubén Vargas Ugarte in volume II of <bibref>
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">Concilios Limenses (1551-1772),</title>
                        <imprint>
                           <geogname>Lima, </geogname>
                           <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1952.</date>
                        </imprint>
                     </bibref> The same author published in 1945, <title render="italic"
                        type="simple">Manuscritos Peruanos en las Bibliotecas América</title> in
                     which he describes, in a summary form, the opinions expressed in this
                     manuscript. Also included are the names of the consultants and the subjects
                     treated in the opinions above mentioned. (See pp.237-240).</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref75_v9l" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Odriozola, Manuel de (1804-1889). Papeles Varios de la Biblioteca
                     Nacional.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a4ed30ca5bcc2ed7566ddcc5ebeec1ff" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b1df434cd1c4578d36259632f66646c8"
                     parent="aspace_a4ed30ca5bcc2ed7566ddcc5ebeec1ff" type="ms">26</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fb41924f027d65d7b84af9de24237aec">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú, 1879. 102 folios.</p>
                  <p>Manuscript copies of originals in the Biblioteca Nacional assembled by
                     Odriozola during 1879. There are poetical works by Felipe Pardo Aliaga
                     (1806-1868), Juan del Valle y Caviedes (1652-1692) and by other poets (folios
                     1-38). Among the prose selections are: <title render="doublequote"
                        type="simple"> Introducción a la historia de los Incas del Perú</title>
                     published in <title render="italic" type="simple">El Mercurio Peruano</title>
                     No. 176, Sept. 9, 1792, (folios 39-45); <title render="doublequote"
                        type="simple">Ejecucion de la pena de muerte impuesta al asesino del General
                        Sucre,</title> copy of the original printed in <title render="italic"
                        type="simple">Bogotá,</title> Nov. 30, 1842 (folios 45-49); <title
                        render="doublequote" type="simple">Diversas noticias historicas. Los
                        Portugueses y la Inquisición</title> (folios 49-52); <title
                        render="doublequote" type="simple">Gigantes,</title> (folio 52); <title
                        render="doublequote" type="simple">Enigma,</title> poem, (folio 53); <title
                        render="doublequote" type="simple">Volcán de Ubinas,</title> (folios 53-54);
                        <title render="doublequote" type="simple">Monstruo,</title> (folio 54);
                        <title render="doublequote" type="simple">Civilización Ratuna</title>
                     published in <title render="italic" type="simple">El Instructor
                        Peruano,</title> (folio 55); <title render="doublequote" type="simple">Ruina
                        de Pasto</title> published in <title render="italic" type="simple">El
                        Nacional,</title>
                     <title render="doublequote" type="simple">Caracas</title> (folios 55-56);
                        <title render="doublequote" type="simple">El Baile de los
                        Mostrencos,</title> poem, (folios 56-57); <title render="doublequote"
                        type="simple">¡Hoy trace un año! En el Aniversario de las matanzas de
                        Arequipa del 25 de Noviembre de 1849,</title> poem (folios 58-60); <title
                        render="doublequote" type="simple">A la Paz,</title> poem (folio 60); <title
                        render="doublequote" type="simple">Soneto, Decima and Estrofa
                        suelta,</title> poems (folio 61); <title render="doublequote" type="simple"
                        >José Marla de Cordova y Urrutia, Restablecimiento de los Archivos
                        destruidos pare former una exacta historia del Perú,</title> published in
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">El Comercio</title> Nos. 2,796 and
                     2,800, Oct. 25 and 27, 1848. (folios 61-66); <title render="doublequote"
                        type="simple">Haciendas o fundos rústicos que en el Perú pertenecieron á los
                        Jesuítas y que fueron vendidas durante los ocho primeros años despuesde la
                        expulsion</title> (folios 66-67); <title render="doublequote" type="simple"
                        >Fundación de la Iglesia y Convento de la Compañía de Jesús que se arruinó
                        en la inundacion del mar en el Callao á cause del terremoto del 28 de
                        Octubre de 1746</title> copied by Odriozola from an unfinished chronicle of
                     the Society of Jesus dated 1651-1653 at the National Library in Lima, March 26,
                     1879 (folios 68-91); <title render="doublequote" type="simple">Carte annua de
                        1639 del Provincial de la Sociedad de la Companía de Jesús del Colegio de
                        San Pablo de Lima al General de dicha Compañía en Roma detallandole el
                        estreno del Nuevo Templo de San Pablo, conocido troy por San Pedro,
                        verificado el 31 de Julio de 1638</title> (folios 92-94); <title
                        render="doublequote" type="simple">Ceremonial en el recibimiento de los
                        Virreyes,</title> signed at Lima on June 25, 1747, by Alvaro Navia Bolaños y
                     Moscoso and copied by Odriozola from the original at the National Library on
                     Oct. 14, 1879 (folios 95-101); followed by a newspaper clipping of a poem
                     titled <title render="doublequote" type="simple">No hay que
                        precipitarse</title> published in <title render="italic" type="simple">El
                        Nacional</title> on March 7, 1879. Odriozola finished assembling this volume
                     on Oct. 14, 1879.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref77_h0k" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Cordova y Urrutia, José Maria de. Restablecimiento de los archives
                     destruídos pare former una exacta historia del Perú.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e38d7da06cb46c9741939ff0b09626cc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
                  <container id="aspace_577bf4496f6107492886de21588afcef"
                     parent="aspace_e38d7da06cb46c9741939ff0b09626cc" type="ms">27</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3715854ad83af991e1acba8010f08f14">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú, 1848. 16 pages. copy.</p>
                  <p>Manuscript copy of articles published in <title render="italic" type="simple"
                        >El Comercio,</title> Nos. 2796 and 2800 on Oct. 25 and 27, 1848,
                     recommending the restoration of the Peruvian archives. This manuscript copy is
                     exactly the same as the one in MS. 26, folios 61-66.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref79_2lj" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Odriozola, Manuel de (1804-1889). Colección de documentos históricos.
                     Cuaderno 3.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ae62c91595492c8a53c3eab361ae2556" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
                  <container id="aspace_64dcf54a2ca30332d60f05e9fb5a99d5"
                     parent="aspace_ae62c91595492c8a53c3eab361ae2556" type="ms">28</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6b23bc52222b56839b16ba1da297daad">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú. 1860. 93 folios. Index.</p>
                  <p>This volume contains manuscript copies and newspaper clippings assembled by
                     Odriozola chiefly of poems and essays published in the Peruvian newspapers
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">El Telegrafo,</title>
                     <title render="italic" type="simple">El Pacificador del Perú,</title> and
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">El Mercurio Peruano</title> after Perú
                     became a republic in 1820. Most of the poems were written by the Peruvian
                     satirical poet José Joaquín Larriva (1780-1832). The newspaper clippings
                     include: a <emph render="underline">Memoria</emph> about the Chilean National
                     Navy read at the University of Chile by Don Antonio Garcia Reyes on Oct. 11,
                     1846; a royal cédula of Sept. 15, 1802, granting royal priviledges to the city
                     of Lima; a biography of General José de San Martin; a letter from San Martin to
                     Bolivar granting him the direction of the war in Perú; and a <emph
                        render="underline">Letrilla</emph> of the Peruvian poet and politician
                     Felipe Pardo y Aliaga (1806-1868). Odriozola assembled this volume between July
                     27, 1855, and June 1, 1859. An index is included at the end of the volume.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref81_ia9" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>García Moreno, Gabriel (1821-1875) Adiós a García Moreno.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b5aed833594b0ec6fb66d9eb41058501" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="ms">29</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ade76c35baad350a37b621ac3c58ce13">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Guayaquil, Ecuador. June 26, 1866. Printed broadside. 2 copies.</p>
                  <p>Broadside printed at Guayaquil, Ecuador, in 1866 by the political enemies of
                     President Gabriel García Moreno after he finished his first presidential term
                     (1861-1865) charging him with tyranny and assassinations. During his second
                     presidential term (1869-1875), his oppressive rule ended in his assassination
                     by young liberals at Quito, Ecuador, on Aug. 6, 1875.</p>
                  <p>Both copies transferred to the International Broadsides collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref83_0i4" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Callao, Perú. Estado jeneral de la matricula de los buques mercantes
                     nacionales, su clasificación, estado y jiro.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ee6c8b8db1fb6a3bd6837e56290a727a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="ms">30</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d5430d6d6ca5217267ae0f8a4be29d07">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Callao, Perú. July 16, 1853. Printed material.</p>
                  <p>This printed broadside includes information about names, nationality, weight,
                     owners, captains, guarantors, trade and conditions of the ships registered at
                     the port of Callao on July 16, 1853. Signed by Alejandro Deustua and Juan de la
                     Puente.</p>
                  <p>Transferred to Rare Book Room.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref85_84n" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>El Aguila de Condorcunca. 13 de Febrero de 1847. Suplemento 2.
                     Frustrado proyecto de monarquía en Colombia. Epitome de la memoria documentada
                     que redactó en el año de 1833, el jeneral de Colombia José Domingo Espinar,
                     antiguo secretario del Libertador Simón Bolivar.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a28fcd01f05150a5b2c9f9df8a844e81" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="ms">31</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_99e1fc73e0d7f8edf4efc016caa3f410">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Cuzco, Perú, Feb. 13, 1847. 2 pages</p>
                  <p>Printed article about a failed project of monarchy in Colombia. Summary of a
                     documented recollection written in 1833 by the Colombian General José Domingo
                     Espinar, former secretary of Simón Bolivar.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref87_zq2" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Paz Soldán Benavides, Carlos (1844-1926). A mis
                     conciudadanos.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_33a014932f99c7628ed64115f185d2e5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="ms">32</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_07fb4965a0e1ea51e51905ab5c02e6df">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú, 1892. Printed Broadside.</p>
                  <p>An expression of Carlos Paz Soldán's views upon constitutional guarantees
                     related to public meetings, the right of assembly and the right of reply.</p>
                  <p>Transferred to the Rare Book Room.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref89_dfn" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Perú. Visita de Tesorerías. Ramos de Jerusalen y Cautivos. Balance del
                     antiguo Ramo de Jerusalen y Cautivos, conforme á las liquidaciónes practicadas
                     en el libro respective y últimos dates presentados en la Visita haste el 31 de
                     Diciembre de 1869.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1f4b3695c1a5055aaf67ce63660f7c2c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="ms">33</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b157d8a0cdb947bc49b392fa13b55577">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú. March 18, 1870. Broadside.</p>
                  <p>This printed broadside is a balance sheet of the branch of <emph
                        render="underline">Jerusalen y Cautivos</emph> of the Peruvian Treasury
                     Department according to an inspection of the register book on Dec. 31, 1869. It
                     includes the name of each account, any representive, the landed property, the
                     annual revenues, the interest, and credit and debit balances.</p>
                  <p>Transferred to the International Broadsides collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref91_ypz" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Travada, Ventura El suelo de Arequipa convertido en cielo. En el
                     extreno del religioso monasterio de Santa Rosa de Santa María que fundó el
                     illmo. S. D. D. Juán Bravo del Rivero del Consejo de Su Magestad dignisimo
                     Obispo de Arequipa. Por el D. D. Ventura Travada.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a677c7e6c65bf13abb9f2fad7993e78f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
                  <container id="aspace_424926467134f954d6367c83460f1a83"
                     parent="aspace_a677c7e6c65bf13abb9f2fad7993e78f" type="ms">34</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_df26ef8daa90cf4e17ad47ddbc76006c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>n. p., n. d. 26, 42, 36 [i. e. 416] pages.</p>
                  <p>A copy of the original in the <emph render="underline">Biblioteca Nacional del
                        Perú</emph> which was first published in 1752, and reprinted and published
                     by Manuel de Odriozola in <bibref>
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">Documentos Literarios del Perú.</title>
                        <imprint>
                           <geogname>Lima, </geogname>
                           <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1863-77.</date> T. X. <date
                              calendar="gregorian" era="ce">(1877)</date>
                        </imprint>
                     </bibref> pp. [5]-324. The volume is replete with details of the ecclesiastical
                     history of the city of Arequipa.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref93_ssf" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Libro duplicado de Alcaldía donde consta la entrada y salida de efectos
                     de Almasenaqe al cargo del Administrador del Puerto del Callao D. Manuel
                     Lastra. Año de 1823. Razón de los efectos existentes en estos Almazenes del
                     Estado de la Administración del Callao de años anteriores qe se comprenden en
                     el presente año de 1823.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_be36a133b4850b7404400b26954ac69a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
                  <container id="aspace_67fb7bc364ad1b599ddf6b49c2a0dd41"
                     parent="aspace_be36a133b4850b7404400b26954ac69a" type="ms">35</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_60fe0ce2789ca5dc1acdb398a28c3160">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Callao, Perú, 1814-1823. 81 pages.</p>
                  <p>This manuscript is a duplicate register of goods and merchandise deposited in
                     the warehouses of the Adminstration of the Port of Callao from 1814 to 1823.
                     Information includes the dates of registration, description of the goods or
                     merchandise, names of the owners, names of the ships, names of the piaces from
                     where the goods were coming, numbers of invoices, and dates of delivery are
                     specified. Names of British and American ships are listed arriving at Callao
                     beginning in 1820. Like MS. No. 9 of this collection, this manuscript is an
                     important source of information on commerce and shipping in Perú at the end of
                     the Wars of Independence.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref95_7xw" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Libro Real del Ramo del Azogue de los Reales Almacenes de Santa Barbara
                     de Lima al cargo del Guarda de ellos e inspección del Interventor que corre
                     desde 1º de Enero haste el 31 de Diziembre de 1786.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1d8d275d8d6bf880978e4f6b6739a0a2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
                  <container id="aspace_84e9708ca833cc8072128d2888e2675e"
                     parent="aspace_1d8d275d8d6bf880978e4f6b6739a0a2" type="ms">36</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_82125f86602531b38b518c73802db77b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú, 1786. [26] pages.</p>
                  <p>This original manuscript records the inspections of the warehouse by the
                     interventor or comptroller Juan de Luque Marmol, to verify the amount of
                     mercury and of dressed sheepskins used as containers for the mercury between
                     Jan. 1st and Dec. 31st, 1786. Information about the dates of arrivals and
                     departures from the warehouses, the weight, geographical sources, names of the
                     owners or shippers of the mercury and the sheepskins are specified in the
                     inspections done during that year. Francisco Argumaniz was the guard of the
                     warehouses during that period. Pages are missing from the volume, but it
                     contains all of the information specified in the index. This volume is a good
                     source of information on mercury production in Perú, similar to MS. No. 3 of
                     this collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref97_3rc" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Olmedo, José Joaquín de, 1780-1847. Versos dichos en Tacubaya en el
                     convite que el Sr. Virrey Arzobispo dió al Sr. Diputado del Perú. El Dõr.
                     Olmedo incitado p r. S.E.I.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2bc5229a6abd4d9ac3bfc5de6bd2a79a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f4283a42cbcbfb57526b585eaacff0f5"
                     parent="aspace_2bc5229a6abd4d9ac3bfc5de6bd2a79a" type="ms">37</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_439d28f243d29b0e145b3b9ddd2307e6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>n. p., n. d. [1] folio. copy.</p>
                  <p>This manuscript is a copy of a poem improvised by José Joaquín Olmedo at
                     Tacubaya, Mexico, in 1811, on his way to the Cortes of <emph render="underline"
                        >Cadiz</emph> as a <emph render="underline">Diputado</emph> representing
                     Guayaquil.</p>
                  <p>For further information see: <bibref>
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">Poeslas completes de José Joaquín de
                           Olmedo,</title>
                        <imprint>Fondo de Cultura Economica, <geogname>Mexico, </geogname>
                           <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1947</date>
                        </imprint> (p. XI-XII, 56-57)</bibref> where this poem was published.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref99_y5n" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Larrea y Loredo, José de (1780-1830). Observación sobre el caracter de
                     los Indios, hecha por el Subdelegado de Pasco Dr. Dn. José de Larrea y
                     Loredo.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ce12de1606fa5994aecf1a4e58aa718d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a53a2ad92d48e7d2864eb0c994e6d979"
                     parent="aspace_ce12de1606fa5994aecf1a4e58aa718d" type="ms">38</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bd6abc10a96c8c732af84d49ab71d3ea">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>n. p., n. d. 1-3 [i. e. 11] pages.</p>
                  <p>Larrea y Loredo, Peruvian diplomat and politician, divides into three periods
                     the history of the Peruvian Indians and describes their values.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref101_yt2" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Luque, Angel. Memoria.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_67389ceedb818e43d8300cb165e448a4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f0f34a74aadf9fd18b7fdbe06a987101"
                     parent="aspace_67389ceedb818e43d8300cb165e448a4" type="ms">39</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8bbb9ac77642e52b9349e0ea1e1236e0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, ca. 1801-1806. [5] folios.</p>
                  <p>Copy of the memorandum sent by Fr. Angel Luque to Viceroy Gabriel de Aviles
                     attacking the <emph render="underline">canónigos</emph> and the <emph
                        render="underline">Fiscal Ecltesiástico</emph> who had charged Fr. Iglesias,
                        <emph render="underline">Parroco de Cathedral</emph> with disrespect to the
                     Archbishop. Fr. Luque complained about the denial by the <emph
                        render="underline">Fiscal Ecltesiástico</emph> of Fr. Iglesia's appeal.</p>
                  <p>According to Manuel de Mendiburu's <bibref>
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">Diccionario Histórico Biográfico del
                           Perú</title>
                        <imprint>
                           <geogname>(Lima, </geogname>
                           <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1931)</date>
                        </imprint>, Tomo I. p. 103</bibref>, Fr. Angel Luque was declared an
                     infamous author in 1812 for writing diatribes against the secretary and the
                     treasurer of Viceroy José Fernando de Abascal.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref103_rz5" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Basadre, Vicente. Correspondence with José de Galvez and Fernando del
                     Mazo.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_164fe1a4995136bf5cf69a8ad8328186" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
                  <container id="aspace_08f745762e09ce3bd87dfcde22276551"
                     parent="aspace_164fe1a4995136bf5cf69a8ad8328186" type="ms">40</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_63296c3e35af0acbc39d7dec0d862ba9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Mexico, 1785. [3] folios.</p>
                  <p>Basadre's letter to Jose de Gálvez concerned trade with China, the discovery of
                     mines in New Spain, and the importation of mercury from the Philippines through
                     the port of Acapulco. Basadre proposed the establishment with Chinese merchants
                     of an exchange of mercury for furs. Nutria and seal furs were available from
                     the missions in California.</p>
                  <p>This letter is followed by a note from Basadre to Fernando del Mazo and his
                     reply of April 16, 1785. These letters are copies.</p>
                  <p>Ms. No. 41 is bound with this manuscript.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref105_dm4" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Philip II, King of Spain. Cédulas and letter concerning the revenue of
                     factories owned by churches and hospitals in Perú and collection of the Quinta,
                     the royal fifth.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_312a6482923552f8184359ad6c578eb3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0428d28eb48dd83066f4eeb35e9e8384"
                     parent="aspace_312a6482923552f8184359ad6c578eb3" type="ms">41</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a1bda069e8fe66c1c3c10f5f3003c041">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Madrid, 1583-1587. 6 folios.</p>
                  <p>Bound with MS. No. 40</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref107_9m6" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Consulta a la Junta Suprema Central sobre la convocatoria a Cortes y
                     número de representantes de la nobleza, y el clero que hen de participar en
                     ellas.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fa3f5b90b2fc7ea91f48207e6babd4f5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a3e7cc680b33c4d188eb49f523731626"
                     parent="aspace_fa3f5b90b2fc7ea91f48207e6babd4f5" type="ms">41A</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b58a9ad1bd42a8dbc1b70c344436581e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>n. p., ca. 1810. [9] pages.</p>
                  <p>A consultation with the <emph render="underline">Junta Suprema Central</emph>
                     concerning the convocation of the <emph render="underline">Cortes</emph> and
                     the number of representatives from the nobility and the clergy that will be
                     members of the <emph render="underline">Cortes</emph>. According to Antonio
                     Cano Manuel's opinion the <emph render="underline">Cortes</emph> should
                     determine its own makeup; the <emph render="underline">Consejo de
                        Regencia</emph> agreed with his opinion. This body was the famous <emph
                        render="doublequote">Cortes of Cadiz</emph> that wrote the Constitution of
                     1812. The <emph render="underline">Junta Suprema Central</emph> and the <emph
                        render="underline">Consejo de Regencia</emph> were the supreme authorities
                     in Spain during the enforced absence of King Ferdinand VII.</p>
                  <p>Originally bound with MS. Nos. 40 and 41.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref109_epy" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Arequipa. Prefectura. Correspondencia Correspondence and a proclamation
                     concerning the Battle of Ingavi in Boliva.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_15afd8780b8a2b196b6dc19e0a12e918" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e56b437e87f02515c287288b3433dcbc"
                     parent="aspace_15afd8780b8a2b196b6dc19e0a12e918" type="ms">42</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_69e6ef1f5090bf851453a2d179984be5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Arequipa, Perú, 1841. [2] folios.</p>
                  <p>Copies of letters dated Nov. 19 and 23, 1841, addressed to the Ministry of
                     State of Perú and to the <emph render="underline">Prefecto</emph> of the <emph
                        render="underline">Departamento</emph> of Arequipa, Perú, signed by Fermin
                     Canseco and Miguel San Román, followed by a letter and a proclamation to the
                     citizens of Arequipa, all of which are related to the Battle of Ingavi that
                     took place south of La Paz, Bolivia, on Nov. 18, 1841, and in which Bolivians
                     under José Ballivián defeated Peruvians under Agustin Gamarra who was
                     killed.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref111_2yt" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>El Mercurio Peruano. Manuscript copy of a manuscript of the Colección
                     de Papeles Varios in the Biblioteca y Archivo Nacional, Lima, Perú, concerning
                     the foundation and publication of the first issues of El Mercurio Peruano, and
                     also with the Sociedad Aciadémica de Amantes del País.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_66678668f55d833b7fc56e5b2d86b075" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
                  <container id="aspace_8c0a3a78c3da3632b674c4fa8c35b7f0"
                     parent="aspace_66678668f55d833b7fc56e5b2d86b075" type="ms">43</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6358640843d4be28834d678e9fbac25c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>n. p., ca. 1791-1794. [4] folios.</p>
                  <p>According to a notice included with this anonymous manuscript, it belonged to
                     Diego de Cisneros, a monk from <emph render="underline">El Escorial</emph>
                     known as <emph render="doublequote">Padre Geronimo.</emph> The manuscript is
                     highly critical of the founders of the newspaper and the members of the
                     academic society, but it still is an important source of information in
                     relation to both, including the names of the first academic and foreign members
                     of the society. For additional information about the newspaper and the society,
                     see: Alberto Tauro, <bibref>
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">Diccionario Enciclopédico del Perú,
                           Ilustrado</title>
                        <imprint>
                           <geogname>(Lima, </geogname>
                           <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1966-67)</date>
                        </imprint>, Vol. III, pp. 176-177.</bibref>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref113_s99" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Perú (Viceroyalty). Arancel que se hen de observer en la recaudación
                     del Real Derecho de Alcabalas de las internaciónes y extraciónes menudas que se
                     verifiquen en las Garitas del Resinto de esta ciudad desde el 1º de Enero de
                     1811...</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6741b4dafe01af69379a2ab72575cb13" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_6dfaa88a52b40dfe3b682a5e88937e51"
                     parent="aspace_6741b4dafe01af69379a2ab72575cb13" type="ms">44-45</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2e04655fa635a110d3f725b1db49d2b9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Cuzco, Perú, 1811, 1816. 234, 212 pages</p>
                  <p>These two volumes are contemporary duplicates of registers sent by the Court of
                     Audit ( <emph render="underline">Contaduría</emph>) to the Court of Accounts (
                        <emph render="underline">Tribunal de Cuentas</emph>). These registers record
                     customs duties ( <emph render="underline">Alcabala</emph>) charged for goods
                     entering and leaving Cuzco at the sentry boxes of San Sebastian and Yanamayo.
                     MS. No. 44 is the register for San Sebastian from Dec. 19, 1810, through Dec.
                     28, 1811. MS. No. 45 is for Yanamayo, Jan. 1-Dec. 28, 1816. The duties were
                     paid to the royal treasury at Lima. The registers record the rates, the names
                     of the persons paying the duties, the types of goods, and the amounts paid.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref115_ad4" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Cuaderno histórico de la fundación, población y establecimiento de esta
                     ciudad de San Francisco de Quito con sus antiguos anales; y una serie
                     chronológica de los Ilustrisimos Señores Obispos que ha tenido esta
                     ciudad...</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fe1341b545e4d3b554bb203f7a36bb91" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_cb2c8e88c3cf19362feb47c96d3c0d8a"
                     parent="aspace_fe1341b545e4d3b554bb203f7a36bb91" type="ms">46</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6ece1f288871f925f31dec9317cc89c0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Quito, Ecuador, 1794. [42] pages.</p>
                  <p>This manuscript is a historical summary of the founding, settling, and
                     development of the city of Quito, Ecuador, prepared by Juan de Ascaray, a
                     notary. It contains a chronological list of bishops of Quito and is based upon
                     documents in the archives of the city in 1794, especially a manuscript work by
                     Dr. Miguel Sánchez Solmirón, dean of the cathedral.</p>
                  <p>Eleven maps of Quito that were formerly filed with this manuscript are now in
                     the Rare Book Room.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref117_hqr" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>La Condamine, Charles Marie de, 1701-1744. Extracto del Viage de Mr. de
                     la Condamine de la Academia Ri de las Ciencias a su regreso de la medida del
                     grade terrestre en Quito pr. el Río de las Amazonas en el Año de
                     1743.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d4d2c663e27efd15cd85f4b99169c5ac" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0e454159438e66fb6c10e77ec0337a8b"
                     parent="aspace_d4d2c663e27efd15cd85f4b99169c5ac" type="ms">47</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_548a8032cdc20a0741b1aab509a801e1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>n. p., n. d. [19] pages.</p>
                  <p>Brief account of the nearly two year's journey of Charles Marie de la Condamine
                     from Quito, Ecuador, to Paris, France, by the way of the Maranón and Amazon
                     rivers, containing data on latitude, longitude, velocity of river currents,
                     width, and depth of streams, and observations on altitude. La Condamine had
                     come to America with representatives of the French Academy of Sciences, and
                     with Antonio de Ullóa and Jorge Juán, scientists representing the King of
                     Spain, to measure a degree at the equator to determine the shape of the earth.
                     This was the expedition which proved that the poles were not round and silenced
                     the enemies of Newton. La Condamine left the southernmost point of his meridian
                     measurement on May 11, 1743, and reached Paris, Feb. 23, 1745. The author of
                     this summary is not indicated.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref119_7hy" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Lima y Sn. Martín. o apuntes pare la histora. de la 1a. epoca de la
                     Patria en Lima. 1821-1822.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e7b0c555cf1ff3cc08637225286377ad" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_1c596f6c54cfaf8111fbf9cdf9e2027a"
                     parent="aspace_e7b0c555cf1ff3cc08637225286377ad" type="ms">48</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_91660ad29d86cc73d3022824b7a0e6e0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1822. [17] pages.</p>
                  <p>A letter dated at Rio de Janeiro, August 15, 1822, in which the author, signed
                     Un Arequipeño (i. e. citizen of the city of Arequipa, Perú), Charged General
                     San Martín and Bernardo Monteagudo with tyranny, robberies and
                     assassinations.</p>
                  <p>Bound with MS. No. 48A.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref121_vmu" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bando publicado en ValparaISO en 1º de Nov. 1823.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_cb563aea93bc5b08eb0201a7dc69ad15" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_29fca002a1eaf4036c7b654724a6bd5e"
                     parent="aspace_cb563aea93bc5b08eb0201a7dc69ad15" type="ms">48A</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_56ddbe1ed6fb3bd45cccf141d30db53a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Valparaiso, Chile, 1823. [2] pages</p>
                  <p>Copy of the edict published at Valparaiso, Chile, the first of Nov., 1823,
                     signed by José Ignacio Zenteno, political governor of the province of
                     Valparaiso, ordering the Spaniards to register with the authorities of
                     Valparaiso within three days. Punishment for non-compliance was prescribed.</p>
                  <p>Bound with MS. No. 48.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref123_a5l" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Al Eximo Sr. Libertador de Colombia y el Perú de su apasionadisimo
                     admirador Antonio Gonzalez. 1825</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_435ab41d1715f10795774e1fbcbcd835" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_9d9e2136586cba7803c69aee3f97f8b2"
                     parent="aspace_435ab41d1715f10795774e1fbcbcd835" type="ms">49</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6b9c9e010181b5540c335cb4067ffbfe">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Bolivia, 1825. 8 folios.</p>
                  <p>Summary of the itinerary between the Province of Santa Cruz in the Republic of
                     Bolivia and the Province of San Pablo (Sao Paulo) in the Brazilian Empire,
                     dedicated to Simón Bolivar by his admirer Antonio Gonzalez, in 1825.</p>
                  <p>This itinerary describes the conditions of the roads, the distances between the
                     cities and towns in leagues (a Spanish linear measure nearly four English
                     miles), the agricultural crops and cattle, the climatological conditions during
                     the different seasons, the rivers and lakes, etc., from the Province of Santa
                     Cruz passing through the Province of Chiquitos in Bolivia entering the
                     Brazilian Empire through the town of Mato Grosso, the town of Guayas (Goiaz)
                     and others, finally reaching the cities of Sn. Pablo (Sao Paulo) and Rio de
                     Janeiro. Information about the troops, the clergy, the Indians and the economic
                     and social conditions of the territories are included in the itinerary.</p>
                  <p>This manuscript is a good source of information for researchers interested in
                     Bolivian and Brazilian history, description, and travel, and social and
                     economic conditions at the beginning of the 19th century.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref125_nhp" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Poesías del Colegio Máximo de San Pablo de la Compañía de
                     Jesus.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3ecd71889cfc735b60dc296ae468e03d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_eec6f42ef9ac7aa892be592868740942"
                     parent="aspace_3ecd71889cfc735b60dc296ae468e03d" type="ms">50</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_583a22ecaf54e73dd887b6c36148c369">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Peru, 1768. 22 folios.</p>
                  <p>Latin poems of the Jesuit Major College of St. Paul in Lima on the occasion of
                     the death of Elizabeth Farnese, Queen of Spain, wife of Philip V and mother of
                     Charles III of Spain. The majority of the poems are elegies written in Latin
                     expressing sorrow for the death of the Queen. Some are translated into Spanish.
                     Laudatory poems on such occasions were typical.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref127_ndq" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Expediente sobre las expediciones de 1814 y 1815 por Andamarca al
                     reconocimiento de las Montañas Peruanas.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_787143f92e951de45a3e133bc20feebd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_5c3e0aa787d5ef9b30df59c0419365e7"
                     parent="aspace_787143f92e951de45a3e133bc20feebd" type="ms">51</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a54b6d59e0c62ab32ad7b075c7d0a68e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Santa Rosa de Ocopa, Perú, 1814-1815. 45 pages.</p>
                  <p>This is a copy of a file on the exploratory expeditions to establish
                     communications between Ocopa and Sarayacú by the Franciscan Fr. Paulo Alonso
                     Carvallo, guardian and vicar of the Missionary College of Santa Rosa de Ocopa
                     in Perú, together with Fr. Diego Ruiz and others. The purpose was to restore
                     the missions of Ucayali in the region of the confluence of the Pangoa and the
                     Chanchamayo rivers <emph render="underline">via</emph> the towns of Comas and
                     Andamarca.</p>
                  <p>The manuscript was copied out in 1847 by Fr. Julián Bovo de Revello. It
                     consists of letters from Carvallo to the Intendent Governor, minutes of the
                     town council of Andamarca, a diary of the 1814 (July 2 to Sept. 28) expedition
                     of Fr. Carvallo, and information on the Fr. Diego Ruiz's 1815 expedition.
                     Certain paragraphs of this manuscript describing the mountains and giving the
                     distances between villages are quoted in Bernardino Izaguirre Ispizua, <bibref>
                        <title render="italic" type="simple">Historia de las Misiones
                           Franciscanas</title>
                        <imprint>
                           <geogname>(Lima, </geogname>
                           <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1922-29)</date>
                        </imprint>, Vol. 9, pp. 13-18.</bibref>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref129_108" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Poesías Sagradas de diversos autores.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f7c990c2688eca0345ef0f14dabda83f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_dbdbbbbec32fce56119ef981291a5706"
                     parent="aspace_f7c990c2688eca0345ef0f14dabda83f" type="ms">52</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9af461931afd5ae44bc39053d98f5227">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú, 1837. 25 folios.</p>
                  <p>Included in this small booklet are several poems and Spanish tranlations of
                     well known religious hymns. The translations are signed by F. Diego Gonzales.
                     The authors are not identified in the volume.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref131_b7h" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Real Cédula de 24 de Diciembre del año pasado de 1788.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c2c572ef417f21cdf7d66c9606ae58dd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a719cb82cd58486b99cf7291fa992603"
                     parent="aspace_c2c572ef417f21cdf7d66c9606ae58dd" type="ms">53</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f6befeb8121c7d563df389299c361116">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Madrid, 1788. [3] folios.</p>
                  <p>Royal Cédula given at Madrid on December 24, 1788, by King Charles IV
                     commanding the Viceroy of Perú, Teodoro De Croix, to announce to the citizens
                     of Perú the death of King Charles III and the accession to the Spanish throne
                     of King Charles IV on December 14, 1788. This Royal Cédula was published at
                     Lima, Perú on May 13, 1789, by order of Viceroy De Croix.</p>
                  <p>Transferred to Rare Book Room.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref133_p8x" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Candamo, Pedro. Carta anónima dirigida a Pedro Candamo.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_08697eda6fff5cf4121341a0a7f671f6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a5574c5c2f99e7499bcbd103f14c6405"
                     parent="aspace_08697eda6fff5cf4121341a0a7f671f6" type="ms">54</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d7ef265b1560a15e0f6464b9b544e66f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú. April 17, 1860. 2 pages.</p>
                  <p>Letter from an unidentified person to Pedro Candamo discussing the planned
                     delivery of a thousand ounces of gold, giving detailed instructions and
                     threatening Candamo with death if the task is not performed.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref135_l2u" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Jesuits. Letters from missions (South America).</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_02e4ba1575343707f2cbdd2cd56a75db" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e2f7be3383c6fc6f613d440045552c9a"
                     parent="aspace_02e4ba1575343707f2cbdd2cd56a75db" type="ms">55</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e917595689e7a4571791097b80cbbf62">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú. 1587. [11] folios.</p>
                  <p>Copies of 4 letters addressed to Fr. Juan de Atienza (1542-1592), Provincial of
                     the Society of Jesús in Perú, from the Jesuit missionary Fr. Diego de Samaniego
                     (1542-1627) at the Santa Cruz de la Sierra mission (now in Bolivia). The
                     letters are dated April 10, June 1st, June 25 and August 3, 1587.</p>
                  <p>Copies of 3 letters addressed also to Provincial Fr. Atienza by the Jesuit
                     missionary Fr. Francisco de Angulo from the Tucumán Mission (now in Argentina),
                     dated March 29, May 9 and June 23, 1587.</p>
                  <p>Another 2 copies of letters to Fr. Atienza from the Jesuit missionary Alonso de
                     Barzana (1528-1598) dated at the Tucumán Mission May 8 and August 20, 1587.</p>
                  <p>Fr. Atienza was the founder of the Tucumán Santa Cruz de la Sierra and Quito
                     (now in Ecuador) missions, and Fr. Barzana, because of his exemplary life as a
                     missionary was known as the Apostle of Tucumán and Paraguay. For additional
                     information about these Jesuit missionaries see: Evaristo San Cristobal, <title
                        render="italic" type="simple">Apéndice al Diccionario Histórico-Biográfico
                        del Perú</title> (Lima, 1935), T. I., pp. 163-166, 285, 342-343, and see
                     also: <title render="italic" type="simple">Historia General de la Compañía de
                        Jesús en la Provincia del Perú</title> (Madrid, 1944), T. I., Vol. 1, pp.
                     25-29.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref137_i67" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Esquadrón de la Guardia de Honor del Excelentísimo Señor Virrey. 1 de
                     Agosto de 1817.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_7699f488e9f04879000ce18926b35f9f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_fd51e018847b780fc4c0f4b7b0c6e36f"
                     parent="aspace_7699f488e9f04879000ce18926b35f9f" type="ms">56</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_36a33c62f4f47cd5b0a57fc155b0dde8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, August 1, 1817. 1 folio.</p>
                  <p>A report on the Viceroy's Honor Guard, giving the number of men, horses, etc.
                     during July and August, 1817. Joaquín de la Pezuela, y Sanchez was Viceroy of
                     Perú from 1816 to 1821. The report is signed by Ignacio Landaruri and José
                     Rodriguez.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref139_erc" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Perú (Viceroyalty). Caja Real de Lima. Razón de las Entradas diaries
                     así por lo que producer los Ramos de Administración come los pertenecientes a
                     la Contaduría, 1766-1767.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_96ae5ae9049906651a8d4ee06eab6535" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f99ef97a4d744a46ef6d2e6e3a401913"
                     parent="aspace_96ae5ae9049906651a8d4ee06eab6535" type="ms">57</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_99eaf0cc5e62cf9a1c37287a4cfd6593">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Lima, Perú, 1766-1767. 96 folios.</p>
                  <p>This register is a daily record of the sums paid by merchants, landowners, etc.
                     to the Royal Treasury ( <emph render="underline">Caja Real</emph>) in Lima,
                     capital of the Viceroyalty of Perú, between January, 1766, and August, 1767.
                     The register records the names of the persons paying the duties, the types of
                     goods, and the amounts paid. The majority of the revenues derived from two
                     principal sources: the <emph render="underline">Alcabala</emph>, an excise tax
                     on sales and exchanges of goods, and the <emph render="underline"
                        >Almojari-fazgo</emph>, an import and exchange duty. These taxes were
                     collected by two offices of the Treasury, the court of Audit ( <emph
                        render="underline">Contaduría</emph>) and the Administration ( <emph
                        render="underline">Administración</emph>).</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref141_fcv" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Woodcuts of a Bird and of a Genealogical Tree.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6ae53bf35489991c004682b18b2f7041" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b64f5c46a93af9766cdbbb4c59553e9d"
                     parent="aspace_6ae53bf35489991c004682b18b2f7041" type="ms">58</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2afbe60331b64d5e92093c7c4297cd21">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Arequipa, 1834. [4] folios.</p>
                  <p>The woodcut of the bird was made from a piece of wood found in an excavation at
                     Cuzco. President Luis José Obregoso gave the order of printing a copy of the
                     figure carved in wood. It was done at the government printing press managed by
                     Benavides at Arequipa on Sept. 22, 1834. President Obregoso gave the copy as a
                     present to Juan Gualberto Valdivia, a Peruvian priest and historian.</p>
                  <p>The woodcut of a genealogical tree of an unknown family, also found carved in a
                     piece of wood, was given to Valdivia by Obregoso.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
