<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/peyrehieraume/">peyrehieraume</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Hieraume Peyre Sketchbook and Commonplace Book, 1620-1640
            <num>RL.11587</num></titleproper>
        <author>Alice L. Poffinberger</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>January 2018</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">008174881</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-01-19 14:59:16
          -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="fre">French</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Hieraume Peyre sketchbook and commonplace book</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname role="cre" source="local">Peyre, Hieraume</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.11587</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">1 item</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1620/1640" type="inclusive">1620-1640</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_404347eb83cb014836f84887f3dfa213">Hieraume Peyre (or Hierosme Peire) was
        a French architect-builder, originally from Saint-Chamond, who lived and worked in the area
        around Saint-Etienne, Isère, Grenoble, and Tullins. Sketchbook and commonplace book
        compiled over two decades (approximately 1620-1640) by the French architect-builder Hieraume
        Peyre. The manuscript is in ink and color [14.9 x 19.3 cm], (187) ff., with some leaves
        showing an earlier pagination that might indicate the loss of some leaves, but with no clear
        interruption of continuity in the text, copiously illustrated (265 of 375 pages carry some
        form of illustration, and 161 of these are full-page). Bound in early tinted vellum. The
        manuscript provides information on both the practical and theoretical concerns of
        early-modern engineers and architectural practitioners.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_07a71dc715324a65e2879cae256a3ec8">Materials in French</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="aspace_8dd6c4911000dfc910c2425651fd3b56">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Hieraume Peyre (or Hierosme Peire) was a French architect-builder, originally from
        Saint-Chamond, who lived and worked in the area around Saint-Etienne, Isère, Grenoble, and
        Tullins.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_7e7c74fcee72182817bd9c6a3a717a70">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_b04853ee6e93190e671babd916e2916a">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_aac1a876e6d9fe920f5f999f6bb8369e">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Hieraume Peyre Sketchbook and Commonplace Book was received by the David M. Rubenstein
        Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2017.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_0e6b17713fa21933d0587ed214c3102e">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Hieraume Peyre Sketchbook and Commonplace Book, David M.
        Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_b83b42339c2fd637bc5fa1a814f16d36">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Alice Poffinberger, January, 2018</p>
      <p>Accessions described in this collection guide: 2017-0216</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_c63629b507f874c63bd1221600758269">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>Sketchbook and commonplace book compiled over two decades (approximately 1620-1640) by the
        French architect-builder Hieraume Peyre. The manuscript is in ink and color [14.9 x 19.3
        cm], (187) ff., with some leaves showing an earlier pagination that might indicate the loss
        of some leaves, but with no clear interruption of continuity in the text, copiously
        illustrated (265 of 375 pages carry some form of illustration, and 161 of these are
        full-page). Bound in early tinted vellum. The manuscript provides information on both the
        practical and theoretical concerns of early-modern engineers and architectural
        practitioners: Peyre made numerous drawings of carpentry designs for vaults and towers he
        worked on, brickwork and ashlar masonry patterns, ornamental motifs for stonework, designs
        for stone intarsia floors, balusters, coffered ceilings, among others. He also engaging
        closely with printed architectural treatises, for example, with a French translation of the
        Spaniard Diego de Sagredo's (c. 1480-1528) Medidas del Romano, from which Peyre copied
        several woodcuts illustrating the classical orders, classical proportions, masonry profiles,
        and more.</p>
      <p>In addition to his illustrations of architectural matter, Peyre includes recipes for "cold'
        cement, hydraulic "ciment chaud" for work on fountains, varnish, "false marble," oil paints,
        gilding, plasters, and adhesives, and provides designs for lathes used in turning. Extensive
        sections on horology and surveying are practical, with Peyre's attention to vertically
        mounted mural sundials reflecting his specialty as a builder of the towers where such
        timekeeping devices were placed. </p>
      <p>Peyre also provides riddles, poetry, prayers (one in Italian), illustrations of various
        inventions (for example, relating to wells, the manufacture of wheat, Jacob's staff, among
        others), botanical and entomological specimens, heraldic illustrations, and numerous
        drawings of sacred and secular figures (including Pope Paul V, and François de Paule, the
        founder of the Order of Minims), labyrinths, cityscapes, religious iconography, armor,
        grotesques, and both real and mythical beasts. He mentions events dated with the years 1620,
        1623, 1624, 1630, 1634, 1636, and 1637 and occasionally provides personal details from his
        life, including a note on the birth of a son, Jehan, on 16 December 1630, and the infant's
        untimely death two months later.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Architectural practice -- France -- History -- 17th century</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Architects -- France</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Architecture -- France -- History -- 17th century</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Building -- France -- Early works to 1800</subject>
      <persname source="local">Peyre, Hieraume</persname>
      <persname source="lcnaf">Sagredo, Diego de</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_fffe3cf5fdd126a5efbf50676d58c373" level="item">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Sketchbook and Commonplace Book</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_d6282db11cfc8988f35a765b21b7249d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
