<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/poindext/">poindext</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Robert C. Poindexter Papers, 1836-1871 <num>RL.01030</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;amp;
               Manuscript Library Staff; machine-readable finding aid created by: Stephen Douglas
               Miller</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">002356530</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 06:55:39
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Robert C. Poindexter papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Poindexter, Robert C., d. 1885</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01030</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1836/1871" type="inclusive">1836-1871</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_bd80a2f6812ffbd5bd257a13692d5850">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <physdesc id="aspace_ff39f662b3c1efe9740a1a279681eb4e">
            <extent>29 items, 3 vols.</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_c0a3a30de76f583d1b2bbbc516a77947">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_a335afd6e8a397ecb299263a0ab2353e">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_51fefe390bc9f04bedaa8003a89d5a16">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in the Robert C. Poindexter Papers have not been transferred to
            Duke University. For more information consult the section on copyright in the
            Regulations and Procedures of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript
            Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_505f11d0b69aab2d411d024fbde74ca8">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Robert C. Poindexter Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_961bb579bd4e04dfc65ea1c5bbc9cba0">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Robert C. Poindexter Papers were acquired by Duke University ca. 1982-1983.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_5cfd155841dba75ab76082f982d83f62">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by: Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library
            Staff</p>
         <p>Completed October 28, 1983</p>
         <p>Encoded by Stephen Douglas Miller</p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_9930b6ec4b7607b7cff93eb345252f06">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Robert C. Poindexter (d. 1885) was a merchant in eastern Yadkin County for many years.
            His general store at East Bend was listed in <title type="simple" render="italic"
               >Branson's North Carolina Business Directory</title> for 1867, 1869, 1872, and 1884.
            He and his store are also mentioned in William E. Rutledge, Jr.'s, <title type="simple"
               render="italic">An Illustrated History of Yadkin County</title> (Yadkinville, 1965)
            in the section on East Bend. In 1857 Poindexter was listed in D. D. T. Leech's <title
               type="simple" render="italic">Post Office Directory</title> as the postmaster at Red
            Plains.</p>
         <p>Three account books, 1836-1860, are from Poindexter's mercantile businesses. At least
            two different partnerships are represented. There are some uncertainties about the exact
            locations and number of his stores. These ambiguities and the difficulties in
            identifying the volumes will require some explanation. All of the business activity took
            place in the eastern section of Yadkin County, the area of East Bend in the northeast,
            Huntsville in the southeast, and Red Plains in between. Red Plains, a locality no longer
            in existence, was close to present-day Enon (Rutledge, P. 77).</p>
         <p>The earliest account book has two distinct sections. It was first used as Daybook, 1836,
            for a general store at Huntsville. The entries (135 pp.) date during January
            22-September 20, 1836. The ownership of this store is not known. Notable customers
            included Col. Richard C. Puryear, Isaac Jarratt, and Thomas L. Clingman. The Clingmans,
            Poindexters, Puryears, and Jarratts were related, and all figure in this collection and
            also in the Jarratt-Puryear Family Papers. Tyre Glen was a customer, and this department
            also has a collection of his papers. There was a post office in the store, for there are
            many entries for postage. At that time Richard C. Puryear was postmaster at
            Huntsville.</p>
         <p>The account book that includes the Daybook, 1836, was subsequently used as the Ledger,
            1843-1848 (353 pp.), by the mercantile firm of Poindexter and Martin whose ownership has
            been identified through various notations. The initials <emph render="doublequote">P and
               M</emph> appear on the spine of the volume. An account on pp. 334-335 is labeled
               <emph render="doublequote">Poindexter and Martin Bills.</emph> This account was
            continued from pp. 30-31 where it was labeled <emph render="doublequote">R. C.
               Poindexter and T. S. Martin.</emph> The first entry in their account was on Nov. 1,
            1843, for a large amount of goods purchased from <emph render="doublequote">P and
               P</emph> according to an inventory. The Ledger's accounts begin in Nov., 1843, so
            that it is clear that Poindexter and Martin began business in that month, probably as
            the successor of an earlier firm named <emph render="doublequote">P and P.</emph> A note
            was given to J. H. P. for a large sum, so one of the earlier owners was probably J. H.
            Palmer. Various accounts have entries for settlements with <emph render="doublequote">P
               and M</emph> (pp. 37, 38) and <emph render="doublequote">T. S. M.</emph> (pp. 33, 46,
            etc.). Poindexter worked in the store, for his account (p. 303) contains entries for
            annual wages.</p>
         <p>The location of the general store represented by the Ledger, 1843-1848, is unclear. It
            was not at Huntsville, for there are too many scattered entries such as <emph
               render="doublequote">cr. by charging on Books at Huntsville,</emph>
            <emph render="doublequote">Cr. by Cash at Huntsville,</emph>
            <emph render="doublequote">settled at Huntsville,</emph> etc. (pp. 117, 148, 178, 184,
            195, 218, 244, etc.). These entries also suggest that the firm did have a store at
            Huntsville. Robert C. Poindexter eventually had a store at East Bend. However, this
            ledger was not kept at East Bend. That town did not have a post office until 1849, and
            numerous entries in many accounts show that the store included a post office. There are
            extensive accounts for Richard C. Puryear, Isaac Jarratt, and Tyre Glen.</p>
         <p>Poindexter and Martin opened a new ledger in 1847, for many accounts were noted as
            continued there (pp. 65, 147, etc.). Some accounts in the Ledger, 1843-1848, remained
            active into 1848. Thereafter, later entries as late as 1855 were usually settlements of
            inactive accounts not continued into the later ledger.</p>
         <p>The mercantile firm of A. P. and R. C. Poindexter had a general store at Red Plains, a
            village near Enon. The Daybook, 1857-1858, belonged to that store. Many pages are
            labeled <emph render="doublequote">Red Plains.</emph> Identification of the store's and
            the volume's owners is supplied by a bill of 1856-1857 filed in the Financial Papers.
            The bill is a statement for purchases made by John D. Hedgcock and William Hedgcock at
            Red Plains from A. P. and R. C. Poindexter. The transaction for May 2, 1857, on the bill
            is also entered in the Daybook. The entries (66 pp.) in the Daybook date from April 30,
            1857, to March 26, 1858.</p>
         <p>On Sept. 26, 1860, the partnership of A. P. and R. C. Poindexter was dissolved, and the
            Daybook includes an account (4 pp.) for the division of property.</p>
         <p>The back pages of the Daybook were used, probably by R. C. Poindexter, to record other
            financial matters. There are 10 1/2 pages, 1862-1863, of alphabetical lists of names
            followed by three columns for recording numbers of persons in the family, pounds, and
            value. These pages also include a short account for the receipt of large quantities of
            salt. It is apparent that these lists are for the distribution and rationing of salt.
            Salt was scarce, and the state set up factories, purchased salt, and sold it to the
            people. These accounts may relate to that effort. Since the number of persons in each
            family is recorded, these lists serve as a partial census. Unfortunately, many pages are
            missing. The Financial Papers also include a salt distribution list.</p>
         <p>Another list (7 pp.) in the Daybook includes columns for names, acreage, location of
            acreage, and value. This list was apparently for taxation. The Financial Papers include
            a notice of March 20, 1863, that R. C. Poindexter and two others were appointed
            assessors for East Bend District for the listing of lands and slaves. Thus, this list is
            an informal tax list. Unfortunately, many pages are missing. Presumably this list dates
            from 1863 or later, and tax lists are unavailable for Yadkin County during 1863-1872
            according to Draughon and Johnson's <title type="simple" render="italic">North Carolina
               Genealogical Reference</title> (p. 452).</p>
         <p>The Ledger, 1850-1860 (557 pp.), is identified as belonging to A. P. and R. C.
            Poindexter, because entries can be traced into it from their Daybook, 1857-1858. An
            example is a purchase by A. P. Poindexter that was entered in the Daybook on June 2,
            1857, and later carried to his account in the Ledger (p. 542). However, the Ledger's
            account for Poindexter includes many transactions that are not in this Daybook from Red
            Plains. This circumstance and references in the Ledger to East Bend suggest that the
            firm had stores in more than one place - Red Plains, East Bend, and perhaps elsewhere.
            There are numerous references such as: <emph render="doublequote">cr. by work at East
               Bend and here</emph> (p. 364); <emph render="doublequote">Amount on Book kept by R.
               C. P. at East Bend</emph> (p. 488); <emph render="doublequote">cr. by work at East
               Bend</emph> (p. 450); <emph render="doublequote">cr. by settlement, this and our East
               Bend book</emph> (p. 541); etc. (pp. 427, 437, 478).</p>
         <p>The location at which the Ledger was kept is not certain except that it was not at East
            Bend. The location may have been Red Plains. R. C. Poindexter was postmaster there in
            1857, and his account in the Ledger was quite active then. There are references (p. 542)
            to transactions <emph render="doublequote">at Huntsville</emph> and <emph
               render="doublequote">at Yadkinville,</emph> so the Ledger was not kept at either of
            those places. Of course, the Ledger may have been a central one into which the business
            of more than one store was entered, and that would make its location difficult to
            determine. Accounts for R. C. Puryear, Isaac Jarratt, and Tyre Glen are not prominent in
            this volume.</p>
         <p>The Ledger, 1850-1860, was begun in 1850 with many accounts continued from an <emph
               render="doublequote">Old Book.</emph> Thus, the firm existed before 1850 and had at
            least one earlier ledger. The accounts indicate that the store's activity ceased by
            early 1858. Later entries are for settlements of accounts. No accounts were marked as
            continued in a later ledger. This situation squares with the 1860 account in the
            Daybook, 1857-1858, for the dissolution of the partnership.</p>
         <p>Transactions for postage (pp. 425, 426, 454) are rare unlike the situation in the
            Ledger, 1843-1848. Either the post office was not in the store, or other books were kept
            for postal matters.</p>
         <p>The nine items, 1856-1871 and undated, in the Financial Papers include stray accounts
            for the stores, a salt distribution and rationing list of ca. 1862-1863, the notice of
            R. C. Poindexter's appointment as an assessor, etc.</p>
         <p>The Miscellany includes 19 small squares of colored cotton cloth that were found between
            pages 387-388 of the Ledger, 1850-1860. The fabric was probably of a type used for
            dresses. There are six different designs. The designs are printed rather than woven. The
            fabric is in excellent condition. Its age is uncertain.</p>
         <p>The Printed Material contains a clipping of 1852 with an advertisement for the
            Statesville Female Academy.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">1 vol. added, 10-28-83.</emph> This volume is A. P. and R. C.
            Poindexter's Ledger, 1848-1850, from their general store. Accounts in this ledger,
            referred to as the <emph render="doublequote">old book,</emph> are marked as continued
            in the <emph render="doublequote">new book</emph> which is their Ledger, 1850-1860, that
            was cataloged earlier as part of this collection. Entries can be traced from the older
            book into the newer one. Since Ledger, 1848-1850 (172 pp.), opens many accounts in
            Sept., 1848, without any references to an earlier ledger, that date must have been the
            start of this partnership, the earlier one having been Poindexter and Martin. A. P. and
            R. C. Poindexter began a new ledger in 1850, but they continued to use the old one for
            some accounts. For that reason Ledger, 1848-1850, includes some later transactions as
            well as settlements of accounts. The primary use of the volume, however, occurred during
            1848-1850. A. P. and R. C. Poindexter's names appear in this volume (p. 83, page before
            p. 1, etc.) as recipients of payments. The pages after p. 165 are missing. There are
            accounts for Isaac Jarratt and Tyre Glen. Postage payments are very scattered. Customers
            paid their bills not only with money and promissory notes but also with goods and
            services.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <genreform source="aat">Ledgers (account books)</genreform>
         <genreform source="aat">Daybooks</genreform>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Yadkin County (N.C.) -- Commerce</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Merchants -- Accounting</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Merchants -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Business records -- North Carolina -- History -- 19th
            century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Postal service -- North Carolina -- Yadkin County</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Account books</genreform>
         <persname source="ingest">Poindexter, Robert C., d. 1885</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
