<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/purviancefamily/"
         >purviancefamily</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Purviance Family Papers, 1757-1932 <num>RL.10133</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Bob Malme</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000873681</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 17:39:25
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Purviance family papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <famname rules="dacs" source="ingest">Purviance family</famname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.10133</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Linear Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">5 boxes, 2,363 items (includes 16 vols.)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1757/1932" type="inclusive">1757-1932</unitdate>
         <unitdate normal="1776/1920" type="bulk">bulk</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_37e66c9fb2d0935746a6ee07b7f0796a">This collection contains
            professional, business, personal and family correspondence and other papers of the
            related Purviance and Courtenay families of Baltimore, Md., and elsewhere. The
            collection pertains to Revolutionary War activities in Maryland, shipping and trade,
            Western lands, settlement of estates, Civil War veterans' activities, the Cuban
            independence movement, and other matters. Includes papers of John Henry Purviance, U.S.
            diplomat in Paris, concerning the Monroe Mission (1794), U.S. relations with Napoleon
            and the Revolutionary French Government; papers relating to the financial affairs of
            Elizabeth Isabella Purviance Courtenay; papers of Edward H. Courtenay, Sr., relating to
            his career at West Point, his later teaching duties there and at other colleges, and his
            investment activities; and letters of Edward H. Courtenay, Jr., written in Washington,
            D.C., during the Civil War, describing the city and political opinion there.
            Correspondents include Alexander Dallas Bache, George William Erving, John Graham,
            Gessner Harrison, Anthony Hart, William Homes McGuffey, William Maclay, George Mason,
            James Monroe, Abner Nash, Fulwar Skipwith, George Muirson Totten, Thomas Tudor Tucker,
            and John Vanderlyn.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_3b685cd60ec6033101d7c35e59424776">Materials in
            English</langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_f4d5dec749d966f022ead48a120f4130">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <bioghist id="aspace_f0be9cb42854c8245d3add4313146062">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Samuel Purviance (d. 1787) was a Baltimore merchant and chairman of the Committee of
            Observation for Baltimore County. John Henry Purviance was a career diplomat, secretary
            and interpreter to the James Monroe mission, 1794-1796, and secretary of the legation in
            London, 1804-1810. Elizabeth Isabella Purviance was his sister. Edward H. Courtenay (d.
            1853) was on the faculty at the U.S. Military Academy at West Point.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_2fa1a1f673075a6306c8a41aa5590452">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Purviance family papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library in 1946.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <prefercite id="aspace_821cc654322846be9068043291789a3c">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], in the Purviance family papers collection, David M. Rubenstein
            Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_fe2b220f7a41aacc7a0de36e7829bbc4">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library staff.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_f2d53cb518d1b26bab99efffaea71881">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The Purviance family papers contain professional and family correspondence and papers of
            two generations of the Purviance family and several generations of the Courtenay family,
            related through the marriage of Henry Courtenay and Elizabeth Isabella Purviance in
            1811. </p>
         <p>The early papers relate chiefly to Samuel Purviance (d. 1787), Baltimore merchant, and
            chairman of the Committee of Observation for Baltimore County, and consist of records
            that include the interrogation of Purviance by the Council of Safety for the failure of
            a plan by the Committee of Observation to capture Maryland governor Robert Eden;
            correspondence discussing British depredations on American shipping, the extension of
            the Mason-Dixon line, cession of western lands, complaints against the Vandalia and
            Indiana Land companies, sale of lands owned by Purviance on the Chillisquaque River near
            Sunbury (Pennsylvania), lands owned by George Washington on the Kanawha River, and
            proposed development of the James River Canal; scattered letters from his wife
            concerning family matters; and letters from his son, John Henry Purviance, regarding his
            supervision of his father's western lands. </p>
         <p>The professional papers of John Henry Purviance, secretary and interpreter to the James
            Monroe mission, 1794-1796, and secretary of the legation in London, 1804-1810, include
            memoranda regarding official diplomatic transactions; accounts, 1795, of interviews
            between Monroe and Jean Debrie, member of the Committee of Public Safety concerning
            arbitration of the war between France and Great Britain, French suspicion of the Jay
            Treaty, and the offices of the French in negotiations pending between the United States
            and Algiers; an account of a conversation between Monroe and one Fulton discussing the
            efforts of one La Chaise to persuade France to take possession of Louisiana and Florida
            as a check on American expansion and as a means of luring Kentucky away from the
            confederation, and Monroe's attempts to strengthen the ties of western territories to
            the union by asking France to influence Spain to keep the Mississippi River open to
            American trade; memoranda, 1796, concerning the difficulties of obtaining cash for a
            draft sent Monroe by the U.S. Treasury; Monroe's outline of a speech to the French
            National Convention; rough draft of a note from Monroe to the French minister of foreign
            affairs, Charles Delacroix, pertaining to the Fauchet letter; from Fulwar Skipwith,
            American consul-general at Paris, regarding Pierre Louis Roederer and the ratification
            of the treaty of 1800 which concluded the XYZ affair; rough drafts, 1806, of articles by
            Monroe describing the relations between the United States, Great Britain, and France;
            copy of a letter from Joseph Lakanal to an unnamed royal personage urging him to assert
            himself as ruler of Spain; rumors among the French peasantry of the impending return of
            Napoleon and gossip current in diplomatic circles; document, 1815, of Bon Adrien Jeannot
            de Moncey, Duc de Conegliano, making recommendations concerning France's foreign policy;
            letter, 1817, from the minister of Brazil to the U.S. minister containing copies of the
            correspondence between himself and the Russian minister dealing with a question of
            diplomatic protocol; and correspondence concerning Purviance's administrative duties. </p>
         <p>Items of a more personal nature include papers relating to the financial affairs of his
            sister, Elizabeth Isabella Purviance, and the claims of her guardian, David Stewart,
            against the British government for capture of his vessels; commonplace book, 1781,
            containing extracts from a tour through Great Britain, excerpts from poems, and a few
            accounts; account book, 1801-1809, of travel expenses in the United States and Europe;
            commonplace book of excerpts from poems; commonplace book, 1811-1834, containing a
            travel diary of England and France, expenses, and a discussion of French government; a
            diary, 1819, of his travels including his impressions of the BayonneBiarritz area noted
            in the course of a diplomatic mission to Spain; and a memorandum book, 1818, with daily
            entries regarding weather, correspondence with President Monroe, and personal and
            financial matters. </p>
         <p>Papers of Edward H. Courtenay (d. 1853) include correspondence with his uncle, John
            Henry Purviance, discussing the former's work and activities at West Point; papers
            dealing with the settlement of the estate of his grandfather, Hercules Courtenay (d.
            1816); correspondence of Edward H. Courtenay, Jr., while attending school in Geneva, New
            York; personal correspondence concerning family and financial affairs; and personal
            correspondence with his brother, David Courtenay, regarding dealings in stocks,
            especially those of the Erie Railroad Company and the Aetna Life Insurance Company. </p>
         <p>Other papers of the Courtenay family include occasional records of the 1st Maryland
            Volunteers under Lieutenant Colonel N. T. Dushane; letters from Edward H. Courtenay,
            Jr., describing his work with the U.S. Coastal Survey, divided sentiment in Maryland
            during the Civil War, and Washington, D.C.; commissions, appointment and other military
            papers of Chauncey B. Reese and Henry Brewerton, husbands of Mary I. Courtenay and Sarah
            Courtenay, respectively, daughters of Edward H. Courtenay, Sr.; correspondence between
            David Courtenay and his son, William, regarding West Virginia lands which were a part of
            the Purviance estate, and the discovery of oil on those lands; papers relating to the
            administration of the estates of various members of the Courtenay family; business
            papers of William C. Courtenay; financial papers, principally in stock speculation, of
            several members of the family; financial records of the Maryland Society of the Sons of
            the American Revolution and of the 5th Maryland Regiment Veteran Corps; letter, 1869,
            from Edward H. Courtenay, Jr., discussing efforts of Cuba to free herself from Spain and
            the attitude of the United States towards such efforts, and commenting upon the
            treatment of Chinese immigrants in the United States; and papers concerning the
            disappearance and probable death of David S. Courtenay, son of Edward H. Courtenay, Sr.,
            and Virginia (Howard) Courtenay. </p>
         <p>Separated volumes include a mercantile ledger, 1781-1816, of Hercules Courtenay
            containing accounts of food products, tar, rum, ginseng, ships and shipping ventures,
            and insurance; ledgers, 1764-1779, and account book for debts receivable, 1764-1776, of
            Dr. John Boyd, Baltimore physician, containing records of an apothecary; books of
            recipes and remedies. list of American vessels destroyed by the British; daybook,
            1801-1804, of merchant Henry William Courtenay with accounts for flour, food, and other
            commodities; account books, 1824-1826 and 1835-1842, of David S. Courtenay recording
            money spent for postage, cash received for legal services, expenditures in lotteries,
            and personal expenses; address book, possibly of David S. Courtenay; anonymous account
            book, 1815; scrapbook, 1836, of H. W. Courtenay; diary, 1861, of a soldier including a
            description of his stay in a Confederate prison; and a scrapbook, 1892-1909, of
            clippings relating to Baltimore and to the Purviance and Courtenay families.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_db53d9bb323d06cbb7b9a817017e9ebb">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">College teachers -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Real estate business -- West (U.S.)</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Cuba -- Politics and government</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Foreign relations -- 1783-1815</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Baltimore (Md.) -- Commerce</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Foreign relations -- France</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Maryland -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">France -- Foreign relations -- United States</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Washington (D.C.) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
         <famname rules="dacs" source="ingest">Courtenay family</famname>
         <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Purviance, John Henry</persname>
         <famname rules="dacs" source="ingest">Purviance family</famname>
         <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Courtenay, Elizabeth Isabella Purviance</persname>
         <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Courtenay, Edward H.</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">United States Military Academy -- Faculty</corpname>
         <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Courtenay, Edward H. (Edward Henry)</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref30_8ud" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Purviance family papers</unittitle>
               <unitdate normal="1757/1932" type="inclusive">1757-1932</unitdate>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref10_in3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Genealogical information</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_da630c28bcbdbcf7610c747aa3cc07a9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref11_0fi" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters and papers</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1757-1812</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_2fdb2f3e9d24c96bd73c4183171fbb0c">3 folders</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_f56b314d9ddd582656fea1640ba63812" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref12_6kc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence with George Mason</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1790-1809</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_a18340820143b5af9e8b9f8b46907d9b">2 folders</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_6ce7530556564d3f464c82843e217be0" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref13_p8o" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters and papers</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1813-1859</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_56fffadce0eef2de299a7c84a7afc288">6 folders</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_0642c80ead972cec462a2a1af9500390" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_x5b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters and papers</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1860-1899</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_2581a4fe94be214d1fff23035c045814">6 folders</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_724c86542852192b69ca6b313d953276" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_h1j" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters and papers</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1900-1932</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_359cc91f8c9feb2d861a65253edb168e">5 folders</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_dc078f2002b8eb5dd1610d0a2a10d7da" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_461" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Papers, poetry and pictures</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_d83c9ac9bbaf7b5d13d85a93bdcca3e8">7 folders</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_fe19da7f3a7c19cb47fca53929352132" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_i7y" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Hercules Courtenay mercantile ledger</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1781-1816</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_a25786eaabedf13bdb376fd146e164a9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">1-2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e8404bc353c65d81f3ea9991c572cec7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Property of Hercules Courtenay containing accounts of food products, tar, rum,
                     ginseng, ships and shipping ventures, and insurance.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_evm" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Henry William Courtenay daybook</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1801-1804</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_39dc68d6d6ca8da361d68eb03ccd7e44" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">1-2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0889d44a350eefe29a03fdf70b430837">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Property of merchant Henry William Courtenay with accounts for flour, food, and
                     other commodities.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_0nu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Henry William Courtenay scrapbook</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1836</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_8ea88ca5c16bedc354894dad6d4134d2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3387</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_703467900326bf44c526d5a1382cd6eb">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>This volume was started as H.W. Courtenay's record of expenses and then taken
                     for a scrapbook.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_hq5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Boyd ledgers</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1764-1779</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_2102206f5f157fa55bc7815a539bacbc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">3-5</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_25a8deaea058ac2d08f16c2c18386cad">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Property of Dr. John Boyd, Baltimore physician, containing records of an
                     apothecary.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref40_zr5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>E. [Elizabeth Isabella] Purviance recipe and remedy book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_9b1a5ba5933855de23820c36b3d19e2a">144 pages</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_a8cd92ec70e78be4862792f01f3adfbf" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:3389</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref42_q1q" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>E. [Elizabeth Isabella] Purviance recipe book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_6f7e86395849e02d7c55984e55901c3d">24 pages</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_3a329e9e92232068382461b950ad4d4e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3388</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_59e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>David S. Courtenay: List of British vessels destroyed by the Americans,
                     War of 1812</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_69ef57100a09582987561d0671fb6aac">11 pages</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_4fc15bbbada824ada03bf6b3f004d64a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3386</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_hel" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>David S. Courtenay account book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1824-1826</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_26c780a370f73448f87dba3d04ade571" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3383</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b2ea8eb9e5f34002fb7919f7d88d301f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Property of David S. Courtenay recording money spent for postage, cash received
                     for legal services, expenditures in lotteries, and personal expenses.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_fyb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>David S. Courtenay account book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1835-1842</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_3edb495051d5f9bd82b3016c96d21ce6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3384</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_331fb11aeb569c33ea752cf7eeb88177">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Property of David S. Courtenay recording money spent for postage, cash received
                     for legal services, expenditures in lotteries, and personal expenses.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_ec4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>[David S. Courtenay?] address book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_2f07ab5d3536505734e1ead93067a1aa" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3385</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_mgf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Henry Purviance account book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1801-1809</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_959ba9fc57967b8986bf9a41bbcf06d0">68 pages</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_54484c3507aa3ef256baa6940900eac3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3390</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bcf62dc25f301495b614517ec81144ff">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Record of traveling expenses in the U.S. and Europe.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref45_g1u" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Henry Purviance commonplace book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1781</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_449c55d7a898553429460cbfedd120f1">101 pages</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_ae4e746bb5b196c62dea05b283dfd0e8" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3391</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7f98604c8c072e74fd100b8e393de50b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Contains extracts from a tour through Great Britain, excerpts from poems, and a
                     few accounts.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_04x" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Henry Purviance commonplace book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1811-1834</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_3dc80c968c7b721209cb85781d04a937">51 pages</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_1e432f2464f05ea28e031d1fd6f852ca" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3392</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b4df4890926b82dded3949630062cdfa">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Combination commonplace book and travel diary (England and France) with expense
                     accounts and a discussion of French government.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref49_30p" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Henry Purviance commonplace book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_c6babddf9f59e1bd87d303b3ffba5ccb">99 pages</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_25ce913390a68c7dbddd68fdcf608c56" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3393</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_09c2eb6f0a3394127909a79876786248">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Contains excerpts from poems.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref51_9h7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Henry Purviance travel diary</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1819</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_5e48e0625ce234a31ae34e29d3873935">16 pages</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_f45866174bf846f31a62b89855e829c1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3394</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5e247d8cfc58d1066d64dab5bb07993d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Records kept in blank pages of a Traveller's Directory. Purviance records his
                     impressions of the Bayonne-Biarritz area in the course of his diplomatic
                     mission to Spain in 1819.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref53_1mn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Henry Purviance memorandum book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1818</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_d3d14da7310b8f21568444c31f2b865e">51 pages</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_6338197fcbd16994f0d88bb508df5f47" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3395</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2fcf5ebbdbe4e1c86ba663bb82f94231">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes daily entries regarding weather, correspondence with President Monroe,
                     and personal and financial matters.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_95t" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Alexander Courtenay scrapbook</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1892-1909</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_04b26d8ec1627438b87ed9281c22cd10" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3382</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ec740ef1b6e7b09e4f94f75d03adb9e9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Contains clippings relating to Baltimore and to the Purviance and Courtenay
                     families.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_9w9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Anonymous account book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1815</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_458415db802c8f4e3ad2fb92e068d310" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3380</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_h2g" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Anonymous Civil War diary</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1861</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_f1188f192ef5e43c35fa18abe22c7255" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3381</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8ecbae3ef1202561731a405bd906ecf6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Property of a Union soldier including a description of his stay in a
                     Confederate prison.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
