<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/recueils/">recueils</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to Recueils. Affaires Diverses du 18e Siècle, Particulièrement de
               Celles de Dauphiné, 1770-1790 <num>RL.01072</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Library Staff; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Noah Huffman</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">005295222</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 08:02:38
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="fre">French</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Recueils. Affaires Diverses du 18e Siècle, Particulièrement de Celles de
            Dauphiné</unittitle>
         <unitid>RL.01072</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.2 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1770/1790" type="inclusive">1770-1790</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_e4269a1629b081ed6f9a2c3f12e72aa0">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_0526205cdbd29afdd479e0fce80bf041">Manuscript volume includes
            thirty-two articles of varying lengths relating mostly to the political, economic,
            social, and ecclesiastical history of the French province of Dauphiné during the
            eighteenth century. No authors are given for any of the writings. The volume probably
            dates from the decade before the outbreak of the revolutions. Topics of the articles
            include: the boundary between Dauphiné and Sardinia; the government of Geneva in 1733;
            extracts from the registers of the Council of State about certain ecclesiastical
            matters; the boundaries of Dauphiné; methods of teaching at the University of Paris;
            population, emigration, and the Huguenots; the condition and productivity of Valence,
            Montélimar, Crest, and Die; commerce, silk and textile production; meat production; a
            history of fiefs; a petition from the nobles to the King, 1770; Princess Charlotte of
            Brunswick-Wolfenbüttel, wife of the Russian Tsarevich Alexius Petrovich; affairs
            concerning the parliament of Dauphiné; and other matters.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_445ff5c4b9ef1fd169de3ebe488a11ef">
            <extent>1 item</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_484d5cb6a1614a8af97893c6133ea0b1">Material in French
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_975df8fc63bac23629c414018f43c04b">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_a3f7106196c7b3e73ad726c40f6641af">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_f33774951cbc17652c27d87d5044cd89">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Recueils. Affaires Diverses du 18e Siècle, Particulièrement de Celles de Dauphiné, David
            M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_cbc1c4cf0439cfc51eb554c5cc24a998">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>Recueils. Affaires Diverses du 18e Siècle, Particulièrement de Celles de Dauphiné was
            received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library as a purchase,
            date unknown.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_a17d72c5db18d3a123f0e333883e3080">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library Staff, April 2012</p>
         <p>Encoded by Robert Malme and Noah Huffman, June 2012</p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_b21d0e37ab73152e3fb3bf93bc65233e">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Manuscript volume includes thirty-two articles of varying lengths relating mostly to the
            political, economic, social, and ecclesiastical history of the French province of
            Dauphiné during the eighteenth century. No authors are given for any of the writings.
            The volume probably dates from the decade before the outbreak of the revolutions. Topics
            of the articles include: the boundary between Dauphiné and Sardinia; the government of
            Geneva in 1733; extracts from the registers of the Council of State about certain
            ecclesiastical matters; the boundaries of Dauphiné; methods of teaching at the
            University of Paris; population, emigration, and the Huguenots; the condition and
            productivity of Valence, Montélimar, Crest, and Die; commerce, silk and textile
            production; meat production; a history of fiefs; a petition from the nobles to the King,
            1770; Princess Charlotte of Brunswick-Wolfenbüttel, wife of the Russian Tsarevich
            Alexius Petrovich; affairs concerning the parliament of Dauphiné; and other matters.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Valence (Drôme, France) -- 18th century</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Crest (France) -- 18th century</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Dauphiné (France) -- Politics and government</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Dauphiné (France) -- History -- 18th century</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Dauphiné (France) -- Economic conditions</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Dauphiné (France) -- Church history</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Textile industry</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Montélimar (France) -- 18th century</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">France -- History -- 18th century</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Die (France) -- 18th century</geogname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Université de Paris</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref11_w9h" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Recueils. Affaires Diverses du 18e Siècle, Particulièrement de Celles de
                  Dauphiné, 1770-1790</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_13a3021f199646d9ac4fed0d4a64d89d">
                  <extent>1 volume; 469 pages; 36 cm. x 25 cm.</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_9bfb7b6dabb12bd1d71cbc786737b3f5">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Volume contains thirty-two articles of varying lengths:</p>
               <list type="ordered">
                  <item>"Mémoire sur les limites de la Province de Dauphiné et sur les contestations
                     existances ou qui peuvant s'élever entre les sujets de France et ceux de S.M.
                     le Roy de Sardaigne à l'occasion des bornes de leurs territoires respectifs."
                     (pp. 1-28)</item>
                  <item>"Mémoire sur la situation et le gouvernement de la ville de Genève en 1733."
                     (pp. 29-56)</item>
                  <item>"Extrait des registrares du Conseil d'Etat privé du roi sur la requête
                     presentée au Roi en son Couneil, par le sindie des réligieux minime du Convent
                     de la Plaine près Grenoble en Dauphiné" (pp. 57-73).</item>
                  <item>"Arret du Conseil d'état du 14 Janveir 1760, qui déboute le sindie du
                     chapitre de Gap et trois chanoines de la cassation d'un arret du Parlement de
                     Grenoble du 30e Juillet 1756 qui a entretenu un traité fait pour dixme [?],
                     attendu la prescription centenaire; extrait des registres du Conseil d'état
                     privé du Roi." (pp. 74-82)</item>
                  <item>"Mémoire concernant la limitacion des provinces de Dauphiné et de Provence."
                     (pp. 83-100)</item>
                  <item>"Methode d'enseigner suivie dans l'Université de Paris au sujet de la
                     correspondance avec les collès de province, dressé en exécution de l'arret du 3
                     Sept., 1762." (pp. 193-231)</item>
                  <item>"Plan d'enseigment élémentaire sur la philosophie déposé par M. le Recteur
                     de l'Université de Paris le 2e Janvier 1765." (pp. 162-192)</item>
                  <item>"Mémoire de l'Université de Paris au sujet de la correspondance avec les
                     collèges de province, dressé en exécution de l'arret du 3 Sept., 1762." (pp.
                     193-231)</item>
                  <item>"Mémoire sur la population, son état actuel, si elle est diminuées, et les
                     causes intérieures et extérieures; l'état des religionnaires, les émigrations
                     qui se sont faites, le nombre de marriages, nuls actuellement suivant nos lois;
                     et les remèdes les plus expédiens pour réparer le mal passé et le prévenir pour
                     les tems avenir, la mandicité, le défaut de culture faute de bras, et enfin
                     tout ce qui touche la population." (pp. 232-246)</item>
                  <item>"Mémoire sur la position des contrées de Valence, Montélimart, Crest, et
                     Die, les Rivières qui y coulent, les secoure dont elles sont, la qualité des
                     terres en général, leurs productions ordinaires et leurs cultures." (pp.
                     247-262)</item>
                  <item>"Mémoire sur le commerce, les manufactures de soye, de draperie; le monde
                     quelles occupent, la quantité de matières quelles emploient, leurs débouchés,
                     les moyens de les étendre et de les augmenter; les entraves actuelles du
                     commerce, et les moyens de l'en dégager; dans les contrées du Valentinois
                     Divis[?], et des Baronies en Dauphiné." (pp. 263-279)</item>
                  <item>"Mémoire concernant la viande de boucherie pour la ville de Grenoble." (pp.
                     281-210)</item>
                  <item>"Historie des fiefs." (pp. 311-378)</item>
                  <item>"Mémoire de la noblesse, présenté au Roy au mois de May, 1770." (pp.
                     379-389)</item>
                  <item>"Anecdote de la Princesse de Bruswick Wolfenbutel, épouse du Czar Witz
                     Alexis, fils de Pierre le Grand." (pp. 389-393)</item>
                  <item>"Mémoire envoyé à Aix à la fin de 1771 aprés la résolution du parlement."
                     (pp. 394-396)</item>
                  <item>"Mémoire envoyé à Toulousse en Janvier 1772, après la résolution du
                     Parlement." (pp. 396-399)</item>
                  <item>"Mémoire envoyé à Dijon en Janvier 1772." (pp. 400-404)</item>
                  <item>"Mémoire concernant la jurisdiction en général des juges consuls, et en
                     particulier celle de prévôtt des marchands et échevins de Lyon, sous le double
                     rapport de juge consul, et de juge conservateur des privilèges des foires."
                     (ff. 406-415)</item>
                  <item>"Motifs de l'arret du Parlement de Grenoble du 17 février 1778, entre les
                     maires échevins et communauté de Courteson appellants du jugement du Bureau des
                     Finances, Le Comte de Modene intimé d'autre." (ff. 415-419)</item>
                  <item>"Parlement de Dauphiné." (ff. 419-425)</item>
                  <item>"De la noblesse du Parlement de Grenoble." (ff. 425-427)</item>
                  <item>"Noms Romains dans le Dauphiné." (f. 428)</item>
                  <item>"Noms et armes." (f. 428)</item>
                  <item>"Ordres de Dauphiné." (f. 429)</item>
                  <item>"Devises." (ff. 430-432)</item>
                  <item>"Elections de Dauphiné." (ff. 432-433)</item>
                  <item>"Feux." (ff. 433-434)</item>
                  <item>"États de Dauphiné." (f. 435)</item>
                  <item>"Forests de Dauphiné." (ff. 436-437)</item>
                  <item>"Faucigni où Foucigny." (ff. 438-439)</item>
                  <item>"Au Roy et à nosseigneurs de son conseil (Les prévôt, dignitaires,
                     chanoines, et chapitre de la ville d'Orange...contre Le Sieur Jean
                     D'___chanoine en l'eglise cathédrale de la ville Bayonne)." (ff.
                     439-469)</item>
               </list>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
