<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/robbinsburr/">robbinsburr</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Burr L. Robbins Papers, 1936-1975 and undated
                  <num>RL.01095</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rita Johnston; machine-readable finding aid created by: Rita
               Johnston</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">002637113</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 08:17:29
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Burr L. Robbins papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Robbins, Burr L. (Burr Lamberton), 1902-1980</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01095</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.1 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1942/1975" type="inclusive">1936-1975 and undated</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_c878b2695f70ae4522065f2bc1e75128">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_fc55e1e2d9b0c5d77d432cd8bcf4f4d3">Burr Lamberton Robbins was president
            of the General Outdoor Advertising Company (GOA). The Burr L. Robbins Papers span the
            years 1936-1975, and chiefly consist of three scrapbooks containing photographs,
            clippings, periodicals, memorabilia, and promotional materials. The majority of
            clippings are from advertising industry publications and Chicago newspapers. The loose
            materials section also includes administrative records. The collection primarily
            documents Robbins' career in outdoor advertising with the General Outdoor Advertising
            Company (GOA), and his involvement with professional advertising organizations,
            particularly the Outdoor Advertising Association of America (OAAA). Professional and
            outdoor advertising themes in the scrapbooks include Robbins' career advancement; his
            public speaking engagements on the role of advertising agencies in America; professional
            meetings and conferences; the history of GOA; outdoor advertising history; tension
            between citizens' groups and outdoor advertisers over billboard zoning; and legal
            decisions. The scrapbooks also touch on topics of personal interest to Robbins,
            including news about the Delevan Lake Improvement Association; Robbinswood Farm sheep;
            and family events. Photographs in the scrapbooks are primarily of professional meetings
            or conferences, or publicity events. Loose materials include items that were once part
            of the scrapbooks, and separate items. This section includes a notebook of 1942
            photographs and papers about the 13th National Contest and Exhibit of Outdoor
            Advertising Art. Photographs of the three prizewinning posters, created by John DeLooy,
            Andrew Loomis, and Albert Staehle, are included in this notebook. Also in this section
            is a spiral-bound GOA publication, Image with Words, that documents a 1963 Chevrolet
            electric outdoor advertising campaign.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_d48ea193d18aaaf0a5947e106761d0b2">
            <extent>1650 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_defe0fd8a8cfc92f4c4cb429bd1374c4">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_0eae8dcf55f5cc6b1f5d7b07251f81e9">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_6813dd5c21e980fbab394586e4668105">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_996f5c956900905b14c8477137f95b19">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Burr L. Robbins Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_acfd72cddff046da9ff692fbbdb611fb">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Burr L. Robbins Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a gift in 1999.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_6092cc1c039ea049aedd44e76eb3d7e5">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rita Johnston, November 2007</p>
         <p>Encoded by Rita Johnston, November 2007</p>
         <p>Accession 1999-0443 is described in this finding aid.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_741c5e46a51fed33a96b756f76a1c4bb">
         <head>Biographical and Historical Note</head>
         <chronlist>
            <head>Burr L. Robbins</head>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1902</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Born Chicago, Ill.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1925</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Graduated from the University of Chicago</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1925</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Married Margaret Ross</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1925</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Employed as billposter, GOA</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1930</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Founded the annual National Contest and Exhibit of Outdoor Advertising
                     Art</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1931</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Promoted to Chicago manager, GOA</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1934</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Appointed Vice-President of the Chicago District, GOA</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1936</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Appointed Regional Manager of the Chicago District, GOA</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1941-1950</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Chairman of the Outdoor Advertising Association of America (OAAA) Outdoor
                     Advertising Foundation at Notre Dame</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1946</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Elected Executive Vice President, GOA</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1951</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Elected President, GOA</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1960</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Awarded the Navy Distinguished Public Service Award for Navy recruitment
                     effors through outdoor advertising</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1980</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Died, Chicago, Ill.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
         </chronlist>
         <chronlist>
            <head>General Outdoor Advertising Company (GOA)</head>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1925</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Burnett W. (B.W.) Robbins, father of Burr Robbins, founded GOA</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1925-1951</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Tenure of B.W. Robbins as President</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1931</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Outdoor Advertising, Inc. (OAI) spun off from GOA to manage selling and
                     operating</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1951-circa 1960s</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Tenure of Burr L. Robbins as President</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1952</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>B.W. Robbins died</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1957</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>GOA purchased Canadian firm Claude Neon General Advertising,
                     Limited</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1963</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Outdoor advertising company Gamble-Skogmo, Inc. acquired control of
                     GOA</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1963-1964</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>GOA sold branches and ceased activity as an operating company</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
         </chronlist>
         <p>Burr L. Robbins was a third-generation outdoor advertising executive whose father,
            Burnett W. (B.W.) Robbins, founded GOA. Robbins's grandfather, Burr Robbins, founded the
            American Billposting Company around 1890 to promote his popular circus, the Burr Robbins
            Circus. </p>
         <p>In addition to the business interests listed above, Robbins served as an executive and
            director of a number of firms and organizations: the Lexington Poster Advertising
            Company; the Executive Committee of Outdoor Advertising Incorporated (OAI); Majestic
            Radio and Television Corporation; Walker and Company of Detroit; Old Colony Advertising
            Company; Mercantile National Bank of Chicago; and the Pittsburgh Outdoor Advertising
            Company.</p>
         <p>Robbins took on an active role in varied professional, social, and charitable
            organizations. In addition to the organizational interests listed above, Robbins served
            with the Outdoor Advertising Association of America (OAAA); the Council on Medical and
            Biological Research at the University of Chicago; the Chicago Crime Commission; the
            Better Business Bureau of Chicago; the Traffic Audit Bureau; the Advertising Council;
            the Advertising Federation of America; the Chicago Federated Advertising Club; the
            Delavan Lake Improvement Association; the German Shepherd Dog Club of America; and the
            American Shropshire Registry Association.</p>
         <p>Robbins enjoyed operating his family farm, Robbinswood Farm, in Delevan, Wisconsin. He
            consistently won awards for his Shropshire sheep, and also raised Hereford and Berkshire
            sheep.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_73ce205fdb9fc4c8f3b136ad126ac6d4">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The Burr L. Robbins Papers span the years 1936-1975, and chiefly consist of three
            scrapbooks containing photographs, clippings, periodicals, memorabilia, and promotional
            materials. The majority of clippings are from advertising industry publications and
            Chicago newspapers. The loose materials section also includes administrative records.
            The collection primarily documents Robbins' career in outdoor advertising with the
            General Outdoor Advertising Company (GOA), and his involvement with professional
            advertising organizations, particularly the Outdoor Advertising Association of America
            (OAAA). Professional and outdoor advertising themes in the scrapbooks include Robbins'
            career advancement; his public speaking engagements on the role of advertising agencies
            in America; professional meetings and conferences; the history of GOA; outdoor
            advertising history; tension between citizens' groups and outdoor advertisers over
            billboard zoning; and legal decisions. The scrapbooks also touch on topics of personal
            interest to Robbins, including news about the Delevan Lake Improvement Association;
            Robbinswood Farm sheep; and family events. Photographs in the scrapbooks are primarily
            of professional meetings or conferences; advertising executives; or publicity events.
            Loose materials include items that were once part of the scrapbooks, and separate items.
            This section includes a notebook of 1942 photographs and papers about the 13th National
            Contest and Exhibit of Outdoor Advertising Art. Photographs of the three prizewinning
            posters, created by John DeLooy, Andrew Loomis, and Albert Staehle, are included in this
            notebook. Also in this section is a spiral-bound GOA publication, <title type="simple"
               render="doublequote">Image with Words,</title> that documents a 1963 Chevrolet
            electric outdoor advertising campaign.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_d636600fe76b9d9ab8dc5be32fa66cd2">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>Materials related to this collection may be found in other Hartman Center collections,
            including the <emph render="bold">Outdoor Advertising Association of America (OAAA)
               Archives</emph>, <emph render="bold">OAAA Poster Design Collection</emph>, and the
               <emph render="bold">OAAA Slide Library</emph>. Materials related to the commerical
            artist Albert Staehle may be found in the <emph render="bold">Garrett Orr
            Papers</emph>.</p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising campaigns</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Administrative records</genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising, Outdoor -- Law and legislation</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising, Outdoor -- Congresses</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
         <genreform source="aat">Memorabilia</genreform>
         <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
         <genreform source="aat">Promotional materials</genreform>
         <genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
         <geogname source="lcsh">John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising &amp; Marketing
            History</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising, Outdoor -- United States -- History -- 20th
            century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising, Outdoor -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising, Outdoor -- History</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising, Outdoor</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising executives -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising executives -- History -- 20th century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising agencies -- Illinois</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising agencies -- United States</subject>
         <persname source="ingest">Robbins, Burr L. (Burr Lamberton), 1902-1980</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Loomis, Andrew, b. 1892</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">General Outdoor Advertising Co</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">General Outdoor Advertising Co. -- History</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Staehle, Albert, 1899-</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Robbins, Burr L. (Burr Lamberton), 1902-1980</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Outdoor Advertising Association of America</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref16_gh7" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Scrapbooks and Loose Materials, 1936-1975 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_b18460b0a512f8b675dd09b101979881">
                  <extent>4 Boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_c5210907c625169bfa0646d12e4e2f6c">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Consists of scrapbooks and loose materials. Scrapbooks contain photographs,
                  magazine and newspaper clippings, periodicals, memorabilia, and promotional
                  materials. The scrapbooks chiefly document Robbins' professional life and the
                  history of the General Outdoor Advertising Company (GOA), but also include items
                  relating to Robbins' personal life. Loose materials include scrapbook items that
                  had been removed or had fallen out, and other materials. Includes a notebook of
                  1942 photographs and papers about the 13th National Contest and Exhibit of Outdoor
                  Advertising Art. Also contained in this section is a spiral-bound GOA publication,
                  "Image with Words," that was created to document a 1963 Chevrolet electric outdoor
                  advertising campaign. Scrapbooks are arranged in original page order. No order
                  could be determined for loose materials.</p>
               <p>Note: This series contains pictorial materials, newsprint, and other fragile
                  materials. Please handle with care. Technical Services staff may need to reformat
                  newsprint or other brittle paper.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_ojr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Scrapbook 1, 1946-1961 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_3b356fdbd452097f7ea623291c091578">
                     <extent>6 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_45318595067ccd98504ee85c93c2b422" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_pp5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Scrapbook 2, 1936-1958 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_424846fff3209c833cdd62496baeeafa">
                     <extent>6 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_237918ebf06680518aac6000de419ab1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_g1v" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Scrapbook 3, 1960-1963 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_8ffe8a84ffc354270cbda6794f0f192b">
                     <extent>9 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_e1e332c44c36a1cf4685ac98c5657f30" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_xvh" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Loose materials, 1942-1975 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_a1618adfe7aa4d5122286524031f3239">
                     <extent>2 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_cf4a9150ab44e2b7bc849e1609685edd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
