<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/rosserfannie/">rosserfannie</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Fannie B. Rosser Papers, circa 1860s-1973, 2012, bulk
               1920s-1973 <num>RL.01111</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Ginny Daley; Jennifer Morgan; machine-readable finding aid created
               by: Joshua A. Kaiser</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2003</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">001021266</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-02-11 15:43:08
               -0500</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2016</date>
            <item>Addition of printed publication, update of collection guide, Paula Jeannet
               Mangiafico</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Fannie B. Rosser papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Rosser, Fannie B.</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01111</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1860/2012" type="inclusive">circa 1860s-1973, 2012, bulk
            1920s-1973</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_b92507a2892e0290172c80f16af5ebb0">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <physdesc id="aspace_c36e130d859a5f5d795361334dfcd4da">
            <extent>750 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_98b12172d983c6bf110d2730cf8b3ca1">English. </langmaterial>
         <abstract id="aspace_dfa4bce8df6a2236fd16941e2358e970">Correspondence, legal and financial
            papers, printed materials, and photographs document the personal relationships and
            professional activities of Rosser, a successful single African American businesswoman.
            Correspondence, 1920s-1940s, pertains to Rosser's business ventures in regard to the
            management of her rental property in Lynchburg, Virginia, and Durham, North Carolina;
            personal loans made to family and friends during the Depression; and her investments in
            government stocks and bonds. Later correspondence centers around her relationships with
            her foster daughter, Mattie Burton Meyers, and Rosser's niece, June. A folder of printed
            materials includes news clippings on both family events and local politics, church
            programs, and obituaries, and a 2012 publication about Fannie Rosser's foster daughter,
            Mattie Burton Meyers, active in the NAACP in Fresno, California. Family photographs date
            back to about the 1860s and include an early ambrotype, cabinet cards, and snapshots of
            Rosser and her friends in the 1920s and her daughter's family in Fresno, Calif., in the
            1960s.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_050ae8a40aaa7e8275ced65229629a46">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_1b2fde7d9cfe3126123314fc81900482">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_0151e153124a56182f76a7bc71a1f0dd">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Fannie B. Rosser Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_d0e8214b3a730d76981c1d1526e938b9">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Fannie B. Rosser Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1976 and gift in 2012.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_514210e29ff4c8b9543f36ec81c799f1">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Ginny Daley; Jennifer Morgan</p>
         <p>Completed January 3, 1991</p>
         <p>Encoded by Joshua A. Kaiser</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_a3fa49482b74858599336a6f089df7f0">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Fannie B. Rosser, a native of Lynchburg, Virginia, was the daughter of Edmond and Callie
            Rosser and sister of Maggie, Pansy, Joseph Irvin and James Boyd Rosser. Edmond Rosser
            was a porter for the Pullman Palace Car Company and the Rosser family apparently
            occupied a position of status and influence in the African American community of
            Lynchburg.</p>
         <p>Rosser moved to Durham, North Carolina after being offered a position by the North
            Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company in September of 1914. For thirty-two years she
            was employed by the Mutual, owned rental properties in both Durham and Lynchburg, and
            lived in Durham for the remainder of her life.</p>
         <p>Although she never married, Rosser was a foster mother to Mattie Douglas Burton, and a
            guardian aunt to her brother's daughter, June Rosser. Burton married Dr. Earl Randolph
            Meyers of Fresno, California in 1946. They had five children, and Mattie Meyers became a
            leader in the Fresno chapter of the NAACP where she served as president for some time.
            June Rosser married Eugene Hudson Penick in 1961. She had a least three children and
            remained consistently financially dependent on her aunt until Rosser's death.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_6fe18e52f98f33ebd9f7e74656a34e40">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The papers of Fannie B. Rosser document the personal and professional life of a black
            businesswoman within a fiscally sound African American community in Durham, N.C.
            Correspondence, legal and financial papers, printed materials, and photographs reflect
            both her business activities and her relationships with close friends and family members
            from the turn of the century to the 1970s.</p>
         <p>The bulk of the correspondence until the 1950s pertains to Rosser's business ventures,
            including maintenance of her property, personal loans made to family and friends, and
            her investments in government stocks and bonds. Letters from her lifelong friend and
            business partner, Virginia Randolf of Lynchburg, Va., document the process of
            maintaining Rosser's rental property over the course of thirty years. They highlight,
            among other things, the apparent ghettoization of the neighborhood in which her houses
            were situated, and Randolf's personal and financial response to that process.</p>
         <p>Friends and family members often deferred financial matters to Rosser, a careful and
            respected business woman, and were often dependent on her for monetary support. The
            correspondence illustrates Rosser's financial acumen and demonstrates the extent to
            which her personal relationships and business activities overlapped. Of particular
            interest is an exchange with the Wilhoite's, a couple to whom she loaned $1000, during
            the Depression. Their correspondence illustrates the personal nature of her business
            dealings and the difficulties Rosser had in balancing finances and friendships.</p>
         <p>Later correspondence centers around Rosser's relationships with her foster daughter
            Mattie Burton Meyers and niece June. There are scattered references to the political
            climate of the 1960s, and correspondence from Mattie mentions her work with the NAACP.
            Also, in the printed materials there is a 2012 published biography of Mattie written by
            her granddaughter Sharon Revis-Green.</p>
         <p>The printed materials consist of materials such as news clippings on both family events
            and local politics, church programs, and obituaries. A large series of financial and
            legal papers, 1895-1969, provide extensive detail on Rosser's investments, insurance
            policies, and legal activities. Many of these documents are associated with firms such
            as the North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company, where Rosser was employed.</p>
         <p>The photographs in the collection date back to the early 1860s and are mostly individual
            portraits and group photographs of African American family members and friends. An
            unidentified ambrotype of an African American woman dated prior to the Civil War
            indicates that the family might have been free.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Pictorial works</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Single women</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Interpersonal relations</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American women -- Virginia</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American business enterprises</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Housing -- Virginia</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Housing -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Mothers and daughters</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Businesswomen</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American women -- California</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American women -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Self-employed women</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Real estate management -- Virginia</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Real estate management -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Correspondence</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American families</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Correspondence</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American business people</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Virginia</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs</genreform>
         <genreform source="aat">Ambrotypes</genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">Cabinet photographs</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Portraits</subject>
         <persname source="ingest">Rosser, Fannie B.</persname>
         <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Meyers, Mattie Burton</persname>
         <corpname rules="dacs" source="lcsh">National Association for the Advancement of Colored
            People -- Branches, chapters, etc. -- California -- Fresno</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref11_zvp" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Fannie B. Rosser papers</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref12_3bi" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1909-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_aaa405bc2700a7aae551cf0374efe3ef" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e37dbf28784f50ce892e3e0c63e25b03">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Correspondence in the collection concerns management of real estate properties
                     in Durham, N.C. and Lynchburg, Va., and other business matters; personal
                     correspondence with friends and family in Lynchburg, Virginia, Fresno,
                     California, and Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Arranged chronologically.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_5363f52b9ffaa1b91692b9682a1b455d" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1963-1968 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_4319274a37da51ffa85906188e8592bb">
                     <extent>5 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_a29affc591ec23e8dcf5351cee7d0e62" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_4j6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Legal papers, 1895-1967 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_ea755850d5d208e2fd2ebd8fabb5764f">
                     <extent>1 folder</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_b3c8931e648786900f9bf2cac42a8163" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_360d0a622a14d0b2074160ed09d0196d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Deeds and assessments of property owned by Rosser in the 1920s to 1950s; stock
                     certificates; codicils to Rosser's will; power of attorney notices from
                     brothers James and Irvin; personal and property insurance forms; Irvin and
                     Goldie Rosser's 1962 divorce papers. Arranged chronologically</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_abt" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Financial papers, 1867-1969</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_205b1dc85509df637c08d9840d8a48fe">
                     <extent>2 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_6ab450cfdfa26f88b46938b97ce44255" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d2ccce263f3369429c13b2f69645c859">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Promissory note dated 1867; loan forms from First National Bank to Rosser; loan
                     forms from Rosser to other individuals; financial statements on Rosser and
                     others; tax forms and receipts; lists of outstanding personal loans due Rosser
                     as of 1966. Arranged chronologically.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_2dt" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Newspaper clippings, 1893-1961 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_4018a36d972282597d2c022da54f896e">
                     <extent>1 folder</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_86be48f2e5c6e1dd8c2c0ffe813fa509" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_453b95e3916d3c5fb167f140490cdee1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Scattered articles and editorials on race relations; obituaries and wedding
                     notices of family and friends. Arranged chronologically.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_ktz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed materials, 1920-1973, 2012 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_5020a7d4eb0dcfcd2289935abeed38ed">
                     <extent>1 folder</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_e32f630cd9c5062891bed5eec6be29ca" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b1f947dec269936ca5a194620eed3554">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Church programs from St. Joseph's A.M.E. Church in Durham, 1960s; miscellaneous
                     invitations; 1920 ballot list; program from black <emph render="doublequote"
                        >Benevolent Order,</emph> undated; 1973 food stamp allotment form. Also
                     includes a 2012 biography of Fannie Rosser's foster daughter, Mattie Meyers,
                        <title render="italic">A record of events regarding: Mattie Meyers a civil
                        rights trailblazer</title>, written by Sharon Revis-Green of Madera,
                     California, Mattie Meyers's granddaughter.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_peg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Other papers and fragments, undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_c378236793f97e216ed8a5b593d70086">
                     <extent>1 folder</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_99d58f0b617097fc72540d3bbbf0f898" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fa8a8947be146bc61c2687d92e52c0bb">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Three essays (author unknown) on education, and one on <title type="simple"
                        render="doublequote">Training the Negro for Social Powers</title>; speech
                     notes for an honorary dinner for C.C. Spaulding; list of Rosser's instructions
                     upon her death regarding the disposition of her property in Lynchburg,
                     Virginia, and her daughter, who was living there at the time. Most of these
                     papers are typed but some are handwritten.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_lpn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photographs, circa 1860s-1960s</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_450a0a9f187f118c59fb57c5ceb5105f">
                     <extent>.2 lin. ft.</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_7ad55402491b347e9f42e8aa9ac419dc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5e3c02a062ebbca51a4b4c49353f7639">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Cabinet cards, cartes-de-visites, mounted albumen prints, tintypes,
                     black-and-white and color snapshots, chiefly of Rosser's family and friends.
                     Most prints ca. 1870s-1910s are unidentified but were taken by photographers in
                     Lynchburg and Richmond, Virginia. Included are an ambrotype of woman from about
                     the early 1860s; a tintype of Rosser's grandmother; albumen prints of Rosser as
                     a young woman during the 1920s; and snapshots of her foster daughter Mattie
                     Burton Meyers' family in the 1950s. Arranged by family group, then
                     chronological therein.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
