<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/rutherfoordjohn/"
         >rutherfoordjohn</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the John Rutherfoord Papers, 1754-1931 (bulk 1781-1865)
                  <num>RL.10087</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Bob Malme</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000874782</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 17:30:54
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>John Rutherfoord papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Rutherfoord, John</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.10087</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.5 Linear Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">6 Boxes (2,745 items)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1754/1931" type="inclusive">1754-1931, bulk 1781-1865</unitdate>
         <unitdate normal="1781/1865" type="bulk">bulk</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_c41387b9e64dc76912ef10fea5512ce8">Collection contains correspondence,
            travel journals, account books, memorandum books, farm records, legal records,
            commonplace books, class notes, and other papers (chiefly 1781-1865) of John
            Rutherfoord; of his son, John Coles Rutherfoord, lawyer, planter, and state legislator;
            and of other members of the family. The papers before 1818 are chiefly legal and
            business papers and include information on family investments in Kentucky lands and
            other ventures. The papers of John Rutherfoord relate to his career as governor, his
            agricultural and business affairs; Virginia and U.S. politics, the American Party; the
            return of fugitive slaves, secession and events preceeding the Civil War, Confederate
            foreign relations; and family matters; and they include letters from Edward Coles,
            William Cabell Rives, and others of Rutherfoord's relatives by marriage, concerning
            agriculture and anti-slavery sentiment in Virginia and relations between the United
            States and France. John Coles Rutherfoord's papers relate to his attendance at
            Washington College (now Washington and Lee University) and the University of Virginia,
            his interests in politics and European travel, his legal activities, his work as a state
            legislator (1852-1865) and as manager of the family estates, westward expansion, and
            social life and customs in Virginia. Includes scattered correspondence of J.C.
            Rutherfoord's wife, Ann Seddon Roy Rutherfoord, referring to life in the South during
            and after the Civil War, and family matters.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_c42bd4e4c3fd11a6ac9b96b76a2eeba0">Materials in
            English</langmaterial>
         <physloc id="aspace_81af6b5563e087059c439c98bfae7a72">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_e0864bd06ec0f2e9846cf1e1ccff5ff6">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <bioghist id="aspace_c05b538880a1112d3be602aa098a3a03">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>John Rutherfoord (1792-1866) was a lawyer, merchant, and governor of Virginia from 1841
            to 1842. His son, John Coles Rutherfoord (1825-1866), was a lawyer, planter, and member
            of the Virginia House of Delegates. Ann Seddon (Roy) Rutherfoord (1832-1906?), was the
            wife of John Coles Rutherfoord. Thomas Rutherfoord (1766-1852), was the father of John
            Rutherfoord, and a Richmond merchant.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <prefercite id="aspace_809f45ce8dfb31408cb2e5ff14dcd549">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], in the John Rutherfoord Papers Collection, David M. Rubenstein
            Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_d9c7535c6176a127d4e3e514c7ab2f50">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstien Library staff.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_3348ccb62f2b62160fa25a1327619cf7">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>This collection contains family, business, personal, and political correspondence of
            John Rutherfoord (1792-1866), lawyer, merchant, and governor of Virginia, 1841-1842; of
            his son, John Coles Rutherfoord (1825-1866), lawyer, planter, and member of the House of
            Delegates; of Ann Seddon (Roy) Rutherfoord (1832-1906?), wife of John Coles Rutherfoord;
            and of Thomas Rutherfoord (1766-1852), father of John Rutherfoord, and Richmond
            merchant. </p>
         <p>Early papers are those of Isaac Holmes, assistant quartermaster at Petersburg, Virginia,
            chiefly from Richard Claiborne concerning provisions for Revolutionary soldiers; and of
            James Webb, apparently a lawyer of Smithfield, Virginia, having connections with John
            Marshall, Spencer Roane, and John Wickham, consisting of legal correspondence and
            papers. The papers of Thomas Rutherfoord include a letter, 1810, expressing objections
            to the embargo; letters concerning family matters and Rutherfoord's ailments;
            correspondence dealing with business affairs, chiefly his large landholdings in Kentucky
            and Ohio, and the title and sale of those lands; and an article, 1812, on the necessity
            of a navy to protect the maritime rights of the United States. Personal correspondence
            of John Rutherfoord is primarily with relatives, including his son, John Coles
            Rutherfoord; his brothers, Samuel Rutherfoord, William Rutherfoord, and Alexander
            Rutherfoord, and their families; relatives of Emily (Coles), Rutherfoord, his wife,
            including Tucker Coles, Isaac A. Coles, Edward Coles, Andrew Stevenson, and William
            Cabell Rives; his brother-in-law, Hodijah Meade; and Jane (Rutherfoord) Meade. Letters
            discuss family news; business matters; agriculture and the operation of their various
            plantations; the painting of family portraits; the marketing of wheat produced at
            &#x93;Rock Castle,&#x94; home of John Coles Rutherfoord, during the 1840s and 1850s;
            visits to various springs in western Virginia; the insurance society headed by John
            Rutherfoord; family illnesses, including full descriptions of remedies and medicines;
            purchase of land; detailed accounts of the construction of a boat for use at "Rock
            Castle"; purchase of a buggy, including description of various types of buggies;
            purchase and price of guano; detailed accounts of shipping by freight boats on the James
            River; purchase of slaves to prevent the separation of families; sympathy for slaves;
            purchase of shoes and making of clothes for slaver at &#x93;Rock Castle&#x94;; details
            of household management, such as the making of candles and the slaughtering of sheep;
            Richmond social life; and current events. Also included are letters from relatives in
            Ireland; letters of advice from John Rutherfoord to his son, John Coles Rutherfoord,
            while the latter was a student at Washington College, Lexington, Virginia, and at the
            University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia; letter, 1837, from Andrew Stevenson,
            U.S. minister to England, describing his and his wife's experiences in diplomatic
            circles in London, and papers relating to the settlement of the case of the U.S.S.
            Caroline, burned in 1837 by Canadian troops; a letter, 1832, from William Cabell Rives,
            while minister to France, concerning the instability of the French government, and
            Rives's conviction that slavery should be abolished; and letters discussing the
            activities of Thomas Ritchie (1778-1854), editor of the Richmond Enquirer, especially
            during 1849. Other papers relate to Rutherfoord's bank stocks, his legal practice, and
            mercantile affairs in Richmond, Virginia. The political correspondence includes
            correspondence between Rutherfoord and John Tyler concerning national politics,
            1827-1831, Andrew Jackson and his policies, Henry Clay, political intrigue, "sectional
            cupidity," European affairs, and Tyler's concern for the welfare of the country;
            correspondence with Governor William H. Seward of New York while Rutherfoord was
            governor of Virginia pertaining to a controversy over fugitive slaves; letters from
            Rutherfoord to John Coles Rutherfoord commenting extensively on the American Party or
            Know-Nothings in Goochland County, Virginia; letters, 1860, from C. G. Memminger
            regarding national politics, secession, and the possibility of war; letter, 1860, from
            Rutherfoord to a cousin in London discussing the election of Abraham Lincoln, national
            politics, and his hatred of abolitionists, and protesting that the Prince of Wales had
            not been mistreated in Richmond; correspondence concerning the coming of the Civil War,
            the scarcity of food during the war, and refugees; letter, 1861, from John Brockenbrough
            describing the Washington Peace Convention and commenting on the compromise plan
            proposed by John Jordan Crittenden; letter, written under an assumed name, to
            Rutherfoord from Sir William Henry Gregory, member of the British Parliament with
            sympathies for the Confederate States of America, regarding the possibilities of
            recognition of the Confederate government by England and the means of communicating with
            Rutherfoord's nephew, who was attending a German university [published: Nannie M. Tilley
            (ed.), England and the Confederacy, American Historical Review 44 (October, 1938),
            56-60]; and papers relating to Rutherfoord's service on a committee to assess damages
            made by the Confederate government in erecting defenses in Richmond. </p>
         <p>The papers of John Coles Rutherfoord consist of his letters concerning literature, the
            activities of the Virginia House of Delegates, work on a banking bill in 1854, the
            Know-Nothing Party in Goochland County and their opposition to Rutherfoord's candidacy
            for a seat in the House of Delegates, visits to various springs in Virginia, trips to
            South Carolina to visit relatives, his courtship of Ann Seddon Roy, and his legal
            practice; correspondence regarding preparations for a European tour made by John Coles
            Rutherfoord and Charles Morris in 1851; letters to Rutherfoord discussing Virginia
            politics in the 1850s; letters from a former college mate, William M. Cooke, describing
            his legal practice in Saint Louis and Hannibal, Missouri, the slavery question, the
            growth of Saint Louis, emigrants to California and the sale of supplies to them, hunting
            grouse on the prairies, and the Know-Nothing Party in Missouri in 1855; letters from
            John D. Osborne and William Cabell Rives, Jr., containing descriptions of their travels
            in the North and in Europe and conditions in Paris, France; scattered letters referring
            to the College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Virginia, and to the Southern Literary
            Messenger and John R. Thompson; and letters from William P. Munford concerning the
            translation of Homer's Iliad by his father, William Munford, and his own plans to have
            it published. </p>
         <p>Correspondence of Ann Seddon (Roy) Rutherfoord includes letters to her husband, John
            Coles Rutherfoord, concerning preparations and plans for her visits to her father,
            William H. Roy, household matters, and their children; letters from William H. Roy to
            Ann Seddon (Roy) Rutherfoord; papers pertaining to the settlement of William H. Roy's
            estate; letters from her sister, Sue (Roy) Carter, and from her aunt, Sarah (Seddon)
            Bruce, describing their children, accouchements, servants, household affairs, crops,
            care for slaves, and, during the Civil War, refugees, the scarcity of food, family
            members in the Confederate Army, and crowded conditions in Richmond, Virginia; letters
            of James A. Seddon regarding the business affairs of Ann Seddon (Roy) Rutherfoord after
            the death of her husband; letters from other friends and relatives chiefly concerning
            personal matters; and papers relating to the operation of "Rock Castle," including
            scattered accounts, contracts for labor, and inventories. </p>
         <p>Volumes consist of a notebook on rhetoric by Emily (Coles) Rutherfoord; legal notebook
            of John Rutherfoord containing notes on Blackstone; personal account book, 1840-1841, of
            John Coles Rutherfoord; autographs and clippings collected by John Coles Rutherfoord,
            1836-1850; commonplace book, 1839-1842, of John Coles Rutherfoord also containing copies
            of several letters; Index Rerum, 1842, kept by John Coles Rutherfoord while at the
            University of Virginia; notebooks of John Coles Rutherfoord while a student at
            Washington College, on various subjects including chemistry, mathematics, Greek history,
            natural and moral philosophy, political economy, Latin history, law, and the
            Constitution; case books, 1844-1852, and memorandum book, 1856-1862, containing records
            of the cases handled by John Coles Rutherfoord; memorandum book, 1846-1864, with notes
            on farming operations; letter book, 1857-1866, letterpress copybook, 1856-1866, and
            letter book and commonplace book, 1852-1858, of John Coles Rutherfoord; index,
            1856-1865, of the letters received by John Coles Rutherfoord; indices to articles on
            politics and major events in the New York Herald, 1856-1859, and in the Richmond
            Examiner, 1862-1865; notebook on Rutherfoord family history; a scrapbook, 1843-1856,
            relating to the career of John Coles Rutherfoord in the Virginia House of Delegates; and
            a legal notebook, 1895-1916, of John Rutherfoord, son of John Coles Rutherfoord.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_cbdac01fff445c55fe093426de70d877">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Territorial expansion</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 --
            Causes</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Governors -- Virginia</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Europe -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Agriculture -- Virginia</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Virginia -- Social life and customs</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Virginia -- Politics and government -- 1775-1865</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Fugitive slaves -- Virginia</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Politics and government -- 1815-1861 </geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges -- Virginia</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Antislavery movements -- Virginia</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Real property -- Kentucky</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Foreign relations -- France</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">France -- Foreign relations -- United States</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Confederate States of America -- Foreign relations</geogname>
         <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Rutherfoord, John</persname>
         <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Rutherfoord, John C. (John Coles)</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">University of Virginia -- Students</corpname>
         <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Washington and Lee University -- Students</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref48_lva" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>John Rutherfoord Papers</unittitle>
               <unitdate normal="1754/1931" type="inclusive">1754-1931</unitdate>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref9_f2b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence and papers</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1754-1843</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_8ee85f1246dbc1a97a792e13fde5f592" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref10_o9y" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence and papers</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1844-1848</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_33b1dd3cad46ee2bb906ba7d1b53eb6f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref11_0gu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Notebooks</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1842-1846 and undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_b4d4b809e8bde9dcb126563da22c9a27" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref12_f9v" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence and papers</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1849-1854</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_7509a4c2c131ff95189f47713979496a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref13_ty3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence and papers</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1855-1860</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_cee7f37cd2bf51787444819273e8f63c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_68e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence and papers</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1861-1931 and undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_f124211becbd05f84ca31fe6e5269dd8" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_lci" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence and papers</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_d89b2118f8b525dab86553db1568bfea" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_es3" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Rutherfoord: Legal notebook</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1814</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_6c2c830c2bddf06add71e49bd4a6681c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">S:3486</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4be1ea4dd29e918856072cbaaa495eec">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Study notes taken by John C. Rutherfoord on Blackstone.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref41_qz6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Rutherfoord: Legal notes, etc.</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1895-1916</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_09d572e592a8cb8304f468d44d7d6efa" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:3487</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref42_jad" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Rutherfoord: Notebook on family history</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_09f247b814386b56c57a6c3923a00e6c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:3488</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_rs6" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Coles Rutherfoord: Personal account book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1840-1841</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_a743200445389b410a41684d44caea45" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:3489</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_16n" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Coles Rutherfoord: Collection of autographs and
                     clippings</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1836-1850</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_9c0d7e9caf85cdaff343ea5b58ae3325" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">L:3490</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_acaae4606e1bd4e2c603869c16204253">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Autographs, letters introducing Sidney Mason in Europe, and news clippings.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_5nq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Coles Rutherfoord: Case book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1844-1850</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_0f774106d78c4ddcb0bbb3816e94b0f0" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:3491</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_o7a" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Coles Rutherfoord: Case books</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1844-1852</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_f0c66e0880fdcff5d0efa33ba8a4d1c4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:3492</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref45_gbe" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Coles Rutherfoord: Commonplace book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1839-1842</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_663416cce390d746d699914121bc20d1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">L:3493</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_tq2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Coles Rutherfoord: Index of letters received</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1856-1865</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_84604455791f3b6f189c07a809767331" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:3494</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref46_y9y" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Coles Rutherfoord: Index Rerum</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1842</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_c2637e128f4f039109e64e6b5b666a99" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:3495</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_jbh" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Coles Rutherfoord: Letterpress copybook</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1856-1866</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_0ee4989c15b0d7ca76682de8c7714fe1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">L:3499</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_9n5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Coles Rutherfoord: Memorandum book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1846-1864</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_a5e59389bd3bc9dfd6346c4589819663" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:3501</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_03451b353ec1fb5c4df3835fdcb7ef3c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes notes on farming operations.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_9c7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Coles Rutherfoord: Notebook</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1842-1843</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_c48171d96b28b61573aa4ed80fd0bad4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:3506</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_cpx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Coles Rutherfoord: Notebook on Greek History</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1841</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_c48704a050de08a72e46a4a2a43ef78d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:3510</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_6o1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Coles Rutherfoord: Notebook</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1930</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_984189ea2e1624dce196bfbdff47966f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:3513</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_j8s" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Coles Rutherfoord: Scrapbook</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1843-1856</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_5ff6aca7753778b718acaed15d269c83" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">M:3514</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
