<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/scottaccountbooks/"
         >scottaccountbooks</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the E.D. Scott Account Books, 1847-1868 <num>RL.01154</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Library Staff; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Meghan Lyon</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">001018412</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 09:12:46
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>E.D. Scott Account Books</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Scott, E.D.</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01154</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.6 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1847/1868" type="inclusive">1847-1868</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_2becf8f400d3bf98da65b80c5285f1cd">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_995696521da0fd5996310047b4d8c26c">Merchant and wholesaler. Originally
            from Philadelphia, Pa. Two account books, one containing an inventory of merchandise
            Scott sold at wholesale prices in Washington, D.C. to Union Army sutlers in 1863 as well
            as a separate index. It lists the sutlers and sometimes the regiments to whom he sold
            supplies. The other account book, chiefly 1866-1868, details the sales and the stock on
            hand in the dry goods store Scott operated in Minneapolis, Minn.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_4bc6054582b363b35238c86125f34ccb">
            <extent>2 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_250010a1809b77fb0e205587bd77460e">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_0863ac268a583653fb62bf953d47e7bf">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_c57e7c92cf37afc8686248db4bd97f01">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_5bb8eb9fedbe6dade64848d4cf82a7b8">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], E.D. Scott Account Books, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_600506e605f2a445bbfe959bcefb5071">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The E.D. Scott Account Books were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1985 and 1986.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_7197f6551115c60c9f424063dfe7c518">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library Staff, 1991</p>
         <p>Encoded by Meghan Lyon, May 2011</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_d51fd34f45f474927c36021259d1e346">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Ebenezer Daniel Scott was born about 1825-1827 in Bristol, Gloucestershire, England to
            Benjamin Scott (baptised March 29, 1786 in Ditcheat, Somersetshire, England; died 1873
            in Camden, New Jersey) and Eliza Owen De Boudry (born about 1785 in Bristol,
            Gloucestershire, England; died 1858 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania). E.D. Scott arrived
            in New York on September 6, 1831 with his mother and siblings from England. He became a
            merchant and wholesaler to Civil War sutlers in Washington, D.C., in 1863. Following the
            Civil War, he appears to have operated a clothing and notion store in Minneapolis,
            Minnesota, from 1866 to 1868, and was prominently associated with St. Anthony's Church
            in that city.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_7541a48b274d6816bb3ee3737eed5f28">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Two account books, one containing an inventory of merchandise Scott sold at wholesale
            prices in Washington, D.C. to Union Army sutlers in 1863 as well as a separate index. It
            lists the sutlers and sometimes the regiments to whom he sold supplies. The other
            account book, chiefly 1866-1868, details the sales and the stock on hand in the dry
            goods store Scott operated in Minneapolis, Minn.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Dry-goods -- Minnesota -- Minneapolis</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Equipment and
            supplies</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Washington (D.C.) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
         <genreform source="aat">Account books</genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">Sutlers -- Civil War, 1861-1865</subject>
         <persname source="ingest">Scott, E.D.</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Scott, E.D.</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">United States. Army--History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_3jx" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Account books, 1847-1868</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_1e3ab2eb4f75bf3e3f30c38be4b9ae8a">
                  <extent>2 volumes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_wf6" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Sale and account book, 1862-1863</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_adbb4fce1b06973d85b0f7ff02ab6fb2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e0b1c844045212d20a654d866196724f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Sale and account book of E.D. Scott for goods sold to various sutlers of the
                     Union Army in Washington, D.C., during 1863. One volume (31x19cm), in limp and
                     worn marble boards and party damaged backstrip.</p>
                  <p>This volume contains 110 pages of text in ink and pencil which list the very
                     extensive inventory of merchandise sold at wholesale in Washington, D.C., by
                     Scott between January and September 1863. The accounts commence on January 5,
                     1863, with a "Bill of Goods Consigned to Wm. H. Ward (of 534 7th St.) by E.D.
                     Scott," almost five hundred dollars worth of items. Sales were much more common
                     than consignments, however, and included a terrific variety of goods needed by
                     soldiers in the field - suspenders, razors, soap, "3 Gross pens," pocketbooks,
                     envelopes, scissors, socks, "4 doz. filled ink stands," currency holders,
                     briarwood pipes, and "2 doz. diaries," among other things.</p>
                  <p>One of the valuable features of Scott's record book is the comprehensive list
                     of goods he furnished for resale to army units, together with the quantity of
                     goods moved, prices charged, and methods of payment or credit extended. No less
                     interesting are the sutlers identified by name as Scott customers. Twenty-one
                     individual sutlers are so named, and the regiments to which they sold goods are
                     specifically identified. Another nine sutlers may be identified in the accounts
                     by reference to Francis A. Lord's <title type="simple" render="italic">Civil
                        War Sutlers and Their Wares</title> (New York: Thomas Yoseloff, 1969).
                     Together, these thirty sutlers served twelve regiments from Philadelphia, six
                     each from Massachusetts and New York, and one each from Ohio, Maryland, Maine,
                     and Vermont, plus one U.S. Colored Troop regiment and two unidentified federal
                     regiments - in all, a wide variety of infantry, cavalry, and artillery units. A
                     highly useful six-page index of both sets of sutlers and their regiments,
                     checked against the Lord entries and with reference to the dates of their
                     accounts with Scott, accompanies the volume.</p>
                  <p>Additional references are made in the volume to incidental expenses, like a few
                     "cash sales" in Washington or Georgetown and notes on express charges (for
                     shipment of goods from Philadelphia). There are also 29 pages of entries in
                     late 1862 for sales of dry goods and fabrics, perhaps in Philadelphia. These do
                     not appear directly related to the 1863 sales to sutlers.</p>
                  <p>In summary, this is an unusual business record from the nation's capital during
                     the Civil War, documenting the activities of one enterprising businessman from
                     elsewhere who appears to have found abundant opportunities to make money in
                     war-time Washington.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_xum" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Account book, 1847-1868</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3b88b96d15ed19d2013a475577c5eec3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b7001b315bd50f95d79799fd048ee50e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Account book of E.D. Scott, kept in Minneapolis, Minnesota, between 1866 and
                     1868 (with some accounts from 1847). This early record (kept within the first
                     decade of Minnesota statehood) gives his "Stock on Hand" as of November 13,
                     1866, and details sales of dry goods with some earlier records of a B. Scott
                     Senr. &amp; Co."</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
