<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/scovillbeecher/"
         >scovillbeecher</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Scovill-Beecher Letters, 1816-1864 <num>RL.01159</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Danielle Moore; machine-readable finding aid created by: Danielle
               Moore</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">004330653</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 09:13:48
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Scovill-Beecher Letters</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Scovill, William H.</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01159</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.2 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1816/1864" type="inclusive">1816-1864 bulk 1817-1820</unitdate>
         <unitdate normal="1817/1820" type="bulk">bulk</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_4f1861cd1dd019450395eb9df76d8e09">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_7b2d383f03e09214730e800a710fecaf">William H. Scovill (1796-1854) of
            Waterbury, Connecticut, businessman and founder of the Scovill Manufacturing Company;
            and Rebecca Beecher (1800-1876), of Kent, Connecticut. The collection includes
            twenty-nine letters, chiefly the courting letters of William H. Scovill and Rebecca
            Beecher during a long period of geographic separation and secret engagement from 1817 to
            1820. Materials in the collection range in date from 1816 to 1864.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_00ae9d53ee94ca1a367d084523aa3e07">
            <extent>29 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_3e2a6ff08adc0d4cdb7624504329432f">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_8c5560ef646fd6f7cdfd180df355e2ad">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_3768d36e8ed69d233d81536526da2f64">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_a2ccccb7e39565d089f02e8e661416a7">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Scovill-Beecher Letters, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_865b3d7edddd2430f1b6d0becbe166e4">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Scovill-Beecher Letters were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2003.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_9f6d01c7076ec181ae6cad6246975b5e">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Danielle Moore, June 2010</p>
         <p>Encoded by Danielle Moore, June 2010</p>
         <p>Accession 2003-0235 is described in this finding aid.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_32dfcc552ce594d11cdfbfa44d74cc52">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>William H. Scovill (1796-1854) was born in Waterbury, Connecticut. At seventeen he began
            working as a clerk, first in New Haven, then in Waterbury. In 1817, he relocated to
            Berwick, Pennsylvania, in an attempt to gain some measure of financial success, but
            abandoned this venture in 1819 to travel to Saint John, New Brunswick, Canada, where he
            hoped to enter into business with his uncle. In 1820, disappointing news about the
            business resulted in his return to Waterbury for a short time before establishing a
            successful business in Turner's Crossroads, Halifax County, North Carolina. Scovill
            returned to Waterbury in 1827 and bought a half interest in the firm of Leavenworth,
            Hayden and Scovill. Together with his older brother, James Mitchell Lamson Scovill, he
            established the firm of J.M.L. and W.H. Scovill which consolidated with other branches
            of the company in 1850 to become the Scovill Manufacturing Company, a leading supplier
            of fasteners.</p>
         <p>Scovill married twice, in 1827 to Eunice Ruth Davies (d. 1839) and in 1841 to Rebecca
            Smith. He had two surviving daughters with his first wife and one surviving son with his
            second wife.</p>
         <p>Source consulted: Anderson, Joseph, and Anna L. Ward, eds., <title type="simple"
               render="italic">The Town and City of Waterbury, Connecticut, from the Aboriginal
               Period to the Year Eighteen Hundred and Ninety-Five, Volume II</title> (New Haven:
            The Price &amp; Lee Company, 1896), 278-82.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <bioghist id="aspace_c5ba3f381a2e16cc54e58964f529ad26">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Rebecca Beecher (1800-1876) resided in Kent, Connecticut, until 1817 when she relocated
            to New Haven to board with Mr. and Mrs. David Hoadley. In 1820, she married Jared Foote
            (1800-1873). They settled in North Haven, had six children, and later moved to a farm in
            Hamden, Connecticut, where they remained until their deaths.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_ac8bd56afd57b0a0d5518e9cb4a872e3">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The collection includes twenty-nine letters, chiefly the courting letters of William H.
            Scovill and Rebecca Beecher during a long period of geographic separation and secret
            engagement from 1817 to 1820. Also included are four letters to Rebecca from
            acquaintances including William's sisters, Caroline and Sarah; one letter from William
            to his brother, James; and one unrelated letter written in 1864? to a Miss Fannie R.
            Sissons. The letters between William and Rebecca are roughly balanced in number, at
            first alternating between the two until March of 1818. Thereafter, only Rebecca's
            letters to William are included in the collection until June of 1819, and only William's
            letters to Rebecca are included from August, 1819, until August, 1820, although it is
            clear they each continued to receive replies from the other.</p>
         <p>William and Rebecca wrote to each other about their letter writing; their own social
            life, activities, and plans; and the activities and temperament of mutual acquaintances.
            Whereas William writes openly of his love for Rebecca and his hope of becoming worthy to
            be her public suitor, Rebecca's letters are more circumspect, although encouraging in
            her professed pleasure at receiving his letters and concern for his well-being as he
            deals with homesickness and loneliness. In November of 1818, Rebecca writes of reports
            she received concerning William's behavior in Pennsylvania. She claims not to believe
            the rumors, but cautions him that it is important to associate with reputable people.
            Although in August of 1820, William is still clearly hopeful in his letter and addresses
            her as "My Dear Rebecca," the next and last related letter in the collection is from
            Sarah and Caroline Scovill to Rebecca, congratulating her profusely on her marriage to
            Mr. Foote.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <arrangement id="aspace_827350e6a302d40cd42702a37a301061">
         <head>Collection Arrangement</head>
         <p>Materials are arranged chronologically.</p>
      </arrangement>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Love-letters</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Courtship -- United States -- History -- 19th century</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Saint John (N.B.) -- Social life and customs -- 19th
            century</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">New Haven (Conn.) -- Social life and customs -- 19th
            century</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Kent (Conn.) -- Social life and customs -- 19th century</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Berwick (Pa.) -- Social life and customs -- 19th century</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Waterbury (Conn.) -- Social life and customs -- 19th
            century</geogname>
         <persname source="ingest">Scovill, Caroline</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Beecher, Rebecca</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Scovill, William H.</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Scovill, William H.</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref14_wwo" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Scovill-Beecher Letters, 1816-1864</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_ef44872c8db6ff10dbe7cb6e8027d32b">
                  <extent>1 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_xw4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1816-1817</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_7e4db1fc6380efd553e5083f7cdc9acc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_itb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1818</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_632b9fd7ccb59a989c03ed566f012fe7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_pji" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1819</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5bdb6f8a544b039083a9e4cded9ae6f1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_0m0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters, 1820, 1864</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b4e1c4576fb723583a90438f05ab9e1a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
