<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
         url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/simpsonjohnarctic/"
         >simpsonjohnarctic</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the John Simpson Papers, 1825-1875 and undated <num>RL.01195</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: L. Colby Bogie; machine-readable finding aid created by: L. Colby
               Bogie</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2010</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">001105583</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-11-01 16:18:30
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>John Simpson papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Simpson, John, 1819-1859</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01195</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5.1 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1825/1875" type="inclusive">1825-1875 and undated</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_c75e5fa2f6bcb1c81723b4189e512f0b">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_b17f17e09953ba1454f378e9151fda69">Irish-born surgeon in the British
            Navy who participated in several Arctic voyages. The papers of John Simpson date from
            1825 to 1875 and span his entire career as a naval surgeon aboard the English vessels
            Blonde, Plover and Superior. The collection is arranged into the following series:
            Accounts of Voyages, Correspondence, Legal Papers, Medical Files, Native Cultures,
            Meterology Files, Additional Papers, Other Printed Material, and Poetry, Plays, and
            Amusements. Simpson's journals from the Arctic voyages on the HMS Plover and Superior on
            which he served as surgeon or assistant surgeon provide detailed accounts of the
            voyages, including life on board and the medical problems afflicting the crew and
            passengers. The collection includes detailed meteorological observations aboard the
            Plover. There are also unique and valuable materials on native cultures in present-day
            Alaska, Canada, and the Arctic which include extensive Simpson's notes on the local
            languages, a number of sketches of Inuit people and culture, hand-drawn maps, and
            drawings of geographical features. Also included in the collection are a variety of
            legal papers; correspondence; papers and items related to poetry, plays, and amusements
            aboard the Plover; and miscellaneous other papers and printed materials. A number of the
            volumes, flyers, and broadsides were printed on board ship. There are additional
            materials that briefly describe voyages to Guyana, and documents relating to Simpson's
            service aboard other ships.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_15e042a145ec7c1c78afc490b157010d">
            <extent>Approximately 1000 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_01c042f31dd3a7c624740e0f2ffc08d1">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_2030cac8097b312909e0a8b27e23b188">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_f95853ef62c375376f476f6e0f165c02">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_71f18559c05e8674515b6b07fed8813c">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], John Simpson Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_d6a527c975d02280a11b16d6b2c6e685">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The John Simpson Papers were purchased by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a part of the Dalton Collection. They were purchased from Emerald
            Isle Books in 1982.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_25fc3864b88e74dc3cff1dfdaa8c9cba">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by L. Colby Bogie, July 2010</p>
         <p>Encoded by L. Colby Bogie and Paula Jeannet, July 2010</p>
         <p>Accession is described in this finding aid. </p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_a6f7ec085e0fca9369a8197665278959">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>John Simpson (1819-1859) was born in Larne, in county Antrim, Ireland, on December 1st,
            1819. He began his medical training at the University of Glasgow in 1835, and then
            completed it over the next four years primarily at the universities of Edinburgh and
            Dublin, the Richmond Hospital School in Dublin (by 1850 known as the Carmichael School),
            and the Edinburgh School. At the 1841 census he was an Assistant Surgeon at the Royal
            Haslar Hospital, Hampshire. Simpson entered the naval service as a surgeon. From his own
            account (a letter dated 1844), he served first on the HMS Queen (Mar. 23-June 18, 1841);
            the HMS Cornwallis (June 19, 1841-Jan. 20, 1842); then as an assistant surgeon on
            voyages with the HMS Blonde (Jan. 21, 1842-Mar. 23, 1843), during which he "landed at
            the capture of Chapoo and Woosung"; the emigration ship Superior (May 30-Dec. 21, 1843),
            which transported "liberated" Africans to colonies such as Guyana; the HM cutter
            Seaflower (1845); and the HM surveying vessel Bonetta (1845-1847). During 1844 he served
            at the Naval Hospital in Plymouth. Simpson was later an officer on the "discovery ship"
            HMS Plover, initiating his service sometime around 1847, while the Plover participated
            in the search for Sir John Franklin (1847-1855). During that time the Plover spent
            several years stationed in the Behring Strait as a supply vessel, including a three-year
            stint from 1852-1855. Simpson's studies of Inuit society and command of Inuit languages
            made him an important liaison between the English and the local populations. While
            stationed in the Artic, Simpson conducted anthropological studies of Inuit culture,
            recorded detailed meteorological observations of the Arctic climate, and printed
            playbills and newsletters on a shipboard printing press. After his journeys Simpson
            served on the receiving ship Ceylon at Malta (1855). Simpson died on August 29, 1859
            while serving at Haslar Hospital in Southampton, England. [Sources include the <title
               type="simple" render="italic">New Navy List</title>, 1855.]</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_38ab25012c2ba7f96edf9b5dd1497015">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The papers of John Simpson date from 1825 to 1875 and span his entire career as a naval
            surgeon aboard the English vessels Blonde, Plover and Superior. The collection is
            arranged into the following series: <emph render="bold">Accounts of Voyages,
               Correspondence, Legal Papers, Medical Files, Native Cultures, Meterology Files,
               Additional Papers, Other Printed Material</emph>, and <emph render="bold">Poetry,
               Plays, and Amusements</emph>. Simpson's journals from the Arctic voyages on the HMS
            Plover and off the coast of West Africa on the Superior provide detailed, vivid accounts
            of the voyages, including life on board and the medical problems afflicting the crew and
            passengers, including scurvy, fevers, gonorrhea, and depression. Journals from the HMS
            Plover also chronicle the provisions that were stockpiled on board and the daily rations
            provided to the officers and crew. The collection includes detailed meteorological
            observations aboard the Plover such as temperature and barometrical readings and
            descriptions of wind and weather conditions.</p>
         <p>Simpson was also a keen observer of native cultures in present-day Alaska, Canada, and
            the Arctic; his unique and valuable materials on Inuit lands and society include
            extensive notes on the local languages, a number of sketches of Inuit people and
            culture, hand-drawn maps, and drawings of geographical features.</p>
         <p>He also described in detail his experiences off the coast of West Africa, where he
            served as surgeon on board the Superior, one of the many British Royal Navy ships that
            transported African "emigrants," often freed from illegal slave ships, to British
            colonies; during Simpson's service the Superior operated between Sierra Leone and
            Guyana. There are briefer references in correspondence and possibly in his journals to
            stays in Malta, Panama, and other locales such as San Francisco (1842).</p>
         <p>Also included in the collection are a variety of legal papers; correspondence; papers
            and items related to poetry, plays, and amusements aboard the Plover; and miscellaneous
            other papers and printed materials, some of which relate to Simpson's education and
            career. A number of the volumes, flyers, and broadsides were hand-printed on board ship.
            There may be references in the papers to Simpson's service on the Blonde, which traveled
            to the coast of China in 1842, but the journals seem to start with his service on the
            emigration ship Superior, following the Blonde.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_75387a2fbeb8f4702d79b01b26cf4174">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>
            <bibref>
               <persname>Stam, David H.</persname>. <title type="simple" render="italic">Books on
                  Ice: British and American Literature of Polar Exploration</title>. <imprint>New
                  York: Grolier Club, 2005</imprint>. </bibref>
         </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Arctic regions -- Climate -- Observations</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Alaska -- Discovery and exploration -- British</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Arctic medicine -- History -- 19th century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Eskimo languages -- Glossaries, vocabularies, etc. --
            Polyglot</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Eskimos -- Arctic regions -- Social life and customs</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Indians of North America -- Arctic regions</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Inuit -- Social life and customs</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Inuit language -- Glossaries, vocabularies, etc.</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Medicine, Naval -- Great Britain -- History -- 19th
            century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Meteorology -- Arctic regions -- Observations -- 19th
            century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Naval hygiene -- 19th century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Ship presses -- 19th century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Ship physicians -- Personal narratives</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Surgery, Naval -- 19th century</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Manuscript maps</genreform>
         <genreform source="aat">Playbills</genreform>
         <genreform source="aat">Broadsides (notices)</genreform>
         <genreform source="aat">Handbills</genreform>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Sierra Leone -- Emigration and immigration</geogname>
         <genreform source="aat">Diaries</genreform>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Canada -- Discovery and exploration -- British</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Guyana -- Emigration and immigration</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Arctic regions -- History, Naval -- 19th century</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Barrow, Point (Alaska) -- Discovery and exploration --
            British</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Arctic regions -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <genreform source="aat">Ships' logs</genreform>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Arctic regions -- Discovery and exploration -- British</geogname>
         <genreform source="aat">Sketches</genreform>
         <corpname source="ingest">Blonde (Ship)</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Great Britain. Royal Navy -- Medical care</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Franklin, John, Sir, 1786-1847</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Great Britain. Royal Navy -- Surgeons</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Great Britain. Royal Navy -- Sea life</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Plover (Ship)</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Superior (Ship)</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref13_cmc" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Accounts of Voyages Series, 1842-1854 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_da2e8edd882f900c5571ed9001787e1e">
                  <extent>1 volume and 7 folders</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_ade0d69b0afb39330950d8c5349f754a">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Detailed accounts of naval surgeon John Simpson's voyages (the one exception being
                  Simpson's copy of Sir John Richardson's <title type="simple" render="italic"
                     >Arctic Searching Expedition</title>). Formats include small bound manuscript
                  journals, volumes with inserted sketches and other manuscript items, folios, and
                  manuscript proofs. Simpson's experiences on the HMS Plover and the emigration
                  transport Superior are given particularly detailed treatments. Arranged in
                  chronological order.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_9nt" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="doublequote">HMS Blonde and HMS Plover</title> (volume and
                     inserts), 1841 Jan.-1842</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_d79e234815efce7d28e84f7c945a035e">
                     <extent>10 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_58fbd71735be9635b10608070133f34b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8b0423b2d4d34e7f236559e85b4b4fcd">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Includes Simpson's highly detailed journal, plus additional journal entries,
                     notes, charts, and sketches originally laid in between blank pages, describing
                     his experiences on the HMS Blonde, which saw action in the Anglo-Chinese War
                     during 1841-1842. Contains many references to other ships, to battles, and
                     weather, and comments on his travels from England to his destination, including
                     descriptions of a stay in Capetown. The journal then turns to his first service
                     aboard the HMS Plover, undated, and contains similarly detailed entries on the
                     voyage, which appears to be his first service on the Plover (circa 1848). The
                     papers also include one sheet that refers to issues faced by the emigration
                     transport Superior, which at that time operated off the West Coast of Africa,
                     transporting Africans freed from illegal slave ships and other individuals from
                     Sierra Leone to colonies such as Guyana. The Superior was one of many ships who
                     performed this work during the period following the abolishment of the slave
                     trade in the 1830s.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_f4u" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="doublequote">Emigration Transport Superior,</title> 1843 June
                     10-1843 Dec. 21 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_2ec5ca9da318a64fb23d56a04b96fcb0">13 items</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_665bb633478cf9654f42b6e0e39380fc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_324e8f965839b19f98a16c6e75bb8a0e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Includes manuscript correspondence relating to John Simpson's service aboard
                     the emigration transport Superior and a paperbound printed volume, <title
                        type="simple" render="italic">Papers Relative to Emigration from the West
                        Coast of Africa to the West Indies</title>, 1843. Many of the letters and
                     papers address the transactions and logistical problems in picking up Africans
                     from Sierra Leone (men, women, and many boys) and transporting them to estates
                     in Guyana as indentured labor. He also comments on his surroundings when he is
                     on land.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_p0z" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="doublequote">The Voyage of the PLOVER,</title>
                     1847-1849</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1ba4e45506c312a2e192a4f6f363745e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4c92129f7216e0831502ba0344179d49">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Contains a loosely-bound portfolio. Includes thermometer readings, sketches of
                     Inuit villages and geographical features, hand-drawn maps, and a narrative
                     account of the Plover's early arctic voyages.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_q1u" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="doublequote">Flight of the PLOVER,</title> 1848</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c133ce19b0e3d92ef8fa9693012ef33f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_92c0cdd94452e9fdc58ea080f78790a6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>A loosely-bound folio containing the handwritten proofs of <title type="simple"
                        render="doublequote">The Flight of the Plover or North Pole
                        Charivari,</title> the newsletter that Simpson printed while aboard the
                     Plover.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_oie" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Accounts of Voyages, 1849 Sept. 8-1854 Mar. 1 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_f9011c34acba20b7419ca7394bd0f1a2">
                     <extent>19 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_ced5986fcbf22c4e6b6e09434031cb4e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2e179fa87dbdc6f3d5423555db03b600">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Notes from Simpson's travels on the HMS Plover in arctic regions.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_57b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Accounts of Voyages, 1849-1854</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_ca31b81f088480932f0aea66f4013f09">
                     <extent>3 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_22af402bdbae0974ad9499fde78e2f5f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_446fad79a4fe763c15dd9e1c3ca19606">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Contains three volumes of Simpson's journals and notes. One volume contains
                     extensive notes on Inuit language; another is entitled <title type="simple"
                        render="doublequote">Journal of Journeys, 1849.</title> The third volume is
                     very small (4" x 2.75") and its back cover is labeled "Plover"; it contains
                     journal entries, language notes, and calculations.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_ad4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">Arctic Searching Expedition: A Journal of a Boat-Voyage
                        through Rupert's Land: Volume II</title> by Sir John Richardson,
                     1851</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0cf1c9f7a9119cc68aae82c99918e9e2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_47fe7a1ba1ab2bcb721338a865cb3fea">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Bound, published volume.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref33_bbh" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Accounts of Voyages, 1851-1854</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_680bfab5528df67f7202cb0c3d8169d5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_881b44c2d744031f296d8b022214bb06">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Oversize portfolio of loosely-bound pages containing John Simpson's journals of
                     his voyages on the HMS Plover. Inserts include handbills printed while at Point
                     Barrow, and pasted inside the portfolio cover, a newspaper clipping on the
                     continuing search for Sir John Franklin's party.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref36_pz2" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence Series, 1840 Dec. 31-1859 May 30 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_c76333656153865801e2c8b50ae40714">
                  <extent>1 folder</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_4864f058f087e9ad2b40a952e0ac47d1">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Much of the correspondence consists of letters, memos, and naval orders sent to
                  Simpson, but there are letters written by him to family members such as his
                  sister, and to other individuals. Letters written by him while aboard the Plover
                  in August 1852 describe his experiences and surroundings; one discusses the
                  growing town of San Francisco. A letter from a Mr. Beechey, who served on the
                  Plover with Simpson and on other Navy ships, discusses fossils at length. In one
                  draft letter written in 1844, Simpson outlines the naval positions he has held to
                  date, and asks for a raise in wages. A late letter written in summer 1855 while he
                  served in the hospital at Malta describes his experience there. Arranged in date
                  order. An additional folder of correspondence can be found in the Medical Files
                  Series.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref38_w9q" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1840 Dec. 31-1859 May 30 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_00431cdc65adff8b578526e157714595">
                     <extent>35 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_b8de4c729529024d5eac17b75f7ade49" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref41_zah" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Legal Papers Series, 1841-1859 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_4d2d88929200d6a74608917e4629b926">
                  <extent>4 folders</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_dec63c3251d59b2ffaf7d8a6a241df5b">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Legal documents principally related to Simpson's naval appointments, but also
                  includes his will (1852) which is attached to documents produced after his death
                  in 1859. Arranged in date order, with oversize documents appearing at the end of
                  the series.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_k62" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Naval appointments and orders, 1841 Mar. 23-1844 Feb. 7</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_872426f9b00232b338aeeca7d8f0c031">
                     <extent>12 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_f8e7c6e3e782812b069ebe48ff46e864" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5bed376846403ec41bf25cdc37956b9b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Orders and appointments issued to Simpson, including his appointment to the HMS
                     Blonde and orders concerning his service on the emigration transport
                     Superior.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref46_2c5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Naval appointments and orders, 1845 Mar. 5-1858 Apr. 1 and
                     undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_77ec4a2009f08679152676ec883a7cbc">
                     <extent>18 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_801b7c071fcd7e42dddc5609ac355143" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b69268b31cbf0c512dec33db236e842e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Orders and appointments issued to Simpson, including his appointments to the HM
                     Cutter Seaflower, the HMS Bonetta, and the HMS Plover; an order appointing
                     Simpson to serve in the Malta Hospital (dated 1855); and a letter notifying
                     Simpson of his promotion to the rank of Surgeon.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref49_tys" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Legal papers, 1856 Sept. 20-1859 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_05a444d7f4cf654df724aa8728a31538">
                     <extent>2 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_b27bf4d9c05e895e08c566ee55a76c79" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6d311261a81180a4a8f16eab05e869f1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Document (1856) in Italian ordering Simpson to testify at a trial in the court
                     of Malta against a "Giuseppe Meli[s?], and a last will and testament of an
                     unknown individual (illegible), written on a small piece of paper dated May 18,
                     no year. The individual appears to be a naval officer.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref52_az0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Simpson's will, 1852 Jan. 19</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3b92f090c611bae1dc833a5a43b7f1ae" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-folder">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_20bbaa5c9b44ef19c30c32e5b7b55e16">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Affixed to a document from Her Majesty's Court of Probate (1859 Sep. 23) that
                     records the date and location of Simpson's death (1859 Aug. 29 at Haslar
                     Hospital in the county of Southampton). The document states that Simpson's
                     effects were disbursed to his sister Ellen Simpson, spinster.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref55_fg6" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Medical Files Series, 1826-1859 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_9603d0af481f0f278a4c805faafbe640">
                  <extent>5 volumes and 10 folders</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_66bd1b1d50ca7575710f85f8907c4a2e">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Contains Simpson's medical papers, including correspondence, Simpson's academic
                  transcript, surgeon's journals and assistant surgeon's journals from several of
                  his voyages, and manuscripts of four medical treatises by Simpson.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref57_rg1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Medical correspondence, 1842 Mar. 24-1858 Mar. 22</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_7519db96a0e15677dd09fce593a7eb58">
                     <extent>7 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_8261b54c75e0c5dfa5d777e137cbe1c7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c629fbcc97a7e1399cd11accb6b303c6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Several letters from Simpson's medical career, including correspondence
                     relating to Simpson's medical examinations, his pay, and reimbursement of
                     expenses. Also includes a transcript listing Simpson's coursework and training,
                     with dates and institutions (dated 1858).</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref60_mrc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed material, 1834 Apr. 15-1858 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1a6707e557543c1f8e5c144f0f239565" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e9495686b4a0041acab605bbe510bed2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Includes a printed copy of Simpson's treatise, "On the Causes of the Spiral
                     Direction of the Umbilical Vessels, and the Convolutions of the Cord in the
                     Human Foetus;" an 1857 report on the Naval Medical Supplemental Fund; and a
                     number of blank forms and certificates, among various other printed matter. (11
                     items)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref62_1pw" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed material, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2aba2937d0ddedaf7cfc817798e7ddcd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6b461e985db14b4389366540eb165b96">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Contains a blank surgeon's log.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref64_mfc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Regulations of the Royal College of Surgeons (London), 1826 Sept.
                     1</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ac75c1532295f0e1078da2a6bd7c10a1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c52c5fbda801640276673bc7da6130bd">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Printed copy of the college's regulations.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref66_vbq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reports, memoranda, notes, etc. (volumes), 1837-1855</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c57adcaa3d46baa7fda2e9f0156dd8bc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_28a1d49c4995bfc6d5df2b6cd41924af">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Folder houses Simpson's "Rough Journal for 1851" and two small notebooks of
                     Simpson's medical notes; five small volumes were removed from this folder and
                     placed in boxes 7 and 8 for improved housing. (3 items)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref68_jza" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reports, memoranda, notes, etc., 1850 Apr. 10-1859 Mar. 18 and
                     undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6292bbd1bd003cfd9950ad6b9a33eb19" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a4d3d7c1bc8319b2494667b489dc7e51">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Contains materials from Simpson's voyages on the Plover, including notes on the
                     ailments suffered by the crew members and inventories of the ship's medical
                     supplies. (28 items)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref70_c3d" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Writings by Simpson, 1859 July</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_91e224692da9ec71f1541d197c435c00" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d203effa9ec876cc3fe818bfea609412">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>A handwritten, paperbound copy (much of its binding missing) of a treatise by
                     Simpson, "On the Causes of the Spiral Direction of the Umbilical Vessels, and
                     the Convolutions of the Cord in the Human Foetus."</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref72_8b1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Writings by Simpson, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_38179ea8350d2ab4091992b151f17652" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6ce7997e98519659e6c74d77704a1dbc">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>A series of handwritten sheets containing a treatise by Simpson, "On Scurvy."
                     The treatise is undated, but it references Simpson's experiences aboard the HMS
                     Plover and thus it must have been written some time after that voyage ended in
                     1855.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref74_hi0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Oversize printed material, 1824-1857 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_97676747ab582a017a2f74f5fe0d47b1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a326bcf2b3dcb00734647d088802f340">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Contents include a published volume entitled <title type="simple"
                        render="italic">System of Anatomical Plates with Descriptive Letterpress
                        (Part VI).</title> (5 items)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref76_wmr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reports, memoranda, and notes, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_564a44552a8ca8040e64b91e263ffdd0" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_70b04f367fb87aa67f1b7aed9ab6a8ac">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Oversize--contains a blank chart for recording human dimensions (1 item)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref78_p37" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Surgeon's journal for the HMS Plover (1 of 2), 1852 July 1-1854 July
                     31</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_eec7398f14683399891676ecbd22bd30" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b8ea6e8edf80650e8be02b62f11b078f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Contains a list of the officers and crew of the HMS Plover; a sick list for the
                     voyage (recording the names of the men whom Simpson treated on the voyage,
                     listing the date they fell ill; the nature of their complaint; and the number
                     of days they remained incapacitated; and a journal recording details of the
                     ship's provisions, the sailors' diet, and the treatments that Simpson
                     administered to each of his patients.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref80_221" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Surgeon's journal for the HMS Plover (2 of 2), 1854 Aug. 1-1855 Mar.
                     26</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_aee684e40d172a55d56f5e02540adce7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_71f9584398b2d9bc80a44086794928a8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>A continuation of Simpson's journal from the Plover, with an updated list of
                     the vessel's officers and crew, a continuation of the sick list, and further
                     journal entries.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref82_8xx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Assistant Surgeon's journal for the HMS Blonde, the emigration
                     transport Superior, the cutter Seaflower, and the HM surveying vessel Bonetta,
                     1841 Dec. 11-1845 Dec. 21</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_75297aae57976e00cf90fb0f623dac6a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_aca5f7dea5d5a2f26c66588c6b89f9b3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Sick lists from four voyages on which Simpson served as an assistant surgeon.
                     The sick list for the Bonetta is incomplete: Simpson seems to have started the
                     list in this volume only to subsequently transfer the first few entries and
                     continue the list in a different volume.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref84_icb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters of commendation and recommendation, 1842 Mar. 24-1844 Nov.
                     29</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fec4e75be08e24b5b2e14f5ca266c16d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c1fc4cb66db921a390c19baee9173cb6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>A volume containing three handwritten letters praising Simpson's service and
                     recommending him for future posts. The first letter, signed by R.H. Brown,
                     surgeon for the HMS Blonde, praises Simpson's work as an assistant surgeon on
                     that vessel. The second letter, signed by T. Bourchire, attests that Simpson
                     landed with an expeditionary force and served admirably during a battle. The
                     third letter, signed by J. Walcott, a secretary in the Colonial Land and
                     Emigration Office, states that Simpson discharged his duties satisfactorily
                     while serving aboard the emigration transport Superior.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref86_cn5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="doublequote">On the Varieties of the Form of the Pelvis,</title>
                     undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8261a1b46772aca9e69d6b4b6cdf6d70" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e0a0d1b4723a7cd2257734afd32b5a65">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Volume containing a handwritten treatise by Simpson.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref88_swz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Sick list for HM Surveying Vessel Bonetta and HMS Plover, 1845 Dec.
                     11-1851 Dec. 13</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2a1f574b2e0969c59824cc284f1af09b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4633855cc70b31740d0e8333ba318369">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Small, paperbound volume containing sick lists for the Bonetta and for
                     Simpson's first voyage on the Plover (commencing 1848 Jan. 1).</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref91_zzf" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Native Cultures Series, 1843-1854 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_40b6d5017d11ea17b1f02a13c9cb83d7">
                  <extent>6 folders</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_61303028a909bb933bef25af11b5fec3">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Simpson's notes and writings on Inuit language and culture, including drawings,
                  maps, and a published copy of Simpson's <title type="simple" render="italic"
                     >Observations on the Western Eskimo</title>. Other observations on native Inuit
                  culture, as well as maps and drawings, are found in his accounts of voyages.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref93_dtj" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Drawings and maps, 1843-1853 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_efccb03197db9cbeea3a516db19d37f1">
                     <extent>15 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_795967d713f3e5e411b36535369710b1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_68f9726990382167e09bf8fe7136f08b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Contains hand-drawn maps of the Alaskan coastline and sketches of Inuit
                     individuals, native dress, and tattooing.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref96_117" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Language notebooks, 1850-1851 Feb. 5 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_8d2c1d6ee87e6f6b6c7562e83eafae6b">
                     <extent>3 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_27808e7ec36b418e7dbfef2a5f8204b8" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref98_roe" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Language notes, 1852-1853 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_d53e1ab526f1bdd35e448700d59612a3">
                     <extent>29 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_8a41ec610c2a991b0fc317e2c95e39db" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b9710cb91ee0fcc701272eedb829e58b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Unbound sheets with further notes on Inuit languages.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref101_pr7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed material, 1850-1854</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0d56916d44f89bf51199b173f5f8fad5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_27c5de8f56b2fe558ff4fd5f7490ccca">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Eskimo-English vocabulary and a published copy of Simpson's <title
                        type="simple" render="italic">Observations on the Western Eskimo</title>. (2
                     items)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref103_uxz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Writings by Simpson, 1853 Aug.-1854 May and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0eb856fa78407972f6a013a0da05f078" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8375f9bb8af50345016aa721e75a9867">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>(36 items)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref105_3qw" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Drawings and maps, 1849-1853 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_530b68049c8bfdc77072518a772bab81" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8ee02f6efeb069cd4b817e8683cb6163">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Additional drawings and maps are housed in an oversize box. (10 items)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref108_bim" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Meteorology Files Series, 1848-1858 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_22cb6122814ff47040a18e87ca3b0731">
                  <extent>5 folders</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_17d14fa5dc525a362c0f6d1c86a7c758">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Simpson's extensive meteorological observations recorded during his time at Point
                  Barrow in the Arctic, including detailed charts of temperatures and other
                  climactic data.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref110_9po" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Notes and data, 1848 Feb.-1853 Mar.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_61d11a012da80c1deac3bcd04829a90b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_57241ffaab80aadf4a24f130753e28fc">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>(18 items)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref112_l7k" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Notes and data, 1854 Oct.-1856 Jan. and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f0f4958c49ed958433c1bc99388c30cf" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ce192a8390583a97a1b9196ae2306c1f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>(15 items)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref114_7mq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed material, 1857 Aug. 14-1858 Dec. 9</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_91ad8cefa55965c1feeef1097110ca40" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8c02f9265f690dd376639bd214d74148">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>(2 items)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref116_ieq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Writings, 1848 Feb.-1857 Aug. and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_216cc58202d6a45f6c9cad685a9d7ec9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5024ef854347456bf7b811da0b95324a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>(5 items)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref118_idy" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Notes and data, 1849-1854</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_464efd5bd11f59f69577b891d0afa902" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_80cb2d917596478e0423aeee2b1dc0be">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Oversize. (12 items)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref121_a0v" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Additional Papers Series, 1819 Sept. 30-1875 Jan. 29 and
                  undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_9dd1fd8c46b56d773854efb24ebe6a13">
                  <extent>2 folders</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_e6cac33eecb1380f23e972b42cd5ca89">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Miscellaneous papers from Simpson's files that fall outside the scope of the other
                  series. Includes a copy of a handwritten treatise <title type="simple"
                     render="doublequote">Navigation,</title> by Simpson's brother, William
                  Simpson.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref123_ig2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous papers, 1849 Sept.30-1875 Jan. 29 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_df55028d5954a5c3e46c3e69dec00894">
                     <extent>18 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_4d2e65a3326acad5dfe0f0cb0f2d3834" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_079cef20a72a2b262741ad98b6c9cec3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Various papers, including a small list of notes jotted down during the passage
                     through the Isthmus of Panama; lists of supplies; small unidentified manuscript
                     charts; a sketch of a writing desk; writings on miscellaneous subjects,
                     including the descriptions of a shark and other fish; and an envelope bearing
                     Simpson's address in Picadilly.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref126_vpa" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"Navigation" by William Simpson, 1824 May 18</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_cc7234795cffd158b0aa22e0b99cd1d5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b64a89086d76db2e859ebc16ee3dc495">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Oversize handwritten arithmetic textbook containing a series of navigational
                     problems and their solutions. It is divided into seven major parts: "Plane
                     Sailing"; "Traverse Sailing"; "Middle Latitude Sailing"; "Mercator's sailing";
                     "Of the Variation of the Compass"; "Oblique Sailing"; and "A Journal of a
                     Voyage from London to Madeira and Teneriffe."</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref129_656" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Other Printed Material, 1844 Nov.-1875 Jan. and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_aa8656ceb66e67799775b4b7a4f82144">
                  <extent>3 folders</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_44b07125ba27015c93373335be0b91ef">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Various printed materials from Simpson's files, unrelated to previous series,
                  including several handbills printed aboard the HMS Plover.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref131_ond" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed material, 1844 Nov.-1875 Jan. 20 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_1c821765fd21bb0276d98fc62fa0210c">
                     <extent>22 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_e5550c812b968ca8aa0894f342f43b6e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0ebb56a8e148f71ce8f84074479b2473">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Contains various printed materials, including two handbills printed aboard the
                     HMS Plover.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref134_8ck" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Oversize printed material, 1859 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_dd5a329407b267d3be52fb1117eb8521">
                     <extent>3 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_a389e83ac630792034e257b7c20adb3e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4ff7658876276189bd4d649a601d9aef">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Includes Simpson's diploma from the College of Edinburg; a page from a
                     Supplement to the Malta Observer" (1859 July 2); and a blank chart entitled
                     "Naval Officer's Certificate" intended for recording the names, genders, and
                     ages of passengers.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref137_pk1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Oversize printed material, 1842 Sept.-1861 Jan. 24</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_4b4efc8211428a49343caeae0e4914cc">
                     <extent>4 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_59c5298a26602844035893410f9c0141" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-folder">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_28acce6cf3f330d227b1bf4c49de3f36">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Includes a printed poster, "Regulations to be Observed on Board Government
                     Emigrant Ships," 1842; a map entitled "Discoveries in the Arctic Sea up to
                     MDCCCLVI"; a supplement to the <title type="simple" render="italic">Illustrated
                        Times</title> of 1858 Nov. 6, entitled "Illustrated Times Map of Scotland";
                     and one page from the 1861 Jan. 24 issue of a South African newspaper,
                     containing a report communicated to the paper by Simpson's brother, William
                     Simpson of an outbreak of measles in the village of Ceres.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref141_dig" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Poetry, Plays, and Amusements Series, 1848 Sept. 16-1855 Nov. 13 and
                  undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_88ce0f6d604f7b16e1777af5143becf7">
                  <extent>2 folders</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_be3a3b1f1f51701c3a1033a92a13ac57">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Playbills announcing various plays, dances, and entertainments aboard the HMS
                  Plover, and a volume containing notes on plays and Simpson's original poetry. Much
                  of this material was printed by Simpson and assistants and are early examples of
                  shipboard printing. Other pieces are hand-lettered.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref143_4jo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Playbills and volume of writings, 1848 Dec. 26-1855 Nov. 13 and
                     undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_0082e4babc2a1df1dac15e045332bca4">
                     <extent>19 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_6733ec40b8d6eca048a191e7e083e0fb" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref145_ieg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Oversize broadsides, 1848</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_fd03737b90f10a2c5e380bb811c589a5">
                     <extent>2 items</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_22a84d50f51eec0a3d753b89b2046ea1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4ade4cc1f015704907d8a341cde64b61">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Fliers advertising a play on the Plover and a dance, hosted on the ship, to
                     which the local Inuit were apparently invited.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
