<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/smalljohnhumphrey/"
         >smalljohnhumphrey</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the John Humphrey Small Papers, 1720-1946, bulk 1850-1870,
               1912-1937 <num>RL.01208</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Library staff; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Ted Holt and Paula Jeannet Mangiafico</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000874797</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 10:10:58
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>John Humphrey Small papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Small, John H. (John Humphrey), 1858-1946</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01208</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1720/1946" type="inclusive">1720-1946, bulk 1850-1870,
            1912-1937</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_2538568f26c4d554b51f9694adea7db4">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_c792de8a16ba4bc0c4a39f756429f74d">Lawyer and U.S. Representative from
            North Carolina. Correspondence, legal documents, and other papers (chiefly 1850-1870 and
            1912-1937) of John Humphrey Small; of his father-in-law, Col. Rufus W. Wharton, lawyer
            and planter; and of Col. David M. Carter, lawyer, planter, businessman, and court
            official, of Fairfield, N.C. Small's papers form the bulk of the collection and concern
            his North Carolina agricultural interests, his legal practice, his activities in
            Congress, river and harbor improvements, the Intracoastal Waterway, patronage, Southern
            financial conditions, U.S. and North Carolina politics, World War I labor problems, and
            the 1929 Depression. The papers before 1850 are mainly deeds, family papers, and legal
            documents. Wharton's and Carter's papers relate largely to the legal profession and to
            their agricultural interests.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_7ccc7b4bce770270f341913f28f7163e">
            <extent>9,721 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_928900a1b585eab3144d4f5ec3974593">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_f2553e3dca802770085bf08aa7e9f6fb">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_aa6d4ffbb7ed4373e86c85203d98d24d">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_eb666db5fc034e4f6487bfbdda346a5c">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], John Humphrey Small Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_12417b81d3c3b0d73990af4f16d59b64">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The John Humphrey Small Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library from 1949-1954.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_c7496fe4f5450c7e4e1b4c1c99c1abb9">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library staff</p>
         <p>Encoded by Ted Holt and Paula Jeannet Mangiafico, August 2008</p>
         <p>Accessions 48-564, 48-1904, and 66-130 are described in this finding aid. </p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_4df196bf0f8034fea466fe1748abec12">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Papers of John Humphrey Small (1858-1946), attorney, planter, and U.S. congressman,
            1899-1921; of his father-in-law, Colonel Rufus W. Wharton (1827-1910?) attorney and
            planter; and of Colonel David M. Carter (d. 1879), attorney, planter, businessman, and
            court official of Fairfield, North Carolina. Arranged in the following series: <emph
               render="bold">Correspondence, Financial Papers, Legal Papers, Miscellaneous Papers,
               Printed Material</emph>, and <emph render="bold">Volumes</emph>.</p>
         <p>The papers centering around Rufus W. Wharton and David M. Carter, principally legal and
            financial papers, include deeds and indentures; wills; inventories; estate and
            settlement papers; note collections; papers relating to the sale of corn by commission
            merchants; stock transactions; charter of the Dismal Swamp Canal Company, 1787; papers
            relating to the Albemarle Swamp Land Company, 1879, the Albemarle and Chesapeake Canal
            Company, 1881, and swamp land transactions for Carter heirs, 1879-1890; papers dealing
            with the administration of the estate of David M. Carter by Rufus W. Wharton, and after
            Wharton's death, by John Humphrey Small; correspondence concerning lumbering and farming
            in North Carolina during the 1890s; and personal correspondence, including letters from
            Frances (Carter) Schaeffer from Germany, Austria, and North Carolina.</p>
         <p>The bulk of the papers focuses on the career of John Humphrey Small in the United States
            Congress, his interest in the development of rivers and harbors and the Intra-Coastal
            Waterway, his membership on the National Rivers and Harbors Congress, and his legal
            practice. Papers relating to his congressional campaign in 1898 concern North Carolina
            politics, especially in the 1st Congressional District, civil service abuses, the Light
            House Service, and the vote of Populists, Republicans, Quakers, and Negroes.</p>
         <p>Correspondence during his years in Congress discusses plans for a white grade school in
            Washington, North Carolina, 1903-1904; conditions of large scale farming at Edgewater,
            North Carolina, including descriptions of seeds, fertilizer, prices, machinery, crop
            conditions, and marketing, 1903-1912; problems of railroads, especially the Norfolk and
            Southern Railroad; the presidential campaign of 1916; coastal highway development;
            various rivers and harbors bills; the Inlet Waterway project; transportation via an
            inland waterway; the National Rivers and Harbors Congress; railroad and water
            transportation in relation to national defense during World War I; land acquisition and
            construction plans for the Intra-Coastal Waterway from Norfolk, Virginia, to Beaufort,
            North Carolina; problems of labor, including the movement for the eight hour day; labor
            shortages in eastern North Carolina during World War I; prohibition; woman suffrage; the
            National Guard; military service and the draft; coal shortages during the war; army camp
            sites; home guards; rising prices; excess profits tax; the Red Cross; various
            agricultural bills, national and North Carolina politics; a Congressional trip of
            inspection to the Far East in 1920, including Japan, Korea, and the Philippines; the
            Railroad Act of 1920; and routine matters such as patronage, post office appointments,
            appointments to West Point and Annapolis, and pensions for Spanish-American War
            veterans.</p>
         <p>Correspondence after Small's retirement from Congress concerns the postwar economic
            depression; immigration legislation in the 1920s; the membership of the State Geological
            Board; the vice-presidency of the Atlantic Deeper Waterways Association; business
            conditions during the early 1920s and during the depression; condition of eastern North
            Carolina banks, 1920-1922 and 1932; Small's service as president of the National Rivers
            and Harbors Congress, 1920-1922; the promotion of the port of Wilmington, North
            Carolina, by the state; Democratic politics; the presidential campaign of 1932; the
            National Recovery Act; railroads in 1935; the development of airmail service; conditions
            during World War II; and Franklin Delano Roosevelt. Other correspondence pertains to the
            opening and building of his law practice in Washington, D.C.; his partnership with Angus
            W. McLean, governor of North Carolina, 1925-1929; and specific legal cases.
            Miscellaneous papers consist of the minutes of the Tri-State Aviation Corporation,
            photographs, invitations, and Small's speech on the inland waterway.</p>
         <p>Legal papers include the papers relating to various estates, including David M. Carter,
            Charles Adams, and others; papers concerning income tax; papers dealing with the
            development of Washington Park, North Carolina; papers pertaining to specific cases;
            incorporation papers of the Tri-State Aviation Company and All-American Aviation, Inc.;
            deeds, indentures and wills; and papers of the legal practices of David M. Carter and
            Rufus W. Wharton.</p>
         <p>Financial papers include bills and receipts, 1830-1940, consisting of household
            accounts, clothing bills, promissory notes, tax receipts, court costs, estate
            inventories, medical bills for family and slaves, and records of slave sales; material
            on Confederate taxation; papers, 1870s, of a Baltimore, Maryland, cotton factor;
            records, 1880s, of corn sales; tobacco warehouse receipts, 1890s, from Greenville, North
            Carolina; business papers dealing with Jonathan Havens, Jr., commission merchant in corn
            and grain in Washington, North Carolina, and founder of the Havens (cottonseed) Oil
            Company and receivership papers of the St. Paul (North Carolina) Cotton Mills,
            1939-1941.</p>
         <p>Among the printed materials are clippings on the Depression, 1930-1934; personal items;
            biographical material on Senator Joseph E. Ransdell of Louisiana and on Rear Admiral
            Colby N. Chester; copies of the Greenville (North Carolina) Daily Reflector, December
            27, 1913, and the Red Triangle, Paris, April 5, 1919; seed catalogues; reprints of the
            House of Representatives reports and bills on immigration, 1921, and airways, 1937;
            broadsides of the 1920 election; plan of organization of the Democratic Party in
            Beaufort, North Carolina, in 1896; the "Declaration of Principles" of the National
            Rivers and Harbors Congress, 1916, and its officers for 1916-1917; and a bond pamphlet
            for the Albemarle and Chesapeake Canal Company, 1879.</p>
         <p>The volume is the Individual Voting Record by Roll Calls in the House of Representatives
            for John H. Small during the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd sessions of the 66th Congress,
            1919-1921.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Patronage, Political -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918 -- Economic aspects</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Lawyers -- Political activity</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Legislators -- United States -- Correspondence</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Southern States -- Economic conditions</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Politics and government -- 20th century</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Depressions -- 1929 -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Agriculture -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Intracoastal waterways -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Harbors -- Maintenance and repair</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Lawyers -- North Carolina -- Washington</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Lawyers -- Correspondence</subject>
         <famname source="ingest">Small family</famname>
         <persname source="ingest">Small, John H. (John Humphrey), 1858-1946</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref11_t2c" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence Series, 1853-1946</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_cca844202d02e834771b8e3967b83a9f">
                  <extent>15 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref13_jdw" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1853-1902</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f19bd849987b4d6e94c73a088a456288" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_7ys" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1903-1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_91f10c8fafda1397bfa2329c880c0fdd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_ftl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1907-1916 Aug.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e94b5149da23e8e271546c022d19a7a4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_1cc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1916 Sept.-1917 Apr.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8b1cc18ffcc9bf313fc2125e98a7ee14" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_srs" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1917 May-Aug.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0a1743c2f6d17ffb6ab7ab9452220325" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_o6g" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1917 Sept.-1918</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f5bb428bcb925cdf133b603c5d61a52e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_394" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1919-1921 Aug.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_bb4df1bf1b0920e760c487bf2f29d881" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_f90" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1921 Sept.-1922 June</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d1f08cd4eafcf75cd8523f3f33e63346" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_dep" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1922 July-1923 Mar.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8aa3504651598d0d18b749be2364585d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_j8j" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1923 Apr.-Dec.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c297275c158e493e9eab954f265c9ede" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">10</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_3co" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1924 Jan.-Sept.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f9cb7a17b025033eb498eac1285dfdf4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_u04" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1924 Oct.-1929</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a04da400dc7bace4f92fb3b86432a255" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_wgx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1930-1936</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_eef9055c54a8c6ab38889a5cb62ec146" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">13</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_h23" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1937-1938</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b8220529d28e9624cf725b65f234c47d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_xi3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1939-1946</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_7e4a72f7fea988df8de3c023e4bc2c2f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">15</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref28_fzx" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Legal Papers Series, 1720-1941</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_8e8495587a6008f087f14ec257ff08e9">
                  <extent>3 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_i58" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1720-1889</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ee4a8ae9501e5008d595afe82fb991b5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_0q3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1880-1936</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4bb01a3433e2ee7ca35e26f1c62c735f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">17</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_2ni" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1937-1941</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3280ceb73ece0ea7f060f91a1643aafc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">18</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref33_jrl" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Financial Papers Series, 1830-1940</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_bd961d767653a981afb7967adbcd9afa">
                  <extent>5 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_nte" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bills and Receipts</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref36_xcd" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>1830-1860s</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_f2c2e82a83bc14d5dd5ba0c2e4528d43" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">19</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref37_6aj" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>1860s-1870s</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_2ac880a26cab021f75e6a3eabbfe5b15" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">20</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref38_ui0" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>1870s</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_c57881718132064ffb1a689ee25aef82" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">21</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref39_o9w" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>1880s-1890s</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_5e16b530432cf04890ab5e86fa885643" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">22</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref40_2rh" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>1900-1940</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_9b09563086ebfc1194e5d66355f5c8a5" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">23</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref41_fhr" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Miscellaneous Papers Series</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_9853269b6b1a481daea01abb5cd25989">
                  <extent>1 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_39h" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Misc. papers</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1adf442a34332d9b3dc41c7905be8077" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">24</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref44_ia8" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Printed Material Series</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_e7dece9527856f7a2ff4010ede45bc17">
                  <extent>1 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref46_zlm" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed Material</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_07cda074b5b0c585f0ff75988e09e034" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">24</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_ejc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Clippings</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5c995c47ef000a518fdf7359e276e6ba" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">24</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref48_s2p" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Volumes Series</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_8822b46ccfd94f8095ff4a51863fa19f">
                  <extent>1 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref50_bqr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Volumes</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2aee0286b4fba7e9d2c636ff1525d9b3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">24</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
