<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/smithfm/">smithfm</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Florence Moss Smith Papers, 1916-1973 <num>RL.01212</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by Rubenstein Library staff; machine-readable finding aid created by
               Alvin Pollock</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000955863</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 10:12:03
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Florence Moss Smith papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Smith, Florence Moss</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01212</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1916/1973" type="inclusive">1916-1973</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_fe9e697a9f0a8e62223771a308642252">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <physdesc id="aspace_130de7998c2c242805da589896945f4d">
            <extent>circa 3,840 items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_1b9d632f1517c63822f2d75112e936c8">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_1b16f8fce947d5c43c8e788dc3e4e4ae">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_6c0e16cabbe3bed4abb2b370cb0d5fab">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Florence Moss Smith Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_2427f50ae7a02209fcfc152242ac8bb5">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Smith Papers were given to Duke University Library in 1989.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_754f123e5fd0a0875a018911496156ea">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Encoded by Alvin Pollock</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_508bd7d2ee1921b4da71fff367297821">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Florence Moss Smith was born in 1911. While she was an undergraduate student at Duke
            University from 1928 to 1932, her parents, Mr. and Mrs. C. W. Moss, lived in Mobile,
            Ala. As an undergraduate at Duke, she was active in the Y.W.C.A., took part in the
            Woman's Athletic Association, and belonged to the White Duchy.</p>
         <p>Receiving her undergraduate degree in 1932, she returned to Duke periodically to pursue
            graduate studies. She worked at the Duke University Press from 1937 to 1938 and on Oct.
            1, 1938, was appointed general personnel worker and counselor-at-large in the Woman's
            College at Duke University. The Woman's College Student Handbook indicates that by 1939
            she held the position of Director of Religious Activities. She held this position until
            1941 when she married Frank Ferrell Smith, also a Duke alumnus, who was with the U.S.
            Soil Conservation Service at that time. From the time her husband joined the U.S. Navy
            in 1942 until his discharge in 1945, Smith stayed with her parents who still resided in
            Mobile, Ala. During the war she was the primary person responsible for rearing their two
            sons, Frank Jr., born in 1942, and Howard, born in 1944.</p>
         <p>After World War II, the Smith family settled in Alabama. By 1959, they were living in
            Loxley, Ala., and a third son James (Jim) had been born.</p>
         <p>Three generations of Florence Moss Smith's family are represented in the collection,
            which ends in 1973. At that time, her son Jim had just competed law school at Vanderbilt
            University in Nashville, and Howard, having completed a tour of duty in Vietnam in 1971,
            was just getting out of the U.S. Army. By 1973, both of them had married. Frank Smith,
            Jr. died in March of 1960. When Ms. Smith gave the collection to the Rubenstein Library,
            she was living in Elberta, Ala.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_cca4a9dd0fa8c7443999e5d64f96e2ef">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The Florence Moss Smith Papers span the period 1916 to 1973 and consist almost entirely
            of correspondence. The bulk of the collection consists of letters exchanged between
            Florence and Frank Smith during their courtship and after their marriage between 1942
            and 1945 when Frank Smith was serving in the U.S. Navy during World War II. While this
            World War II correspondence forms the crux of the collection, the papers also chronicle
            Florence Smith's life from her undergraduate days at Duke University until the marriage
            of her children more than three decades later. One of the greatest research values of
            the collection, is its depiction of the impact World War II had upon families.</p>
         <p>A theme running throughout Frank and Florence Smith's correspondence from 1942 to 1945
            was that of forced separation brought on by the war. Their letters document the
            difficulties presented to both Florence Smith, who is without "masculine support", and
            her husband, who was far removed from the circle of family and the births and rearing of
            their two sons, Frank Jr. and Howard. In addition, one sees the importance of the letter
            as the principal, often sole, method of communication during the war which <emph
               render="doublequote">made the waiting endurable.</emph>
         </p>
         <p>Frank Smith trained at the U.S. Naval Training School (Indoctrination) at the University
            of Arizona in Tucson and also near Boston, before being assigned to overseas duty. He
            was commissioned as a lieutenant and served primarily in the South Pacific, the
            Philippines, and Japan, before he returned to the states after the war in late 1945.
            There is a lengthy letter from him dated Sept. 28, 1945, describing how his ship took
            occupation troops into Japan. He described the port city of Wakayama, his opinion of the
            Japanese people, and the effects of the B-29 bombings on the area.</p>
         <p>Two of Florence's brothers, Howard and John Moss, also served in World War II. Howard
            Moss, who was in the Army, was stationed in the European theater and John Moss, a doctor
            in the U.S. Navy, served in a military hospital on Guam in 1945. Several of their
            letters, chiefly to their parents, are included in the collection.</p>
         <p>The legacy of war shadowed the next generation of Florence Smith's family after her son
            Howard joined the U.S. Army. Eventually obtaining the rank of captain, he served in
            Vietnam from 1969 to 1971. There are similarities in the war experiences of both
            generations of the family. A letter dated Aug. 15, 1968, from Frank Smith to his son
            Howard, who is grieving over the death of a friend killed in action in the Vietnam War,
            relates a similar experience during World War II when a friend of his was killed.</p>
         <p>The early correspondence, 1928-1941, consists chiefly of exchanges between Florence
            Smith and her parents while she was an undergraduate at Duke University and later while
            she was employed at Duke. Her correspondence with Frank Ferrell Smith, also a Duke
            graduate, began around 1938 while he was working for the Soil Conservation Service in
            Arkansas. The letters became more frequent and intimate after their engagement,
            particularly between April and May of 1941 shortly before their marriage.</p>
         <p>There is a gap in the correspondence from 1949 to 1958. In 1960, soon after the
            correspondence begins again, there are several letters of sympathy to Frank and Florence
            Smith. The letters were occasioned by the death of the Smith's eldest son, Frank, in an
            automobile accident in March 1960. The later correspondence is mostly among Florence and
            Frank Smith, their parents, their two other sons, and their daughters-in-law.</p>
         <p>While correspondence comprises the bulk of the collection, there are also a few
            miscellaneous items, including a small group of unidentified photographs and a few
            printed materials.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">United States. Navy -- Officers -- Correspondence</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Husband and wife</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Duke University -- Religious activities</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Duke University. Woman's College -- Students</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Parent and child</subject>
         <persname source="ingest">Smith, Florence Moss</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref10_ggm" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Florence Moss Smith Papers, 1916-1973</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref11_6yz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1916, 1924, 1927-1939 May</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_d60485cbf939ac9d31c864c593cc4734">
                     <extent>11 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_f66fbd62c6bc315d58d897008f08b838" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref13_jnc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1939, June -1941 April 11</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_a0a0a2e563e1f6f3d4c7b9eea56361a8">
                     <extent>7 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_a002be9b7b9f8fe95718c8775346fbf3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_utv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1941, April 12-May 20</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_4eecec06b1d3aed96a094ae53ca586a4">
                     <extent>8 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_9005a4576adc5e19ab9810a61d4ebe0a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_kk1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1941, May 21-1942 May</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_c69a175491e520be55415a0bd24bbe26">
                     <extent>7 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_217877b2874a6edf368229e6b15fff81" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_otm" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1942, June -December</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_e73a979ca3608a517b481f93bbd9cede">
                     <extent>8 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_3851adfcdfc4c99eac3d376f3d190a81" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_7yw" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1943, January-August</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_b49b99dd8a0cfe12cf888e6817183f7f">
                     <extent>8 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_51e77a27538f57c6cee28bb3260e1b9d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_97r" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1943, September-1944 May</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_5a5e25eaaab36402ad70eeeb4da07367">
                     <extent>8 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_232b4e2086f026e95cd4aadf1eeaf340" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_qw6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1944, June-1945, April</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_787eb91662e8868e80edc2dadd7aa5a8">
                     <extent>9 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_9cac1f0cd0b32d34a31659cd8e433f5a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_c1w" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1945, May-1960</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_84918d13d40aa71ce9fa339daec4d6e9">
                     <extent>8 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_b3b0361a0b9817a8a20cce02d4bddd09" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_ega" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1963-1973 and undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_fa090a6d58047afcfb95e424b6c2ba05">
                     <extent>8 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_e7a9439fe201f9a86058c2d89b3f5e00" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">10</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_ohq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous, 1940-1942 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_eeeec639c75fcc3f792dbc5eae013a0b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">10</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
