<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/snareedmund/">snareedmund</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Edmund Snare Papers, 1836-1867 <num>RL.11555</num></titleproper>
        <author>Alice Poffinberger</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>November 2017</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">008010309</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-11-17 13:48:33
          -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Edmund Snare papers</unittitle>
      <unitid>RL.11555</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.8 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">4 items</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1836/1867" type="inclusive">1836-1867</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_15a49408b1b409649a08703eceaec40c">Edmund Snare was a physician and
        resident of Huntingdon (Huntingdon Co.), Pennsylvania. Collection comprises a ledger (dated
        1836-1867) and three documents, including a letter (1864 January 19) appointing Edmund Snare
        as an examining surgeon of the Pension Office; a printed document (dated 1864-1866) with a
        handwritten list of pensioners he examined; and a letter (July 1866) from Snare to pensioner
        John Horst requesting more details regarding his injury, with Horst's responses. The last
        portion of the ledger (approximately 53 pages) contains Snare's records regarding his
        examinations of soldiers, primarily from Pennsylvania regiments, who had been discharged for
        various injuries and diseases from both the Civil and Mexican wars. The ledger was initially
        used (118 pages) to record transactions for a mercantile business belonging to another
        Edmund Snare, presumably a relative of Dr. Snare.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_5d28792cf21ee182045b22852cf199eb">Materials in English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="aspace_cd29321b6f2db0a3ada346e6eb3fc745">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Edmund Snare was a physician and resident of Huntingdon (Huntingdon Co.), Pennsylvania. He
        was the son of David Snare and Catherine Colestock. He received his medical degree from the
        University of Pennsylvania in 1860. He married Ada M. Zeigler in 1862, and died of
        consumption on 27 February 1867.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_a39c22dde15bdf275b5cad492d93834d">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
        research use.</p>
      <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_6ed49a6120d70749bb99853355a7fa9f">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_3706a979d06c228b7c460b7999fa3b76">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Edmund Snare Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript
        Library as a purchase in 2017.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_7ed6cc23797f8d553f4b6965ade8f5af">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Edmund Snare Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_bdca200477c6fe27fbfbea4b3697d3c2">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Alice Poffinberger, November, 2017</p>
      <p>Accessions described in this collection guide: 2017-0150</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_2f98e13d489d8c718e01e00d2c0237d5">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>Collection comprises a ledger (dated 1836-1867) and three documents, including a letter
        (1864 January 19) appointing Edmund Snare as an examining surgeon of the Pension Office; a
        printed document (dated 1864-1866) with a handwritten list of pensioners he examined; and a
        letter (July 1866) from Snare to pensioner John Horst requesting more details regarding his
        injury, with Horst's responses. The last portion of the ledger (approximately 53 pages)
        contains Snare's records regarding his examinations of soldiers, primarily from Pennsylvania
        regiments, who had been discharged for various injuries and diseases from both the Civil and
        Mexican wars. One soldier was from New York, one from Illinois, and one was an African
        American with the 32d Regt. U.S. Colored Troops. Entries recorded the soldier's name, home
        town, regiment and immediate commanding officer, as well as the attorney representing the
        soldier in his petition. Sometimes the battle in which the injury was received is mentioned,
        including Antietam, Gettysburg, and Cold Harbor; other notes mention men who were captured
        and sent to Confederate prisons, including Andersonville. Snare then provided a detailed
        medical description of the injury or wound and any resulting damage. Several of the men had
        contracted diseases while on duty, such as typhoid or tuberculosis, had sustained hernias or
        were sidelined by rheumatism, but most of the men suffered gunshot wounds or injuries from
        cannon fire. In the margins Snare recorded his estimates for awarding a pension, according
        to guidelines set by the Pension Office. Some of the soldiers were examined annually or
        biennially over the course of three years, to reassess their continued eligibility. </p>
      <p>The ledger was initially used (118 pages) to record transactions for a mercantile business
        belonging to another Edmund Snare, presumably a relative of Dr. Snare. This Edmund Snare of
        Huntingdon, Pennsylvania, and New York, sold goods such as coffee, flour, wine, tea, dried
        fruit, and Cuban tobacco, among other items, and purchased goods from a variety of firms.
        Includes an alphabetical listing of his customers; along with records of expenditures,
        invoices, and sales; and tabulations of profits, primarily between May and July 1836.
        Acquired as part of the History of Medicine Collection.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Businessmen -- Pennsylvania</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Disabled veterans -- Pensions -- United States -- History -- 19th
        century</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Merchants -- Pennsylvania -- Huntingdon County</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Merchants -- Records</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Mexican War, 1846-1848 -- Veterans</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Military pensions -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Military pensions -- United States -- Civil War, 1861-1865</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Veterans --
        Pensions</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Pennsylvania -- Commerce</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Huntingdon (Pa.) -- History</geogname>
      <genreform source="aat">Ledgers (account books)</genreform>
      <persname source="local">Snare, Edmund, 1828-1867</persname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf">United States. Pension Bureau</corpname>
      <corpname role="rps" source="naf">History of Medicine Collection (David M. Rubenstein Rare
        Book &amp; Manuscript Library)</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_3121b0181e90b39cc250cba2e587b47e" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Ledger and documents</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_918a3d3046da7808054fe0db5b16b5f3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
