<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/spanishadvertisingbroadsides/"
         >spanishadvertisingbroadsides</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Spanish Advertising Broadsides (Auca and Alelujas), 1938-1985
               and undated <num>RL.11006</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Jessica Del Villar, Richard Collier</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">005768678</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 20:18:17
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Spanish Advertising broadsides (Auca and Alelujas)</unittitle>
         <origination label="source">
            <corpname source="ingest">John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising &amp; Marketing
               History</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.11006</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1938/1985" type="inclusive">1938-1985 and undated</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_2f33c2f1c785378dbd7e2444fb7e2cc0">An auca is a graphic format popular
            in Spain and especially in the region of Catalonia around Barcelona. The genre dates at
            least to the 17th century but was banned during the 18th century before experiencing a
            renewal during the 19th and later the 20th centuries as a uniquely Catalonian form of
            expression. It takes the form of a cartoon or a comic strip, typically with 48 blocks of
            image and text, although some may have less. An auca is generally produced as a single
            sheet, but occasionally a booklet form is used. The captions tend to have some sort of
            consistent rhyme to assist with the flow and storytelling. Many times the term “auca”
            appears in the title, but another term, “aleluya,” is used, apparently interchangeably.
            Some sources indicate that the aleluya originated in Castile and originally included
            religious elements that were shed over time. The aucas found in this collection are
            focused primarily on advertising a range of products, businesses, services or
            entertainments such as films, but also present are public service announcements for
            topics such as safety, health or the National Lottery. A common format is to relate some
            sort of tangential or episodic story and end by directly promoting the product or
            company of choice. Narratives tend to focus on everyday events that most families would
            be able to at least partially relate to. Many involve nuclear families and the
            day-to-day trials that they may go through. Common themes involve food, gender roles,
            entertainment, education, family, race and hygiene. Companies represented in the
            materials include GAMA, Philips, Procter &amp; Gamble, Puig, and Unilever. Items in this
            collection appear in both Spanish and Catalan. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman
            Center for Sales, Advertising &amp; Marketing History.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_80f7aca05521c89ec36844950a894541">Materials in Spanish and
            Catalan</langmaterial>
         <physloc id="aspace_a9e46d60b1fca6563e50bd6a2fd8bf2e">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_d1d1b8078e9a635f0229be6055f27e7f">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <arrangement id="aspace_c8f8165eee7a0224a2ffd6cab3a15113">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>Items are numbered consecutively and housed by size.</p>
      </arrangement>
      <userestrict id="aspace_d2443c17110292832f5b36bc166809f5">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_aa4d03df726f92f48121c28f08bebf8d">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The aucas found in this collection span 1937-1985 and are focused primarily on
            advertising a range of products, businesses, services or entertainments such as films,
            but also present are public service announcements for topics such as safety, health or
            the National Lottery. A common format is to relate some sort of tangential or episodic
            story and end by directly promoting the product or company of choice. Narratives tend to
            focus on everyday events that most families would be able to at least partially relate
            to. Many involve nuclear families and the day-to-day trials that they may go through.
            Common themes involve food, gender roles, entertainment, education, family, race and
            hygiene. Companies represented in the materials include GAMA, Philips, Procter &amp;
            Gamble, Puig, and Unilever. Items in this collection appear in both Spanish and Catalan.
            Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising &amp; Marketing
            History.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_b5dfb5ad7333a0c0afced7625f7bcaa1">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Spanish Broadsides, Auca and Aleluya were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare
            Book &amp; Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2013-2014</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <prefercite id="aspace_46e70fee5216db07cb00db23f6085d8b">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Spanish Broadsides, Auca and Aleluya, David M. Rubenstein Rare
            Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_8349e000ee1dd1413774014c3d0ba1eb">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by: Jessica Del Villar and Richard Collier, Feb. 2015</p>
         <p>Accessions described in this finding aid: 2013-0022, 2013-0102, 2014-0147</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_d3ecfb9cd19da1d7e68c6d80e1208ab6">
         <head>Historical note</head>
         <p>The term "auca" refers to a paneled, cartoon-like graphic genre that originated in
            Catalonia in the 17th century. Some sources argue that the origin comes from the Latin
            "ave" in the sense of a sign or hailing, others that the term derives from a Catalan
            dialect word for "goose" which is the name of a game that still exists. Originally auca
            consisted only of images, possibly derived from playing cards or games of chance. The
            form evolved to comprise 24-48 panels (almost always in a multiple of four) with a
            rhymed couplet of text typically of seven syllables, although the poetic structure could
            vary. Mode of production evolved with available technology, from ink drawings to
            lithography to photography and modern printing methods.</p>
         <p>During the 18th century, text and images tended to center around local fairs and
            festivals, anniversaries and other private and public events. By the mid-late 19th
            century the narrative served a more pedagogical function, and the genre came to be
            included in the ensemble of advertising literature. Also in the 19th century, the
            popularity of the Auca spread to Madrid and Castile, where it was known as "Aleluja"
            presumably linking the genre to the prevalence of religious tracts of the region.</p>
         <p>Sources:</p>
         <p>
            <extref xlink:href="http://magimo.net/tag/aleluya/">
               <emph render="bold"> Tag Archives: Aleluya--Érase una vez: un "Auca"</emph>
            </extref>
         </p>
         <p>
            <extref xlink:href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Auca_(cartoon)/">
               <emph render="bold">Wikipedia: Auca (cartoon)</emph>
            </extref>
         </p>
      </bioghist>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising -- Spain</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising -- Spain -- 20th century</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Broadsides (notices)</genreform>
         <corpname role="fmo" source="ingest">John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising &amp;
            Marketing History</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Unilever (Firm)</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Philips</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Procter &amp; Gamble Company</corpname>
         <corpname source="naf">Gama (Firm)</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref1_x72" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Spanish</unittitle>
               <unitid>1</unitid>
               <unitdate normal="1938/1985" type="inclusive">1938-1985 and undated</unitdate>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref2_8wt" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1. Paraguas Alujes. Para Lo que Sirve El Paraguas--The Purpose of the
                     Umbrella</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_efcaafbb92784fc4a66482e70bdc882a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c5d1728a24a4442f80785be6ca0127c7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: This auca details the many uses of the umbrella which include:
                     making the user look presentable, providing shade, hiding from a debt
                     collector, finding he who is in debt and many more. With a tone of humor, the
                     auca ends by stating that the only situation in which the umbrella is not
                     usable is during the rain.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref4_w5a" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>2. Viandox. Pulgarcito (El Ogro Satifecho)--Pulgarcito (The Satisfied
                     Ogre)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_c4bf48407f6270e2295ef36fa04cc746" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4e39df9edeac1fb8a7a4a9a1a7b68fde">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Viandox is a seasoning/condiment produced by Unilever and marketed under the
                     Knorr brand. Summary of text: Pulgarcito is a young boy who goes on an
                     adventure and returns with the local orges boots and bag. Searching for another
                     adventure, Pulgarcito goes back out and finds himself at the ogres house. The
                     ogers wife then tells Pulgarcito that the ogre no longer eats children because,
                     in order to save money, she has begun seasoning her food with VIANDOX. In the
                     end, Pulgarcito returns to his mother with "the ultimate treasure: the secret
                     to good cooking."</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref6_rbo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>3. Tex-Ton. El "Tex-ton" Salvador--The Savior "Tex-ton"</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1943</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_0b1a5544d9ffdbb3df935b91ba477e8b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9b892c251bb773475e2c76cfadf510f6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Tex-Ton was a packaged goods producer. Summary of text: One day the hero,
                     Canuto, awakes on a deserted island. He begins to scream in search of help when
                     a "fierce black man" who "eats white men with rice" takes Canuto hostage. The
                     black man feeds Canuto plenty in order to fatten him up and eventually eat him.
                     One day, a box washes ashore containing TEX-TON SOUP. This soup was so tasty
                     and filling that the tribe begins to celebrate and forgets about Canuto, giving
                     him the chance to happily run away.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref8_lqb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>4. Aleluyas de Panito--Aleluyas of Bread</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_21b4f9313af99e8aa4faf5a4ee696dc4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e81aefa6bcc97c75431c10345ee0c8bb">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: This auca details the process of breadmaking beginning with
                     the products used to make it and ending with the bread being sold at a bakery
                     and eaten by a child. It ends stating that bread is the first natural
                     nourishment and that when abundant in life, it reduces spending and brings
                     happiness to one's life.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref10_171" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>5. Film: 75 Minutos de Angustia/The Man Who Cried Wolf. Una Historia
                     sin Precendentes en los Anales Policiacos--A Story Without Precedents in Police
                     Proceedings</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1939</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_6144cbd9a91ee011317b0e5227059f79" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0825ba1e3ef485966156148fc75af002">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>American film starring Lewis Stone, Barbara Read and Tom Brown. Filmed in
                     Universal City, California. Produced by Universal Studios. Released August 29,
                     1937 in USA. Released 17 June 1940 in Madrid. Directed by Lewis R. Foster.
                     Summary of text: This auca is equivalent to what would now be considered a
                     movie trailer. It is an advertisment for the 1937 film The Man Who Cried Wolf.
                     It tells the story of a Lorenzo Fontaine, a muder that had been commited and
                     the wrongful accusation of Fontaine's son. Fontaine, must now do what he can to
                     prove his son's innocence before it is too late and his son is sent to the
                     electric chair.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref12_vfc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>6. Maxbel. La Historia de la Gastronomía puesta por MAXBEL--The history
                     of gastronomy as told by MAXBEL</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_68c6b29edd620c83e72d1eba804d4ea8" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_57eb1eb065c22fd0f951f666c8c11655">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Appliance manufacturer. Summary of text: An ad for a butane and regular gas
                     MAXBEL stove, this auca beings by mentioning food from various countries
                     including Greece, Italy and Russia. All the while, the owner of this stove has
                     been cooking delicious food from these various countries using her "modern,
                     simple yet marvelous" stove.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_ezj" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>7. Tip-Top. Esta historia verdadera, es la de un señor cualquiera--This
                     true story could pertain to anyone</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_245203083a4168e7763d533151560cf3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_90cd8ef874a5431eb05e613cf89b12b9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: A man is constantly late for work because he fails to tie his
                     shoe laces correctly, which leads to a series of mishaps and misfortunes. His
                     boss is quite unhappy with him when one day the man discovers TIP-TOP, a
                     elastic closing for one's shoes that eliminates the need for shoe laces. With
                     this invention he is able to catch his train, be on time for work and make his
                     boss happy.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_u4z" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>8. Airesan. Apuros de la familia KUSAN que el regresar de veraneo los
                     soluciona con AIRESAN--The plight of the KUSAN family which, upon returning
                     from their summer vacation, is resolved by AIRESAN</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_c97c22f143ef2b5d34f446d3860233fb" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1b622e2703a9d73fb9990e02cf336fce">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Airesan is a bug spray that helps a family out after they have
                     returned from summer vaction to see that their house is infested with bug. This
                     bug spray fights against cockroaches, fleas, mosquitoes, flies and many more
                     insects.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_aqw" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>9. Tex-Ton. La Jornada de Doña Gertrudis--Miss Gertrudis'
                     Journey</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1943</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_cb7ec9455bda76b7bdd50ef9a65efd62" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_65625a94df8d64cf6f2f887d98709f8e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Tex-Ton was a packaged goods producer. Summary of text: Miss Gertrudis has a
                     slew of errands to run. Between taking her kids to school, sweeping, making the
                     beds and cleaning the house, she loses track of time and before she knows it
                     her husband is home from work annd angry that there is no food on the table. In
                     her quick thinking, Miss Gertrudis remembers TEX-TON soup and in five quick
                     minutes the soup is ready and her husband is happy to have such a tasty
                     meal.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_hsy" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>10. Yo periodical. La Revista de los Niños "yo" aparecerá el viernes
                     día 4 Junio--The periodical/magazine of the children "I" will appear Friday,
                     the June 4th</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1937</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_f1aa7984cca6fced356d156b799c47bb" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_edd5544e29483e013401e8c6d1603dfc">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Two chldren ask their father for something amusing. While
                     searching, the father finds a periodical that will keep the children
                     entertained and that is full of emotion and stories. The periodical keeps the
                     children so entertained that the mother has time to look for new recipes and
                     cook enjoyable food. The periodical is available in millions.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_kcs" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>11. Divulgación popular del libro siempre libros baratos--Popuar
                     release of book always cheap books</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1937</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_74d3662652313c6fc08af68cb4aebf89" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5513170b31c9ea0a700ecae6a9133bf1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Local bookstore. Summary of text: The book store being advertised offers a wide
                     array of literature that is sure to entertain any audience. From
                     adventure-based children's books, to book about wars and revolutions to books
                     so emotional that they could even make a lion cry, this book store carries
                     everything and a visit will surely have you leaving happy.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_5kh" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>12. Agua del Carmen. Auca del Agua del Carmen--Auca of Carmen's
                     water</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_5b400deff2e8d5fe3820fba04b328b66" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a9a206593001620b6e70bae47ef1f22d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Created in the 17th century. Formula is a concentration of medicinal plants.
                     Product is still sold in pharmacies. Apparently, the main usage of this water
                     was to prevent anxiety attacks or calm nerves. Supposed to be prescribed by a
                     doctor. Summary of text: This water is advertised as being some of the best
                     water possibly imaginable. It serves many, many purposes and can cure most
                     illnesses. The advertisement warns agaisnt forgetting it when going on an
                     important trip or eating dinner. Agua del Carmen can cure headaches, stomach
                     aches and even insomnia. It is such a grand invention that it surely deserves a
                     monument in the city.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_gbl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>13. Film. Primavera en el Corazon: risa en imágenes graciosas, con
                     bellas mujeres, bonitas canciones y muchas más cosas--Spring in the Heart:
                     laugh with funny images, beautiful women, beautiful songs and many more
                     things</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1957</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_892ae6c5fd7c84c5d7f1caa3b80e59eb" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_360eb50f1d3f294f152475854e63b02c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Mexican film. Released September 26, 1956 in Mexico. Starring Andy Russel and
                     Irasema Dilian. Directed by Roberto Rodriguez. Summary of text: This auca
                     advertises a movie with what is supposed to be a humorous plot line. A couple
                     finds themselves falling in love but later having issues when the woman in the
                     relationship becomes jealous. She proposes marriage, in which the man is
                     portrayed as literally being tied to a post with a rope. There is confusion and
                     two brides show up to the wedding but in the end there is a happily ever after.
                     This film is said to be sure to make the audience laugh and they will
                     undoubtedly be back tomorrow to watch it again.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_j77" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>14. CADETE book collection. El mejor regalo, el mejor CADETE--The best
                     gift, the best toy: a book from the CADETE collection</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_e806695895d96a45670c530ea58888c1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d1c1ef91f7052fc6f83d6d4683284db3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: A young boy is teased on the playground for not knowing who
                     Dickens, Alcott or Walter Scott are. He goes home and asks his father for money
                     to buy educational books from the CADETE collection. After reading these books
                     the young boy is education about all things past and present. He is then
                     portrayed as being the man in charge at his place of employment. In the end,
                     the boy has become well-educated without concern of whether he was rich or poor
                     because he was able to read CADETE.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_paw" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>15. National lottery. Aleluyas de la lotería. Juegan el Blas y su
                     tía--Aleluyas of the lottery. Blas and his aunt play</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_b0e09c76410c484589ca05be91fdaa71" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5540d7bfcb230dc8fb3a603b4b1a5dec">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Spanish lottery has been organized every year since 1812 and is organized by
                     the Spanish Public Administration. This lottery is the second longest
                     continuously running lottery in the world and is considered the biggest lottery
                     in the world. Summary of text: Blas and his aunt have very good luck playing
                     the lottery and start imagining all the things they could buy depending on the
                     winning price of the gamble.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_nwz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>16. Foundry of Salvador Manclus Andres. Lee con mucha atención, esta
                     pagina que ves ¡Viva la Gran Fundicion, Salvador Manclus Andres!--Read this
                     page that you see with much caution. !Long live the Grand Foundry, Salvador
                     Manclus Andres!</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_e68ba3046def2caff7e97d6548f46479" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e6983d47c06c5429ec94ee42277cf1c4">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: When the bell at a local church stops working, the worried
                     priest looks to Salvador Manclus Andres to fix it. Manclus does an
                     extraordinary job at replacing the bell and the whole town is happy. Following
                     that incident, the local clock breaks and Manclus comes to the rescue again,
                     saving the day. His clocks and bells are of the highest quality and are sure to
                     impress.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref34_rrx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>17. National lottery. De como la lotería da optimismo y alegría--How
                     the lottery gives optimism and hope</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_484096955c085e537b0e7e36d8ed4f00" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5834706b75f2de3c10a9fd785462a5a3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Pachin is a very poor man who just can't seem to make it. He
                     struggles to make any money and it is implied that his girlfriend is a
                     prostitute. One day he and his girlfriend sit and talk about what they wish
                     their life would be. Pachin decides to buy a lottery ticket and ends up winning
                     a lot of money. He and his girlfriend can now live a luxurious life and are
                     able to give back to those who are also lower class. His girlfriend no longer
                     has to prostitute herself and they now live a happy and prosperous life.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref36_wit" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>18. CADETE book collection. El mejor regalo, el mejor CADETE--The best
                     gift, the best toy: a book from the CADETE collection</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_0c80e93ae4a25df99e933037b822fa9e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6c0fbd0cf07e05d8e701a0da7cce9d6b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: A father is frustrated with his 12 year old daughter and 13
                     year old son. His daughter has become very superficial and his son has begun
                     smoking cigarrettes. The father is unsure of what to do when he decides to
                     purchase books from the CADETE collection for his children. The two then become
                     very well-mannered and educated and the father is very proud to have been about
                     to amend their ways. He is sure that the collection will reach at least 1000
                     volumes because it is so beneficial and useful.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref38_4n4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>19. Escuela de Ingenieros Industriales de Barcelona. Auca de las Bodas
                     de Plata de la Promoción 1933 Escuela de Ingenieros Industriales de
                     Barcelona--Auca of the Weddings of Gold of the 1933 graduation from the
                     Engineering Industrial school of Barcelona</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1958</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_e003e88fcc1f8f1a1cf822c2381a58fd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9ceb2369e132eb7effd438fd9670332c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>The School of Industrial Engineering is part of the larger Universitat
                     Politecnica de Catalunya (Technical University of Catalonia, UPC) and was
                     created in 1851. This school is the biggest engineering school in Catalonia.
                     Summary of text: Students at this school were able to learn about many, many
                     different fields of study during their time at the school. There were courses
                     on dance, mathematics, the sciences and so on. As the students graduated some
                     obtained wealth while others didn't but in the end they were each able to find
                     their field of study.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref40_1wy" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>20. Artilene. Relato en forma sencilla, de unas telas sin igual tesoro
                     de maravilla--Story in simple form of some fabrics without the same treasure of
                     marvel</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_3056663cc01b7bc87755c83b8fda51e7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b6e848e2f83f2e6caa5ce25699a35f44">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Fabric was originially created by Adam and Eve when they
                     couldn't find adequate clothing. The auca tells the story of the many styles
                     and time periods that fabric has gone through since its creation. ARTILENE is a
                     company that produces the finest fabrics possible, which do not crease, are
                     easy to wash and store and generally make life less complicated. These fabrics
                     are sure to be stupendous.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref42_996" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>21. Radio Barcelona. Vida de Radio Barcelona--Life of Radio
                     Barcelona</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_769f42520e6b478f423df931a5098270" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a5478352f39a06978170988b5af9e828">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Radio Barcelona provides any kind of entertainment or
                     information one could want. It's weather announcements are helpful in preparing
                     for the day. A religious station provides comfort for ones home and the cooking
                     station allows one to learn new recipes. Along with the mentioned stations, the
                     radio provides entertainment in the form of music, announcements and
                     events.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref44_bvg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>22. OKAL (medication). Contra el Dolor tableta OKAL--Anti-pain tablet
                     OKAL</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_39e07be4615c50772fb6443cb28e6191" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a02e7dfc491dd78a090da5e81f3c72a8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: A wise religious leader opens a store where he sells seemingly
                     majestical, white pills that are said to cure everything. Men, women and
                     children visited his store with a variety of ailments looking to cure their
                     suffering. With these pills, they never again experienced ailments and were
                     very happy for the man and the OKAL pills. This auca is also translated into
                     Arabic and French and seems to have references to Islam.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref46_cqb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>23. Tío Nelo. Historia de Tío Nelo--The story of Uncle Nelo</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_64dda2601790f59091efb9c3ec8530b2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_60b7f1437a13e6be008fe86a6d1865e7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Tio Nelo is the name of a cafe specializing in horchata, a drink made from
                     nuts, seeds and milk. Summary of text: Tio Nelo is a great cook and makes
                     products that everyone loves. He eventually makes a lot of money off of his
                     restaraunts and stops being as active as he once was. When he see that people
                     are sad due to his absence he returns to cooking , which makes everyone very
                     happy.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref48_1gk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>24. Rover/Ebano. Pavimientos--Pavements</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_4a2ec6f6a983f7b6faa04e3aee14ba7a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_328c81b4d2362ae8e3caaf7f91325d7a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: A couples home is in bad condition as the ceiling, walls and
                     floor are due to be changed. The wife keeps telling her husband that it is time
                     to update their house but their husband is very worried about the finances. He
                     visits the ROVER/EBANO location and recieves a very low estimate for the cost
                     of the materials. Luckily, he and his wife are able to update their house and
                     can now enjoy their new ceiling, walls and floors thanks to ROVER/EBANO.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref50_5ru" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>25. Soldados GAMA. Juan y su amigo con sus soldados desmontables--Juan
                     and his friend with their removable soldiers</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_dce331f91f096dd5a19d9266634fd3d8" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4afd5b6ecad9604746c337ee0e29c61a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>GAMA is a German toy company that has been around since before WW1. Summary of
                     text: A young boy is showing his friend his GAMA toy soliders. As the boys play
                     they create a scenario involving the toy soldiers and the toy Indians. The
                     friend decides that he will ask the 3 magi for them as a gift.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref52_tpf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>26. Film. "De pillo a pillo" se aclama por su lujo y por su
                     trama--"From one scoundrel to another" is praised for its extravagance and
                     drama</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_fdb4ce8b5697ef2bd7c37dd68200d49a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b5a369995de767315272c8d6d115dca7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Spanish film, a 1955 musical comedy by Adolfo Torrado and Daniel Montorio,
                     starring Angel de Andres and Antonio Casal. Summary of text: This film follows
                     3 characters who start out as impoverished city dwellers but then encounter a
                     fortune and begin to live a lavish lifestyle. They soon encounter issues and
                     are forced to find a way to resolve them and live happily ever after.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref54_hvy" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>27. Marisa clase italiana helado (ice cream). En la Historia del Helado
                     Marisa Fama ha Alcancazo--Marisa has reached fame in the story of the ice
                     cream</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_e9f47483661375e9e39704161e148284" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_346e3aa70a4ac0d6f89465dc369e322c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Ice cream is enjoyed far and wide and Marisa brand ice cream
                     only makes the experience more enjoyable. The whole world is now inclined to
                     eat ice cream from this brand.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref56_ure" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>28. NORIT laundry detergent. Aventuras de Jaimito o NORIT el
                     borreguito--The Adventures of Jaimito or NORITO the little sheep</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_1b9a6ff1bc2e30292d522ece4770d373" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3dcbc69633828d360e4a305993bec3a7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Jaimito is a very destructive young boy who is constantly
                     breaking things and getting himself into trouble. One day his father becomes so
                     angry at him that Jaimito gets grounded. Of course, Jaimito tries to hang from
                     a shelf which he ends up knocking over and in the process dirties his close.
                     His father becomes even angrier but his mother decides is that all she needs is
                     a little NORIT to thoroughly clean the shirt.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref58_lq4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>29. Werner pianos. Untitled</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_313aa29055df1ed821ce408d9c461ee3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6ca617c1b0e8fccac13cb5ed46944a36">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Werner was established in Chicago in 1902. Summary of text: A neurotic man is
                     constiently acting out and harming other people and himself. It is implied that
                     one day he decided to take a broom for a ride (like a witch) but before going
                     outside he sees an ad for a WERNER piano, which saves his life. He buys a piano
                     and his neurosis is cured.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref60_wfo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>30. Cel-lo tape. Untitled</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_e79e11b5ce3cbc7e575dbb355a9c4685" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8fc8e0f3fbb4244b9b25ec371d632963">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Name originated from "Sellotape", a British brand of transparent tape. Summary
                     of text: The wise discovered CEL-LO tape and it was a life changing experience.
                     It can be used to fix torn bills, torn books or for a variety of general uses.
                     The whole world recognized that this tape is the best tape out there.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref62_wyg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>31. Vermicidia Barcelo. Las Lombrices de Toto--Toto's Worms</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_ffc63614ca3fa54a377298bd56b6436a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b2bac6fcc67f3c3f65dbcc84297d5d83">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Vermicide, for intestinal parasites. Summary of text: Toto is a young boy who
                     gets in trouble and is essentially put on a time out. During this time Toto
                     comes across a cake and starts eating it. He somehow gets stomach worms from
                     this cake and proceeds to become very ill. His father is looking for a remedy
                     when he comes across Vermicidia Barcelo, which effectively cures him of his
                     illness.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref64_7wg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>32. Benet Campabadal. De Una Cinta Sin Igual: Aleluya de la cinta que
                     ciñe adorna y precinta--Of a belt like no other: Aleluya of a belt that
                     encirles, adorns and seals like no other</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_6601305bfa12d863f5ad4259d5a0c221" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_67c5f58e48d096e071ebfb005d2c8b57">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Benet Campabal is a company that advertises making over
                     100,000 different kinds of belts and ribbon. This ad, details the many uses of
                     the belt and ribbon throughout history. It mentions Adam and Eve, the Roman and
                     Chinese empires and the "discovery" of America by Christopher Columbus. This
                     last mention includes an image of what are assumed to be Native Americans
                     bowing down to the colonists.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref66_o8u" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>33. Festival de la infancia--Children's Festival</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1964</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_7caf8b1f868c01cba97fbcbbe78f2015" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5d1fb823e98a5f8acf8184539b9b0301">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: The yearly children's festival is coming back to town and will
                     be in Barcelona from Dec 19 1963 to Jan 5, 1964. This festival will include all
                     the attractions a child could possibly want. There will be a ferris wheel,
                     swings, an acrobat and many more. At one point there is a mention of "savages",
                     one of who is portrayed as a native.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref68_qou" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>34. Bomba Prat water pumps. Aleluya de la "Bomba Prat" o una solución
                     verdad--Aleluya of "Bomba Prat"; or, a true solution</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_767afc0faa8f9d23360f74df098d9758" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_af8b5940460dbefe27704a60dbcdefd7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: A farmer is struggle to get his crops to grow because of the
                     sever lack of water present that season. He prays and does everything he can to
                     try to make his crops successful but they continue to fail nonetheless. One day
                     we comes across "Bomba Prat" a pump that is supposed to draw water from the
                     ground and make it readily available. After purchasing this pump, his crops
                     begin to grow and his harvest is so succesful that be becomes rich.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref70_yci" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>35. Casa Piulachs. Es probado y es notorio la eficacia del papel para
                     hacer un envoltorio--The efficacy of this paper to serve as wrapping paper is
                     tried and renowned</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_5dd6a2b54975b847f26a1e79078fa694" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7d72bc42fc0b17378e407dcc191951d5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Many shop owners are notorious for using cheap wrapping paper
                     that comes undone easily, which leaves their clients very unhappy. Instead of
                     using newspaper or this cheap wrapping paper, CASA PIULACHS offers a much
                     better alternative. They print store's information on high quality wrapping
                     paper that can be used to advertise the business and keep the customer happy.
                     This alternative helps the business owner save money on advertisements and
                     attracts more customers because of the high quality wrapping paper that is
                     used.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref72_hti" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>36. Industrias Reunidas de Utensilios Metalicos (IRUM). Es un termo lo
                     mejor para el frío y el calor--It's the best thermos for cold and
                     hot</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_cfcd05d90ec58811c1d9f2354025b8d6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5b26ead39fa4dcf26795d13e376b3c08">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: This thermos can be used in a vast array of situations and
                     environments. Mothers, fathers, bikers, skiiers, pilots, the eldery, the sick
                     and many more people can use it to keep their soups or drink either hot or
                     cold. Even Satan can use this thermos to keep his water cold in hell. Anyone
                     who resists using it will surely regret it.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref74_f02" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>37. Caldo OXO en cubitos. El Caldo OXO en Cubitos de la compañia
                     LIEBIG--OXO brand bouillon cubes from the Liebig Company.</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_6989f07e16ff51dda0ca86aa790e1f22" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_dd3881464a7614b0d2217a5bbd11cd4d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Trademark of OXO was designated in 1899. Dehydrated bouillon cube.
                     Commercialised by OXO in 1910. OXO was sold by UNILEVER to the Campbell soup
                     company in 2001. Summary of text: Although a homemade meal is great, it can
                     very easily take four hours to prepare. When one is short on time Caldo OXO en
                     cubitos is the perfect solution. This soup is delicious and ready in only
                     minutes. It's perfect for an elderly man who that lives by himself or soldiers
                     who are out in battle and do not have access to other meals.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref76_hpo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>38. Para qué y para quien sirven los libros--For who and for what do
                     books serve</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1956</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_6a97ab55cd9823549985a9e052272bc1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9a9f86eb45508e5bbbb0efafc75eb819">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Books are the most useful resource as many people can benefit
                     from them and because they serve a variety of purposes. They can be read for
                     fun, to learn about medicine, to read law, to know more abut history or to win
                     over a true love. Everyone is encouraged to buy books.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref78_gp5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>39. Book fair. Auca de la vida y aventuras de un libro viejo--Auca of
                     the life and adventures of an old book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1956</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_b6492ee8a70489924d67372b7f1b8abd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3eb73819edc5cb18468cfbf125fca460">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: A 100 year old book tells his life story which begins in a
                     book store. He is purchased by a young couple and for many years the book gets
                     passed from owner to owner. Eventually he falls in love with another book and
                     they travel to Paris. Unfortunately he finds himself left alone in Paris and
                     spends the rest of his years bitter about deteriorating, old age until one day
                     a man restores him to a prior conditions. Now he will be at the upcoming book
                     fair waiting for an owner to permanently add him to his collection.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref80_crg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>40. Frigo Yogurt. Aleluyas del Yogur Frigo--Aleluyas of Frigo
                     Yogurt</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_86f1a8cfd975c77e83d14a42bbb9ac91" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e9b462f326933039afec3cd69edf0105">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Frigo is part of the Unilever company in Spain and was founded in 1948. Summary
                     of text: Yogurt is a snack that is enjoyed on all (5) continents by many, many
                     people. Scientists have proven that it has lots of health benefits and FRIGO
                     makes the experience even more enjoyable by making delicious, natural yogurts
                     with fresh fruit.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref82_jnr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>41. Fonobilingue. El saber no ocupa lugar o El que aprende puede
                     llegar--Knowing doesn't require a place; or He who learns can arrive (at his
                     goal)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_06fc132a44e5876da8afacf753d946d1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_393ffe97e2ab55ae81e59197b5009f59">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: A young man is looking to learn French and begins using
                     records created by FONOBILINGUE to learn the language. He quickly picks up on
                     it and as a result is able to receive many more opportunties because of his
                     language ability. He eventually also learns English. Because of his vast
                     language abilities and the help of FONOBILINGUE he is now very successful.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref84_wx9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>42. Auca Confortcamp</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_0f7ef7b9f3b75d7e7e22be7bc8b0360b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c96c2c9deeae96f05729f97860394a43">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Confortcamp is a cot-like device that is meant to me a light
                     and easy to carry item. It can be used in various situations such as camping or
                     for going to the beach and it also has other accessories that can be purchased
                     to extend the already wide usability of this item.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref86_vtn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>43. National lottery. Auca de la Lotería o la historia de unas tías que
                     les toco la lotería--Auca of the lottery or The history of some aunts who won
                     the lottery</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1952</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_5cb0854f2d5e919f3438bab7f988cf41" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_82b8c83bac2c59d985cd68908fda9f09">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: One of three sisters seem to be sad and struggling when one
                     day she wins the lottery. Because of this she is able to travel, buy nice
                     things and meet a nice man who she eventually marries and has twin girls with.
                     They live a happy life and the 2 daughters grow up to want to win the lottery
                     as the ad claims that the lottery makes everything possible.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref88_h8m" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>44. La rata sus costumbres. Precausiones que debe adoptar contra la
                     misma--Rats. Their customs. Precautions you should take against
                     them</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_473c54470b3ccb8e0dfddce0722d6eee" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3b1d535f8b1fae078d471f12226d8795">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: This is more of a public service announcement as to how to
                     prevent rats from entering their house than it is an ad. It gives advice such
                     as keeping windows closed, keeping lids on trash cans, not leaving and food on
                     the counters and know where to put your rat posion. However, it does not
                     advertise or ever mention a particular poison or product to be used for this
                     purpose.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref90_krt" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>45. Wynn's automotive products. Vida más larga y segura, para su motor,
                     Señor--A longer and more secure life for your engine, Sir</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_503794d157991ba23aa8652a23ff44c6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_362e8aff191bb03edc2cf2cb9c9704a5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>USA brand of car care products founded in 1939. Summary of text: To test out
                     the capabilities of an engine, two men are put to a test involving a vehicule
                     and two eggs. The men are supposed to drive and as soon as they hit 80km the
                     passenger should drop the egg out of of his window. Then some WYNN's is put
                     into the engine and the same procedure is repeated. The second time, the egg is
                     dropped farther because the Wynn's product helped revive the engine and make
                     the vehicule run faster.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref92_m2y" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>46. POTAX. Aleluya que te enseña, la tradición navideña--Aleluya that
                     shows you the Christmas tradition</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1941</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_6543590a5ee5e93a248ab8a353665942" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_aaf8c92fcf73480d08d5cca73400ef13">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Maker of food products, now owned by Unilever. Summary of text: Christmas
                     season is a great holiday to spent with family. The children are eating sweets
                     and everyone is excited about the festivities and food. However, cooking
                     requires a lot of time and patience so instead families should you POTAX soup
                     which will be filling and will satisfy.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref94_vvf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>47. Baños populares. Anales de la dulce y Hermosa Elvira--Tales of the
                     sweet and beautiful Elvira</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_801e0a3cc430093aba3653242c9226e6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b47b2a669d0d06d0a16d90c5bfc81e6e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Elvira is trying to take a bath at home but encounters many
                     difficulties in attempting to do this. Because she does not have a bathtub, she
                     must heat up water and fill up a small basin that she will bathe in. This ends
                     up being very messy and water is spilt all over the kitchen floor. Elvira then
                     has to spend a lot of time cleaning up and this process leaves her dirty again.
                     When her husband comes home she is very agitated so he suggests going to the
                     public bathrooms where bathtubs are also available. Elvira is able to take a
                     wonderful bath and leaves BAnOS POPULARES feeling clean and looking beautiful.
                     She is the talk of the town and her husband's lust towards her is renewed.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref96_3pn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>48. Baños populares. Baños populares de Barcelona--Public bathrooms in
                     Barcelona</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_564d0a40ac80b91bc8ccf318df0c9236" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b414a6cf928537557afbc8a0aa559b8f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: This auca tell the same story as auca #47 but in a different
                     format. The drawings are on one side of the sheet while the story is broken up
                     into pieces on the other side. The reader is supposed to number each part of
                     the story to correspond to the correct drawing.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref98_wu9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>49. National Lottery. Gran idea ese a fe mia - esta de la
                     lotería--Grand idea, this of the lottery</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_c11e590231a36e94b12de0a0f5a381ea" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_90013a6efba445b26e39dab41298e5f5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: This auca's purpose seems to serve as a means to build hype
                     about the lottery drawing. It tells the stories of many people that would like
                     to win and all the things that could be done with the money won.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref100_vd1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>50. Auca del GIB (firm)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_5471d6df84ce2d094520f3ea1384cbe9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e91f8f237829cf51e36cdcc8646ec1cf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: GIB is a company that produces entertainment for children. As
                     they are usually bored when they have to attend events that are typically more
                     entertaining for adults, such as religious holidays and birthdays for adults,
                     GIB has provided a cure for the children's boredom. They put on events that
                     include trapeze events, ventriloquists, plays and theatre, magic shows and so
                     on.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref102_n14" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>51. Teatro Barcelona - Gracia y Justicia--Barcelona Theatre - Humor and
                     Justice</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1940</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_983e325df53884e184f0eb7da7e83c54" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_47c3d13a34084993895b419fb61a4eac">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Gracia y Justicia: Spanish Film from 1940, directed by Julian Torremocha and
                     starring Mary Santamaria and Mario Gabarron. Summary of text: Humor and Justice
                     is a play that will follow Trinidad, a local gypsy, who falls in love and gets
                     married. Trinidad and her husband have a child and all seems to be going well
                     until another woman falls in love with Trinidad's husband. What will Trinidad
                     do? What will become of her marriage? All the audience can know is that by the
                     end, Trinidad will go from being a gypsy to being a classy woman.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref104_ig5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>52. Salon de proyecciones = Rambla del centro, 34--Movie House, Center
                     Rambla, 34 (location)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_5650e16dab2317b8bf00f62f3b3095b8" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_809de42ebad36c9321f27c3803ae8a5d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Movie theater that dates back to the early 1900s. Summary of text: A young boy
                     is given a real (currency) and decides to go to the SALON DE PROYECCIONES to
                     watch movies and enjoy all day entertainment. When the boy does not show up at
                     home later on in the day, his parents become very worried and phone the police.
                     In searching for the boy they decide that he was probably gone off to a movie
                     theatre. When the boy is found, his mother is very angry but the police man
                     says she has no reason to be since the boy was smart enough to spend his money
                     on something worthwhile. The family agrees and decides to watch movies until
                     dinner time.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref106_rdr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>53. Public service announcement. Aleluyas para contribuir a evitar
                     accidentes de la circulación: Dedicadas a los niños de las escuelas
                     primarias--Aleluyas to avoid car accidents: dedicaded to elementary school aged
                     children</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1943</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_da3cd98d5c6cc662541f5fad2ad57ed4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e4c8a69d4d1363dfc1a4d9cdee86ddf0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: This aleluya is basically a list of tips for young children
                     who will be crossing the street. It includes tips such as looking both ways
                     when crossing the street and knowing what different colored stop lights
                     mean.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref108_s3w" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>54. Grafia Hispana magazine. Solo nos faltaba "ver" el auca de
                     Gutenberg--We just had to "see" Gutenberg's Auca</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_ed4cb2ae8479a9c0ab03294c40ca68c2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e969848a654f5c7a02bc54ce2900ebcf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Before the printing press, there were many other forms of
                     recording written material that other societies were utilizing such as scrolls
                     and eucalyptus but those were never very time efficient and did little for mass
                     printing. After Gutenberg invented the printing press, the printing industry
                     changed. GRAFIA HISPANA is a magazine that keeps its readers up to date about
                     new methods and techniques for printing.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref110_wqi" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>55. Brillol. Maravillas de BRILLOL--BRILLOL's wonders</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_191629be0e33125c0dfa043e4ecacc3b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f92e32f3c2bce27dc5ccad8ece69cb0f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: BRILLOL is a metal-cleaning product that comes in either
                     liquid or paste. It does such a fantastic job at cleaning metal that it's been
                     used by angels to brighten the stars and even the sun has been blinded by
                     seeing its reflection in a BRILLOL cleaned product.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref112_8em" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>56. Auca de la Maxima Garantia del comprador--Auca of the maximum
                     garauntee for the buyer</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_abec88c29a14282a980bac7efb623586" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7457e25f0a69f3250f19d2c27525049f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: This ad includes descriptions of the services that multiple
                     businesses provide. A map is included. Many of the characters portrayed appear
                     to be Mexican (based on their attire). Many of the men are wearing sombreros or
                     charro outfits (typically worn my men who are in a mariachi band). There are
                     also French translations for the entire Auca.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref114_tyf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>57. Artesanías Forcano. En esta "Auca" se relata la historia de la
                     alpargata--The story of the alpargata is told in this "auca"</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_157883465c3efa3a4ec86a2ee20dd5af" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f9b6843fec0a398e775b249a816b466f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Alpargatas are flat and comfortable shoes that have been used
                     for many different situations throughout history. These shoes make it much
                     easier for people to go who are planning on taking a long, strenuous walk or
                     for women whose heels are becoming incresingly bothersome. ARTESANIAS FORCANO
                     provides alpargatas in many different styles and heel heights. They are often
                     used by locals and tourists alike.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref116_com" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>58. Blendi toothpaste</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_cbfdbf019f4ccd793d56787da1b64d6b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_496681a42342016082c5878c5b46464d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Blendi is a product acquired by Procter amd Gamble in 1987 that is advertised
                     under Blend-A-Med. In most other countries, this brand name is Crest but is
                     advertised under the name of Blend-A-Mend in many countries in EuropeSummary of
                     text: Blendi is an otter who has very white teeth and who has decided to help a
                     young boy who does not like brushing his teeth. Blendi shows the young boy that
                     this toothpaste, also named BLENDI, tastes good and also effectively fights
                     cavities.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref118_vc8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>59. Esposition. Aleluyas del Vino--Aleluyas of Wine</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_381257dc5a51615b9c2a71e0406b987a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_32438f0c509e1628d1e314e043c57b0e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: This aleluya contains some history of wine but besides that it
                     focuses on the benfits of wine and all the countries that can attest to this.
                     There will be lots of wine at the Exposition Fair which is something that no
                     one should miss.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref120_rlu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>60. La Bruxa Borracha (restaurant)--The Drunk Witch</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_8420d20e7f066b9a5f7d54bbc7523c9a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_71a6eeebac8487800d4aacda9c403fc5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: A woman who was long ago accused of being a druken witch
                     receives pardon and begins cooking. She ends up cooking for a restaurant (La
                     Bruxa Borracha) which becomes the new "chic" restaurant in town.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref122_u7u" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>61. Argentina Bar Restaurante. Auca de "Arca de Noe" para el papá y el
                     bebe--Auca of "Noah's Ark" for the father and child</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_37902bae0b1c56d190f82b00abf9b793" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_379e1d3f7ca536620d6442d0d92515fc">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Noah's ark arrives full of animals who end up celebrating
                     their survival so intensely that many of them get hurt and have to visit the
                     veterinerian. In order to cover the cost, the ark opens up as a sort of zoo for
                     people to come to visit to see the animals.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref124_eq3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>62. Molfort's. Historia del Calcetín--The story of the sock</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_c473a45552c1d713738b93ef2a04e34f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e4076cf6b9f81f1a844c52ef17ffe164">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Socks have been used by many, many successful conquerer's and
                     warriors throughout the years and are part of the reason as to why they have
                     been so successful. For example, when Christopher Columbus introduced himself
                     to those native to America, they were completely fascinated by his use of
                     socks. MOLFORT'S is a business that provides socks. Everyone knows that they
                     are the solution.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref126_48b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>63. IBERIA (shaving products). El mas Importante invento - es el que
                     cuento--The most important invention is the one that I am talking
                     about</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_1ad59d03d193366b51aae2cdcbad6902" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5088a5cf6842804177a1de1e542ac522">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Shaving has been an issue for many men - and sometimes even
                     women and children until IBERIA razor blades came along. With these new blades,
                     shaving can be much more effective and pain free.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref128_0ko" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>64. El Cantabrico. Aleluya original que de "El Cantabrico" cuenta, en
                     versos, que no estan mal, la cocina suculenta--Original aleluya about "El
                     Cantabrito", the succulent kitchen</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_9258951f99ab2b2d2fd5b1d9e45a19ad" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_969cf25760f25f7c8b5a0ec67106d86d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Restaurant El Cantabrico serves some of the freshest, best
                     tasting food in town. Their food is always fresh and they get new ingredients
                     every day. If you ever do visit this restaurant, you'll be visiting everyday
                     simply based on how good it is.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref130_yph" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>65. Fiesta Mayor. Auca de la fiesta mayor</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_8296528032b7b5b1a3716539b2a006de" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_67e43b19aa34fef52e570af66e0c95f3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: Similar to aunca #56 Auca de la Maxima Garantia del comprador,
                     this auca is an ad for various businesses that will be at the Fiesta Mayor that
                     is coming up. There are ads for liquor, clothing, furniture, meat markets and
                     more.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref132_lid" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>66. Ramblas de Barcelona. Auca de la Ramblas</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1953</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_c8023bb462c92837888c2c95f9e6d1a0" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_165e9e3a099ec5400e3cdb6a0a434bf6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: The Rambla of Barcelona is a street located in the city with
                     many shopping opportunities. There are business that offer a variety of
                     products as well as numerous hotels. This area is visted by local and tourists
                     alike.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref134_gdj" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>67. Philips. Lamparas de garantía?--Warrantied lamps?</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1985</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_4559281dba50fc5a165656e508fbc708" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3dea4731f915a487ea5fa9573e35aabb">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Summary of text: A man who is constantly buying cheap light bulbs keeps getting
                     into accidents when the bulbs suddenly go out. As a result of trying to save
                     money on the light bulb, he has medical bills that arise from the accidents he
                     has gotten into. If he had simply spent a little more on PHILIPS light bulbs,
                     he would have never had any issues.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref136_41f" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Catalan</unittitle>
               <unitid>2</unitid>
               <unitdate normal="1946/1979" type="inclusive">1946-1979 and undated</unitdate>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref137_kek" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>68. Mataro Fair. Adam I Eva a la Fira de Mataro--Adam and Eve at the
                     Mataro fair</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_362cfd2548d5be8a2a48e160f1fc4c33" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e76a59cf5d584574f7d674dfa415eae9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Mataro is the capital of Maresme.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref139_c3o" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>69. Ciutat Comptal. La guia comercial - D'un troc de ciutat
                     comptal--Commercial guide for Ciutat Comptal [?]</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_b706aa93456b9e974cb2bebb57d964f1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7c17e90588f90668ab62b49a33c3860c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Ciutat Comptal is a reference to Barcelona's business district [?]</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref141_pi7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>70. Us oferim I'auca origina del clot comercial--We offer the story of
                     the origins of the commercial district [?]</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_acffe60ffa9ba91be36d28ee038613d9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref142_bdj" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>71. Auca del paper CARLETS--Story of Carlets papers (for
                     cigarettes)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_7c10e1a38b5525bd8b835f786a9b99a6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1d8aa836009a1de7b5cf931bd9e233f5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Carlets is a brand of cigarette rolling paper.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref144_dfp" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>72. Us oferim l'auca original del comerc I mataro industrial--We offer
                     the story of the origins of Mataro's trade and industry [?]</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_d375c374f252058b9bf1ff8cdc57cab5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2e4d2ba75eef18456de96954464b19c5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Mataro is the capital of Maresme.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref146_aoe" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>73. Auca de Barcelona--Story of Barcelona</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1950</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_0879bd6406b0b4e6c5299f9d9d98c77e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref147_m5b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>74. Auca de Sant Gervasi--Story of Sant Gervasi</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_e0693f95f574555a92f8326118cec4af" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_eb44ef93c8f528979250f916ad381a32">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Sant Gervasi is a district in Northwestern Barcelona</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref149_e4w" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>75. Auca historia I rodona del futbol club barcelona--History of the
                     Barcelona soccer club [?]</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_bfe632afa5d3c99cf1e85f05c57ab0c9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref150_12p" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>76. L'auca del primer ferrocarrilaqui trobarau combinada amb l'historia
                     d'en biada--Story of the first railroad [?]</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_a40173e5a012a62d39261d61301df69d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref151_lso" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>77. Auca de bella-terra--Story of Bellaterra [?]</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_80bc990aa4bce710811bf236dc25c2aa" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8da7379a1b91e4fc163bad5b7e1ae571">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Bellaterra is a suburb in Barcelona</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref153_hev" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>78. Gracia Festival. Auca de la festa major de gracia comercos
                     acreditats:--Story of the authorized shops for the Gracia festival
                     [?]</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_3dae1b60a7292d717e1b008294aa9451" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1b8de243bb6f82c84846811a5e49502f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Gracia Festival takes place currently in August in the Gracia neighborhood of
                     Barcelona</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref155_en7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>79. Auca dels magatzems Alemanys--Tale of Alemanys</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_729b22c22ba60f3e3ba6918203129360" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8c202c3a5a8aa0b0da959019ee1fdcb1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Magatzems Alemanys was an early department store in Barcelona</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref157_yjn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>80. Teatro Romea La compania maragall de Carlos Lloret y Luis Nonell
                     con la eximia Maria Vila--Teatro Romea, the company of Carlos Lloret and Luis
                     Nonell with the superb Maria Vila</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_accac8b9544ff505d1e4e2122ab4ab56" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_193c3c6efda8df08c11494d89c661bf0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Teatro Romea was built in Barcelona in 1863 as a Catalan language theater.
                     Carles Lloret (1921-2006) and Lluis Nonell (1926-1982) were notable Catalonian
                     actors.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref159_sdu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>81. Auca dels magatzems Alemanys--Tale of Alemanys</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_451812babe9330e65674e804361ab6c4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_351eef6b6ca52918332fe785c7eea01f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Magatzems Alemanys was an early department store in Barcelona</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref161_sox" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>82. Auca dels aplecs de la sardana (II)--Tale of the Sardana
                     gathering</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_85a5ce5d8dc995206c47904c728b1f6d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bf7ce958fe9a2379c3d7bc9d42792423">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Sardana is a circle folk dance of Catalonia</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref163_4ub" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>83. Auca dels aplecs de la sardana--Tale of the Sardana
                     gathering</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_04c576be195051108e9f611ccfa32f40" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2227663a15a412a329123204f33e20da">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Sardana is a circle folk dance of Catalonia</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref165_uzk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>84. La ferreria--The blacksmith</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1967</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_847c2901ce8c87b5cdd7d5c245465575" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref166_zyh" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>85. Auca del bon bibliofil--Tale of the bibliophile</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_48eb2cb23329d08f45d8814f35bf3c8d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref167_cyv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>86. Auca de la tisis (Aventuras del microbi de la tuberculosis)--The
                     thesis (story of the tuberculosis microbe)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_d135004107a5fb22885edace1020749b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref168_2b0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>87. Llibret Auca de la Pastisseria Publicat per Forn de Sant Jaume S.A
                     Barcelona--Story of the Bakery published by the Oven of Saint James SA,
                     Barcelona</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_7586349b64cb6a9977bd5f76cd318608" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_772d82848cc8bc8875b4c19608b7f7f3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Forn de Sant Jaume is a bake shop and cafe in Barcelona, still in operation</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref170_gqs" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>88. Auca del perfecte futbolista--Tale of the perfect football
                     player</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_e4b8244a5eaef5b79e055b30ef528389" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref171_l6w" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>89. Auca de "Les Set Portes"--Tale of the Seven Doors</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1961</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_17aae23b29d85081e3d8697cc792ecd9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b1b1773185139a77d9e955e1c10ce16d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Les 7 Portes is a restaurant in Barcelona</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref173_x5i" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>90. Puig. Auca de Puig cerda Meitat d'Espana, meitat de Franca, no hi
                     ha terra, com la Cerdanya--Tale of Puig, halfway in Spain and in France, there
                     is no place like Cerdanya [?]</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_6e8190e630763b028c5ecd41cbe0d6a9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c05529a71c6f4c624755c886383a4b14">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Puig is a fashion and fragrance business. Cerdanya is in the Pyrenees.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref175_v1c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>91. Guardiet. Auca de Mobles Guardiet- Historia d'un casament--Tale of
                     Guardiet Furniture: story of a wedding</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_33ab10f4f0b9449ddc226c2ba11beddf" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_521374e7534700277194d2d467cc4981">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Guardiet is a home furnishings and appliance store</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref177_g2b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>92. Auca d'En Filigrana, campio de Futbol--Tale of "En Filigrana,"
                     soccer champion</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1937</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_c94bc6aff6cc6d81b15b9a3eb5a85c1f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref178_561" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>93. Festival, Falla Joaquin Costa--Conde de Altea. A modo de
                     introduccio precisa esta explicacio. Auca del llibret dela falla dels carrers
                     de joaquin costa I conde altea, del an 1946--A way of precise introduction is
                     explained. Tale of the booklet of the celebration in the streets of Joaquin
                     Costa in the Conde of Altea.</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1946</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_3a76f9bee41d202baea5e85aca9bf71f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8ecdd797eb62b7202657ddbd32bfff91">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Falla Joaquin Costa--Conde de Altea, a festival, takes place in March.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref180_023" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>94. Calendari del Llaminer</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1979</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_f11d3661bb97f16b4fdfb25025c94f22" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3fe12d28b3619296fac9f995094192c9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Seems to be highlighting different holidays celebrating in this part of
                     Spain</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref182_e33" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>95. L'auca de radio scope (versificada per la colla de Taradell)--Tale
                     of the radio scope (verse from Taradell) [?]</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_732a18487c0f31f2e579d9bd13268426" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ac99783122331ebab5ed138031f1c90d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Taradell is a town near Barcelona</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref184_fmx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>96. Auca dels 'Torrons puig d'agramunt'--Tale of the Torrons of Mount
                     Agramunt [?]</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1956</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_fe9b8ab41ea28cbe16d9041e271a92c7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_881fb9be367f92654fcbd3e54872f8e1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Turrones, a nougat-type of confection from the locality of Agramunt in
                     Catalonia</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref186_9b3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>97. Per poguer be repartir, un "Patria" haureu de tenir--for
                     distribution, there is a fatherland [?]</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_66c94f2e98142aed8ab2e8a20ad315fc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
