<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/sprinklefamily/"
         >sprinklefamily</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Margaret Jordan Sprinkle and Henry Sprinkle Papers, 1935-1986
                  <num>RL.01243</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Barrye Brown; Meghan Lyon; machine-readable finding aid created
               by: Barrye Brown; Meghan Lyon</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">005952460</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 11:05:43
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Margaret Jordan Sprinkle and Henry Sprinkle papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <famname source="ingest">Sprinkle family</famname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01243</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.5 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1935/1986" type="inclusive">1935-1986</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_91959b25f66aaa3445de70cb35b24697">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_3b570292d61aaef1b483bee20edaee4b">Dr. Henry Call Sprinkle was a
            Methodist Minister from Mocksville, North Carolina, and graduate of Duke University and
            Yale University. Henry married Margaret Louise Jordan in 1930. The Sprinkle family spent
            the majority of their lives travelling the world for missionary work. The collection
            contains diaries and notebooks detailing the travels of Dr. Henry Call Sprinkle and his
            wife, Margaret Jordan Sprinkle. Main subjects are family life in North Carolina, Duke
            University events, European politics, WWII, and missionary travel throughout Europe,
            South and Central America, the Caribbean, Africa, Asia, and Australia. Materials range
            in date from 1935 through 1986.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_7245071090555206a15fe2e707a94a7d">
            <extent>150 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_1ba1f1a192f3359648386f6007b75184">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_fc211f394204cd37510ca5984b070a37">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>Also, all or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's
            Library Service Center. Consequently, there may be a 24-hour delay in obtaining these
            materials.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_11e27131275713f554a7d4ebe9d950a0">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_be061ca6f0e6b83ee34749350597ff6b">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Margaret Jordan Sprinkle and Henry Sprinkle Papers, David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_f14e45e108e2c5ec9ef495c0cdf09396">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Margaret Jordan Sprinkle and Henry Sprinkle Papers were received by the David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library as a gift in 2013.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_409f2100a855d2f9864c034dde087bcf">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Barrye Brown; Meghan Lyon, September 2013</p>
         <p>Encoded by Barrye Brown; Meghan Lyon, September 2013</p>
         <p>Accession(s) described in this finding aid: 2013-0025</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_0e17088f6ff7f21545381c0758544481">
         <head>Biographical and Historical Note</head>
         <p>Henry Call Sprinkle, born November 20, 1902, in Mocksville, NC, was the son of Henry
            Clay Sprinkle and Annie Van Eaton Call of Mocksville, NC. Margaret Louise Jordan was
            born on January 20, 1903. Henry attended Trinity College (now Duke University) and
            obtained an A.B. in 1923 and an A.M. in 1924. That same year, Henry joined the North
            Carolina Conference and was assigned as a junior preacher and director of religious
            education at First Methodist Church, located in Rocky Mount, NC. He earned a B.D. in
            1927 and Ph.D. in Philosophy, 1929, both from Yale University. On February 17, 1930,
            Henry Sprinkle married Margaret Jordan. Dr. Sprinkle pursued post-graduate studies in
            1935-36 and spent a year at Cambridge University in London, England. From 1929 to 1942,
            Dr. Sprinkle continued to serve a number of churches throughout North Carolina. He went
            on to serve as a Navy Chaplain in the US Navy during WWII, and held the rank Lt.
            Commander. Dr. Sprinkle also served as assistant editor of the Adult Student in
            Nashville (1930-1935), editor of the North Carolina Christian Advocate (1945-1949),
            Associate Editor of World Outlook (1949-1952), Editor of World Outlook (1952-1966). The
            Sprinkles retired from ministry work and settled in Mocksville, NC in 1967. In 1981,
            Mocksville United Methodist Church established The Sprinkle Preaching Mission in honor
            of Henry and Margaret Sprinkle, recognizing the many contributions they made to
            Mocksville and Davie counties. Dr. Henry Call Sprinkle died on May 7, 1989. Margaret
            Louise Jordan Sprinkle died in December, 1996.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_cf2d06757a179559f9a2e9042e961071">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The collection includes the travel diaries and notebooks of Margaret Jordan Sprinkle and
            Henry Call Sprinkle, written from 1935 to 1986. This collection is arranged into two
            series: Margaret J. Sprinkle Diaries and Henry C. Sprinkle Diaries and Notebooks. Early
            diaries and notebooks contain detailed information about their travels in Europe,
            providing commentary on the differences between American society and various other
            places, particularly English society, culture, attitudes and perspectives. Margaret's
            entries provide significant insight relating to political climate of Europe at the time
            and events leading up to WWII. Starting in the 1950s, the diaries reflect the broader
            international travels of the Sprinkles, as a result of their involvement in missionary
            work. Entries usually include travel itineraries, as well as descriptions of various
            social, cultural, and political conditions of various cities and regions throughout
            Europe, Africa, Asia, South and Central America, and Australia. The majority of diary
            entries detail daily activities, family life, social obligations, events in North
            Carolina, particularly in Durham, and events at Duke University.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_7ac11779f4058916cc566af517c3f5f7">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>Margaret Jordan Sprinkle was the sister of Charles E. Jordan and B. Everett Jordan,
            whose papers are also held at the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript
            Library.</p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Europe -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Africa -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Travel -- Diaries</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Soviet Union -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women missionaries</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Personal narratives, American</subject>
         <famname source="ingest">Sprinkle family</famname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- History</corpname>
         <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Sprinkle, Margaret Jordan</persname>
         <persname rules="dacs" source="naf">Sprinkle, Henry</persname>
         <famname source="ingest">Sprinkle family</famname>
         <corpname source="ingest">United Methodist Church (U.S.) -- Missionaries</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref13_gus" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Margaret Jordan Sprinkle Diaries, 1935-1986</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_caf2b90d0baf6a74c34baa707fc16b3c">
                  <extent>5 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_jz0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Collection information, biographical file, genealogy</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b588f3be6d6e18cff9cb11183dfc364b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_klr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Diaries, 1935-1936</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_8cad5a849ea3310e841d24c8ea3d80e7">
                     <extent>4 volumes</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_314487444604a9962573f3fdfea74864" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4b889470ddc762ae6ebfd6b97ccab626">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Box 1 contains the original diaries, as well as digitized, bound copies,
                     detailing Henry and Margaret Sprinkle's year abroad (1935-1936) at Cambridge
                     University in England. While living in London, the Sprinkles travelled
                     extensively throughout Europe, visiting France, Belgium, Holland, Northern
                     Ireland, Scotland, Norway, Sweden, Denmark, Finland, USSR Russia, Poland,
                     Czechoslovakia, Austria, Switzerland, and Germany. Margaret Sprinkle frequently
                     wrote about their travels in Europe, providing commentary on the differences
                     between American society and various other places, particularly English
                     society, culture, attitudes and perspectives. Throughout the diaries,
                     Margaret's entries provide significant insight relating to political climate of
                     Europe at the time and events leading up to WWII. Many entries mention Soviet
                     Russia; various labor strikes in France and Belgium; the election of a
                     socialist president in France; Adolph Hitler; Benito Mussolini in Abyssinia;
                     Haile Selassie's visit to England; and a number of other observations on
                     international politics.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_an6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Loose papers, articles, and photographs, 1935-1936</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6c52900388f9d863967caaaaec3e10cb" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_68ba6dd1cc7e02a1d7571543ae3e71f8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Folder includes Margaret Sprinkle's writings and reflections on Soviet Russia,
                     miscellaneous clippings on the Moscow Power Institute, a Vogue magazine article
                     from 1941 on Belgium's Great Cathedral, as well as cards, postcards, and
                     photographs.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_evv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Diaries, 1941-1959</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_87f2e96689d7e0303edbc5c7d2d9fb2d">
                     <extent>13 volumes</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_296aa3b6ddc391e8d2ec8c3cf1ba4f8f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_52536393dcc84112b9aef79dc1ab928b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Box contains yearly diaries, with dates ranging from 1941 to 1959. Entries from
                     1948-1952 are contained in one diary and there are no diaries for 1945 or 1955.
                     This box also contains miscellaneous inserts from the 1944, 1948, and 1958
                     diaries.</p>
                  <p>These diaries include details of Margaret's personal and professional life,
                     including lists and descriptions of daily activities such as meetings,
                     appointments, visits, and special events throughout North Carolina, especially
                     related to Duke University. Margaret's diaries also include travel itineraries,
                     documenting her domestic and international travels with her husband. Among the
                     countries visited by the Sprinkles beginning in the late 1940s throughout the
                     1950s were, England, France, Holland, Switzerland, Mexico, Guatemala, Costa
                     Rica, Panama, Peru, Bolivia, Chile, Argentina, Uruguay, Brazil, Haiti,
                     Dominican Republic, Puerto Rico, Cuba, Wake Island, Japan, Hong Kong, Saigon,
                     Singapore, Thailand, Burma, India, Ceylon, Yemen, Egypt, Lebanon, Syria,
                     Jordan, Jerusalem, Greece, Italy, Spain, and Portugal. Also included are
                     entries about Henry during his service in the US Navy during WWII, Franklin D.
                     Roosevelt, and D-Day. Three ballot books are among the inserts from 1948. These
                     ballot books also serve as a travel diary noting a family trip to Europe in
                     1948, with Henry and Henry II.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_rds" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Diaries, 1960-1969</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_93dc835c12f33545c725b8d05425e32b">
                     <extent>14 volumes</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_7a89ee5742df4f934ec46fd3952d23b1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f274918754ed2a3d5c75980faf50db3a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Box contains yearly diaries, with dates ranging from 1960 to 1969. The
                     following years have multiple volumes: 1964 (2 volumes), 1967 (2 volumes), and
                     1968 (3 volumes). This box also contains miscellaneous inserts from the
                     following diaries: 1962, both volumes for 1964, 1965, 1966, the 1967 Day Book,
                     one of the 1968 diaries, and the 1969 diary.</p>
                  <p>The entries within these diaries provide details of Margaret’s personal and
                     professional life, including lists and descriptions of daily activities such as
                     meetings, appointments, visits, and special events throughout North Carolina,
                     especially related to Duke University. Margaret’s diaries also include travel
                     itineraries, documenting her domestic and international travels with her
                     husband, particularly detailing their mission trip to Africa. Countries visited
                     by the Sprinkles during the 1960s include the Netherlands, Germany, Austria,
                     Liechtenstein, Switzerland, Italy, Monte Carlo, France, Luxembourg, Denmark,
                     Sweden, Norway, Holland, England, Belgium, Spain, Ghana, Ivory Coast, Liberia,
                     Nigeria, South Africa, Congo, North Rhodesia, Zimbabwe, Rhodesia, Mozambique,
                     Kenya, Ethiopia, Sudan, Greece, Italy, France, Mexico, Italy, Greece,
                     Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Switzerland, Yugoslavia, Moravia, Japan, Hong Kong,
                     Philippines, Australia, Brazil, El Salvador, Morocco, Portugal, and
                     Bermuda.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_new" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Diaries, 1970-1979</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_f432e54e91cd531756035cf4bcc5d99d">
                     <extent>11 volumes</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_8540ffbdcde6137f6c899d87e83ae5ec" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_544545488c2328c01cfde02da67b2c09">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Box contains yearly diaries, dates ranging from 1970-1979. Diary entries for
                     1973 span 2 volumes. This box also include miscellaneous inserts from the 1972,
                     1973, 1977, and 1978 diaries.</p>
                  <p>Diaries include entries related to Margaret’s personal and professional life,
                     including lists and descriptions of daily activities such as meetings,
                     appointments, visits, and special events throughout North Carolina, especially
                     related to Duke University. Many entries, as well as some inserts and loose
                     materials, include information on the purchase and renovation expenses of a
                     house located in Pinellas County, Florida. The Sprinkles continued their
                     international travels throughout the 1970s, visiting such countries as Holland,
                     France, England, Ireland, Scotland, Wales, Iran, China, South Korea, Taiwan,
                     Thailand, Malaysia, Singapore, Hong Kong. This box also include miscellaneous
                     inserts from the 1972, 1973, 1977, and 1978 diaries relating to Pinellas
                     County, FL; Methodism in America; and loose travel notes.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_u2u" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Diaries, 1980-1986</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_711019329d067a77b841cf80f7340eb6">
                     <extent>9 volumes</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_e72528d82f3699b1db52879890d4ec78" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7999796a09e31109ab6dfb16b98e30e6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Box contains yearly diaries, dates ranging 1980-1986, as well as a travel
                     journal, listing the various trips taken by Margaret and Henry Sprinkle from
                     1960-1982. This box also contains loose papers from 1980s.</p>
                  <p>These diaries include details of Margaret’s personal and professional life,
                     including lists and descriptions of daily activities such as meetings,
                     appointments, visits, and special events. Unlike the previous decades of
                     diaries, documentation throughout the 1980s is sparse. Of particular interest
                     is a travel journal, listing the various trips taken by Margaret and Henry
                     Sprinkle from 1960-1982. During the early 1980s, the travel journal notes that
                     the Sprinkles traveled to Bermuda, China, Japan, Hong Kong, and the islands of
                     Britain. This box also contains loose papers from the 1980s relating to Duke
                     Alumni holiday activities; travel and cultural information about Hong Kong,
                     China, and Japan; and the Sprinkle Preaching Mission.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref33_lwx" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Henry C. Sprinkle Diaries and Notebooks, 1935-1984</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_21a3d983361739533732423e28ed7ca7">
                  <extent>1 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_f1q" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Diaries and Notebooks, 1935-1984</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_3b2f3ad327b8785855cd1aca34f0ed0c">
                     <extent>25 volumes</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_88a78d843d9cd6cd596d48a1907bcdae" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5dc4c47759b4407156f962a14003e33d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Box contains diaries, notebooks, notepads, and address and date books, ranging
                     from 1935-1984, as well as undated materials. There are no notebooks, diaries,
                     or other materials from 1936 to 1960. This series is also missing entries from
                     1962-63, 1965-1968, 1970-1971, and 1977. This box also contains miscellaneous
                     inserts and letters from the 1935 notebook, and a guidebook to Historic
                     Savannah, including miscellaneous Savannah pamphlets.</p>
                  <p>Henry recorded his notes and thoughts on philosophy, ethics, and religion
                     within these notebooks and diaries. Many of the notebooks also feature a
                     schedule of personal and professional activities, as well as various adresses
                     and contact information. Of particular note within this series are letters of
                     recommendation from Yale and Henry's request to study abroad at University of
                     Cambridge.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
