<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
         url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/staelmadame/">staelmadame</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Madame de Staël letter to LeRoy, Bayard &amp; McEvers
                  <num>RL.11424</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Megan E. Lewis</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>March, 2017</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">007809701</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-04-06 14:34:16
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Madame de Staël letter to LeRoy, Bayard &amp; McEvers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname role="crp" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Staël, Madame de
               (Anne-Louise-Germaine), 1766-1817</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="n92076709" role="fmo" source="naf">Baskin, Lisa
               Unger</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.11424</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 Linear Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">1 item</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1814-08-12/1814-08-12" type="inclusive">1814 October 12</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_9da560a5594035ab74a724e850ce6ef7">Madame de Staël (1766-1817) was a
            French literary figure whose writings were highly influential in late 18th and early
            19th century Europe. She was a political polemicist whose famous confrontation with
            Napoléon Bonaparte led to her exile from Paris until the Bourbon Restoration. This
            letter was written in 1814 towards the end of her life. She writes from Paris to the
            prominent New York mercantile firm LeRoy, Bayard &amp; McEvers concerning a financial
            transaction in the amount of $20,000. She states that she has transferred the sum to
            McEvers in London, and wishes to confirm that they will, in turn, transfer it to her
            account with another firm. At the time she wrote this letter, Madame de Staël owned a
            large tract of land in upstate New York. Her father originally purchased the land in the
            event that the family wanted to escape France's instability and settle in America.
            Although she and her children never moved to the United States, de Staël both increased
            her land holdings and invested in developing her property. LeRoy, Bayard &amp; McEvers
            represented Europeans purchasing property in New York State, so it's highly likely that
            the $20,000 was used to either increase or develop Madame de Staël's American land
            holdings. This letter is evidence of a degree of financial and business independence
            that was highly unusual for a woman at the time.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_b4fe5e823cb107502e34485c630a8a36">Materials in
            English</langmaterial>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_1c8241a70e9dbf37c1049a8d2593bbcc">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Madame de Staël (Anne Louise Germaine Necker de Staël-Holstein) was a French woman of
            letters who was active during the period of the French Revolution and the Napoleonic
            era. Her father, Jaques Necker, was a Swiss banker who served as the finance minister
            for Louis XVI, and her mother hosted a popluar Paris salon. de Staël was an independent
            woman of means who was very active in both the political and intellectual life of her
            times. She published novels and literary criticism, as well as political and
            philosophical essays. She was a vocal supporter of the French Revolution and an opponent
            of Napoleon, who consequently banished her from Paris. She was celebrated for her social
            and conversational abilities, and hosted long-running salons in both Paris and
            Switzerland. She is an important figure in the history of ideas who contributed to
            European Romanticism and to the transition from the Age of Enlightenment to the 19th
            century. </p>
         <p>LeRoy, Bayard, &amp; McEvers was a prominent New York City mercantile firm. They
            represented the Holland Land Company in the United States, which was formed so that
            Dutch investors could buy land in what is now upstate New York and western Pennsylvania
            in 1792-1793.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_100de03f0282135c08fb12475b0f87d5">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_1ee3ec68ef997fdb8b4f639acf27213b">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_8a03c118792c266e613a1a978b956c93">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Madame de Staël letter to LeRoy, Bayard &amp; McEvers was received by the David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2015.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <prefercite id="aspace_06e35b5091f3e620372c534d903fb190">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], The Madame de Staël letter to LeRoy, Bayard &amp; McEvers,
            David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_62cbbe56768645272ce7013e40c20347">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Megan E. Lewis, March, 2017</p>
         <p>Accessions described in this collection guide: 2015-0050-LUBMSS462</p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_f2d249249d4f8224a0b9a0f4442ba630">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Collection consists of a single one page autograph manuscript letter from Madame de
            Staël to the firm LeRoy, Bayard &amp; McEvers in New York City regarding a financial
            transaction of $20,000. The letter is dated 1814 October 12; a note on the back states
            that it was received in New York 1815 March 10. In the letter, de Staël writes that she
            is sending their partner in London, Mr. McEvers, a note for $20,000. She asks if they
            have received her letter of July 25 in which she asked them to transfer the $20,000 to
            her account with the firm Doxat &amp; Divett, and reiterates this request in the event
            that they have not received it. The letter is signed Necker de Staël Holstein. At the
            time, Madame de Staël owned an estimated 30,000 acres of land in what is now upstate
            New York, (Sakolski) and it's likely that this transaction was related to her American
            property holdings. Madame de Staël's father purchased land in America for his daughter
            and her children with the thought of leaving unstable France and settling in America.
            Although she never lived there, de Staël increased her American land holdings and
            reportedly invested $20,000 in developing the property. -- Sakolski, The Great American
            Land Bubble (1932)</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) -- History -- 1775-1865 -- Sources</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">France -- History -- 19th century -- Sources</geogname>
         <corpname role="rps" rules="dacs" source="naf">Lisa Unger Baskin Collection (David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library)</corpname>
         <corpname role="rps" rules="dacs" source="naf">Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History
            and Culture</corpname>
         <corpname rules="rda" source="lcnaf">LeRoy, Bayard &amp; McEvers (New York,
            N.Y.)</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_4348e12de83d617f0b88133a37de68a0" level="file">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Letter</unittitle>
               <container id="aspace_d043f15210986851d4064efdc9cd9b13" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="folder">1</container>
            </did>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
