<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/strobridge/">strobridge</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Strobridge Lithographing Company Advertisements, 1910-1954 and
               undated <num>RL.01263</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Lisa C. Chandek-Stark and Sierra Stults; finding aid by Lisa C.
               Chandek-Stark and Kristen Kramer; machine-readable finding aid created by: Lisa C.
               Chandek-Stark</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">002495297</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 11:29:04
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Strobridge Lithographing Company Advertisements</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="ingest">Strobridge &amp; Co. Lith</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01263</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1910/1954" type="inclusive">1910-1954 and undated</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_8036db552589052f5f8a1b7246437557">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_7600a82386c177fdf43873779f17f445">Lithography company founded in
            Cincinnati, Ohio, in about 1847. The Strobridge Lithographing Company Advertisements
            span the years 1910 through 1954, documenting much of the company's printed poster
            advertising work from that era. All images are black and white. The core of the
            collection, the Image Files Series, consists of around 1000 8x10 photographs ("A"
            images) of advertising designs, and a similar number of smaller printed cards (approx.
            5x7 to 5x8, "B" images) of outdoor advertisement designs. The images are accompanied by
            three different Access Files to be used to browse the collection. These files are in the
            form of image photocopies ( "job tickets" ) and catalog cards. Most images are of poster
            (billboard or transit card) designs, but there are also some photographs of tabletop
            display advertising, window cards and other point-of-purchase displays. The collection
            documents advertising during a time when transportation was changing in America, and the
            automobile was gaining in popularity. Billboards began to replace smaller posters,
            accommodating a more mobile public. It was then that Strobridge turned from its emphasis
            on circus and theater posters (not represented in the collection) to billboard ads for
            mass-produced products. Many different products are featured, but perhaps the two most
            prominent and well-represented campaigns are those for Camel cigarettes and Palmolive
            soaps. The images form a valuable reference collection of advertising designs, relevant
            for researchers from a variety of disciplines including commercial artwork, advertising
            history and design, and popular culture. The collection documents outdoor advertising
            design during the first part of the twentieth century for what were mostly national
            brands. Numerous examples are from the era of hand-drawn and painted designs, often
            signed by artists including Norman Rockwell, Howard Scott, and Dr. Seuss (see his
            designs for the product Flit). Rarely, an artist is listed on the back of the image.
            Later designs from the 1940s and 1950s include photographic images, often peppered with
            celebrity likenesses including John Wayne, Maureen O'Hara, and Charlton Heston. Many of
            the celebrity advertisements promoted tobacco products. Some designs are clearly
            war-era, such as advertisements depicting a 1943 female factory worker, or one from
            Schlitz (1942) mentioning war bonds.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_b28f037f9e6d84a71a8f57879e173857">
            <extent>7166 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_d63098e017b6ceb1c61a5bad5fac2139">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_f0c7381e12d59b26e4b8bb45a76550e1">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_1b6ec6ac419f69a09608c114865ec7dd">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_acd62d2ecc2e2e3725c3fccf20ad2f36">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Strobridge Lithographing Company Advertisements, David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_31d235d8808d7333a1bf2d236d19defa">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Strobridge Lithographing Company Advertisements were transferred to the David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library by Fairleigh Dickinson University Library
            in 1998 and 2000.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <odd id="aspace_13f8c6d182625677d863f04aeb73e4a0">
         <head>General note</head>
         <p>Processing of this collection was supported by the National Endowment for the
            Humanities.</p>
      </odd>
      <processinfo id="aspace_4e92d305aaecf62a7f66fa94ab6ad3e5">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>The collection came to Duke in good order with all of the "A" images (mostly 8x10
            photographs of advertisements) together and all of the "B" images (advertisements on 5x7
            and 5x8 printed cards) together. The "job tickets," which are actually photocopies of
            all the images, have been copied again onto acid-free paper. The original set is in
            numerical order. The second set was put in order according to product type categories
            used by the outdoor advertising industry. Thus, there are three access files to all
            images in the collection: (1) photocopies in order by number, (2) photocopies in order
            by product type or service (topic), and (3) a card file with descriptive information
            ordered by the pictured advertisement's brand name. The card file does contain some
            generic product-type headings also, e.g., gas ovens. It arrived with the collection and
            appears to be incomplete.</p>
         <p>The Access Files (the photocopied job tickets and card file) and Image Files
            (photographs and printed cards) all refer to an "A" and "B" numbering system. Each file,
            however, does not have exactly the same number of items, and so certain series may be
            missing some individual numbers. Photographic materials have been sleeved in
            polypropylene.</p>
         <p>As of October 2002, the advertisements in this collection were not indexed in the
            library's Resource for Outdoor Advertising Description (ROAD) database.</p>
         <p>Processed by Lisa C. Chandek-Stark and Sierra Stults; finding aid by Lisa C.
            Chandek-Stark and Kristen Kramer</p>
         <p>Completed September 2002</p>
         <p>Encoded by Lisa C. Chandek-Stark</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_3b869c83d7c12b2ac137fb73db34df0d">
         <head>Historical Note</head>
         <chronlist>
            <head>Chronology</head>
            <chronitem>
               <date>ca. 1847</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>
                     <persname>Elijah C. Middleton</persname> founded an engraving (steel and
                     copperplate) establishment in <geogname>Cincinnati, Ohio.</geogname>
                  </event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1849</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>
                     <persname>W. R. Wallace,</persname> a lithographic engraver, joined Middleton
                     to form the partnership of <corpname>Middleton and Wallace.</corpname>
                  </event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1854</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>
                     <persname>Hines Strobridge</persname> entered the partnership and the company
                     became <corpname>Middleton, Wallace, and Company (Lithographers).</corpname>
                     General trends in publications showed a transition from woodblock and engraving
                     to <subject>lithography.</subject> Early prints were mainly black and
                     white.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1857</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>
                     <persname>Martin B. Ewing</persname> entered the partnership.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1858</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Wallace left the firm, which became <corpname>Middleton, Strobridge and
                        Company.</corpname>
                  </event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1859</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>
                     <persname>Dominique C. Fabronius</persname> joined the partnership. "In this
                     establishment are embraced all kinds of <subject>lithographing</subject> such
                     as views of cities and buildings, landscapes, etc., in one or more
                     colors-portraits, maps, bonds, certificates of stock, drafts, checks in all
                     kinds of commercial work almost equaling the finest engraving on steel. Value
                     of work per annum, $25,000. Hands employed 20." (from <persname>John W.
                        Merten</persname> article, listed below)</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1860</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Fabronius and Ewing left the partnership.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1861</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Middleton left the partnership. The company's
                        <subject>lithographs</subject> could now simulate oil portraits. During the
                     Civil War era, the firm was credited with producing the first <emph
                        render="doublequote">oil portraits</emph> of Washington, Lincoln, and Grant,
                     among others.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1865</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>The name of Middleton was dropped from the firm. It became
                        <corpname>"Strobridge and Gerlach,"</corpname> or <corpname>"Strobridge,
                        Gerlach and Wagner."</corpname> The company moved to Pike's Opera House
                     Building.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1866</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>A fire in Pike's Opera House caused the <corpname>Strobridge
                        Company</corpname> to lose all possessions, including its early
                     records.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1867</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Strobridge purchased <corpname>"E. C. Middleton and Co.,"</corpname>
                     publishers of oil portraits. A reorganization and incorporation took place
                     under the name <corpname>"Strobridge and Company."</corpname> With the
                     invention of power machinery and the lithographic steam press, the industry saw
                     an era of rapid development. For the next 25 years, Strobridge would be the
                     largest producer of circus and theatrical posters in the country.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1871?</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>William Sumner became president of the company.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1872?</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Hines Strobridge was named as manager.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1878</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Matt Morgan presumably crafted the first large multiple-sheet poster. The
                     first large (16-sheet) <subject>outdoor poster</subject> ( <title type="simple"
                        render="doublequote">Eliza Crossing the Ice</title>) was exhibited at
                     Fountain Square in <geogname>Cincinnati.</geogname>
                  </event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1880</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>The firm changed its name to "The <corpname>Strobridge Lithographing
                        Company."</corpname>
                  </event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1881</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>George Fox became president.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1882</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Development began on a large modern building on Canal St. in Cincinnati.
                     Clifford B. Wright was named president.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1883</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Hines Strobridge took over the company presidency (no longer listed as
                     manager). Procter and Gamble's <subject>Ivory Soap</subject> was advertised on
                     an outdoor poster developed by the firm. ("[This] is noteworthy on several
                     counts: first, because it marks the recognition by industry of the large
                        <subject>outdoor poster</subject> as an effective advertising medium;
                     second, because it is reputed to be the first time that a photograph was 'blown
                     up' to furnish the pictorial subject of a poster." (from <persname>John W.
                        Merten</persname> article listed below)</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1887</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>On December 1, a fire destroyed the Canal St. building. In July, the
                     company moved back into the rebuilt building.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1896-ca.1912</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Strobridge produced theater posters (by artists Mucha and Paul Jones, among
                     others). The firm also issued company calendars, highlighting its renowned work
                     in color by artist Harry Birdwell and others.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1909</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Hines Strobridge died. His son <persname>Nelson Strobridge</persname>
                     became president of the company.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>ca. 1910-1920</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Strobridge began making posters for motion pictures (e.g. for producer
                     Pathe). Posters were now printed from zinc, not stone, and the offset press was
                     introduced. A number of additional advancements changed the way the company
                     functioned. The focus of the firm turned from entertainment to the commercial
                     poster. This era marked the growth of the automotive industry and thus of
                     commercial outdoor advertising.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1913</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>William Merten was named company general superintendent.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1916</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Merten became vice president.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1922</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Merten no longer held position of general superintendent.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1925</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>The firm expanded by acquiring <corpname>Henderson Lithographing
                        Co.</corpname> in Norwood. Through Merten, the firm participated in the
                     creation and direction of the Lithographic Technical Foundation.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1937</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>The entire firm relocated to the Norwood plant. Nelson Strobridge became
                     chairman of the board. William Merten became president (and was also active as
                     director of the Lithographers' National Association). John G. Strobridge
                     (grandson of Hines) became vice president.</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1960</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>H. S. Crocker, Inc. acquired Strobridge Lithographing Co. (listed as
                     division until 1970)</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
         </chronlist>
         <p>NOTE: Research and text for timeline by Kristen Kramer. Source of information and direct
            quotations: John W. Merten, <title type="simple" render="doublequote">Stone by Stone
               along a Hundred Years with the House of Strobridge,</title>
            <title type="simple" render="italic">Bulletin of the Historical and Philosophical
               Society of Ohio,</title> January, 1950, 8:1. </p>
         <p>The Strobridge Lithographing Company, especially well-known for its production of circus
            and theatrical posters from the late 1800s and early 1900s, also produced a variety of
            printed items including maps, portraits, diplomas, counter displays, and blotters. The
            collection at Duke University contains only printed poster advertising work created from
            1910 through 1954. The firm was established in Cincinnati, but a New York address can
            also be seen on the backs of some images in this collection.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_3503bf59f7c0367a94bb1ded862ec259">
         <head>Related Archival Materials note</head>
         <p>Other Strobridge collections - including Strobridge images in color - may be found in a
            variety of repositories including the following: National Museum of American Art
            (Washington, D.C.), Cincinnati Art Museum (Ohio), Cincinnati Historical Society (Ohio),
            Cincinnati Museum Center (Ohio), Public Library of Cincinnati and Hamilton County
            (Ohio), Henry Ford Museum and Greenfield Village (Dearborn, Mich.), Harvard University
            (Boston, Mass.), New York Public Library, Illinois State University-Milner Library
            (Normal, Ill.), Ringling Museum (Sarasota, Fla.), Circus World Museum (Baraboo, Wisc.),
            and the Library of Congress (Washington, D.C.) among others.</p>
         <p>In addition to the Merten article cited above, see the following sources for additional
            information: </p>
         <p>
            <title type="simple" render="italic">Art as Image: Prints and Promotion in Cincinnati,
               Ohio.</title> Alice M. Cornell, Editor. Athens, Ohio: Ohio University Press in
            association with the University of Cincinnati Digital Press, 2001.</p>
         <p>Alden N. Monroe, <title type="simple" render="doublequote">Bigtop to Bijou: The Golden
               Age of the Show Poster,</title>
            <title type="simple" render="italic">Queen City Heritage</title> 1984, 42:2</p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_0b71aa9fed6b2fd1d04654f454208cc8">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The <title type="simple" render="bold">Strobridge Lithographing Company
               Advertisements</title> span the years 1910 through 1954, documenting much of the
            company's printed poster advertising work from that era. All images are black and white.
            The core of the collection, the <title type="simple" render="bold">Image Files
               Series</title>, consists of around 1000 8x10 photographs ("A" images) of advertising
            designs, and a similar number of smaller printed cards (approx. 5x7 to 5x8, "B" images)
            of outdoor advertisement designs. The images are accompanied by three different <title
               type="simple" render="bold">Access Files</title> to be used to browse the collection.
            These files are in the form of image photocopies (<emph render="doublequote">job
               tickets</emph>) and catalog cards. Most images are of poster (billboard or transit
            card) designs, but there are also some photographs of tabletop display advertising,
            window cards and other point-of-purchase displays. The collection documents advertising
            during a time when transportation was changing in America, and the automobile was
            gaining in popularity. Billboards began to replace smaller posters, accommodating a more
            mobile public. It was then that Strobridge turned from its emphasis on circus and
            theater posters (not represented in the collection) to billboard ads for mass-produced
            products. Many different products are featured, but perhaps the two most prominent and
            well-represented campaigns are those for Camel cigarettes and Palmolive soaps. The
            images form a valuable reference collection of advertising designs, relevant for
            researchers from a variety of disciplines including commercial artwork, advertising
            history and design, and popular culture. </p>
         <p> The collection documents outdoor advertising design during the first part of the
            twentieth century for what were mostly national brands. Numerous examples are from the
            era of hand-drawn and painted designs, often signed by artists including Norman
            Rockwell, Howard Scott, and Dr. Seuss (see his designs for the product Flit). Rarely, an
            artist is listed on the back of the image. Later designs from the 1940s and 1950s
            include photographic images, often peppered with celebrity likenesses including John
            Wayne, Maureen O'Hara, and Charlton Heston. Many of the celebrity advertisements
            promoted tobacco products. Some designs are clearly war-era, such as advertisements
            depicting a 1943 female factory worker, or one from Schlitz (1942) mentioning war bonds. </p>
         <p>The first series, the <title type="simple" render="bold">Access Files,</title> can be
            used to browse the collection and narrow a search for an individual advertisement before
            moving on to the <title type="simple" render="bold">Image Files</title> themselves.
            Items in the <title type="simple" render="bold">Image Files</title> are labeled with an
            "A" or a "B" indication. The "A" group holds the larger 8x10 photographs and the "B"
            group contains smaller images (primarily 5x7 and 5x8) printed on cards. There is some
            duplication between the "A" and "B" groups. The "A" images contain advertisements from
            the 1910s through the 1950s, and the "B" advertisements were created mainly in the 1920s
            and 1930s. All point-of-purchase advertising is in the "A" group. There is often
            indication of the size poster the design was made into (e.g. 24-sheet), a design or
            perhaps job number (e.g. Camel No. 93), and a title (e.g. <title type="simple"
               render="doublequote">Perfect</title> for a Camel advertisement with the text "Perfect
            Taste"). Most designs are presumed to have been created and published by Strobridge, but
            there are some images stamped "W. J. Rankin Corp." Some images show billboards as they
            were posted; some of these show the nameplate of the outdoor advertising company that
            owned the billboard structures.</p>
         <p> The name of the collection is seen on folders and sometimes elsewhere as the
            "Strobridge Lithography Company," but the materials themselves as well as other
            documentation reveal the name to be "Strobridge Lithographing Company" at the time when
            most of this collection was created. Almost all advertisements are in English,
            presumably for posting in the U.S., but a few, such as Spur cigarette advertisements,
            are in Spanish.</p>
         <p>Related collections in the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library
            include a number of other outdoor advertising collections, such as the Outdoor
            Advertising Slide Library, the John Paver Papers, the John Browning Papers, the Duplex
            Advertising Co. Records, the H.E. Fisk Collection of War Effort Mobilization Campaigns,
            the Outdoor Advertising Association of America Records, the Outdoor Advertising Poster
            Design Collection, the Garrett Orr Papers, the R.C. Maxwell Company Records, the Howard
            Scott Papers, and the John E. Brennan Outdoor Advertising Survey Reports. There are also
            numerous published items from the era of this collection which provide even more context
            for the designs.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Lithography -- 20th century -- History</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Commercial art -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Lithography, American - 20th Century -- History</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising layout and typography</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising -- History</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising, Outdoor -- Posters</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising, Outdoor -- Design and construction</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising -- Posters</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Advertising, Outdoor -- United States</subject>
         <genreform source="ingest">Cards</genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">Billboards -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Signs and signboards</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Posters -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Posters -- Design</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Posters, American -- 20th century -- United States</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Black-and-white photographs</genreform>
         <corpname source="ingest">Strobridge &amp; Co. Lith</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Strobridge &amp; Co. Lith</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising &amp; Marketing
            History</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref16_0ci" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Access Files</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_aa49be1c7322f7d6a64f8d20e58baa7d">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>This series contains three subseries which should assist the user in searching for
                  individual advertisements within the <title type="simple" render="bold">Image
                     Files.</title> The first two <title type="simple" render="bold">Access
                     Files</title> subseries are photocopies (called here "job tickets") of all the
                  images in the <title type="simple" render="bold">Image Files</title> arranged in
                  two different ways. The first group of job tickets is arranged as the images are,
                  in number order. The second subseries is an exact copy of the first, but arranged
                  by advertising topic, described below. Each file, however, does not have exactly
                  the same number of items, and so certain series may be missing some individual
                  numbers. The third subseries is the card file, comprised of cards with brief
                  description and indexed terms from the advertisements. The images contain
                  additional information recorded on the verso side.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_tsy" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>SUBSERIES ONE: Job Tickets</unittitle>
               </did>
               <arrangement id="aspace_97ff4e2d5708e57714998de5b994c745">
                  <head>Arrangement note</head>
                  <p>In Order by Number</p>
               </arrangement>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref18_11i" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-1 to A-135</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_825a49e169ef4ed4c5e23a66814b07b8" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref19_kyl" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-136 to A-280</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_a48b7a3712261964b8c801378029abf2" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref20_zpz" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-281 to A-433</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_42ed0ba6fcb90630c1d40145cdac460e" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref21_78i" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-434 to A-570</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_99c67a2bc11cdd3172b6b7d77c8221f0" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref22_d3e" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-571 to A-712</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_97d1b91d56f86c32cf384140c299dedf" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref23_sij" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-713 to A-850</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_46ac27dc4bd782d66fb70ed1b3bd7bfd" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref24_9t2" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-851 to A-991</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_66e46cdd4f6f5fccc899ddb19f5e1283" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref25_im7" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-993 to A-1081</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_15340a6d96a4837a7ad4bca5ab29b360" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref26_1xy" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-1 to B-129</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_c11fbc13e7567af143a6d7aec36fc1a7" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref27_xou" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-130 to B-270</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_a5774972e4091cd50ddda7c09d0098c5" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref28_47a" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-271 to B-417</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_a8551e76e742437630e6309d7db7689b" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref29_nkp" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-418 to B-558</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_c5e97d29a17234ea30c0df678b9653ee" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref30_icn" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-559 to B-712</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_c8ceb3311b6a7cefc875dfccd3ca5b21" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref31_rb5" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-713 to B-849</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_fd2f759e217198c14e14f461c67c08ce" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref32_jsi" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-850 to B-1009</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_cc706babd6ff20e8178dbf1385bfcc9e" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_y7p" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>SUBSERIES TWO: Job Tickets</unittitle>
               </did>
               <arrangement id="aspace_92413203c6291fa0710268204b5b1f3e">
                  <head>Arrangement note</head>
                  <p>In Order by Topic</p>
               </arrangement>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref36_tks" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Apparel</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_7fb9c037efa30777a620b1ed6681cdcf" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_2c9c61d759ce4da96bef2fc57c86a8bf">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>This category includes advertisements for clothing brands, boots, and
                        watches. Clothing mainly includes overalls, union suits, swim suits, and
                        hosiery with brand names such as Munsingwear and Admiration Costume
                        Hosiery.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref38_qh5" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Retail</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_9a037be6091ed789197ecba768b1185b" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_febb901b7cc11b04159d77dfc43e447a">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>This category includes one advertisement for Efird's Department Store in
                        Charlotte, NC, and one for the "future home of" Stewart's York Road Store
                        and shopping center.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref40_jkj" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Media</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_46466d54e8e11c76e7a2c66a078be5f5" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_19671b1a71131c6436cfb1c2d8be8420">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>This category holds advertisements for outdoor advertising.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref42_d42" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Amusement and Entertainment</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_d05302889bea94405f6fc16bf00ca955" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_f0bee719d4c2d76c721f3669ede15684">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>This category includes advertisements for live arts productions and
                        amusements including a Porgy and Bess benefit, a Lawrence Welk production,
                        and an amusement park.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref44_9t4" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Public Service</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_f7e19f895901f6a4f47d25ac1a5f0ab1" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_0e34a424016becf06b7769a988fd3a2c">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>This category includes advertising created for charitable causes such as
                        Christmas Seals or by non-profit organizations. Government organizations are
                        listed under Business and Technology, but government sponsorship of an
                        advertisement was often difficult to discern. Check this category and
                        Business and Technology for a comprehensive search of government-sponsored
                        or government-related advertisements. Political issue advertisements may be
                        found here and include presumably World War II era cartoons of the "Axis
                        Ape." Some Public Service-type advertisements were placed under the
                        sponsor's usual category, if the sponsor's name was an obvious part of the
                        advertisement. For instance an advertisement saying "Buy War Bonds...
                        courtesy of Coca-Cola Products" may have been placed under Beverages. At
                        least one advertisement in this category is signed by Norman Rockwell.
                        Themes include Christmas as well as World War I and World War II troop
                        support. Organizations represented include the Cincinnati War Chest, Red
                        Cross, a state fair, and churches.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref46_xg8" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Business and Technology</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_117cf077ff9e0cf1cf0db704078e4918" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_1ac94d7247a6c541dee2e61706a0b544">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>This category includes advertisements for the following: the armed forces
                        (such as recruitment posters), including one for a London battalion,
                        building products, business to business services, government organizations,
                        and life insurance (Lincoln National Life). Upsom Boards is one product
                        featured as well as an industrial exposition and heating and air.
                        Government-sponsored advertisements can be found in this category but if
                        sponsorship was unclear, advertisements may have been put into the Public
                        Service category.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref48_uq1" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Beverages</unittitle>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_52f80d58f49bc18428ad0b3d2057ad1c">
                        <extent>2 folders</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_b255c9a1feaeaace18b9eeb88051669c" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_c87a71fd5691ebda9048469b277265f7">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>This category includes advertisements for alcoholic beverages, especially
                        beer and whiskey, and non-alcoholic beverages, especially coffee, tea, and
                        some sodas. Evaporated milk is most often found in the Food category. For a
                        comprehensive search of all beverages, also check the Food category.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref51_tkg" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Automotive</unittitle>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_7fea83b3bfa669801a0e554081cd2a8a">
                        <extent>2 folders</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_c210c2d02f4a15ccf8b2dee13339f0d2" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_b9fa6a6ff9b1043382240f420c4d5bb9">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>This category includes advertisements for automotive parts, service, and
                        manufacturers; motor oil; and tires. Gasoline and gas stations were placed
                        under Travel and Transportation (T and T). Advertisements showing motor oil
                        and gasoline (and/or car service) were put in the category of the more
                        prominent item. A search for all gas stations should be completed in both
                        this category and T and T. Autos frequently mentioned include Packard, Nash,
                        Ford, Lincoln-Zephyr, Dodge, Chevrolet, and Oldsmobile. Other brands
                        mentioned frequently within this category include Oilzum, Union Oil, Gulf,
                        Esso, Conoco, Dunlop, and Tuxedo tires.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref54_k78" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Travel and Transportation</unittitle>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_7475bb22f6ae94943363744158e508fe">
                        <extent>2 folders</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_61078790d7787e59a12bc2712add1fc5" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_d3c1d5c467ff11051650bd069a3d3afe">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>This category includes advertisements for airlines, gasoline, and gasoline
                        stations. Since gas stations, but not car service, are included in this
                        category, search both this and the Automotive category for an advertisement
                        featuring a company that sold gas and provided auto service. The two most
                        common brands are Esso and Gulf. Atlantic and Richfield were among others.
                        The only airline advertisements are for American Airlines.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref57_ogd" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Food</unittitle>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_f274d704881db75e47c3eaaa5188e20a">
                        <extent>2 folders</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_66d85149bfc5e420b7198555ba82a9c0" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_4fb235fa1b0232f678808f4e70b8ed3e">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>This category includes advertisements for candy, food, ingredients, prepared
                        foods, and produce. Gum, pet food, and tobacco products were most often
                        placed in Consumer Goods and Services. Drinks, including coffee and milk,
                        can usually be found in the Beverages category. The largest subgroup within
                        this category is baked goods including ads for matzos. Brand names include
                        Merita, Tastykake, Hostess, Baur's Aunt Hannah's Bread, and American-Maid
                        Bread. Other kitchen products represented include Fleischmann's Yeast, Davis
                        and Rumford Baking Powders, Snowdrift, Pillsbury Flours, Nucoa and Jelke
                        Margarines, and Purity and Best Foods Mayonnaises. Other food items in the
                        collection include Kellogg's Cereals, Powerhouse and Milky Way Candy Bars,
                        Eline's Sweet Milk Chocolate, Reymers' candies, and assorted fruits and meat
                        products. There are also some dairy products including evaporated milk
                        (Pet), and Tech Ice Cream.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref60_jmy" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Consumer Goods and Services</unittitle>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_5c5470dda80ea9660d5fecd8c1db6ced">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>This category includes advertisements for the following: appliances,
                        electronics, gum, health and beauty products, household products,
                        over-the-counter medicines, pet food and supplies, sporting goods, tobacco
                        products, toys, and vitamins. Tobacco is the largest sub-group by far,
                        dominated by Camel Cigarettes. Prince Albert and Lucky Strike are also
                        common brands. The second-largest group is comprised of soap advertisements.
                        Various types of soaps are represented including Palmolive, White King,
                        Crystal White, Sapolio, and Peet's. Other toiletry items include Listerine
                        Antiseptic, Palmolive Shaving Cream, and Dr. Lyon's Tooth Powder. Gums
                        mentioned include Clark's Teaberry and Adam's Black Jack. Other products
                        include home fuels like Berwind Briquets, Parker Pens, Grunow Radios,
                        Frigidaire, Graybar, and Crosley appliances, animal feeds, insect
                        repellents, and other items. Search for watches in the Apparel category.
                        Cars, motor oil, and car-related products can be found mostly in the
                        Automotive category. Gasoline can be found in the Travel and Transportation
                        category.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref61_ffh" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Consumer Goods and Services-Tobacco</unittitle>
                        <physdesc id="aspace_b3f508ed99b91f752d1ab6d7112e24c8">
                           <extent>2 folders</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <container id="aspace_6fbe069d7078e44bc48d739d07fa69e7"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref63_m19" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Consumer Goods and Services-Tobacco</unittitle>
                        <physdesc id="aspace_52df8c87d5a674d7c62bdbb2bf9ccd34">
                           <extent>2 folders</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <container id="aspace_c2cdac816903aad2e59dae2350eedda9"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref65_y07" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Consumer Goods and Services-Soaps</unittitle>
                        <physdesc id="aspace_b6f9fc65175c821845c976b07fd30485">
                           <extent>2 folders</extent>
                        </physdesc>
                        <container id="aspace_1ddb2d72896cbbdc328a91614dadc955"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref67_e99" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Consumer Goods and Services-Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_2ca9b1da1ceb9813709b0d4b425bdd25"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref69_m9y" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_6acecec2ca70f3ff963021c217bc20dd" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">4</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_aee2ee65e193bc46ba5e7a2783309681">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>This category includes advertisements which did not easily fit into one of
                        the other categories, or ads in which the product was unclear. One image
                        shows a Strobridge exhibit of many small advertisements.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref73_ta6" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>SUBSERIES THREE: Card File</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_586994541498ca4f9a7e9a59fab1f200">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Cards are in order primarily by advertisement brand name with occasional
                     headings for product types such as "public service" and "used cars." This file
                     is incomplete. Use the card file in conjunction with the job tickets (ordered
                     by topic) for a comprehensive search.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref74_shl" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A to Parker</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_22a0a80bdfaf23868e8d5c55ba982644" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref75_v11" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Peets to Zest</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_f63abc9f51e29b3960a1bcf2fa10d4d9" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">6</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref78_zch" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Image Files</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_b31d7252ca58fc1b1be36f8c23458c27">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>This series contains original photographs and printed cards of all the
                  collection's images.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref79_ko6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"A" Images (8x10 Photographs)</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_59874e1be9f1eb675867f87e5e5d4701">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Most advertisements are poster (billboard-type) designs shown against white
                     backgrounds. Approximate dates can be found on the backs of most photos. These
                     dates are unconfirmed.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref80_3hc" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-1 to A-130</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_9e1196b88cbd83d2884360e8db970ccd" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">7</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref81_8yu" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-131 to A-259</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_6107f57a013fd3075f72fb6a38b10c84" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">8</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref82_ui6" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-260 to A-374</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_7ab6ee5c96b749edfc3f10b1bf006b50" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">9</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref83_wh3" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-375 to A-488</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_e28dee5f56661adf3c8924e9a00e45ca" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">10</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref84_x5c" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-489 to A-626</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_a5b7fbd96c95f38934d32ab7ba8bd0da" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">11</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref85_392" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-627 to A-735</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_bb3a908de19632c1ab123ee6bb3dbcec" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">12</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref86_0fu" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-736 to A-856</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_be0d27a3c573c6286982bcd5d762126d" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">13</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref87_57n" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-857 to A-967</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_caa27e32dd01491fb610a014f4b5ba4d" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">14</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref88_kc8" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>A-968 to A-1099</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_48cbee9154dd4475f4e578589a0a4f3d" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">15</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref90_t71" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"B" Images (Printed Cards, approximately 5x8)</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref91_2vo" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-1 to B-47</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_b28894a5722bb7a69cffc42b46b20a61" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">16</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref92_dkl" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-49 to B-91</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_5b91bbc1966efdb5580b91c173a3b575" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">16</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref93_6w7" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-92 to B-136</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_d837cc79853175124380a12c52d33a01" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">16</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref94_iim" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-137 to B-194</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_bb304882be2f9ff601a86f6509484952" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">16</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref95_jxz" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-195 to B-243</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_0fa6c4fc37e41f11dd4a9ce26e163f79" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">16</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref96_cnd" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-244 to B-291</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_91e211fa038939da1b2406d7aa3c7bff" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">16</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref97_ly2" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-293 to B-338</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_f7faccd11380a926a8cc27ba51e9537f" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">16</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref98_4lm" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-339 to B-392</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_f1e624a169feb9ab6b6f5ed8da876100" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">16</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref99_ldq" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-393 to B-441</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_573d5e5eb5bd891458aead948ebe2c9e" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">17</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref100_nz9" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-442 to B-497</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_4897a984757911cce1d039b8042f9c5b" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">17</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref101_z3o" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-498 to B-549</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_8451ca667e30e6d3bbbb65cb89ef4b79" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">17</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref102_vpn" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-550 to B-609</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_a80103c50243fbbe9fec007996e092c2" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">17</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref103_ad5" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-610 to B-662</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_8466b982ab071cba9763ff58a402ce21" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">17</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref104_8ie" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-663 to B-713</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_3d3b4860d9cebf1d4d295cbe107fba9b" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">17</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref105_vzj" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-714 to B-768</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_b632470823a36e197c19d5a269b27caa" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">17</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref106_jhq" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-769 to B-827</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_d48199822af168541e64b47989da2438" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">18</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref107_h3b" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-829 to B-887</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_b418e9a10376dff6203e0b2d0b784688" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">18</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref108_noj" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-888 to B-935</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_6d8e4111e564066828ac0acf6bc43b16" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">18</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref109_syh" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-936 to B-986</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_dacd9af6e0d5f2e8a21edaeb1c4cb649" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">18</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref110_4bz" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>B-987 to B-1014</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_45e3072e77347bfc42fecad368a52ed0" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">18</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
