<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/taveauaugustin/"
         >taveauaugustin</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Augustin Louis Taveau Papers, 1741-1931 <num>RL.10090</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Bob Malme</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000875799</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 17:31:21
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Augustin Louis Taveau papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Taveau, Augustin L. (Augustin Louis), 1828-1886</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.10090</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Linear Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">6 boxes, 1,862 items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1741/1931" type="inclusive">1741-1931</unitdate>
         <unitdate normal="1830/1836" type="bulk">bulk</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_b1700ed5e7669402027c77af0acf41ac">This collection contains family,
            personal, literary, and business correspondence and other papers (chiefly 1830-1886) of
            Taveau, of his father, Louis Augustin Thomas Taveau, and of their family. The collection
            centers around Augustin Louis Taveau and relates to his education, activities as a poet,
            European travels (1852-1854), career in the Confederate Army, postwar condemnation of
            Confederate leaders, removal to Maryland (1866), and agricultural efforts. Other
            subjects include family and legal matters, social life and customs in South Carolina,
            the education of Southern girls, rice planting before the Civil War, planting in
            Mississippi and Louisiana (1850s), agriculture and scientific farming in Maryland,
            Charleston during the Civil War, postwar politics, and other matters. Correspondents and
            persons mentioned in this collection include William Aiken, Josias Allston, Henry L.
            Benbow, A. R. Chisholm, Ralph Elliott, Nathan George Evans, J. A. Gadsden, Horace
            Greeley, William Gregg, Thomas S. Grimké, Robert Y. Hayne, O. W. Holmes, W. H. Huger,
            Robert Hume, T. J. Hyland-MacGrath, Andrew Johnson, Carolina Olivia Ball Laurens, Eliza
            G. Maybank, James L. Petigru, J. J. Pettigrew, William Gilmore Simms, Clifford Simons,
            Keating L. Simons, Admiral Joseph Smith, Horatio Sprague, John R. Thompson, and members
            of the Girardeau, Swinton, and Taveau families.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_e9326989fc3629a0708b0940cc1ece61">Materials are in both French and
            English.</langmaterial>
         <physloc id="aspace_b08ae6b1c49d17a3df9cd786f713826e">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_f2310b0e62ad5696815576d6bfe42468">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <bioghist id="aspace_c285bb84fde39bc0c526798afbd2c1e9">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Augustin Louis Taveau (1828-1886), was a planter and author born and raised in South
            Carolina. He was the son of Louis Augustin Thomas Taveau (1790-ca. 1857), planter; and
            his wife, Martha Caroline (Swinton) Ball Taveau (d. 1847). He attended school at Mt.
            Zion Academy, Winnsboro, South Carolina starting in 1838. From 1848 until 1854 Taveau
            lived usually in or near Charleston studying law while also developing an interest in
            poetry. During this time he took a two year trip to Europe largely financed through his
            father's estate. In 1855 Taveau had a book of his poems, "The Magic Word and Other
            Poems" (Boston, 1855), published under the pseudonym of Alton. </p>
         <p>Late in 1861 Taveau settled on a farm near Abbeville, South Carolina, but soon
            afterwards joined the Confederate Army. His career in the army continued until 1865.
            Immediately after the war, papers containing letters and copies of letters were
            published in the New York Tribune by Taveau under the title of A Voice from South
            Carolina. In the letters he stated that former Southern leaders could not be trusted and
            condemning them for having allowed conscription. After searching for a place to live
            after leaving the army, Taveau and his family finally settled in 1866 on a farm near
            Chaptico in St. Mary's County, Maryland. From 1866 until his death he continued to write
            poems and other literary works, worked to get patents for several inventions and oversaw
            work on his farm. </p>
      </bioghist>
      <odd id="aspace_ad2ddf15afa72785c64002bc415ae829">
         <head>Description Note</head>
         <p>For a more complete description of this collection see Davis and Miller, Guide to the
            Cataloged Collections in the Manuscript Department of the William R. Perkins Library,
            Duke University (1980).</p>
      </odd>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_390e7201f66fe2ee858c782aa123afd9">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Augustin L. Taveau papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library between 1934 and 1936.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_653d8535926f70617b74ae7e4f6dd834">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>This collection contains family, personal, literary, and business correspondence of
            Louis Augustin Thomas Taveau (1790-ca. 1857), planter; of his wife, Martha Caroline
            (Swinton) Ball Taveau (d. 1847); of their son, Augustin Louis Taveau (1828-1886),
            planter and author; of the latter's wife, Delphine (Sprague) Taveau (1832-ca. 1909); and
            of relatives and friends. </p>
         <p>Papers prior to 1829 consist of a copy of the will of William Swinton made in 1741 and
            letters between the Swinton and Girardeau families recording Charleston events, the
            marriage settlement of Martha Caroline (Swinton) Ball and Louis Augustin Thomas Taveau,
            and a copy of the will of Caroline Olivia (Ball) Laurens, daughter of Martha Caroline
            (Swinton) Ball Taveau by her first marriage. Beginning in June 1829, and continuing for
            more than a year, the collection contains letters to Martha Caroline (Swinton) Ball
            Taveau from her husband, Louis Augustin Thomas Taveau, while he was in France
            endeavoring to settle his father's estate. </p>
         <p>In 1838 the papers begin to center around Augustin Louis Taveau (1828-1886), while in
            school at Mt. Zion Academy, Winnsboro, South Carolina and while later studying law and
            dabbling in poetry while living in or near Charleston, South Carolina and touring Europe
            from 1852 to 1854. From 1855 until 1860, the papers contain correspondence with the
            publisher of Taveau's book of poems, The Magic Word and Other Poems (Boston, 1855),
            published under the pseudonym of 'Alton,' correspondence with the Sprague family in an
            effort to obtain the remainder of Delphine (Sprague) Taveau's patrimony, papers relative
            to a mortgage on Oaks Plantation held by Robert Hume, letters relative to the failure of
            Simons Brothers in Charleston in 1857 and the consequent loss of Oaks Plantation,
            letters of Taveau describing a trip to New Orleans (Louisiana), with his slaves and
            their sale, letters of Taveau to his wife describing various plantations in Mississippi
            and Louisiana, and a series of letters in 1860 to and from Taveau, Ralph Elliott, and
            Clifford Simons regarding a supposedly slighting remark involving Taveau's credit. </p>
         <p>Late in 1861 Taveau settled on a farm near Abbeville, South Carolina, but soon
            afterwards joined the Confederate Army. His career in the army continued until 1865.
            Letters to his wife during the war period, include Taveau's accounts of his efforts as a
            soldier, descriptions of Charleston during the war, copy of a letter evidently intended
            for a newspaper, protesting that gentlemen of birth and education could get no
            commissions in the army while sons of tinkers could; accounts of his duties as guard at
            the "SubTreasury" in Charleston; papers relating to an effort to permit Delphine
            (Sprague) Taveau and her three children to sail for Europe in December, 1864; and oaths
            of allegiance and passports issued to Taveau and his wife and children, March 3, 1865,
            for going to Boston, Massachusetts. </p>
         <p>Immediately after the war, the papers contain letters and copies of letters published in
            the New York Tribune by Taveau under the title of A Voice from South Carolina, stating
            that former Southern leaders could not be trusted and condemning them for having allowed
            conscription. Included also are drafts of letters from Taveau to Horace Greeley and
            William Aiken; letters relative to Taveau's efforts to get the position of collector of
            the customs at Charleston; accounts of an interview of Taveau with Greeley and with
            President Andrew Johnson; letter of June 25, 1865, describing conditions in Charleston
            and Columbia, South Carolina; a copy of a petition signed by Henry L. Benbow, A. R.
            Chisholm, William Gregg, and Taveau begging President Johnson to appoint a provisional
            governor for South Carolina; several letters to and from William Aiken; and letters
            written by Taveau to his wife in the autumn of 1865 from various points in Virginia
            including areas near Richmond, Alexandria, and Warrenton, where he had gone in search of
            a farm. </p>
         <p>Taveau and his family finally settled in 1866 on a farm near Chaptico in St. Mary's
            County, Maryland. From 1866 until 1881, the correspondence is concerned with efforts to
            obtain patents and money for developing a revolving harrow and a steam plow invented by
            Taveau; efforts to obtain money for meeting the annual interest on the sum owed for the
            farm near Chaptico; and accounts of Taveau's literary activities. There are letters and
            papers bearing on Taveau's efforts to interest the Ames Plow Company, as well as
            manufacturers of farm machinery in Dayton, Ohio, in his inventions and drawings and
            circulars relative to the inventions. From 1878 until Taveau's death, his papers contain
            manuscripts of his poems and correspondence with many leading publishing houses
            regarding the publication of Montezuma (published in New York in 1883 and again in
            1931). Thereafter much of his correspondence consists of letters of thanks from various
            relatives, friends, and well-known literary figures for copies of Montezuma sent them by
            Taveau; and letters to newspapers and magazines submitting his poems and usually
            followed by letters of rejection. </p>
         <p>Throughout the collection there are many letters from the mother and sisters of Delphine
            (Sprague) Taveau, usually in French. Letters of her brothers, however, were generally in
            English. Among the correspondents are William Aiken, Oliver Wendell Holmes, James
            Johnston Pettigrew, William Gilmore Simms, Joseph Smith, and John R. Thompson. Also
            included are some Unpublished Letters of John R. Thompson and Augustin Louis Taveau,
            William and Mary College Quarterly, XVI (April 1936), 206-221; Letters of Georgia
            Editors and a Correspondent, Georgia Historical Quarterly, XXIII (June, 1939),
            [170-176.]</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <processinfo id="aspace_809c9c9a00ff92eea5bac36026f772cc">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library staff.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <userestrict id="aspace_8315f2b8754b05c9d7ec6482ce9d4bc1">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_fa49efb4c52c64dd7f675113fbc94579">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], in the Augustin Louis Taveau Papers Collection, David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Agriculture -- Maryland</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Europe -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Education -- Southern States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877) -- South Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Poets, American -- Southern States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Plantations -- Southern States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Authors -- Political and social views</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">American literature -- South Carolina</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Southern States -- Intellectual life</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Southern States -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">South Carolina -- Social life and customs</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Charleston (S.C.) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
         <persname source="ingest">Taveau, Augustin L. (Augustin Louis), 1828-1886</persname>
         <famname rules="dacs" source="ingest">Taveau family</famname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref21_wpu" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Augustin Louis Taveau papers</unittitle>
               <unitdate normal="1741/1931" type="inclusive">1741-1931</unitdate>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref10_w1a" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>History and family genealogy</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_3b158056b088227780a058e5f5d924a9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref11_a5m" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1741-1849</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_dd16ff880b58c0270dced408e7cc575e">8 folders</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_d440be566de77bded24b13bf80f447ab" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref12_vbx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1850-1856</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_93ae6677a3cf3278b8716a0d9f866237">7 folders</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_461a7be2ddd54c0d8a41dd5710fc5490" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref13_xji" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1857-1868</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_db10d51710be819b0bd70f2e50718f2d">11 folders</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_f175248c4e7d7b8e2472587d55b81ce3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_r74" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1869-1882</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_94019f6d4e3546fbfc8701736f0c773d">10 folders</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_7ae79e885c7f47f32a06a20816fc516a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_c1h" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letters</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1883-1931 and undated</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_1c8b6e49258125f33651da29af1b07ef">7 folders</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_0b8b1af4fad67d0d51efc0d3f65ca748" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_zmd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Clippings and documents</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_57afe62c72e238ab60d93f25f24c9ef2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_wgd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Poetry volumes</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_04a61c30b30ec463b428c5970f17eed3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_jyx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Works: poetry, agriculture, and genealogy</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_6e4118d879b1cc5715dd0f38f6505e0d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
