<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/thorpe/">thorpe</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Earl E. Thorpe Papers, 1942-1990 <num>RL.01294</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Alexander X. Byrd; machine-readable finding aid created by: Paula
               Jeannet Mangiafico, Stephen Douglas Miller</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">001530459</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 12:02:48
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Earl E. Thorpe papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Thorpe, Earl Endris, 1924-1989</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01294</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">1225 items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1942/1990" type="inclusive">1942-1990</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_b3fe20850388aa01377011e3530ce6f5">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_f8146eb6e0bc4ddd54d39c1cbb73efdb">Historian, professor, clergyman, and
            activist; resident of Durham, N.C. The papers of Earl E. Thorpe span the years
            1942-1990, the bulk of the materials having been generated during the years 1965 to
            1982. Primarily, materials in the collection address Thorpe's work at North Carolina
            Central University (formerly North Carolina College), and his tenure as visiting
            professor at Harvard and Duke universities. Topics include student activism, teaching,
            racial and departmental politics on campus, and the development of viable African
            American Studies programs. Thorpe's service as chair of the program committee for the
            1979 meeting of the Association for the Study of Afro-American Life and History (ASALH),
            and his term as president of the ASALH in 1980 are also well represented. Personal
            correspondence with family and students, and material reflective of Thorpe's life in the
            ministry are scattered throughout. Some materials also touch on North Carolina and
            Durham politics and race relations.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_cc6513c69ad7f29bf89e9faf77f791b1">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_8fc1111a4eccebf6e53094bea09a1305">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>However, collection may contain materials to which the Acknowledgment of Legal
            Responsibilities and Privacy Rights form applies. Patrons must sign this form before
            using this collection.</p>
         <p>Also, all or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's
            Library Service Center. Consequently, there may be a 24-hour delay in obtaining these
            materials.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_97f4836edfaad3b0f99ba3ef00f6ff00">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_a626aa057b0f2c243cd8603f97ff59ce">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Earl E. Thorpe papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_675f6993ffbda22140cf962d0bb10088">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Earl E. Thorpe papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a gift in 1982, 1985 and 1990.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_098e475d96d00f5da44af3294a2bfa3d">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Alexander X. Byrd, November 1993</p>
         <p>Encoded by Paula Jeannet Mangiafico, Stephen Douglas Miller, 1993 and 2011</p>
         <p>Accession(s) described in this finding aid: 3-18-82, 3-22-82, 7-6-82, 9-25-85, and
            90-100</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_3035a78c7b174bbf340befc5bd932b20">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <chronlist>
            <head>Chronology</head>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1924, Nov. 9</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Born, Durham, NC</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1942</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Graduated from Hillside High School, Durham, NC</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1943-1946</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Served in U.S. Army</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1946</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Married Martha Vivian Branch</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1948</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Received B.A. degree from North Carolina College (now North Carolina
                     Central University)</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1949</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Received M.A. degree from North Carolina College</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1951-1953</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Held various teaching positions in St. Louis, MO; Normal, AL; and Baton
                     Rouge, LA</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1953</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Received Ph.D. in history from Ohio State University</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1962</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Joined history department at North Carolina College</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1966</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Appointed chairman of the History Department at North Carolina College,
                     previously served as acting chairman</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1972</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Visiting professor of Afro-American studies at Harvard University</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1976 </date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Ordained as minister</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1978</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Chaired the program committee for the 1979 meeting of the Association for
                     the Study of Afro-American Life and History (ASALH)</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1980</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>President, ASALH</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1989, Jan. 20</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Died, Durham, NC</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
         </chronlist>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_b91dfac77bae6acf8bc2c44b0529fd55">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The papers of Earl E. Thorpe - historian, clergyman, and activist - span the years 1942
            to 1990, the bulk of the materials having been generated during the years 1965-1982. The
            collection consists of six series: <emph render="bold">Correspondence, Writings and
               Speeches, Pictures, Printed Material, Clippings</emph>, and <emph render="bold"
               >Genealogical Papers</emph>. Primarily, materials in the collection address Thorpe's
            work at North Carolina Central University (formerly North Carolina College), and his
            tenure as visiting professor at Harvard and Duke universities. Thorpe's service as chair
            of the program committee for the 1979 meeting of the Association for the Study of
            Afro-American Life and History (ASALH), and his term as president of the ASALH in 1980
            are also well represented. Personal correspondence with family and students, and
            material reflective of Thorpe's life in the ministry are scattered throughout.</p>
         <p>The bulk of the collection consists of the personal and professional correspondence of
            Thorpe. To 1970, material in the <emph render="bold">Correspondence Series</emph>
            centers on departmental politics at North Carolina College - specifically confusion and
            dissension over Thorpe's promotion to the chair of the history department. Letters from
            Thorpe's daughter at Spellman College in Atlanta, missives from friends and former
            students, a World War II era note from Thorpe to Martha V. Branch - Thorpe's future wife
            - and a small amount of professional correspondence are also represented.</p>
         <p>Beginning in 1971, correspondence turns to Thorpe's appointment as a visiting professor
            of Afro-American Studies at Harvard University. The letters reveal the substance of
            Thorpe's classes, and the intellectual environment at Harvard - especially as it
            concerns the Afro-American studies department. The challenges fading the organization
            and the development of a viable Afro-American Studies program emerge in correspondence
            between Thorpe and Ewart Gunier - chair of the Harvard black studies program - letters
            copied to Thorpe from others, and internal memoranda from Harvard's Afro-American
            Studies program.</p>
         <p>From 1972 through 1978, correspondence focuses again on Thorpe's duties at North
            Carolina Central University: tenure proceedings, student activism, class organization,
            personnel searches, and race politics on campus. Of particular interest are letters
            concerning the appointment of a white instructor to teach NCCU's Afro-American history
            survey, and the organization of the Helen G. Edmonds history colloquium. Matters
            unrelated to the history department or the workings of the campus are touched upon -
            planning for family reunions, and correspondence concerning Thorpe's health, for
            example.</p>
         <p>Beginning in 1978, correspondence turns to Thorpe's duties as chair of the program
            committee for the 1979 meeting of the Association for the Study of Afro-American Life
            and History (ASALH). In some detail, the letters recount the organization of the ASALH
            conference program - especially the politics and compromise involved in such a labor.
            Principal correspondents are ASALH officials, but included are notes from prominent
            African American historians. Panel and papers abstracts submitted for the committee's
            consideration are filed in the <emph render="bold">Writings and Speeches Series</emph>.
            A number of letters and abstracts represent efforts by the Association of Black Women
            Historians to organize panels at the meeting.</p>
         <p>In 1980, correspondence shifts to matters concerning Professor Thorpe's tenure as
            president of the ASALH. The organization of the 1981 conference in New Orleans is
            prominent. Correspondence pondering the future of the ASALH in light of recent
            mismanagement is also present. Of material not related to ASALH in this period,
            correspondence between Thorpe and Lerone Bennet, Jr. is especially interesting. In 1981,
            Thorpe charged Bennet with plagiarizing Thorpe's work in preparing a piece for <title
               type="simple" render="italic">Ebony</title> magazine. As if preparing for a trial,
            Professor Thorpe went so far as to collect evidence and build a case. The matter,
            however, was never fully resolved.</p>
         <p>Paul Zwillenberg has written a history honors thesis probing Professor Thorpe's thoughts
            and writings. <title type="simple" render="doublequote">I Dream a World: An Intellectual
               Biography of Earl Endris Thorpe</title> may be examined in the reading room of the
            Rubenstein Library.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina -- Politics and government</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Durham (N.C.) -- Politics and government</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Durham (N.C.) -- Race relations</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Historians -- United States -- Correspondence</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges, Black -- North Carolina -- History --
            20th century</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American clergy -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American historians -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African American college teachers -- North Carolina --
            Durham</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- History -- Study and teaching</subject>
         <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Association for the Study of Afro-American Life and
            History</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Thorpe, Earl Endris, 1924-1989</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">North Carolina Central University -- History -- 20th
            century</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Harvard University -- History -- Sources</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref14_tf0" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Earl E. Thorpe papers, 1942-1990</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_1c53013a910536431f2e4e27790e183a">
                  <extent>3 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_umd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1944-1980, Sept.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1a0062108ea1b4c7c344341e53f8424f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_6ma" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1980, Oct.-1990</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f7e2bb7a7c8acddb7d5a7d5be595ebb3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_jzc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Writings and speeches, 1942-1989</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_cf7a51461024b472fc566a6e4b746ae8" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_72c78f9a19b39a6dcfdd741657c7eb9c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Contains a number of Thorpe's sermon notes, tape recordings of Thorpe
                     preaching, some of the professor's course syllabi and essays, including a
                     discourse on Alex Haley's <title type="simple" render="italic">Roots</title>
                     and abstracts sent to Thorpe in his position as chair of the 1979 ASALH program
                     committee.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_ygi" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed material, 1970-1989</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a9194c3186546d57aa84657fd0add0ef" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_31a6d88e39e2c58b9873990a5ff1d3f6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Contains programs and publications from the ASALH, as well as various
                     newsletters, announcements, and minutes representing Thorpe's myriad political
                     interests. Fugitive pieces from the Durham People's Alliance and the Edgemont
                     Community Center are also included.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_ufm" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photographs, bulk 1950s</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_151ee2cba1a0a44283e5db49023a2370" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e859626b33a490b82ab6e57279269fa9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Consists of photos from North Carolina College during the 1950s. Subjects
                     include John Wheeler, Alphonso Elder, Albert Turner, Benjamin Mays, Rayford
                     Logan, and others. Copies of photographs from Thorpe's personal collection are
                     also present.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_xsc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Clippings, 1940s-1980s</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_99f97f9204bdcfe822e71e4566b8c9af" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ab786abd604af158bcc07c56bc1179bd">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Contains pieces written by or on Thorpe, mostly in the local press. Included is
                     a letter Thorpe wrote to his high school newspaper while stationed in Italy
                     during World War II. The letter criticized Durham's black leaders for what
                     Thorpe sees as their less than principled stance on local race matters.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_ip0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Genealogical papers, 1946 and undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3c3f492577829f3ae61fd2254deb6f8e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_85dcb34d824f23996fc19b9a55fa42ec">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Along with official papers, such as Thorpe's Army discharge and various birth
                     certificates, the genealogical papers contain drafts of family histories
                     written by Thorpe.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_wip" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Oversize</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f63d8014adc9422fd0de855586f3cd47" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_148529c9769578ece3cbd220058a2ac5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Two issues of <title type="simple" render="italic">The African World</title>,
                     1975</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref30_4w8" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>1990 Addition, 1965-1983</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_f54057c9e251814d60d5acae6bfcdc07">
                  <extent>2 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_yws" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1965-1982</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_60070af7021b9b31089c6135d26b297a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref33_86b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Guess Road Citizens' Advisory Committee, 1974</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_7516f5938ebe2ef6d978ee768cfd074f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref34_s9g" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Panhellenic Council, 1974</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a35e79a1c6001044b533a6201a886a70" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_gze" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Clippings, 1973-1982</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f4ec6b26f36300daccf523efb56dd5d1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_02418704be4ce8be32548d2f477939b6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Clippings deal with various legal matters and race issues. One clipping
                     regarding Miriam Makeba, then-wife of Stokely Carmichael; <title type="simple"
                        render="doublequote">White Rule in Black Africa,</title>
                     <title type="simple" render="italic">Journal and Guide</title>, 1973; <title
                        type="simple" render="doublequote">Thorpe Connects Racism, Nuclear
                        War,</title>
                     <title type="simple" render="italic">The College of Wooster Voice</title>,
                     1982; and <title type="simple" render="doublequote">The Planter on the Couch:
                        Earl Thorpe and the Psychodynamics of Slavery</title> by John Blassingame,
                        <title type="simple" render="italic">Journal of Negro History</title>,
                     1975.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref37_aeo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous Papers</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0db709f9b112f69c7d0f4d091884817c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d730ba500682ff967880fa2b879b383a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Folder includes additional correspondence, 1982; <title type="simple"
                        render="doublequote">The Untold Story of the Durham Committee on the Affairs
                        of Black People,</title> 1981 by Thorpe; <title type="simple"
                        render="italic">State Supported Traditionally Negro Colleges in North
                        Carolina Special Report</title>, 1967 by the North Carolina Board of Higher
                     Education; and <title type="simple" render="italic">Department of History and
                        Social Science Self-Study Reports</title>, 1971-1974 from North Carolina
                     College.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
