<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/trent-simpsonjamesyoungletters/"
         >trent-simpsonjamesyoungletters</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the James Young Simpson Letters, 1868-1911, and undated.
                  <num>RL.10869</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Staff; finding aid derived from MARC record using
               DukeMARC2EAD-HOMproject.xsl</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">002169676</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 19:35:26
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>James Young Simpson letters</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Simpson, James Young, 1811-1870</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.10869</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">106 items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1868/1911" type="inclusive">1868-1911, and undated.</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_9582deaf9289e18b2ceafaf41d0ce2a1">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_39df1117b2eb2be56a194c3911aaaf49">92 ms. leaves of Simpson's notes on
            obstetrics, H.A. Kelly's description of contents of notes, 6 items printed material, 4
            ALS from Simpson, a holograph poem, a signed calling card, and ms notes on Simpson in
            Kelly's hand. In his letters, Simpson writes of acupressure, animal magnetism, smallpox,
            scarlet fever, classical education, the importance of physical exercise and electoral
            politics. Printed material relates to members of the Simpson family, including Alexander
            Russell Simpson and Margaret Stewart Barbour. In his notes, Simpson writes of diseases
            of the placenta and the fetus, of pregnancies, abortions and premature labor, and of the
            use of collyria in the treatment of eye diseases.3 ALS. Only named correspondent is a
            Mr. Hutchison. Letters reflect Simpson's wide range of interests. He urges measures to
            stamp out' smallpox and scarlet fever; refers correspondent to Mr. Farrar's lecture on
            classical education, presented at the Royal Institution; stresses the importance of
            physical exercise for the student, Miss Campbell of St. Margaret's College; and
            discusses the electoral prospects of a Liberal candidate, Mr. Pender.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_c3bb0da3efea455f298e7fe73675ffed">Materials in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_51723cba3916df03bd09278b59a343d2">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the Rubenstein to use this
            collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_a385af0c93236c7faaf0c86d3e8fb7a6">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_f62725b1a041c8f48610797cdda35abb">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>James Young Simpson Letters, 1868-1911, and undated., David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_cda217172c5226b1aae1e93150a92cad">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>Winifred A Myers, purchase, 1970</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_c5fa330c6a083d7856481e5a8bb0febc">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by: Rubenstein Staff</p>
         <p>Finding aid derived from MARC record using DukeMARC2EAD-HOMproject.xsl, December
            2014</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_6de4f91342bdf63bf2dca2af00b47fd3">
         <head>Historical Note</head>
         <p>Scottish obstetrician; introduced use of chloroform.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_048a4ac9707ec0bb80ccd27c6b245732">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>92 ms. leaves of Simpson's notes on obstetrics, H.A. Kelly's description of contents of
            notes, 6 items printed material, 4 ALS from Simpson, a holograph poem, a signed calling
            card, and ms notes on Simpson in Kelly's hand. In his letters, Simpson writes of
            acupressure, animal magnetism, smallpox, scarlet fever, classical education, the
            importance of physical exercise and electoral politics. Printed material relates to
            members of the Simpson family, including Alexander Russell Simpson and Margaret Stewart
            Barbour. In his notes, Simpson writes of diseases of the placenta and the fetus, of
            pregnancies, abortions and premature labor, and of the use of collyria in the treatment
            of eye diseases.</p>
         <p>3 ALS. Only named correspondent is a Mr. Hutchison. Letters reflect Simpson's wide range
            of interests. He urges measures to stamp out' smallpox and scarlet fever; refers
            correspondent to Mr. Farrar's lecture on classical education, presented at the Royal
            Institution; stresses the importance of physical exercise for the student, Miss Campbell
            of St. Margaret's College; and discusses the electoral prospects of a Liberal candidate,
            Mr. Pender.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <odd id="aspace_06d543bf522cc95acbfac395533e0cd0">
         <head>General note</head>
         <p>Forms part of the Trent Manuscripts Collection.</p>
      </odd>
      <controlaccess>
         <corpname source="ingest">History of Medicine Collections (Duke University)</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Simpson, James Young, 1811-1870</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
