<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD" url="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/m1gd7d"
      >trent-thompsonhenrypapers</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Sir Henry Thompson papers, 1851-1913 and undated
            <num>RL.10914</num></titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Staff; finding aid derived from MARC record using
          DukeMARC2EAD-HOMproject.xsl</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>2014</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">002169673</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-12-09 08:52:19
          -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2020</date>
        <item>Accession 2019-0171 (transfer from Wisconsin Historical Society) incorporated;
          collection guide significantly revised to include these letters and their
          description.</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Sir Henry Thompson papers</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname source="ingest">Thompson, Henry, Sir, 1820-1904</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.10914</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear Feet</extent>
        <physfacet>approximately 90 letters</physfacet>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1851/1913" type="inclusive">1851-1913 and
        undated</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_e827cfb7d34d830fc902f44395bb8060">Collection of letters to and from Sir
        Henry Thompson (1820-1904), an English surgeon and a founder of the Cremation Society of
        England. Most letters in this collection are largely polite and perfunctory notes between
        Thompson and peers; some correspondents include his wife, the pianist Kate Loder; Empress
        Frederick of Germany; King George V of England; and King Leopold II of Belgium. The
        collection documents Thompson's social status and activities between the 1850s and early
        1900s. It contains few details about his medical practice, aside from some materials
        advocating for the adoption of the practice of cremation. Some materials are addressed to
        members of his family, including son Herbert Thompson. Letters are numbered and itemized
        inventory is included with the materials.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_45bfdf250997ed24a79b0ea145bb2ded">Materials in English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_3993ca6ef5c6b0cc46bbf967cd5f39a1">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_a808aa1baa0bccf0dd7baa6dcf095217">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_71557867bda27586ec04eb09194ff05a">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Sir Henry Thompson papers, 1851-1913, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript
        Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_86a9c2afa8f19b4c857ac2f19543966a">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The initial Rubenstein collection consisted of two letters transferred through the Trent
        Manuscripts History of Medicine collection. (Their origins and acquisition history are
        unknown.) In 2019, the bulk of the collection was acquired through Accession 2019-0171, a
        transfer to Rubenstein Library by the Wisconsin Historical Society.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo id="aspace_5fce3c2390c0442be2001642110db494">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by: Rubenstein Staff. Finding aid derived from MARC record using
        DukeMARC2EAD-HOMproject.xsl, December 2014. Accession 2019-0171 incorporated by Meghan Lyon,
        Oct. 2020.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_fcbaf59f31c918ae64bef7f8a2a8a938">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>Originally from Suffolk, Henry Thompson was a white British surgeon and professor at the
        Royal College of Surgeons, specializing in the bladder and urinary tract. Thompson's
        surgical expertise and reputation led him to be appointed as surgeon-extraordinary to King
        Leopold I and II of Belgium; he also operated on Napoleon III shortly before his death.
        Thompson helped found the Cremation Society of England (now Great Britain) in 1874, and
        served as its first president. The society sought to legitimize the practice of cremation in
        Great Britain.</p>
      <p>Thompson's other interests included painting, astronomy, and collecting Chinese porcelain.
        He was knighted in 1867 and became a baron in 1899. </p>
      <p>Thompson married Kate Loder in 1851, and the couple had three children. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_d925bcaa4438cc4e826205a727f6d91b">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>Collection of letters to and from Sir Henry Thompson (1820-1904), a white English surgeon
        who was a founder of the Cremation Society of England. Most letters in this collection are
        largely polite and perfunctory notes between Thompson and peers; some correspondents include
        his wife, the pianist Kate Loder; King George of England; and King Leopold II. The
        collection documents Thompson's social status and activities between the 1850s and early
        1900s. It contains few details about his medical practice or personal life, but indicates
        many high-profile and celebrity acquaintances and contains some autographs (for example,
        Henry James). Letters are numbered and an itemized inventory is included with the materials.
        There is also a detailed correspondents' list, transcriptions of some of the more
        information-heavy letters, and an appraisal of the letters, conducted for the Wisconsin
        Medical Society Foundation in 2003.</p>
      <p>The original Trent Manuscripts Collection is foldered separately within the collection, and
        consists of the following items: ANS, a dinner invitation, and ALS, advocating the adoption
        of the practice of cremation. Items are accompanied by a bibliographic note describing
        Thompson's dinner parties.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <odd id="aspace_b170532e33a2f7db3998a82cdec19cc6">
      <head>General note</head>
      <p>Forms part of the Trent Manuscripts Collection.</p>
    </odd>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="mesh">Mortuary Practice</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Physicians -- Records and correspondence</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Surgeons -- England</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Etiquette</subject>
      <persname authfilenumber="nb2013006237" rules="dacs" source="naf">Loder, Kate,
        1825-1904</persname>
      <persname authfilenumber="n 79088906" rules="dacs" source="naf">Léopold II, King of the
        Belgians, 1835-1909</persname>
      <corpname authfilenumber="nb2006007411" rules="dacs" source="naf">Cremation Society of
        England</corpname>
      <persname authfilenumber=" 88639277" rules="dacs" source="naf">Thompson, Herbert, Sir,
        1859-1944</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_f47797d1f6dd7b3a290d58d695089bd0" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Assorted letters and correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1851/1913"
            type="inclusive">1851-1913</unitdate>
          <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" type="inclusive"
            >undated</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_99065659bfe404e23ebeade2eac95313" label="mixed materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_75c74721591a332b3a9b4f98311079a7">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Folders of materials arranged loosely chronologically, with some undated materials in
            later folders. Includes an 1851 letter to Kate Loder, called "Kit", which contains a
            doodled self-portrait by Thompson and describes his current illness. An undated letter
            from Henry James in the House of Commons seeks to secure a vote from MP W. H. Leatham,
            then suffering from gout and under Thompson's care. There are letters to Thompson from
            King George V (a thank you note, 1893), Empress Frederick of Germany (1891), and King
            Leopold II (1869, 1872, 1875, 1876, 1880). Some letters are directed to Henry's son Sir
            Herbert Thompson, including a condolence note from King George in 1904, following Henry
            Thompson's death. One letter from Thompson advocates the adoption of cremation.</p>
          <p>The majority of the letters are perfunctory and polite, without many details beyond
            dinner invitations and customary exchanges of courtesies between Thompson's
            acquaintances in the British aristocracy and elite society. Some materials are not
            correspondence - there are empty envelopes and some scrap notes.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_3341c302406bca9c09a8ace23f290c49" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Information folder with inventory of collection, appraisal, and other
            accompanying correspondence regarding the collection's transfer to the RL</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_fb2fa46c2f8ff90780dae229957a2d3d" label="mixed materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
