<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/trent-rushbenjamin/"
         >trent-rushbenjamin</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Benjamin Rush Letter, 1784, June 25, to John Bayard
                  <num>RL.10837</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Staff; finding aid derived from MARC record using
               DukeMARC2EAD-HOMproject.xsl</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">001662422</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 19:33:35
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Benjamin Rush letter, to John Bayard</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Rush, Benjamin, 1745-1813</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.10837</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1784/1784" type="inclusive">1784, June 25</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_8fff73ddb019e6ee7d14401333cbf632">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_5d7fb93b313268528c360fcc7a460bfc">A copy, in an unknown hand, of a
            letter from Rush to Bayard regarding sentiments expressed in an earlier letter to
            General John Armstrong. The letter reflects post-revolutionary state politics in
            Pennsylvania. In the letter, Rush censures his fellow Presbyterians, who refuse to
            revoke the test laws and to admit amendments to the state constitution. He also condemns
            the taking over by the Presbyterian dominated state government of the charter of the
            College of Philadelphia, now the University of Pennsylvania, and refers to the College
            of Carlisle, or Dickinson College, established in protest to the first action. He
            regrets the inflammatory remarks and publications made by members of the state's single
            legislative body, the Council of Censors, and by Joseph Reed and Mr. Smiley, and
            deplores the character of Henry Osborn and Owen Faris.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_53f94cb0b3db028cf95023b8b1e8937b">Materials in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_60140fd2497f49a760e7023459f634c0">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the Rubenstein to use this
            collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_c81242ed07e15dd6c1baa0e8aa141802">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_4ca2037a95e76c36c1b647ed26745716">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Benjamin Rush Letter, 1784, June 25, to John Bayard, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_aac309e14a8a7818069f126932fddff7">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>Hildegard Ryals, purchase, 1988</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_89b96bb6837509c8c3abf81bf104c365">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by: Rubenstein Staff</p>
         <p>Finding aid derived from MARC record using DukeMARC2EAD-HOMproject.xsl, December
            2014</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_741b33a3163a197dd29538c2ea2de70a">
         <head>Historical Note</head>
         <p>Physician of Philadelphia and American Revolutionary patriot.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_18c044a23d9768a9ecadf545d4b1549f">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>A copy, in an unknown hand, of a letter from Rush to Bayard regarding sentiments
            expressed in an earlier letter to General John Armstrong. The letter reflects
            post-revolutionary state politics in Pennsylvania. In the letter, Rush censures his
            fellow Presbyterians, who refuse to revoke the test laws and to admit amendments to the
            state constitution. He also condemns the taking over by the Presbyterian dominated state
            government of the charter of the College of Philadelphia, now the University of
            Pennsylvania, and refers to the College of Carlisle, or Dickinson College, established
            in protest to the first action. He regrets the inflammatory remarks and publications
            made by members of the state's single legislative body, the Council of Censors, and by
            Joseph Reed and Mr. Smiley, and deplores the character of Henry Osborn and Owen
            Faris.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <odd id="aspace_b7ca7c580cd8c2b68f4910224aff8cf0">
         <head>General note</head>
         <p>Forms part of the Trent Manuscripts Collection.</p>
      </odd>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Pennsylvania</geogname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Dickinson College</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Bayard, John Bubenheim, 1738-1807</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Rush, Benjamin, 1745-1813</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">History of Medicine Collections (Duke University)</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Armstrong, John, 1758-1843</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">University of Pennsylvania</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
