<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/vicarsgeorge/">vicarsgeorge</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Henry George Austin Vicars diaries, 1853-1865
          <num>RL.01332</num></titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Library staff; machine-readable finding aid created by:
          Paula Jeannet, Elizabeth Shesko; updated by Meghan Lyon</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>2014</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">002205150</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-02-28 11:08:27
          -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2014</date>
        <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported to
          Archivists Toolkit</item>
      </change>
      <change>
        <date>2019</date>
        <item>Collection guide enhanced with item-level description for diaires; name changed to
          reflect RDA standards (and update the name of the event to current language)</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Henry George Austin Vicars diaries</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="ingest">Vicars, Henry George Austin</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.01332</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1853/1865" type="inclusive">1853-1865</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_b1a67aa3929d383f844299265568457c">Henry George Austin Vicars was a
        British Army officer stationed in India in the 1850s and 1860s. He entered the army in
        October 1851, and was Adjutant of the 61st Regiment during the Sepoy Rebellion of 1857 and
        1858. In his diaries, dated 1853-1855, 1857-1860, and 1864-1865, he reports on the mutinies,
        the Delhi siege and massacres, executing mutineers, cholera epidemics and fevers, and daily
        life as a soldier. Entries discuss his daily routine, the weather, his amusements and
        engagements, his clothing, his friends and fellow officers, his travels with the army, news
        and rumors he has heard, sermons and other church services he attended, and his home leave
        in London. </abstract>
      <physdesc id="aspace_03f6165e64a480925344629b4d1b323c"><extent>16 Items</extent></physdesc>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_5dcf12e114a1e1c435fa7bd6d0de5a2a">Material in English </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_7bf985246937d63770bf9690e0ca7071">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_87d7451f42683e8cd5116bd2611a7bca">
      <head>Copyright Notice</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_a36832458fff4b1d823c3ab2fe68b9eb">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of volume, page, and date], Henry George Austin Vicars diaries, David M.
        Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_7b96539919608e52c3e5d7ceb6620a54">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Henry George Austin Vicars diaries were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1975. Purchase was supported through the Hamilton
        endowment.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo id="aspace_950ab583e040eda12cf2868b9beb55ca">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library staff, 1975. Finding aid completed by Meghan Lyon,
        2019.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_5b16e8bb4b396e9c7f3b56c62165ac6b">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>Collection consists of nine diaries kept by Vicars, largely during his service in India, as
        well as a small amount of loose pages originally tucked into the volumes. The diaries are
        dated 1853-1855, 1857-1860, and 1864-1865. Volumes are all Letts's Diary, including almanacs
        and other reference materials printed at the front of the book; they are in varied physical
        condition, ranging from fair to poor. They contain daily entries discussing Vicars's
        routines, including his daily schedule, military activities and movements, his amusements
        and leisure time, sermons he heard and news he read, correspondence and other communications
        he maintained, and his general thoughts and personal prayers. Entries discuss army life
        including parades, drills, firing and target practice, distribution and preparation of
        Enfield rifles and ammunition, and other changes in British uniforms and clothing during
        this period. Vicars also records his work as adjutant in attending different court marshals
        and punishments for army men due to theft, drunkenness, or more serious crimes. More routine
        topics discussed include the climate and weather; his current view and location at different
        forts and locales in India, Mauritius, Ceylon, at sea, and England; hobbies and pursuits he
        enjoyed such as horseback riding, shopping, reading, photography, and cricket; and different
        dinners and events he attended as an officer. </p>
      <p>Vicars's volumes for 1857 and 1858 contain detailed reports about his regiment's role in
        suppressing the Sepoy Rebellion. He records hearing initial news of the Delhi massacre in
        May 1857, and describes his march and movement toward Delhi and his participation in the
        battles of July 1857. Later entries describe attending the execution of mutineers, ongoing
        cholera epidemics and fevers plaguing British troops, and the fallout from ongoing conflict
        throughout India. The battles of 1857 had a lasting impact on Vicars; he refers to the
        anniversary of the Delhi siege and sorties in the 1864 volume.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <bioghist id="aspace_d165e74bfb97fabc12c9bb3c8b553c64">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Henry George Austin Vicars was a British Army officer in the 61st Regiment of the Foot, and
        later in the 18th Regiment (Royal Irish); he was stationed in India in the 1850s and 1860s.
        He entered the army in October 1851, and was Adjutant of the 61st Regiment during the Sepoy
        Rebellion of 1857 and 1858. He was present at the siege and attacks on Delhi in July 1857,
        and described them in his diary. He was awarded the British Army's Indian Mutiny Medal and
        clasp for his service during the rebellion. Vicars was promoted to brevet-major in Nov.
        1863, and appointed as aide-de-camp of John Lawrence, the Governor General of the East
        Indies. Vicars died in 1867.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Soldiers -- Great Britain -- Diaries</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Cholera -- India</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Delhi (India) -- History -- Siege, 1857 -- Personal narratives,
        British</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">India -- History -- Sepoy Rebellion, 1857-1858 -- Personal narratives,
        British</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Great Britain -- Foreign relations -- India</geogname>
      <genreform source="aat">Diaries</genreform>
      <subject source="lcsh">Executions and executioners -- India -- 19th century</subject>
      <corpname source="ingest">Great Britain. Army. Regiment of Foot, 18th (Royal Irish)</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Great Britain. Army -- Military life</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Great Britain. Army. Regiment of Foot, 61st</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_71ca4174914610e2b25ea00e61eccd57" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Information folder about the collection and Henry Vicars</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_feee0668e5c2b5fbfd737484c9269d92" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >2</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_b0cf75a85ea23eb0fbf868bdb65da82d" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Loose items removed from the diaries</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1850s-1860s</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_fa68ce4952996f8d5ce57eb80fac7bb9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >2</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_039539551696227092974895e2913a0d">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Includes a clipping about Vicars, a "sketch map of the probable track of the cyclone"
            from 1864 Oct. 4-6, and other stray manuscript pages and Letts's Diary appendices.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_d799896d613c31d8aa18bd5190e311b4" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Diary</unittitle>
          <unitdate>1853</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_c045da6f4f02515939d2fc38bb5097cc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >2</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_735fe27bb4e54ff7002f1b3690f854c9">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Letts's Diary with loose spine. Cloth cover is labeled "Private" by hand and
            autographed by Henry Vicars. Title page is autographed by Vicars with note "Kupowhi
            [Khopoli?] 1853." Pages for January through May have been re-copied onto a new set of
            paper (appears to be done by Vicars's hand) which was then sewed into the volume; the
            original diary's entries begin on the page for May 22.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_d3ef8adf46193949b08948e9910aeaa3" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Diary</unittitle>
          <unitdate>1854</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_b4a241fecbb19251adeab3d6eec70772" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_d3ee160789975dc8b544c9c45b12b859">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Letts's Diary for Vicars' "third year in India which I have enjoyed thank God excellent
            health and have been comparatively very happy" (Jan. 1 1854 entry). Vicars's location in
            India is "Wuzurabad" which appears to be Wazirabad, Delhi. He references accounts with
            Agra Bank. Vicars writes he is an ensign in the 61st Regiment. Entries for January
            11-February 15 have been tipped into the volume; Vicars writes on Feb. 17 that "I got
            this book today." Also includes a list of correspondence, accounts/debts, and other
            notes.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_746cc699f9e9539dce932dccdaa5587a" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Diary</unittitle>
          <unitdate>1855</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_62a1b65706ae85832810d42d1024fc60" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_468fe92acef725778a865fe5eb66bd51">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Letts's Diary with loose pages laid in for Vicars's fourth year in India. "Here I am at
            Wuzurabad in my little bungalow I am the world will say, prosperous - may I endeavor to
            be a servant of Xt [Christ] and [?] up for myself happiness for futurity by living a
            Xtian life..." (Jan. 1 1855 entry). Vicars's location in India is "Wuzurabad" which
            appears to be Wazirabad, Delhi. Vicars writes he is a lieutenant and adjutant for the
            61st Regiment. Loose entries for January 1-February 10 have been laid into the volume;
            the diary's printed pages for those dates are largely blank (it appears Vicars started
            copying his entries in, but then opted to just include the loose pages instead.) Also
            includes a list of correspondence, accounts/debts, and other notes.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_2af76a2dd8e4c75cbc6289cf5e84a8a9" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Diary</unittitle>
          <unitdate>1857</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_f348fb92b3a8236bc42393ff9928bd88" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_ca2687f954f5f69ed15e8e713bceeb45">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Letts's Diary with loose pages laid in for Vicars's sixth year in India. Vicars's
            initial location in India is "Ferazipore" (Firozpur). Vicars is Lietenant and Adjutant
            for the 61st Regiment. This volume contains Vicars' accounts of the growing mutinies
            across India. News of the May 10 Delhi massacre reached him on May 13. Entry reads:
            "astounding intelligence came that the Europeans at Delhi had all been murdered! and
            that troops at Lahore had mutinied. A council of war was held at once and it was
            resolved to remove all families to our Barracks..." (May 13, 1857). Later entries remark
            that "the news from the Puujab satisfactory but around Delhi the insurgents are
            committing outrages, robbing treasuries and little amusements of that kind" (May 31,
            1857). Vicars's entry on June 12-June 13 includes a drawing of the layout of the fort
            and scaffold for the execution of the 45th mutineers; the execution is described in the
            entry of June 13: "10 of them were fastened on to the muzzles of the guns which had been
            loaded with powder. They seemed quite cool and said they were martyrs, etc. etc. The
            guns were fired together and a shower of legs arms and heads etc was all that remained
            of the mutineers. The others were let off with transportation. It was a fearful sight."
            Entries of Sept. describe the siege, fighting, and British retaking of Delhi and his
            participation in the looting of the king's apartments ("I got a curious cane and a
            pistol", Sept. 20). The remainder of the diary contains more routine military
            activities. Also includes a list of correspondence, accounts/debts, and other notes.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_79546c26594f82566354041f540c9158" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Diary</unittitle>
          <unitdate>1858</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_c68ede0f408e27b5367ed929a1dc89ba" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_3b11eed56ce4dcaeb58ac3c5db701de3">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Letts's Diary with entries from Vicars's seventh year in India; he records he is
            Lieutenant and Adjutant for the 61st Regiment. Vicars's initial location for 1858 is
            Delhi. The pages are blank from Feb. 24 through June 2; June 2's entry reads "This Diary
            turned up only today the one sent before having been lost in transit. It is nearly 3
            months since I have left off my Diary I wonder if I shall take to it kindly again."
            Ongoing news and accounts of the rebellion and the aftermath of the seige of Delhi is
            reported in this diary, as well as routine activities by Vicars as adjutant.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_4c2a1922c6b2f5312728446231eea5cb" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Diary</unittitle>
          <unitdate>1859</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_e996d7c097257f11a90c43f49c048567" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_b4c152543c113efb7aa9597545c2e448">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Letts's Diary with entries from Vicars's eighth year in India; he records he is
            Lieutenant and Adjutant for the 61st Regiment. Vicars records his location for 1859 as
            Delhi. Includes a list of draft and correspondence packets sent and received by Vicars.
            The early pages of the year are blank; entries begin on Feb. 25 where Vicars writes they
            "march from Agra"; the movements of his unit being detailed for the next several weeks.
            Vicars describes a cholera outbreak in June and July 1859, and a sea voyage from Poona
            to Mauritius in July 1859: "there is a considerable degree of monotony in one's present
            life on board ship" (July 21). After reaching Mauritius, Vicars paused entries for
            August and offered a summary (dated Sept. 11 but written on pages for August 2-16) of
            his activities since arrival. His recap includes the various crimes, largely "habitual
            drunkenness," he prosecuted; he mentions "one man Ph Downy committed suicide by shooting
            himself through the head without any apparent reason." Vicars's regular entries resume
            Sept. 11 and revert to routine activities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_b279469c01219632bca405555559ae27" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Diary</unittitle>
          <unitdate>1860</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_9880c54082a2d3df7882347245b7a53a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_eb2b599e72f5ebd99c05bba75065a8aa">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Letts's Diary for 1860, with cloth boards and loose spine. Vicars records he is Lt. and
            Adjutant for the 61st Regiment, stationed at Mauritius. The diary includes description
            of his travel to London by ship from February to March 11, when "we were greeted with
            snow! It did not fall much but it was terribly cold all day. Sheet and rain. I landed in
            old (and cold) England as soon as possible" (Mar. 11). The remainder of the entries
            record Vicars's activities in England and Scotland. The volume is blank from Sept. 4
            through the end of the year.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ace3a9cbb249123ce80eda28c95585ba" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Diary</unittitle>
          <unitdate>1864</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_2e5e1d05a9bf802fad50768f1f76466e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >2</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_57a6be380dafbb2bb27d55b440988d8d">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Letts's Diary for 1864; missing cover boards and introductory printed pages. Vicars's
            first entry reads "At Sea 4 days W. of Galle [Sri Lanka]. Here I am beginning a diary
            again after 3 years cessation - I don't mean to keep it up though regularly. I am on my
            way to India with Sir John Lawrence as his ADC. We left ... London on 9th Dec. another
            fortnight D.V. will see us in Calcutta" (Jan. 1). This volume contains regular but
            sometimes brief entries for 1864. One entry records "The 7th anniversary of the Storm of
            Delhi. Col. Norman gave a dinner to all the Delhi men and we mustered our 30 and enjoyed
            ourselves and made a good noise" (Sept. 14). Vicars includes a list of names of men who
            attended the dinner.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_3a97fac4fc99f9e631f5703a6b58ed3f" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Diary</unittitle>
          <unitdate>1865</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_b79ba6459d81dd7fbe72aeab00e50d64" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >2</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_b33580224d37739c88222c63e71913dd">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Letts's Diary with cloth boards. Vicars writes that he is "B. Major and Capt. 1st
            Batl., 18th Royal Irish ADC to H. G. the Viceroy of India", based in Calcutta. Contains
            routine daily entries about military and personal activities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
