<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/webb/">webb</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Alexander Russell Webb Journals, 1892 <num>RL.01354</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;amp;
               Manuscript Library Staff; machine-readable finding aid created by: Stephen Douglas
               Miller</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000877868</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 12:44:52
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Alexander Russell Webb Journals</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Webb, Alexander Russell, 1846-1916</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01354</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.2 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1892/1892" type="inclusive">1892</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_ed88c0cb87d99d42cd6d2b1e3cd755f5">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <physdesc id="aspace_981890d11f4986fea4c8d9093376288b">
            <extent>3 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_55669b6e9ca9a3056a2dca87521ef0f5">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_6812cdce69ee1d84b174507702791635">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_a46dff6077778f9d689e53ebcf1a7ecd">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in the Alexander Russell Web Journals have not been transferred
            to Duke University. For more information consult the section on copyright in the
            Regulations and Procedures of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript
            Library.</p>
         <p>A Xerox copy of Journals 1 and 2, on acid-free paper, is filed with the collection.
            Further photocopying should be done from these copies, not from the original
            volumes.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_d9966d52795851b1da974ddab0e11629">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Alexander Russell Webb Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_ef3b2e747a14e5f8dd11add0e142751a">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Alexander Russell Webb Journals were purchased by Duke University in 1980.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_afe840055c95965858915d10cc48c358">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by: Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library
            Staff</p>
         <p>Completed October 8, 1981</p>
         <p>Encoded by Stephen Douglas Miller</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_ec5f833f173993fc40b2fadf1ca6331d">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Alexander Russell Webb (1846-1916) has the distinction of being the first known American
            convert to Islam and of being the first person to conduct a major effort to spread Islam
            within the United States. Born in Hudson, New York, he had a short journalistic career
            as editor of the St. Joseph <title type="simple" render="italic">Gazette</title> and
            Missouri <title type="simple" render="italic">Republican.</title> In 1887 he was
            appointed American consul at Manila. There he befriended several Indian Muslim
            businessmen and studied works about Islam. In 1888 he declared in a pamphlet his
            conversion to Islam. He resigned from the consular service in 1892 and returned to the
            U. S. by way of Singapore, Penang, Rangoon, a number of cities in India, and possibly
            other places. Back in America, Webb established an office in New York City as the
            Oriental Publishing Co. In May, 1893, he published the first issue of the <title
               type="simple" render="italic">Moslem World, Devoted to the Interests of the American
               Islamic Propaganda,</title> the earliest Islamic missionary periodical in America. In
            connection with his <emph render="doublequote">American Mission,</emph> as Webb called
            it, he wrote a number of books and pamphlets among which were several of his lectures in
            India that were published there during 1892-1893. Biographical information about Webb
            appears in: Nadim al Maqdissi, <title type="simple" render="doublequote">The Muslims of
               America, 80,000 Muslims and 12 Mosques in the United States and Canada,</title>
            <title type="simple" render="italic">Islamic Review,</title> Vol. 43, No. 6 (June,
            1955), pp. 28-29; Nelson R. Burr, <title type="simple" render="italic">Critical
               Bibliography of Religion in America</title> (Princeton, 1961), pp. 536-538; and V. S.
            Naipaul, <title type="simple" render="doublequote">An Islamic Journey, Among the
               Believers,</title>
            <title type="simple" render="italic">The Atlantic Monthly,</title> Vol. 248, No. 2
            (Aug., 1981), p. 63. Copies of the pertinent pages from these sources are filed in the
            Information Folder in this collection.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_a00f41bd76f56337783c1fe336ea505f">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The collection contains Webb's <title type="simple" render="doublequote">Journal No. 1,
               From Manila to Calcutta</title> (142 pp.), Aug. 29-Oct. 19, 1892, and his <title
               type="simple" render="doublequote">Journal No. 2, From Calcutta to Bombay and
               Agra</title> (144 pp.), Oct. 20-Dec. 15, 1892. This is the first journal that Webb
            ever wrote (Vol. 1, p. 1). His journal continued beyond Vol. 2; the last sentence was
            continued elsewhere, and no pages appear to be missing from this volume. A later volume
            or volumes contained the account of the rest of his journey which is incomplete
            here.</p>
         <p>Webb's descriptive style is good, and he did extensive touring wherever he went. Thus,
            his volumes are good travel journals. The most important feature of his account is his
            contact with Muslim scholars, re-ligious leaders, businessmen, rulers, ordi-nary people,
            etc. Beginning in Rangoon, he and his mission to spread Islam in America were
            enthusiastically received not only by individuals but literally by throngs of
            well-wishers. He was received by many influential Muslims, and his comments about some
            of them are quite interesting. Webb did not like the English or local people who catered
            to them, and this attitude, often expressed, colored his reactions to persons whom he
            met. Some of the significant Muslims whom he discussed have been identified by using S.
            M. Ikram's <title type="simple" render="italic">Modern Muslim India and the Birth of
               Pakistan</title> (Lahore, 1977). Spellings of names are given as Webb wrote them
            unless they are found written otherwise in Ikram's book or other reference sources.</p>
         <p>Webb's journals record the following travels in 1892: Vol. 1: Manila, Aug. 29-Sept. 6
            (pp. 1-10); ocean travel, Sept. 6-13 (9-23); Singapore, Sept. 14-21 (24-64); ocean
            travel, Sept. 21-28 (64-80) with a visit at Penang, Sept. 23-25 (66-74); Rangoon, Burma,
            Sept. 28-Oct. 9 (80-113); ocean travel, Oct. 9-12 (113-122); Calcutta Oct. 12-19
            (122-142); Vol. 2: Calcutta, Oct. 20-23 (pp. 1-11); Patna, Oct. 23-24 (11-15); Benares,
            Oct. 25-26 (15-19); Bombay, Oct. 28-Nov. 17 (21-54); Poona, Nov. 17-19 (56-62);
            Hyderabad, Nov. 20-Dec. 8 (65-120); Madras, Dec. 10-12 (127-140); and Agra, Dec. 15
            (143-144). Travel inside India was by train, of which Webb gave some interesting
            descriptions.</p>
         <p>The item is a printed program for a horse race given by the Sultan of Johore at
            Singapore on Sept. 15, 1892.</p>
         <p>A Xerox copy of Journals 1 and 2, on acid-free paper, is filed with the collection.
            Further photocopying should be done from these copies, not from the original
            volumes.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="italic">Description from the Manuscript Card Catalog located in the Duke
               University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</emph>
         </p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Singapore -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Diplomatic and consular service</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Pinang Island (Pinang) -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Rangoon -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Islam -- Missions -- India</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Missionaries -- India</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">India -- Description and travel</geogname>
         <persname source="ingest">Webb, Alexander Russell, 1846-1916</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref11_vk4" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Alexander Russell Webb Journals, 1892</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_b8f7153c59f0db837f13343e7f43b91b">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>The following description does not include references to every person, place, or
                  topic mentioned in Webb's journals, but sufficient detail is provided to indicate
                  the richness of their contents and to serve as a guide to them.</p>
               <p>The journal begins on Aug. 29, 1892, at Manila when Webb was concluding his
                  affairs at the consulate. His wife and children had left earlier for the U. S. He
                  remarked that he had never before kept a journal. The section for Manila is on
                  pages 1-10.</p>
               <p>On Sept. 6 Webb sailed for Singapore on a Spanish steamer, a trip that lasted
                  until Sept. 13 (pp. 9-23). He commented about the crew and about the bad
                  conditions on the ship.</p>
               <p>Webb's visit in Singapore lasted from Sept. 14 to 21 (pp. 24-64). He considered
                  Singapore one of the most beautiful of cities, and he provided a fine description
                  of many aspects of it. He commented about: the Raffles Hotel (25-26, 54-55); a
                  Chinese open-air theater (26-28); the Singapore Cricket Club (29); the Chinese
                  section of the city on various occasions; English snobbishness (31-33); carriages
                  and carriage drivers often; a horse race given by the Sultan of Johore (33-34);
                  Sir Charles Warren (34, 57), army commander at Singapore; Hindu temples (36-40,
                  42-43); an Islamic mosque (38-39); a Buddhist temple (39-40); the tomb of Iskander
                  Khan, an Islamic shrine (40-42); the home of a wealthy Chinese (43-45); the
                  Raffles Library and Museum (46-47); the Leogan (?) Library of oriental material
                  (47-48); a Chinese club dinner, a social custom among wealthy Chinese (48-51); the
                  girls imported to be sold as wives, mistresses, and prostitutes and their role at
                  the dinner (49-51); a Chinese street festival to propitiate the devil (51-53); the
                  Botanical Garden (55-56); psychical researcher Ridley and two experiments in
                  thought transference (57-58); prostitutes on Malay St. (59); a Chinese ceremony
                  over the dead (59-61); and botanist Henry Nicholas Ridley (57-58).</p>
               <p>Webb resumed his journey on Sept. 21 with a voyage from Singapore through the
                  Malacca Strait and Bay of Bengal (pp. 64-80). This ship was better. He described a
                  number of European and Asian passengers. The ship paused during Sept. 23-25 at
                  Penang, and Webb, who was charmed with this city, described it and its
                  environs.</p>
               <p>On Sept. 28 the ship entered the Irrawaddy River and soon docked at Rangoon,
                  Burma, where he visited until Oct. 9 (80-113). He was greeted at the wharf by a
                  throng of Muslims, and he was driven to the principal mosque where he addressed a
                  large gathering and where he was congratulated for becoming a convert to Islam. He
                  toured the city extensively. He met with many Muslims at the mosque, an assembly
                  hall, offices, and private homes. He delivered several addresses. At the principal
                  mosque he was given his Islamic name of Alexander Russell Abdulla Webb (88), but
                  he was known later as Muhammad Alexander Russell Webb. Muslims whose names appear
                  frequently in the text are Abdul Careem Sookar, Abu Beher, and Abdulla Arab. There
                  are a few references to Ismail Mohammed (107-108), Mohammed Dawood (84, 87-89),
                  and Moolah Ismail (82).</p>
               <p>Notable references include: Buddhists and Buddhist temples (101-104); funeral
                  customs (85, 105-107); a museum and zoo (110-111); an oil-mill or petroleum
                  refinery (112); opinions of the English (109, 112); etc. The Imam endorsed Webb's
                  mission to convert Americans to Islam, and subscriptions were raised (102).</p>
               <p>Webb traveled by boat to Calcutta, and his visit there is described in Vol. I, pp.
                  122-142 and Vol. II, pp. 1-11, covering the period of Oct. 12-23. As usual he was
                  well received by the Muslims, and he met with many of them. Of particular interest
                  are his comments about Nawab Abdul Latif (1828-1893), a magistrate, first Muslim
                  member of the Bengal Legislative Council, and founder of the Mohammedan Literary
                  Society at Calcutta. Webb toured extensively in the city and commented upon places
                  of interest associated with the British, Muslims, and Hindus. Religious
                  observances of both Muslims and Hindus occurred during this time. Some of the
                  Muslims whom Webb met were: Hajee Noor Mohammed Jackeriah (123-124); Hajee Abdulla
                  (often); Abdul Jubbar (131); Nawab Jan Mohammed (136, 140); the editor of the
                     <title type="simple" render="italic">Mohammedan Observer</title> (138-140,
                  142); Hajee Abdul Wahed (139); Dewan Synd Ameer Hossein (131, 139); Mohammed
                  Yussuf Khan Bahadur (139; II, 6); Moulin Abdul Jubbar (139; II, 9); Nawab Meer
                  Mohammed All (II, 9); etc. Prominent Hindus included Dr. Sambha C. Mookerjee (II,
                  2).</p>
               <p>Webb left Calcutta by train on Oct. 23 and next visited the Muslims and sights at
                  Patna (II, 11-15). Of special interest is his visit to Moulin Khuda Bakhsh Khan
                  Bahadur and the Bakhsh Oriental Library of books and manuscripts in his mansion.
                  This notable collection is now the Khuda Bakhsh Oriental Public Library
                  (11-12).</p>
               <p>Webb's next stop was at Benares on Oct. 25-26 (15-19). While en route from Benares
                  to Bombay, Webb was joined by Budmddin Abdulla Kur whom he was to see often in
                  Bombay. Kur was the publisher of Webb's lecture at Bombay.</p>
               <p>Webb was at Bombay during Oct. 28-Nov. 17 (21-54) where he received his most
                  cordial reception up to that time. His traveling companions and helpers, Hajee
                  Abdulla and Hassan Ali, were with him through most of his journey in India. Some
                  notable aspects of the Bombay visit were: meeting with Shaikh Abdul Rahim, a
                  Muslim mystic and clairvoyant (28); opinions of Nawab Zada Nasrullah Khan of
                  Sachim and his cousin the Nawab of Jungera (32-33); critical remarks about the
                  English scattered through both volumes; a Muslim wedding procession (34-35); a
                  Parsee wedding (37-39); the Elephanta Caves (40-43); Hajee Yussuf Soliman (48-49);
                  the shrine of Ali (49); and Badr-ud-Din Tyabji, a justice who once presided over
                  the Mohammedan Educational Conference (51-52).</p>
               <p>The next city that Webb visited was Poona on Nov. 17-19 (56-62) where he met Hajee
                  Haroun Hajee Jaffer, a wealthy bookseller and businessman (57, 59, 61) and Khan
                  Bahadur Kazi Shahabudin (60-61).</p>
               <p>Webb traveled by train inside India, and his descriptions of these experiences,
                  especially from Bombay to Hyderabad, Hyderabad to Madras, and Madras to Agra, were
                  rather colorful.</p>
               <p>Webb had a particularly interesting visit in Hyderabad, the capital of the native
                  state of Hyderabad that was ruled by the Nizam with British assistance. He was in
                  the city during Nov. 20-Dec. 8 (65-120). Notable references include: the
                  Superintendent of Public Instruction (66); marriage procession for a daughter of
                  the Nizam (68-69); Shah Abdur Rahim, a sort of high priest to the Nizam (70-75,
                  79); Mohammed Sharful Hak of Delhi, a Muslim missionary (71, 74); the Nawab Mehdi
                  Ali, that is, Syed Mehdi Ali, a high official in the government of Hyderabad who
                  retired in 1893 and soon became an official of the important Aligahr College (75,
                  79, 87, 89-90, 93, 104-105, 107-108, 116-118); a juggler (77-78); the Prime
                  Minister (78, 87-89); Webb's speech before 2000 people (80) that was soon
                  published; visits to a dervish (91-92) and to a Muslim saint who conducted a
                  seance before his followers in a mosque (99-101); the old city of Golconda
                  (102-104); Hassan Ali's public lecture and troops to keep order in case the
                  Muslims revolted (104-106); and the lack of success of the movement here
                  (110-111).</p>
               <p>Webb's next stop was at Madras during Dec. 10-12 (127-140). Notable references
                  include: Mirza Ismail Khan Bahadur (129-131); Col. Henry Steel Olcott, founder of
                  the Theosophical Society (128-129, 132-133); the performance of a fakir (135-137);
                  presiding over the opening of the new asylum for Moslem converts (137-138);
                  Mohammed Ahmad (138-139); and various references to Anjumani-Islam, a society that
                  hosted him.</p>
               <p>The second volume of the journal ends during the visit at Agra on Dec. 15
                  (143-144).</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
