<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/whartonrichard/">whartonrichard</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Richard Wharton Slave Trade Contract, 1671 May 20
            <num>RL.11497</num></titleproper>
        <author>Alice Poffinberger</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>July 2017</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">007841126</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-10-03 16:54:04
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Richard Wharton slave trade contract</unittitle>
      <origination audience="internal" label="creator">
        <persname role="cre" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Wharton, Richard, -1689</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>RL.11497</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 Linear Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">1 item</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1671-05-20/1671-05-20">1671 May 20</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_bf63e3dd27ac330ce35ee63176730a03">Richard Wharton was a prominent Boston
        merchant, land proprietor, attorney, and political figure. Collection comprises a 1671 slave
        trade contract committing Boston merchant Richard Wharton to acquire slaves for Jonathan
        Sybury of Maryland in return for tobacco. This contract specifies that prior to the last day
        of July, 1671, Wharton will "Send forth and Imploy A vessel to Some one or more Islands of
        America where Negroes are ordinarily to be Sold wch sd vessell shall bee loadon wth a
        sufficient Cargoe for obtayning and purchasing ten or more healthy &amp; sound Negroes halfe
        Males and halfe females none exceeding ye age of forty years and not more than two the age
        of thirty five years" and that the vessel "shall...Carry and Transport to Wye River in
        Maryland The sd Negroes..." The contract further stipulates that within seven days after the
        arrival of the vessel in the Wye River, Sybury "will show present and Deliver at some [?]
        convenient shipping place...the quantity of Three Thousand six hundred and Eighty pounds of
        bright and large Tobacco without ground leaves or seconds." Failing such payment, Sybury is
        required to pay with bills of exchange redeemable in London. Much of the contract reckons
        with various circumstances that might arise and the terms specific to these. The document is
        signed by Wharton on the lower right and by witnesses John Walley and Georg Young on the
        lower left.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_51eeb650bf3cbe9199df371025365fe3">Materials in English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="aspace_089df88a2b90d198f7e0cbb0493b2cbf">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Richard Wharton was a prominent Boston merchant, land proprietor, attorney, and political
        figure, whose vigor and numerous activities frequently led him into controversy.
        Well-connected in England, he emigrated to America to seek his fortune, settling in Boston,
        where he improved his connections by marriage. An Anglican, Wharton nevertheless married
        into Puritan families with ease. His first wife, Bethia Tyng, was the daughter of wealthy
        merchant William Tyng; his second, Sarah, was the daughter of Rev. John Higginson of Salem,
        and his last, Martha, was a daughter of Governor John Winthrop of Connecticut. Wharton
        acquired a large tract of land in Narragansett country, and subsequently purchased the
        Pejepscot Patent in Maine (including the town of Brunswick) from the heirs of Thomas
        Purchase and John Way. In addition to his land investments, Wharton engaged in the
        production of salt used in the preservation of the "refuse fish" that were shipped to the
        West Indies to feed slaves, produced lumber and masts, and founded a New England mining
        company. He is said to have engaged periodically in the West Indies slave trade.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_f719aa9afc9065c16c9456913b118bb3">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
        research use.</p>
      <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_71859df6d9151783c006c5b1d6172250">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
        For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of the
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_22129cd81d60f587316b5dd5c93a22ed">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Richard Wharton Slave Trade Contract was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2017.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_f8e62fb61eed1bd9fde95067cc51be41">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Richard Wharton Slave Trade Contract, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript
        Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_8ad5403f6d05def3120be2476db5544c">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Alice Poffinberger, July, 2017</p>
      <p>Accessions described in this collection guide: 2017-0084</p>
    </processinfo>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_69a076fc8a4c4a93ea5db5b855d5ca0b">
      <head>Related Materials</head>
      <p>Sybury's copy of this contract and the record of a legal suit he initiated because of
        Wharton's failure to fulfill the contract may be found in the Archives of Maryland Online,
        Proceedings of the County Courts of Kent (1648-1676), Talbot (1662-1674), and Somerset
        (1665-1668), Vol. 24, Preface 25, pp. xv, 519-522; also Archives of Maryland Online, Vol. 5,
        Proceedings of the Council of Maryland, 1667-75, p. 72.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_599446c0e99260bd99b919df4fc973f9">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>Collection comprises a 1671 slave trade contract committing Boston merchant Richard Wharton
        to acquire slaves for Jonathan Sybury of Maryland in return for tobacco. This contract
        specifies that prior to the last day of July, 1671, Wharton will "Send forth and Imploy A
        vessel to Some one or more Islands of America where Negroes are ordinarily to be Sold wch sd
        vessell shall bee loadon wth a sufficient Cargoe for obtayning and purchasing ten or more
        healthy &amp; sound Negroes halfe Males and halfe females none exceeding ye age of forty
        years and not more than two the age of thirty five years" and that the vessel "shall...Carry
        and Transport to Wye River in Maryland The sd Negroes..." The contract further stipulates
        that within seven days after the arrival of the vessel in the Wye River, Sybury "will show
        present and Deliver at some [?] convenient shipping place...the quantity of Three Thousand
        six hundred and Eighty pounds of bright and large Tobacco without ground leaves or seconds."
        Failing such payment, Sybury is required to pay with bills of exchange redeemable in London.
        Much of the contract reckons with various circumstances that might arise and the terms
        specific to these. The document is signed by Wharton on the lower right and by witnesses
        John Walley and Georg Young on the lower left. Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin
        Research Center for African and African American History and Culture.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Slave trade -- America</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Slavery -- Maryland -- History -- 17th century</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Contracts</genreform>
      <persname rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Wharton, Richard, -1689</persname>
      <persname role="cre" source="local">Sybury, Jonathan</persname>
      <persname role="wit" source="local">Walley, John</persname>
      <persname role="wit" source="local">Young , Georg</persname>
      <corpname source="ingest">John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American
        History and Culture</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_d3a4533cedb425d4fe247170895cfb32" level="item">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Contract</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_abc0f54e037704fdb5fd9b9efd82bfd3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
