<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/woodyfamily/">woodyfamily</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Woody family papers, 1784-1939 <num>RL.01412</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Rubenstein Library staff; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Willeke Sandler and Paula Jeannet Mangiafico</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">000877903</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 13:34:46
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Woody family papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <famname source="ingest">Woody family</famname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01412</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1784/1939" type="inclusive">1784-1939</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_e0d4746ea9c5fdf5efa1302e9e0f600f">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_dd569f552d276c8c80cb2ac705002f3e">Family of Quaker merchants and
            millers residing in Guildford County, North Carolina, with relatives in Indiana and
            Montana Territory. Collection comprises a rich array of business and personal
            correspondence and other papers (chiefly 1835-1887) relating to Newton D. Woody,
            merchant and miller of North Carolina, his Civil War service, and his flight to Indiana
            in 1865 and eventual return to N.C.; the activities of Frank H. Woody, who traveled to
            and described life in the territories of Washington and Montana before and after the
            Civil War. There are also important materials regarding the Civil War and its aftermath,
            including descriptions of camp life by Confederate soldiers, one of whom was in the 21st
            North Carolina Regiment; experiences of Confederate soldiers in Union prisons at
            Johnson's Island, Ohio, and Elmira, New York, during the war; accounts of Reconstruction
            in Augusta, Georgia, given by a Union sympathizer, 1867-1868, as well as economic
            conditions in North Carolina before, during, and after the Civil War. There are also
            some documents and letters concerning African American life in the South before, during,
            and after the war. Printed matter in the collection relates to the activities of
            Unionists in North Carolina during the Civil War and opposition to Ulysses S. Grant and
            the Radicals. Other topics include the activities of Woody relatives who had migrated to
            Indiana; the activities of the children of Newton and of his brother, Robert Woody,
            postmaster, miller, and merchant; and the history of the Society of Friends in
            antebellum North Carolina. Includes legal documents, business records, and minutes of
            the Orange Peace Society, Orange County, N.C.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_d93fa7211c7231701c82bb0d74aa55b7">
            <extent>2,389 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_cc405c563a8e261148dee65d016b9065">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_1dc72eefde57c9eacc2ca10b88196733">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_ee835eef5c2ef076ade0d5945d860f07">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_129c7a9cab361de88f310f05ebc7b3ac">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Woody Family Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_ed59bf05ef42d780fefe215a90316183">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Woody Family papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a gift from 1952 to 1982.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_958c54728c1c2578e35af147853c2e1b">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Rubenstein Library staff</p>
         <p>Encoded by Willeke Sandler, March 2014</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_21e51bee4f0c93023bc7f7183d0737d8">
         <head>Historical Note</head>
         <p>Robert Woody was a merchant of Chatham County, North Carolina, and was postmaster at
            Mudlick in that county in the 1830s. For a number of years he had a business partner
            named Dixon. The papers of Newton D. woody start in 1848. He was a Quaker, as Robert may
            have been, and in the 1850s was in the mercantile and milling business with Thomas
            Dixon. He lived at Snow Camp and near Shaw's Mills, Guilford County. According to a
            printed letter written by Bryan Tyson in Oct. 1872, Newton held a petty office at the
            beginning of ate Civil War which exempted him from military service, but later he had to
            choose between serving in the Confederate Army or fleeing north. He chose the latter,
            leaving his wife and children behind. The Woody family papers reveal, however, that he
            was a captain in the 68th Regiment of N.C. Militia from at least some time in 1862 to
            the latter part of 1864. By Jan. 1865 he had gone to Indianapolis. In Sept. 1865 Newton
            Woody, along with H. Stewart, was issued a permit by the Freedmen's Bureau as a
            destitute loyal refugee to travel to Greensboro, N.C. at half rates. In 1872 he was
            still living at near Shaw's Mills. Along with his sons, Newton Woody established High
            Falls Manufacturing Company in Moore County, which was in operation into the early 20th
            century, making warps and yarns; he also owned a series of mills and a cotton gin.</p>
         <p>Other papers in the collection are those of Frank H. Woody, Newton's brother. He
            migrated to Indiana and then to Washington and Montana Territories before the Civil War.
            In the West he engaged in a variety of occupations; in Dec. 1865 he describes himself as
            a pettifogging lawyer in Montana Territory. He married in 1871 and by 1872 was a county
            clerk and recorder in Missoula, Montana.</p>
         <p>There are obituaries in the collection for Frank H. Woody, Newton Dixon Woody and his
            wife, Susan E. (Corsbie) Woody, John M. Woody, first president of Penn College in Iowa,
            and others.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_400609e91262d4ce9fa074830b0fbbd3">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Papers of Robert Woody, Newton Dixon Woody, and other members of the Woody family
            include a rich trove of business and personal correspondence; legal and financial
            papers; printed materials; and manuscript volumes. The papers of this family concern the
            mercantile and milling businesses of Robert Woody in Chatham County, North Carolina, and
            Newton Dixon Woody in Guilford County, North Carolina, in the 1850s; the decision of
            Newton D. Woody to leave North Carolina during the Civil War and his return in 1865;
            experiences of Frank H. Woody, a lawyer and clerk, in the Washington and Montana
            territories in the 1860s and 1870s, in which he mentions clashes with Native Americans
            and settlers, and reports seeing Sherman in 1878. There are also letters with news from
            relatives living in Indiana.</p>
         <p>Other papers include information about temperance meetings, including the General
            Southern Temperance Conference at Fayetteville, North Carolina, 1835; hog droving;
            commodity prices in the last half of the 19th century; general economic conditions in
            North Carolina and the United States in the 19th century; the upkeep of roads in
            Guilford County; and the experiences of Mary Ann Woody as a student at New Garden
            Boarding School, Guilford County, 1852-1853. In addition, there is a bill of sale for
            slaves and a letter from Alabama describing African American celebrations at Christmas,
            1857.</p>
         <p>There are also important materials regarding the Civil War and its aftermath, including
            descriptions of camp life by a soldier in the 21st North Carolina Regiment during the
            Civil War; experiences of Confederate soldiers in Union prisons at Johnson's Island,
            Ohio, and Elmira, New York, during the war; and accounts of Reconstruction in Augusta,
            Georgia, given by a Union sympathizer, 1867-1868. Printed matter in the collection
            relates to the activities of Unionists in North Carolina during the Civil War and
            opposition to Ulysses S. Grant and the Radicals. There is also a May 1865 letter saying
            that John Gilmore of N.C. was dividing land with freed African Americans, and a letter
            mentioning African American violence during elections in an unspecified state in Dec.
            1870.</p>
         <p>Volumes in the collection include minutes of meetings of the Orange Peace Society,
            Orange County, North Carolina, 1824-1830; memorandum books; an account book kept during
            the construction of a Quaker church at High Falls, North Carolina, 1905-1909; minute
            book of meetings of the Friends of Prosperity, 1913-1914. Other papers in the collection
            mention camp meetings and religious revivals in North Carolina and their effect on
            Quakers. There are also financial record books of Robert Woody and Newton Dixon
            Woody.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <arrangement id="aspace_825014d482ce4a785a91378ddc8bb560">
         <head>Collection Arrangement</head>
         <p>Correspondence, business, and other documents are arranged in chronological order,
            followed by series of printed materials and volumes.</p>
      </arrangement>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Montana -- Emigration and immigration</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877) -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877) -- Southern
            States</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Indiana -- Emigration and immigration</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Political refugees -- Confederate States of America</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Migration, Internal -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Merchants -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Quakers -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Peace -- Societies, etc.</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Southern States -- History -- 19th
            century</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Montana -- History -- 19th century</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Lawyers -- Montana</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Flour mills -- North Carolina</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina -- Economic conditions</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">North Carolina -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Washington Territory -- History</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Prisoners and
            prisons</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal
            narratives, Confederate</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Politics and government -- Civil War,
            1861-1865</geogname>
         <persname source="ingest">Woody, Robert</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Orange Peace Society (Orange County, N.C.) -- History</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Confederate States of America. Army. North Carolina Infantry
            Regiment, 21st</corpname>
         <famname source="ingest">Woody family</famname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Society of Friends -- North Carolina -- History</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Woody, Newton Dixon</persname>
         <famname source="ingest">Woody family</famname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref13_zk8" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Woody Family papers, 1784-1939</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_5afbb3788d574e913909e5b31e469bc3">
                  <extent>8 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_guo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Papers, 1784-1843</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_97b823a39c349be0ff96a4539d454b51">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_7ed4a1165d3de19a44919555d72053c7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_u53" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Papers, 1844-1856</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_999568f81c2ea632c48d4c19664b4513">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_90baae5c7f7131b49846ccdab0533e2d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_hmh" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Papers, 1857-1861</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_4c9bd8ee865a6e04cbdf3c661e013045">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_b1efa8892f0803af0185291070dd1f19" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_iwg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Papers, 1862-1870</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_b666514a67616b08f6cabd72df0b14ef">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_ba285856ab018f2d2cfc575a89f28e05" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_kxr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Papers, 1871-1882</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_913f307b68385372a79d33307bf537a5">
                     <extent>4 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_9ead468b7b5b53c26233e959ba429f25" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_6vd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Papers, 1883-1939</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_3d9d6d34b50e5a6358fee329683404d7">
                     <extent>5 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_a8c517ae9ebc63b79f68943a59ad6dda" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_shg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Papers, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f96f9b6927f68bd3b34d96b174442a18" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_pii" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Clippings and other printed materials, 1838-1919 and
                     undated</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_26eab1c5acf8208267e7d6fc1458a359">
                     <extent>3 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_1d09fb9762dcda59fd8038a341840053" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_oac" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Broadsides</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_7bc3f637af5c7a4a69e2391ea059074d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_tjo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Small bound volumes</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_ae7a493233045d2bd0f0d2c2c2b00310">
                     <extent>approximately 15</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_3a227b8577cd92e104ca46672d0e3f30" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref33_nht" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Account book, Chatham and Guilford Counties, N.C.,
                     1836-1853</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ed2cdc222a11cd8333a36f18a6a9f25d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">F:6701</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref34_phc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Daybook, Mudlick, Chatham County, N.C., 1839-1870</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3b3f0f2a8278ce2d59407426f7203dcb" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">F:6702</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_4gr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ledger, Chatham and Guilford Counties, N.C., 1850-1856</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9d1e936f2a8763586b6a93aa9c7a39a6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">F:6703</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref36_u16" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Account book, Chatham and Guilford Counties, N.C.,
                     1852-1854</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_71f7a2a1682cb09425f18f1263ec70d8" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">L:6704</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref37_fn8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Daybook, Chatham and Guilford Counties, N.C., 1854-1855</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5af0017a85fbe9280860987d8db22855" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">L:6705</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref38_0uz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ledger, Chatham and Guilford Counties, N.C., 1855-1858</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a992f540523e1c6aab2ad832a7f9410f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">L:6706</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref39_tsd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Account book, Chatham and Guilford Counties, N.C.,
                     1855-1874</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_89ceb87f1f4675b3f09863cea0fc3de5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">F:6706-A</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref40_afv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Daybook, Chatham and Guilford Counties, N.C., 1860-1861</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_18ae753016b3103ab20f722945d98bb7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="volume">L:6707</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
