<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
         url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/youngerscoletta/"
         >youngerscoletta</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Coletta Youngers Papers, 1977-2004 and undated, bulk 1983-1998
                  <num>RL.01424</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Christian Ferney; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Christian Ferney and Paula Jeannet Mangiafico</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2008</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003879309</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-01-09 15:03:09
               -0500</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2017</date>
            <item>Updated with 2016 accession by Meghan Lyon</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Coletta Youngers papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Youngers, Coletta</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>RL.01424</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">21 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1977/2004" type="inclusive">1977-2004 and undated</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_73a6fae82ee7c523c11a75e0210060ad">Human rights researcher and policy
            advocate at the Washington Office on Latin America. The Coletta Youngers Papers span the
            dates 1977-2004, and consist of reports and scholarly research, clippings,
            correspondence, and government documents related to socio-political conditions and human
            rights issues in Perú, gathered by Youngers while living in Peru during the 1980s and
            researching her 2003 book on political violence in Perú.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_c912c28d655ff87652318c0dba724fac">Material in English and Spanish
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <userestrict id="aspace_85a939be7ed506c433d8a223d5251a2d">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>The copyright interests in this collection have not been transferred to Duke University.
            For more information, consult the copyright section of the Regulations and Procedures of
            the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_65cf69b71e4a7ebf3604ace7ae216356">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Coletta Youngers Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library, Duke University</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_03b4309f34973d6d19b7753c3aaa5111">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Coletta A. Youngers Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
            Manuscript Library as a gift in July 2007.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_1fdfaf7b0b3b55e3507c0b3cc446c877">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Christian Ferney, November 2007</p>
         <p>Encoded by Christian Ferney and Paula Jeannet Mangiafico, January 2008</p>
         <p>Portions of this collection have not been ordered and described beyond their original
            condition. </p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_65d0291106182c3b93c4e88ba54fab05">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <chronlist>
            <head>Chronology</head>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1975</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Washington Office on Latin America (WOLA) founded</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1980</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Sendero Luminoso (Shining Path), Maoist guerrilla group, became active in
                     Perú</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1982</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Youngers interned at Washington Office on Latin American (WOLA)</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1983</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Eight Peruvian journalists killed at Uchuraccay</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1985</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Youngers earned a Masters Degree in Public Affairs at the Woodrow Wilson
                     School at Princeton University</event>
                  <event>Coordinadora Nacional de Derechos Humanos founded in Perú</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1985-1987</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Youngers served as Project Manager at the Perú-Chile Office of the Catholic
                     Relief Services, where she developed, monitored and evaluated rural and urban
                     development and human rights projects by Peruvian NGO's</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1987</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Youngers began working at Washington Office on Latin America (WOLA);
                     currently monitors, analyzes, and disseminates information on political
                     developments, human rights and U.S. Policy in the Andean region of South
                     America</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1990</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Alberto Fujimori elected president of Perú</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1992</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Fujimori dismissed Peruvian legislative and judicial branches in "self
                     coup"</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1997</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Youngers published <title type="simple" render="doublequote">Reluctant
                        recruits: The U.S. military and the war on drugs</title> (August) (WOLA),
                     and <title type="simple" render="doublequote">The only war we've got: Drug
                        enforcement in Latin America,</title>
                     <title type="simple" render="italic">NACLA Report on the Americas</title>, Vol.
                     I, No. 2 (September/October) (WOLA)</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>1998</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Youngers published <title type="simple" render="doublequote">Drug
                        Certification Doesn't Make the Grade</title> in <title type="simple"
                        render="italic">The Christian Science Monitor</title> (February 17)</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>2000</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Youngers published <title type="simple" render="italic">Deconstructing
                        Democracy: Perú Under President Alberto Fujimori</title> (WOLA)</event>
                  <event>Fujimori resigned in the wake of public outcry over an election bribery
                     scandal involving his advisor Vladimiro Montesinos</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>2002</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Youngers published <title type="simple" render="doublequote">Collateral
                        Damage: U.S. Drug Control in the Andes</title> (WOLA) and <title
                        type="simple" render="doublequote">Perú's Coordinadora Nacional de Derechos
                        Humanos: A Case Study in Coalition Building</title> (WOLA)</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>2003</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Youngers published <emph render="italic">Violencia Politica y Sociedad
                        Civil en el Perú: Historia de la Coordinadora Nacional de Derechos
                        Humanos</emph>
                  </event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>2005</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Youngers co-edited, with Eileen Rosin, <title type="simple" render="italic"
                        >Drugs and Democracy in Latin America: The Impact of U.S. Policy</title>,
                     which came out of the Drugs, Democracy, and Human Rights (DDHR) project
                     directed by Youngers and Rosin at WOLA</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>2006</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Montesinos, Fujimori advisor, sentenced to 20 years in prison for arms
                     trafficking</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
            <chronitem>
               <date>2007</date>
               <eventgrp>
                  <event>Fujimori extradited to Perú to stand trial for his involvement in massacres
                     and "disappearances" at Los Barrios Altos and La Cantuta</event>
               </eventgrp>
            </chronitem>
         </chronlist>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_0f862ad9455d11fd9363b8ee96e223e8">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The Coletta Youngers Papers span the dates 1977-2004, and consist of reports and
            scholarly research, clippings, correspondence, and government documents related to
            socio-political conditions and human rights issues in Perú, gathered by Youngers while
            living in Peru during the 1980s and researching her 2003 book on political violence in
            Perú. The collection is divided into the <emph render="bold">Printed Material</emph> and
            the <emph render="bold">Subject Files Series</emph>; there is also a separate listing at
            the end of this finding aid of printed works transferred to the Duke University Perkins
            Library general collections. Beyond the research materials in these series, there are
            currently no additional personal papers of Youngers in the collection. The Printed
            Material Series contains published reports on human rights circulated by a wide variety
            of organizations working inside and outside Perú. Most of the Perú-based human rights
            organizations are connected with the Coordinadora de Derechos Humanos (CNDDHH), an
            umbrella human rights organization based in Lima. Youngers' research files on human
            rights issues and a subseries of Peruvian and Latin American serial publications
            complete the Printed Material Series. The Subject Files Series contains files and
            informal reports of the CNDDHH and associated human rights organizations, most notably
            the Asociación Pro Derechos Humanos (APRODEH), El Centro de Asesoría Laboral del Perú
            (CEDAL), and the Instituto Defensa Legal (IDL). Further documentation of human rights
            abuses by government and rebel factions, drug policy files, papers related to former
            Peruvian president Alberto Fujimori's security advisor Vladimiro Montesinos, and the
            Maoist guerrilla group Sendero Luminoso complete the collection. Material in this
            collection documents the complex links between Peruvian government policy and
            international pressure, and the violent tactics employed by revolutionary groups as well
            as agents of the Peruvian government. Further, it chronicles the consequences of those
            actions, especially for rural and indigenous populations and local human rights
            advocates. The collection also contains numerous U.S. government documents obtained
            through the Freedom of Information Act which give insight into U.S. diplomacy, military
            and drug policy. Substantial portions of the collection are in Spanish. Aquired as part
            of the Human Rights Archive.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <separatedmaterial id="aspace_5da0d86c46237671c5268a57a241360a">
         <head>Separated Material</head>
         <p>Books and Other Bound Volumes:</p>
         <p>These items have been transferred to the Duke Perkins Library general collections; they
            can be located through the Duke Libraries online catalog.</p>
         <list type="ordered">

            <item>Alvarez, Elena. <title render="italic">Politica Economica y Agricultura en el
                  Perú, 1969-1979</title>. Lima, Perú: Instituto de Estudios Peruanos, 1983.</item>
            <item>Amery, Jennifer and Roberto López. <title render="italic">Medicamentos en el Perú:
                  Comercialización y Consumo</title>. Chimbote, Perú: Instituto de Promocion y
               Educacion Popular, 1985.</item>
            <item>Arbulú, Javier Tantalean. <title render="italic">Enemigos de la
               Democracia</title>. Lima, Perú: 1994.</item>
            <item>Blum, Volkmar. <title render="italic">Campesinos y Teóricos Agrarios: Pequena
                  Agricultura en los Andes del sur del Perú</title>. Instituto de Estudios Peruanos,
               1995.</item>
            <item>Carlessi, Carolina. <title render="italic">Mujeres en el Origen del Movimiento
                  Sindical: Cronica de Una Lucha Huacho, 1916-1917</title>. Lima, Perú: Ediciones
               Lilith, 1984.</item>
            <item>Cotler, Julio, ed. <title render="italic">Estrategias para el Desarrollo de la
                  Democracia: En Perú y America Latina</title>. Lima, Perú: Fundacion Friedrich
               Naumann, 1990.</item>
            <item>
               <title render="italic">Deuda Externa, Desarrollo y Cooperacion Internacional:
                  Conferencia de las Organizaciones no Gubernamentales, 25-29 de Enero de 1988,
                  Lima, Perú</title>. Paris, France: L'Harmattan, 1989.</item>
            <item>De Toledo, Eliane Karp. <title render="italic">Hacia Una Nueva Nación: Kay
                  Pachamanta</title>. Lima, Perú: 2002.</item>
            <item>
               <title render="italic">Estrategias para el Desarrollo de la Sierra</title>. Cusco,
               Perú: Universidad Nacional Agraria "La Molina" and Centro de Estudios Rurales Andinos
               "Bartolome de Las Casas," 1986.</item>
            <item>Goldenberg, Sonia, ed. <title render="italic">Decidamos Nuestro Futuro</title>.
               Lima, Perú: Universidad del Pacifico, 1985.</item>
            <item>Gonzalez, Alberto and German Torre, eds. <title render="italic">Las Parcelaciones
                  de las Cooperativas Agrarias del Perú</title>. Chiclayo, Perú: SOLIDARIDAD,
               1985.</item>
            <item>Gonzalez de Olarte, Efrain. <title render="italic">Economia de la Comunidad
                  Campesina</title>. Lima, Perú: Instituto de Estudianos Peruanos, 1986.</item>
            <item>Gonzalez de Olarte, Efrain. <title render="italic">En las Fronteras del Mercado:
                  Economia Politica del Campesinado en el Perú</title>. Lima, Perú: Instituto de
               Estudios Peruanos, 1994.</item>
            <item>Guardia, Sara Beatriz. <title render="italic">Mujeres Peruanas: El Otro Lado de la
                  Historia</title>. Lima, Perú: Empresa Editora Humboldt, 1985.</item>
            <item>Hopkins, Raul. <title render="italic">Desarrollo Desigual y Crisis en la
                  Agricultura Peruana, 1944-1969</title>. Lima, Perú: Instituto de Estudios
               Peruanos, 1981.</item>
            <item>
               <title render="italic">La Democracia en Cuestión</title>. Lima, Perú: Instituto de
               Estudios Peruanos, 1992.</item>
            <item>Mar, Jose Matos and Jose Manuel Mejia. <title render="italic">La Reforma Agraria
                  en el Perú</title>. Lima, Perú: Instituto de Estudios Peruanos, 1980.</item>
            <item>Maskrey, Andrew and Gilberto Romero. <title render="italic">Urbanizacion y
                  Vulnerabilidad Sismica en Lima Metropolitana</title>. Lima, Perú: PREDES
               Ediciones, 1986.</item>
            <item>Nyrop, Richard F. <title render="italic">Perú: A Country Study</title>.
               Washington, DC: US Government Printing Office, 1990.</item>
            <item>Ortiz de Zevallos, Felipe. <title render="italic">The Peruvian Puzzle</title>. New
               York: Priority Press, 1989.</item>
            <item>Perez, Jaime Carbajal and Percy Uriarte Otoya. <title render="italic">Economia y
                  Violencia: Los Costos Ocasionados por el Terrorismo: Un Marco Teorico y un Modelo
                  de Estimacion</title>. Lima, Perú: Instituto Constitucion y Sociedad, 1993.</item>
            <item>
               <title render="italic">Poder Politico con Perfume de Mujer</title> (Ana Maria Yanez,
               Lisbeth Guillen, eds.). Lima, Perú: Instituto de Estudios Peruanos, 1998.</item>
            <item>Trujillo, Raul Torres and Carlos de la Torre Postigo. <title render="italic">La
                  Informacion Macro-Economica en el Perú</title>. Lima, Perú: DESCO, 1982.</item>
            <item>Zuniga, Felicitas, ed. <title render="italic">El Menor en Situacion de Abandondo:
                  Alternativas</title>. Lima, Perú: Ediciones TIPACOM, 1987.</item>
         </list>
      </separatedmaterial>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_e5249ad204dea3af88e66b1860682ff7">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Access restricted: Accession (2008-0151) is closed for 25 years, until 2033.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Peru -- History -- Autonomy and independence movements</geogname>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Peru -- Politics and government -- 1980-</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Sendero Luminoso (Guerrilla group) -- History</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Sendero Luminoso (Guerrilla group) -- Press coverage</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Human Rights -- Perú</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Human Rights -- Perú -- Cases</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Human Rights -- Perú -- History -- 20th century</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Peru -- History -- 1980-</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Communist parties -- Perú.</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Fujimori, Alberto -- Press coverage -- Perú.</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Drug production, illicit</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Drug policy</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Foreign relations -- Perú.</geogname>
         <genreform source="aat">Machine-readable records</genreform>
         <corpname source="ingest">Human Rights Archive (Duke University)</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Youngers, Coletta</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Washington Office on Latin America</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Montesinos Torres, Vladimiro</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Instituto Defensa Legal</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Fujimori, Alberto</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">El Centro de Asesoría Laboral del Perú.</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Coordinadora Nacional de Derechos Humanos (Perú)</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">APRODEH (Organization)</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref13_a10" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Printed Material Series, 1978-2002 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_62ee7009a072e79439b1155687d3e456">
                  <extent>13 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>






            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_ff77fe43b65e88d72e2d1cf657f0ab28">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Separated into <emph render="bold">Human Rights Reports</emph>, <emph
                     render="bold">Research Files</emph>, and <emph render="bold">Serials</emph>
                  subseries. The Human Rights Reports and Research Files subseries are organized as
                  received; the Serials Subseries is organized alphabetically by title and
                  chronologically within each title.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_uxk" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Human Rights Reports</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1978-2002 and undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_6623e3b4d02d0f3a9d5ab10b18f45725" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_5e80fc52f4eb941c5a9857a12a994887" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_1a81bb06290b968b48bd3879ed40b3fe" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_c8d9f30e1800682d57f6ebab3d259904" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_1fe49f59a2abce6366214ad06910a3ef" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">35</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9e02868eae8824d30184a5bbe938cce8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The Human Rights Reports Subseries is further divided into reports by
                     organizations headquartered in Perú and international human rights solidarity
                     organizations. In the Peruvian Organizations grouping, reports by prominent
                     organizations such as the Asociación Nacional de Familiares de Secuestrados
                     Detenidos y Desaparacidos del Perú (ANFASEP), the Asociación Pro Derechos
                     Humanos (APRODEH), El Centro de Asesoría Laboral del Perú (CEDAL), the Comisión
                     Andina de Juristas (CAJ), the Comisión de Derechos Humanos (CODEH), the
                     Comisión Episcopal de Acción Social (CEAS), the Comisión Nacional de Derechos
                     Humanos (CONADEH), Coordinadora Nacional de Derechos Humanos (CNDDHH),
                     Defensoria del Pueblo, and the Instituto Defensa Legal (IDL) are included,
                     among others. </p>
                  <p>Reports by major international human rights organizations are included in the
                     International Solidarity Organizations grouping. Of these, Amnesty
                     International and Human Rights Watch (as well as Americas Watch) are the major
                     contributors. Numerous occasional papers and conference proceedings from
                     institutions based in the United States, including the Washington Office on
                     Latin America (WOLA), also appear in this grouping as do reports by
                     organizations based in Canada and the United Kingdom.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_1ut" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Research Files</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1983-2002 and undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_c582a953d771e8a83c50bd4faac83d01" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_fe8da932c9a98a5f8563d2fc1caff198" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_c6c7b89807f33017ac4cbcf1e268e7cd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
                  <container id="aspace_adbfa4bfa29a58aed8a5e85610c6fdbe" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d3dc9aa30418516a5693b75bd0bcd067" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">31</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7e1fbfdbc8db1bd47490ea3d0d64cbb6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Additional conference papers and proceedings as well as drafts of articles on
                     Perú by scholars in anthropology, history, and political science make up the
                     Research Files Subseries. Topics covered in this series include case study
                     articles of human rights abuses, articles on the communist revolutionary
                     movements Sendero Luminoso and the Movimiento Revolucionario Túpac Amaru
                     (MRTA), and peasant-organized village protection movements (rondas). Oversize
                     excerpt of Cambio newspaper (1988 Sept.) in Box 31.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_po0" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Serials</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1981-2002 and undated</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_f905ad4308e63d05d6225b0f3bb85525">
                     <extent>6 boxes</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_53801ba1230105ff9c8d43939b6090c4">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The Serials Subseries consists of magazines and journals chiefly printed by
                     Peruvian media and advocacy organizations. These include runs of issues of the
                     Andean Newsletter (published by the CAJ) from 1993-1998, Cuestion de Estado
                     from 1992-2001, Flecha en el Azul, Ideele (published by IDL) from 1991-2000,
                     and selected issues of Debate, Iglesia en Sicuani, Paginas, and Perú Hoy. A
                     number of single issues of serial publications may be found in this subseries
                     as well. The publications in this subseries focus on Peruvian economy, society,
                     and politics, with publications on rondas, socioeconomic development, Sendero
                     Luminoso and the MRTA included.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref20_393" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">Andean Newsletter</title>-<title render="italic"
                           >Cuestion de Estado</title>, 1992-1994</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_1206a0ebcb851c68836b814ecbe4c6da" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">8</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref21_aka" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">Cuestion de Estado</title>, 1995-2001-<title
                           render="italic">IDEAS-Programa Piura</title>
                     </unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_f9bf885d561b429d362502c7328fc26d" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">9</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref22_zqr" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">Ideele</title>, 1991-1995 June</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_084af01435d23f5bbf31e06c6f1e87a4" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">10</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref23_5w4" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">Ideele</title>, 1995 July-1998 July</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_7a99b2215a24b05d8546e4bf779ca26c" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">11</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref24_ufg" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">Ideele</title>, 1998 Aug.-2000 Jan.-<title
                           render="italic">Ninas y Adolescencias</title>
                     </unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_1514ad461e4966a00203770e4e7c0ff9" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">12</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref25_ubn" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">Paginas</title>-<title render="italic">Viaje a
                           Eutanasia</title>
                     </unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_74c55564d1eab0c889dce2a0950822b6" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">13</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref27_gmo" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Subject Files Series, 1977-2004 and undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_d23f9a549db6d2b7003fccd73eee33a2">
                  <extent>20 boxes, 1 oversize folder</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_4766a75190d535b1403823881d34956d">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Divided into the following subseries: <emph render="bold">Coordinadora Nacional de
                     Derechos Humanos</emph> (CNDDHH); <emph render="bold">Drug Policy Files</emph>;
                     <emph render="bold">Human Rights Organizations and Cases</emph>; <emph
                     render="bold">Vladimiro Montesinos Files</emph>; and <emph render="bold"
                     >Sendero Luminoso</emph>, or the Shining Path.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_y2k" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coordinadora Nacional de Derechos Humanos (general)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-2003 and undated</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_1f81887dfb4b37f4e12a124afb07b1bc">
                     <extent>56 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_5cc465ab823c7e588e012eeb7ccd52ef" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14</container>
                  <container id="aspace_255dfbeeca76a1e3a4d06923cb64f93a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">15</container>
                  <container id="aspace_ba15e00976339e968cf5a221159fa2cb" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">16</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d72a20ec37ec4eb6d17b896b75a763d0" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">17</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4965819c883bee1961a29f580fac0673">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The Coordinadora Nacional de Derechos Humanos Subseries contains internal files
                     of the CNDDHH dated between 1985 and 2003. Included are files, reports, and
                     research materials of the CNDDHH as well as partner organizations under its
                     umbrella. Among the major organizations are the Asociación Nacional de
                     Familiares de Secuestrados Detenidos y Desaparecidos del Perú (ANFASEP), the
                     Asociación Pro Derechos Humanos (APRODEH), the Comisión de Derechos Humanos
                     (CODEH), the Comisión Episcopal de Acción Social (CEAS), the Comisión Nacional
                     de Derechos Humanos (CONADEH), Defensoria del Pueblo, and the Instituto Defensa
                     Legal (IDL). Several theses or dissertations related to human rights in Perú
                     are contained in this subseries, as are press releases (including photocopies
                     of the CNDDHH publication Carta Circular from 1989-1998), and some email
                     correspondence between Youngers and CNDDHH members. In addition to chronicling
                     the activities of the CNDDHH and affiliated organizations, this subseries
                     contains information on death threats received by CNDDHH leaders from the Grupo
                     Colina, an extrajudicial death squad linked to former Peruvian President
                     Alberto Fujimori and Vladimiro Montesinos, who controlled his security forces.
                     Other topics covered in this subseries include human rights marches or
                     demonstrations, "disappearances" and detentions of human rights advocates, and
                     documentation of cases of torture by the government. One electronic file
                     contains a 104-page report entitled 1° Informe Parcial Sobre La Situación De
                     Derechos Humanos En El Perú, Febrero 2003, and is available to use on special
                     request. Additional materials related to CNDDHH and other human rights
                     organizations working in Perú as well as cases of human rights violations can
                     be found in the Human Rights Organizations and Cases Subseries and in the
                     Printed Material Series. Subseries is organized as received.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref51_flz" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coordinadora Nacional de Derechos Humanos (oversize)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1988 and undated</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref52_c27" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>CNDDHH Peruvian human rights movement map, undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_75bebcdf1411ad27b905a640918001b9" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">34</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref53_ha5" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Campana Para Los Desaparecidos, 1988 Dec.</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_9582521815f3c1cda9f52d72081dd609" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">34</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref54_mt8" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Women's rights posters, undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_4acfad7f580068a1d9b38c8c4a4ff059" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="oversize-folder">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_k8r" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Drug Policy Files (general)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1991-2004 and undated</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_75984065c2144dcace1d675681e26a12">
                     <extent>38 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_6dd9942675c289a86d332ef0b54f8f07" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">17</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7456a76d945a792f6e9f7d23915ae93c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">18</container>
                  <container id="aspace_62d6e0f3980b9dab5dc58fd95a2b4826" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">19</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_832ae5ecd63fda69e9b024cc766c682f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The Drug Policy Files Subseries is primarily comprised of intelligence reports
                     on narcotrafficking in Perú, the bulk of which are declassified documents from
                     the US State Department and various intelligence organizations. In addition,
                     files and reports from the Peruvian national drug control agency DEVIDA
                     (Comisión Nacional para el Desarrollo y Vida sin Drogas) as well as Peruvian
                     court and government documents are included. The role of the U.S. government in
                     Perú as an observer, military advisor, and as an active counter-narcotics
                     presence are documented. Some intelligence reports include information on the
                     Sendero Luminoso as well as efforts to cripple the drug trade, both through
                     military action and biologically through agents such as the fungus fusarium
                     oxysporum (Agent Green). Vladimiro Montesinos and his relationship with drug
                     traffickers are often featured prominently in this subseries. Organized as
                     received.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref55_2sm" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Drug Policy Files (oversize)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1984-2002</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref56_otr" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Newspapers and clippings, 1984-2002</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_fdd63265bad9ccb73892d4ac9a93ffa8" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">34</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_3hj" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Human Rights Organizations and Cases (general)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1982-1999 and undated</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_3fee19829bf03ea001ead6824163fd59">
                     <extent>61 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_41f3ae8f5afcfc76a59bb764e1893b1d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">20</container>
                  <container id="aspace_4c28e6b1dd82d8fc0ed29865f1150982" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">21</container>
                  <container id="aspace_00bf9681eaef3f74c3997b980d011361" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">22</container>
                  <container id="aspace_2886d2f2b0be3282bc58736fbd69bd97" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">23</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_562af3f07961f7eda3aea86864f1c4f0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The Human Rights Organizations and Cases Subseries chiefly consists of magazine
                     and newspaper clippings and press releases covering human rights abuses
                     primarily by agents of the Peruvian military (and Grupo Colina) but also
                     Sendero Luminoso. It contains informal reports as well as some email
                     correspondence and press releases from WOLA and prominent Peruvian human rights
                     organizations, including CNDDHH as well as ANFASEP, CEAS, El Comité Nacional de
                     Familiares de Detenidos-Desaparecidos y Refugiados (COFADER), the Instituto
                     Peruano de Educación en Derechos Humanos y la Paz (IPEDEHP), Defensoria del
                     Pueblo, IDL, and the Instituto Educación Rural. Bound reports by Peruvian and
                     international solidarity organizations generally are housed in the Printed
                     Material Series. Material and communications from prominent international
                     solidarity organizations such as Amnesty International and Human Rights Watch
                     (as well as its subsidiary Americas Watch) appear in this subseries as well.
                     Topics of note in this subseries include documentation and media coverage of
                     detentions, torture, and "disappearances" of journalists and human rights
                     activists, the 1985 prison riots, and well-known mass killings that took place
                     at Los Barrios Altos, La Cantuta, Cayara, Chumbivilcas, and especially
                     Uchuraccay. Subseries is organized as received.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref57_skr" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Human Rights Organizations and Cases (oversize)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1983-1989</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref58_p46" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Files and clippings on Jaime Ayala and Sybila Arredondo,
                        1984-1985</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_f39b975d2a741330dd91600f694a872d" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">34</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref59_y8k" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Uchuraccay and Cayara massacre files and clippings,
                        1983-1989</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_15f92affd7e0c8ec76f01c5e045cec05" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">31</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref60_2ph" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>La Cantuta investigation, 1993</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_ac597dc85a79bb45e0acbd2f8b322851" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">31</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref61_8ot" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Detentions of human rights workers and general Perú information,
                        1983-1988 and undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_7bbcc1ca91d972f929a6cbcdbc13fe1a" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">31</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref62_x22" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Assassinations and Franco death squad files, 1988-1989</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_cde289d4378a59702aae6faaeb04c5ca" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">31</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref63_080" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Nuns killed at Lurigancho, 1983 Dec.</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_8e4d140044e0b5158e668a6b3aacb284" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">31</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref64_pha" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Perú prison riots, 1986-1987</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_31bc7d29548d91afa54b450c14386bc6" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">31</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref38_5br" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Vladimiro Montesinos Files (general)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-2003 and undated</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_fd69f10e7df8842906f37fa7b8515b90">
                     <extent>71 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_3da97c39540855400e0550344a415116" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">24</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b8f20577e73c6d42760ddd651a16136a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">25</container>
                  <container id="aspace_8ac0198727d1164471dea4e2af525072" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">26</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7b375631255c513b641b2183cd69bb6e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">27</container>
                  <container id="aspace_10d22c1e7ed2ed3c08b7c76a54ef5127" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">28</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_68ff8e0e7aeb00fd72bba1275920f4f1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Montesinos' connections with United States intelligence services, drug
                     trafficking, and human rights abuses are further explored in the Vladimiro
                     Montesinos Files Subseries. In addition to declassified US government documents
                     (which comprise the bulk of material in this subseries), this subseries
                     contains a number of informal reports related to Montesinos by human rights
                     organizations as well as numerous newspaper and magazine clippings. Files
                     related to information on coup attempts against Alberto Fujimori, the MRTA
                     Japanese embassy hostage crisis of 1996-1997, and the Montesinos bribery
                     scandal that served as a catalyst for the collapse of the Fujimori government
                     are included. Subseries is organized as received.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref65_s01" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Vladimiro Montesinos Files (oversize)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1996-2002</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref66_lok" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Files and clippings on the military, judiciary, and SIN/SIE
                        intelligence forces, 1998-1999</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_82e9795cb4626e253c0b707e0c7ebda5" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">31</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref67_pkk" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>General files on Montesinos and drug policy, 1996-2002</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_78b40a2b89566f989d83724387b14822" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">34</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref41_y8c" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Sendero Luminoso (general)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1982-1994 and undated</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_b53dd49324e4d022a74791c0880144bf">
                     <extent>18 folders</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_6b7cd0d92ab16d201de377913ef93be4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">29</container>
                  <container id="aspace_01e979f10088069a8df57f31742fb4d6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">30</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_abfcf6e5674fab74cf4c68c7b44d4715">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The Sendero Luminoso Subseries contains clippings and files on the Maoist
                     guerilla organization from 1982 through 1994 and undated. The bulk of the
                     newspapers and clippings are from El Diario, an underground, Lima-based
                     Communist publication affiliated with Sendero Luminoso. In addition, clippings
                     from the Peruvian La Republica and prominent publications from the U.S. media
                     are included. Beyond El Diario, the subseries does not contain many direct
                     publications from Sendero's primarily rurally oriented operations, though there
                     are several pieces of propaganda from unknown sources. Numerous draft
                     publications of scholarly articles on Sendero Luminoso are included in this
                     series; most of these are authored by U.S.-based researchers though some are
                     from Latin American scholarly institutions. Together, the materials in this
                     subseries chronicle Sendero Luminoso's early activities in Perú's rural
                     mountain provinces through its acts of urban terrorism near the height of its
                     power in the mid-1980s and finally the trial and imprisonment of leader Abimael
                     Guzman after his capture in 1992. Subseries is organized by year.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref68_smh" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Sendero Luminoso (oversize)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1983-1991 and undated</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref69_6nq" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Newspapers and clippings, 1983-1991</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_a7b8e2ade54bfe1aa020e80d21600d89" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">31</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref70_pq8" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">New York Times Magazine</title>, 1990 Dec.
                        2</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_e9fd10eb51a1751fccf25271231f743a" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">31</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref71_gmf" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Newspapers and clippings, 1983-1991 and undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_ef906eb1c6f60a844bc9f85731d24d4d" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">34</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref72_vgk" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Headline sheets, undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_3814696f59c888b1c925d8852833c4d0" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="oversize-folder">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref74_t81" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Accession (2008-0151) (CLOSED)</unittitle>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 boxes</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate type="inclusive">1985-2000</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_46163ac1bd9301e39bf83ffa3baae833">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Addition (2008-0151) (900 items; 1.2 lin. ft.; dated 1985-2000) includes internal
                  documents from the Coordinadora Nacional de Derechos Humanos (Perú). Acquired as
                  part of the Human Rights Archive.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <accessrestrict id="aspace_ed4a13fdac3d7e81c925ee9b433e71af">
               <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
               <p>This addition is CLOSED until 2033.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <processinfo id="aspace_a7a7932ce0062edc7884a6811b5395ed">
               <head>Processing Information note</head>
               <p>This addition has not been processed. Materials have been reboxed, but no further
                  arrangement has been done at this time. The creator's original folder titles are
                  listed below.</p>
            </processinfo>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref76_p54" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coordinadora Archivo</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2db5180fa112682b6849ea37976033db" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref77_nyu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>IDL Evaluations</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a0ce548735ea0bb43167bf64ed152cf4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref78_8pe" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: Internal Evaluations</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fc937953d429417a15af0703b4cd6090" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref79_ink" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: Primer Encuentro</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2181f77d1f89b9fad677954893fc3c46" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref80_tye" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: 1988</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4077baa062057fbd4233fa55e54fe89f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref81_6fv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: 1985-1987</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2093470661b5cb9fd03cc6d46d493c88" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref82_yr9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: 1989</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c17f64e2cbdc59986f759ee8cbe5bcd9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref83_a1i" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: 1989 Encuentro, III Encuentro</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b24d3058f9e87c836543c8769f6f27b7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref84_tz9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: 1990</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5a214c811313eb2ca4ed79caf325750f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref85_81b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: 1991 Encuentro, IV Encuentro</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5221b2f9e1098c4b9faba5314039bf84" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref86_6t5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Discussion of DIH, 1991</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6fe8dfbb42ddb0ebf7b8c90d3391af6d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref87_fhk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: 1991 Meetings of CD</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_def812690d2e8c6acbe4a56cd3756522" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref88_6hq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: 1991-Capac Yupanqui Rocal Dispute</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1ef7271f317e78ec56421cdde1622a7b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref89_t0p" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: 1991/Various Communication</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_27eece2296847f981c0d98432e72f255" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref90_3uo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: 1992</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1939b71dfb92c188b1e7849f5ee47e0b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">32</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref91_h58" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: Medicas de Comunicación, 1992-1994</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2cc63e7815cb1762631fb0a6bda5c902" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref92_z7c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: 1993</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fe84672830128552cb584cf6fe004ff7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref93_oe0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Quinto Encuentro: 1993</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_561be4bebd782b7e4dfa71dd3e9ec689" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref94_hqu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: 1993 Reinscription</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3d2b4ae9cff55827ec58545ade0751e1" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref95_gnc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: 1994</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_59c9f7f0053fcb5fc9738316a0fa1807" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref96_5f8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: 1995</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f0b59d96623ea14ac9d13e77cd65ec25" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref97_x0n" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: 1997 Encuentro, VII Encuentro</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8754be5f4eeea4f75d7902db0151266d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref98_1il" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: Informo/Actividades, 1997-1999</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_25b68f1b95da75bad77b70b80a53fc1c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref99_0d2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Workplan, 1998-1999</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b30ac076f0a69b455e44d1ba03b666af" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref100_h4g" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coord: Workplans/Activities, 1993-</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_849b2abc96abe321ee43aea7f9adcf7a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref101_urx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Journa's Interviews</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e7a01ed3e34c8dc80d7e65ab594ad829" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref102_niz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>AID Evaluation, April 2000</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4e22c05780fff1f01fd9129feb324637" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref103_8pk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Coordinadora List of Members</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_49b742816dca319f3b2127d48b0eb25c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref104_9xn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Evaluations by Sofia Lind.</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9d82dc2f60da8df783075770ef570174" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref105_8q5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Quinto Encuentro Nacional de Organismos de Derechos Humanos,
                     1993</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_19884d40157f9ff08e9fed7934def697" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">33</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
