<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="https://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uaabelejulian/">uaabelejulian</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Julian Abele Reference Collection, 1974-2009
            <num>UA.01.11.0086</num></titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: Kimberly Sims; machine-readable finding aid created by: Kimberly
          Sims</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>2013</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">005758002</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-03-23 09:59:47
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Julian Abele reference collection</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <corpname source="naf">Duke University. University Archives</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>UA.01.11.0086</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1974/2009" type="inclusive">1974-2009</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_e47c288e1cb540426a52ec1c89f91839">Julian Abele was the chief designer for
        Horace Trumbauer's architectural firm in Philadelphia, PA. He designed the buildings for the
        Duke University campus, including Duke Chapel. The reference collection includes articles,
        correspondence, clippings, printed and genealogical material, and other files related to
        Abele.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_409a57aff75d17aff79453e36f7a4709">Material in English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_3eccabcfe23569b224257f0834e6ad39">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_30b590edb25a28534f171332816363f9">
      <head>Copyright Notice</head>
      <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Duke University; all other copyright
        is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as stipulated by
        United States copyright law.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_dfec93ec073e7a1dcff4a03484632209">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Julian Abele Reference Collection, Duke University Archives,
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_2cddb2b45bd889f258b5a414a0f64f5a">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Julian Abele Reference Collection was compiled by the University Archives from a
        variety of sources.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo id="aspace_49643b1c0fda4e7f67bc91a58967dc71">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Kimberly Sims, January 2013</p>
      <p>Encoded by Kimberly Sims, January 2013</p>
      <p>Biographical note added by Tracy M. Jackson, November 2015</p>
      <p>Accession UA2013-0013 added by Tracy M. Jackson, May 2016.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_56caab14aa5e0e0c489525a5f9e4ffc1">
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p><extref xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uatrumbauer/">Horace
          Trumbauer Architectural Drawings Collection</extref>, Duke University Archives, David M.
        Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <bioghist id="aspace_8d1f0619feea183bff815ae5e5051dd9">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Julian Francis Abele was born in 1881 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. He was the youngest of
        eight children in a prominent African American family, and attended the Institute for
        Colored Youth, Brown Preparatory School, and the Pennsylvania Museum and School of
        Industrial Art before studying architecture at the University of Pennsylvania and the
        Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts. He was the first African American to graduate from the
        University of Pennsylvania when he did so in 1902 at age 21.</p>
      <p>In 1906, Abele began working as an assistant to the chief designer of the architecture firm
        of Horace Trumbauer. In 1909, Abele became the chief designer. Around that time, he designed
        a home for James Buchanan Duke in New York City. Duke was impressed with the Trumbauer
        firm's work, and they were hired to design and oversee the building of West Campus when
        Trinity College became Duke University in 1924.</p>
      <p>The design and construction of Duke's campus was a massive undertaking, and Julian Abele
        took the lead in much of the design work. As was common practice, his architectural drawings
        were signed with the name of the firm of Horace Trumbauer and not his own name. He worked on
        most of the Gothic style buildings on West Campus, including the Chapel, the library, the
        football stadium, the gymnasium, the medical school, the hospital, and the school of
        religion (now the Divinity School). He largely oversaw the work from Philadelphia over the
        more than two decades he was involved with Duke's campus; although it is generally accepted
        that he did not travel to Durham or the segregated South, some evidence exists to suggest he
        may have visited the campus at one point. He worked on a library addition and signed a
        drawing for Cameron Indoor Stadium after Trumbauer's death, as well as the Allen Building,
        which was incomplete at the time of his death.</p>
      <p>Abele designed and contributed to many buildings in the Classical and Beaux Arts styles,
        including Harvard University's Widener Library, the Philadelphia Free Library, the
        Philadelphia Museum of Art (in collaboration with the firm of Zantzinger, Borie, and
        Medary), and the New York Evening Post building. The Great Depression took a toll on the
        firm of Horace Trumbauer, which specialized in large, luxurious buildings and residences,
        and when Trumbauer died in 1938, Abele and the remaining architect, William Frank, kept the
        name of the firm to reduce uncertainty. However, Abele did begin signing his own name to his
        drawings.</p>
      <p>Julian Abele was close to his sister, Elizabeth Abele Cook, and she and her children lived
        with him for a time in the 1910s and 1920s. Abele married Marguerite Bulle, a French
        musician who immigrated to Philadelphia, in 1925, and the couple had three children: Julian
        Junior, Marguerite Marie, and Nadia. Marguerite Marie died at the age of 5, and the Abeles
        separated in 1933. In 1942, Julian Abele became a member of the American Institute of
        Architects. He died in 1950 at the age of 68, of a heart attack.</p>
      <p>Although evidence for Abele's involvement in the design and construction of Duke's West
        Campus existed in the University Archives, including evidence that some University
        administrators knew of his role and likely his race, his name was not generally known or
        associated with the design for many years. During the time Abele worked on the design and
        construction of the campus, Duke University was only open to whites, and Jim Crow laws
        severely limited the rights and activities of African Americans in the South; if he did
        visit the campus during that time, he would not have been welcome in many places. His
        involvement in the work was acknowledged in several sources, but did not become widely known
        in the Duke community until 1986. That year, students protesting Duke's investment in
        apartheid South Africa built shanties in front of the Chapel. A student wrote to the
        Chronicle to complain that the ugliness of the shanties "violates our rights as students to
        a beautiful campus." Susan Cook, a Duke student and Julian Abele's great grand-niece, wrote
        a response that claimed her great grand-uncle, as an African American and the designer of
        the campus, would not have objected to the shanties as he was himself "a victim of
        apartheid" in his own country. This letter brought Julian Abele's name to the attention of
        the student body and many others who had not known of his existence and involvement in the
        design and building of Duke, and in the years that followed his contribution has been
        recognized and honored in a variety of ways. In 1987 the Black Graduate and Professional
        Student Association began the Julian Abele Awards and Recognition Banquet and unveiled a
        commissioned portrait of the architect. This portrait was hung in the foyer of the Allen
        Building, the first of a black person at Duke. This portrait now hangs in the Gothic Reading
        Room of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book and Manuscript Library, a building Abele
        designed.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_53c470677b728b5a16069cdcc721d263">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>The Julian Abele reference collection includes articles, correspondence, clippings, printed
        and genealogical material, and other files related to Julian Abele, his work, his family,
        and African American architects.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- History -- 20th century</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Buildings -- History -- 20th century</corpname>
      <persname source="ingest">Abele, Julian, 1881-1950</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref13_22l" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Chronology and Genealogy, Family Information [Abele and Cook families],
            1985-1986, undated</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_edd3c8f62e2137fa0d7795f3f057944a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref14_yas" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Copies of Letters and Articles on Duke Architecture [originals held in Duke
            University Archives]</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_d8c0ac8bf10272be2339efc4b9608135" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref15_epy" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Notes and Articles on Horace Trumbauer and Julian Abele</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_a88e7d19bbb688381cc27afe06661b83" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref16_aba" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Select Bibliography: Julian Abele</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_9b0eafb95d4309ece7840ffb62556d79" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref17_9o3" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Clippings</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_8cda00acb66f2afd1d9cbac4f1efdfab" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref18_55j" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence and Notes: Exhibit Book, 1999</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_5ab48a864a229b7c7caa3a6a94fbf024" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref19_gk2" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Exhibit Publicity and Thank-You Notes, 2000</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_dc7abb05bdaed613fb25f87ac98f5028" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref20_qut" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Images (xeroxed copies)</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_9887dff8603bd3f3eea216443d56a26a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref21_87r" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>"Spire and Spirit," by Alice Phillips, 1974</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_9ba25be04f26cc87db6724c24160b9a4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref22_z8t" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>"The Discovery of an Architect," by William E. King, published in <emph
              render="italic">Southern Cultures</emph> 2009 Spring issue</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_7b2a4cf7959ff6a5c77d274e6305c335" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref23_qgw" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>NC Chapter of the National Organization of Minority Architects: Awards Program,
            1995</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_0abe865831f37d47f1e35cf91f943c35" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_7eed90e43a9592438c267d75e797e4b7" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Abele research by Mason Barnett</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1986/1986" type="inclusive">1986</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_350f7213f765ef2f112c44df083f8597" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_1d3363bfc9407338d256b504fde70a4d" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Printed information and clippings</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1997/2004" type="inclusive">1997-2004</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_8fa43306281998f05072c1a469396110" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_8d08410126648f792f717a0b31e0c08e" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Oral history interviews, Athaneum, PA</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1989/2000" type="inclusive">1989-1990, 2000</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_babe54d68fd3d9c390d1bf6aea25bb72" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_b3e917ba445df4a1998c85fc7885ffd4">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Interviews with Julian Abele, Jr., John Cook V, Nadia Abele Jones, Robert Harris,
            Joseph Anton, Cogley Jones, Sr., Joan Kowalewska Yelcick, Henry Magaziner, Jr., James
            Johnson, and Valentine Lee, Jr. Interviews were conducted by Drek Wilson.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_f358c699010d040e14e9b506ac022187" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Photocopies from University of Pennsylvania Archives</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_ef4a5b5530e8e9ee3d277414808488b9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_7780c1c6da11e4d90349dbccd9a4b185" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Images and articles (photocopies) of Abele and Trumbauer buildings</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_7aca2f6ffc0987ae78089d3951929739" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_0094a4c19e78070d8c1e6c75e748540d" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Clippings, Horace Trumbauer obituary</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1938, 1992-2002, undated</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_b3670413938e395c0cb232f411655a10" label="Mixed Materials"
            type="oversize-folder">1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
