<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uabanham/">uabanham</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Preliminary Guide to the Katharine M. Banham Papers, 1910-1995
                  <num>UA.29.02.0020</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Laura Micham; Edited by: Jill Katte; machine-readable finding aid
               created by: Joshua McKim</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003205740</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-30 04:08:47
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Katharine M. Banham papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Banham, Katharine M., b. 1897</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>UA.29.02.0020</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">26 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1910/1995" type="inclusive">1910-1995</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_f5b4f11df2800b68e947fa5c6b104485">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Duke University Archives.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_584a237f8eeff20b251d6affe5160ad7">Katharine May Banham (1897-1995)
            served as a professor in the Department of Psychology at Duke University from 1946 to
            1967, specializing in child psychology and development. Papers include correspondence,
            writings, speeches, case files and research notes, teaching materials, diaries,
            memorabilia, photographs, and oral history interviews of Katharine M. Banham, relating
            to her work in the field of psychology and her contributions to Duke University, Durham,
            and North Carolina. Prominent subjects include psychological experimentation, child
            psychology, geriatrics and gerontology, human social and emotional development, children
            with cerebral palsy, the Woman's College, Duke Preschool, Duke Institute for Learning in
            Retirement, the North Carolina Psychological Association, the Durham Child Guidance
            Clinic, and the Center for the Study of Aging and Human Development. English.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_2cbf1227fe995a75b3dad145c1120c6e">
            <extent>20,000 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_dce92ae88e730de8d4b0a17f2419fe69">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_ff40798f437c46e8bf9fb26213830b14">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing
            from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After
            twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission
            of the University Archivist.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_f0bc29fc012f9ab26fd42d13eea74b39">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>Series 1. Materials that are personally identifiable and relate to psychological
            evaluations and testing are restricted (contained in white envelopes and stamped
            restricted).</p>
         <p>Series 4. Letters of reference and recommendation as well as correspondence between Ruth
            A. Baker, secretary of the Psychology Department and Katharine Banham, 1990-1995
            (contained in white envelopes and stamped restricted). To be opened only by the
            permission of the University Archivist.</p>
         <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Duke University; all other
            copyright is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as
            stipulated by United States copyright law.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_4fea6c59d7152fc7eb1a3d2dc9fa0cb9">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Katharine M. Banham Papers, Duke University Archives, David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_9b3755ebb02e1d8b082857c0575a9544">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The University Archives received this collection as a transfer in 1977, 1992, and
            1995.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_6c8883f4e19a93531eb04a3c5dae00d2">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Laura Micham</p>
         <p>Completed November, 1996</p>
         <p>Encoded by Joshua McKim, December 2002; Jill Katte, April 2003</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_74956b089aca1830d26815166d982c3c">
         <head>Biographical and Historical Note</head>
         <p>Katharine May Banham was born 26 May, 1897, Sheffield, England and died 7 May, 1995, in
            Buckinghamshire, England. Educated at University of Manchester (England), BS., 1919;
            Cambridge University (England), M.S., 1921, though this institution did not award
            degrees to women at that time; University of Toronto (Canada), MA., 1923; and University
            of Montreal, Ph.D., 1934 (Cum Laude), the first woman to be awarded a Ph.D. from that
            university.</p>
         <p>After faculty and professional positions in Canada, England, Iowa, and New Jersey,
            Banham was appointed to the Duke University faculty of psychology as Associate Professor
            in 1946 and Duke University Associate Professor of Psychology, Emerita in 1967. She was
            appointed Senior Psychologist at the North Carolina Board of Public Welfare in 1950. In
            addition to summer positions at the New Jersey Children's Home Society (1948),
            Children's Services of Cleveland, Ohio (1950), and visiting professor at University of
            British Columbia, Vancouver, B.C. (1960 and 1962), Banham was appointed as Head
            Psychologist of the Infant Program at the North Carolina Cerebral Palsy Hospital in 1967
            and Consulting Psychologist at Lenox Baker Hospital (formerly called the N.C. Cerebral
            Palsy Hospital) in 1980. Banham cofounded the Duke University Nursery School in 1946,
            with Dr. Wally Reichenberg-Hackett, helped to establish the Duke Film Society and the
            Duke Institute for Learning in Retirement, served in various faculty committees,
            developed a freshman counseling program, and created psychology courses in the area of
            infant and child development.</p>
         <p>Outside of the Duke community, Banham helped to establish many organizations including
            the Child Guidance Clinic of Durham; the Committee for Successful Aging; the North
            Carolina Psychological Association; the Altrusa Club, an all-women philanthropic
            organization; the French Club; and the Photographic Arts Society of Durham. She was a
            member and officer of many professional organizations in the United States and abroad.
            She established and funded the Alice C. Hundley Piano Student Award in 1970, for
            promising piano players between twelve and fourteen years old and the Anne McDougall
            Memorial Award for women in 1985, for women students to pursue study in the broad area
            of psychology whose education has been interrupted or who have not had the opportunity
            for college education. Honors and awards received by her include the N.C. Cerebral Palsy
            Award for Merit (1972) as well as certificates and awards of recognition and merit from
            regional, national, and international organizations. Published in both English and
            French, major publications include The Social and Emotional Development of the Preschool
            Child, (London: Kegan Paul, 1931) and Ring and Peg Tests of Behavior Development,
            (Chicago: Psychometric Affiliates, 1965).</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_044fd181685e97d8a74ec31d33403ce3">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The Katharine May Banham Papers span the years between 1910 and 1995, with the bulk
            occurring between 1945 and 1984. These papers include her master's theses and
            dissertation work, professional and academic writings, case files, and data documenting
            psychological experiments that culminated in the development of tests, as well as
            research articles and one monograph; transcripts of talks and addresses; translations of
            French psychological texts, teaching materials; administrative records of and records
            documenting her role in various civic and academic clubs and organizations; professional
            and personal correspondence; and personal materials including art, photographs,
            memorabilia, poetry and other personal writings, diaries, biographical information,
            legal documents, and tapes and transcripts of an oral history interview done in 1980.
            The main subject areas include Banham's contribution to the profession, her
            participation in the Duke community, and the Durham community as well as regional,
            national, and international communities and agencies.</p>
         <p>The collection chiefly reflects Banham's career as a woman psychologist during a period
            when there was little support for women in professional or academic careers. The papers
            document Banham's research and teaching in three countries; her contributions in the
            areas of child psychology and geriatrics, particularly human social and emotional
            development; functioning and development of children with cerebral palsy and
            disabilities; the history and especially the development of psychological testing of
            children and adults; and parapsychological phenomena. Research and teaching materials
            are located within the Academic and Professional Psychology series and Duke Activities
            series. Materials relevant to Banham's professional development are scattered throughout
            all five series.</p>
         <p>The collection is also important for the perspective it offers on the Duke University
            Psychology Department and the Woman's College during the 1940s to the 1960s. Information
            related to both as well as her role in the Admissions and scholarships Committees among
            other faculty committees (see the folder list located in the description of Duke
            Activities series), the Duke Preschool, the Duke Film Society, and the Duke Institute
            for Learning in Retirement can be found primarily in the Duke Activities series.
            Material regarding the development and teaching of an infant and child psychology
            curriculum and a series of correspondence with graduate students are also of special
            interest and can be found in the Duke Activities series. Other materials relating to her
            contributions to the Duke Community are located in the Academic and Professional
            Psychology series, the Correspondence series, and the Personal Files series.</p>
         <p>Banham's contribution to the city of Durham is reflected in the Agency and Club
            Participation series with the most in depth materials relating to her role in
            establishing the French Club, the Photographic Arts Society, the Altrusa Club, and the
            Committee for Successful Aging (which became the Golden Age Society and finally, the
            Coordinating Council for Senior Citizens), and, to a lesser degree, in the Academic and
            Professional Psychology series specifically in her role as one of the founding
            psychologists of the Durham Child Guidance Clinic. Banham co-founded the North Carolina
            Psychological Association in addition to being an active member and officer of other
            regional, national, and international organizations such as the League of Women Voters,
            the American Association of University Women, and the International Council of Women
            Psychologists.</p>
         <p>Banham's life was defined by her professional and academic commitments and so her
            closest relationships were with her colleagues and the many individuals to whom she gave
            her time and the benefit of her professional skills. The Correspondence and personal
            series best reflect her tireless efforts on behalf of the people with whom she come into
            contact. Her papers are particularly useful as they document the period of the 1920s
            through the 1960s in England, Canada, and especially the United States from the
            perspective of a highly educated, professional woman.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Emotions -- Social aspects</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Emotions in children</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Emotions -- Child</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Children with disabilities</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Child psychology -- Study and teaching</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Child guidance clinics -- North Carolina -- Durham</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Cerebral palsied children</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Oral histories (document genre)</genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">Psychology -- Experiments</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Gerontology -- Study and teaching</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Geriatrics -- Study and teaching</subject>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Department of Experimental Psychology</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Department of Psychological and Brain
            Sciences</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">North Carolina Psychological Association</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Psychology Department</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Woman’s College -- History</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Banham, Katharine M., b. 1897</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Banham, Katharine M., b. 1897</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Center for the Study of Aging and Human
            Development</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Faculty</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_85t" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Accessions: 77-214, A92-97, A95-84</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref13_tqw" level="series">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Academic and Professional Psychology, 1916-1986 (bulk
                     1946-1981).</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_05c869da4b68ee3cfe730b9e5520dd4c">
                     <extent>[9.6 linear ft.]</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_68a913f5b3b6b65a6f687ebc5ba086b4">Also includes one map
                     cabinet drawer</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_30ec5f0d84ec85264d2b4fd6c3a6790d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1-8</container>
               </did>
               <arrangement id="aspace_6915ff8cd7f655357ee7d18d54e79404">
                  <head>Arrangement note</head>
                  <p>The whole of the Academic and Professional Psychology series is arranged
                     chronologically and then subdivided into geographic regions. These
                     subdivisions, England, Canada, Iowa, New Jersey, and North Carolina, represent
                     the locations in which Banham was working when the contents of the folders were
                     created.</p>
               </arrangement>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bd4e5bbe5b7b067aa0d0a538bd76eb4e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Comprised of Banham's collection of 3x5 cards of bibliographic citations from
                     1948-1962; talks and addresses; writings including student papers and master's
                     theses, essays, reviews, translations of various articles in French as well as
                     books by Alfred Binet and Remy Chauvin, and research articles; research notes
                     and materials relating to the development of psychological tests including
                     School Readiness Inventory, Social Competence Inventory for Adults, Maturity
                     Level for School Entrance and Reading Readiness, Quick Screening Scale of
                     Mental Development, Ring and Peg Tests of Mental Development, Social Competence
                     Inventory for Older Persons, human and animal empathy tests, visual irradiation
                     tests, and various parapsychological tests; administrative materials related to
                     research and testing; materials documenting professional positions at the
                     McGill University Nursery School in Canada, the Leicester School Psychological
                     Service in England, Division of Psychological Services in Iowa, the New Jersey
                     State Board of Children's Guardians, the Durham Child Guidance Center, the
                     North Carolina Cerebral Palsy Hospital, the North Carolina State Board of
                     Public Welfare, the Duke University Nursery School, Lenox Baker Hospital
                     (formerly the N.C. Cerebral Palsy Hospital), and numerous consultancy positions
                     for agencies and individuals throughout North Carolina; professional and
                     academic interests files; news and magazine clippings; and curricula vitae from
                     1928-1983.</p>
                  <p>The series documents Banham's propensity to work on several projects and in
                     more than one position at any given time throughout her career. While she was
                     developing new psychological tests, writing essays and articles for various
                     audiences, teaching and advising undergraduate and graduate students, and doing
                     secretarial tasks in the psychology department, Banham worked as a consultant
                     doing psychological evaluation for individuals and agencies while helping to
                     establish the Duke Nursery School. The series also documents Banham's extensive
                     travel through England, Canada, and the United States in her many academic and
                     professional capacities. Finally, the series provides a picture of Banham's
                     research and professional methodologies, the variety of her intellectual
                     interests, and the depth and breadth of her commitment and service to her
                     profession and the individuals with whom she came into contact throughout her
                     career.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref16_d78" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>England, 1916-1921</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_4b99e38664883a5324006502de06d973" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1-8</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref17_6iy" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Canada, 1921-1936</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_9004005269ff134829c0919b0ba85d44" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1-8</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref18_cgf" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>England, 1936-1942</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_9846b4b7982c1827c9d7094c508813cf" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1-8</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref19_9yd" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Iowa, 1943-1945</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_291a25eaf5b367a9bb4ee52d1756da97" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1-8</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref20_ed9" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>New Jersey, 1945-1946</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_fa29f77a4141529c40fdf4e8fdf7bc62" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1-8</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref21_i9e" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>North Carolina, 1946-1986</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_846fa0b2d68a216792591ec23f409a23" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1-8</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_div" level="series">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Duke Activities, 1946-1986 (bulk 1946-67).</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_04491242125e48105aa456b9f2b6247d">
                     <extent>[4.8 linear ft.]</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_088ce7ce048751616a2eb373b894e751" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9-12</container>
               </did>
               <arrangement id="aspace_56f88a38b88a6c8ffcb2a98737dbf2f7">
                  <head>Arrangement note</head>
                  <p>The Duke Activities series is arranged alphabetically by activity and divided
                     into eight different activities: Admissions Committee, Department of
                     Psychology, Duke Institute for Learning in Retirement, Duke Preschool, Faculty
                     Committees and Clubs, Film Society, Library Committee, and Scholarship
                     Committees.</p>
               </arrangement>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref26_ifz" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Admissions Committee</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_ce2b3533eec05d2f38159e53f13a73fd" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">9-12</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_8dc9fcaf1f31b5551e63798137f67096">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>The Admissions Committee subseries spans the years 1958-1961 and contains
                        materials relating to admission requirements, admission statistics,
                        correspondence with registrar staff, and students considered for admission
                        to Duke University Woman's College.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref28_d2p" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Department of Psychology</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_222463ca049711eea560c08edd06a5c9" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">9-12</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_08a64f10a393c004bc21e8bc93c4fb20">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>The Department of Psychology subseries is further divided into three
                        categories: history and development, course materials, and correspondence
                        with graduate students. The history and development section spans the years
                        1946-1986 contains materials documenting Banham's role in starting the
                        clinical psychology program; department of psychology colloquia
                        announcements, memoranda, notices, a description of the history of the
                        department; inventories from psychological test library maintained by
                        Banham. Also included is a record of graduate student research during the
                        1940s, 50s, and 60s along with copies of qualifying exams taken by Ph.D.
                        students during this same period. The course materials section spans the
                        years of Banham's professorship at Duke and contains bibliographies of
                        psychological texts, course syllabi and packets, and lecture notes for
                        classes in abnormal, social, behavioral, and clinical psychology and
                        particularly for the child psychology curriculum. Course materials from
                        Banham's two summer teaching positions at the University of British Columbia
                        are included here. The third section contains correspondence with nine
                        graduate students. One of these individuals maintained a correspondence with
                        Banham for over thirty years (1949-1985). The materials in this section are
                        of particular interest as the practice of faculty-student correspondence was
                        uncommon during this period.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref30_htm" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Duke Institute for Learning in Retirement</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_9d5784c43fcc28bca4521cad4daf2048" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">9-12</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_cc34993582a9326948f344a4014bfe17">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>The Duke Institute for Learning in Retirement subseries spans the years
                        1977-1986 and contains extensive administrative records of the Institute
                        including correspondence, notices, meetings minutes, workshop and course
                        materials (both given and taken by Banham), and a draft of an autobiography
                        written by Banham during a writing workshop.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref32_0wq" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Duke Preschool</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_9655d405c56d04221d5baf023e5d7415" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">9-12</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_700829171a3cc28e157562641f476deb">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>The Duke Preschool subseries spans the years 1936-1967 and contains the
                        first plan for what was then (1936) being called the Institute for Child
                        Study. The plan includes a mission statement, budget, and the curricula
                        vitae of the persons who would run the program. The next part of the series
                        is a similar plan with blueprints of the Child Study Laboratory (1946-1949),
                        the second permutation of the preschool. The remainder of the series
                        consists of materials documenting the day-today events of the preschool
                        including administrative records as well as copies of the "Duke Kindergarten
                        Newspaper." (See Series 5 for photographic documentation of the school.)</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref34_4ew" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Faculty Committees and Clubs</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_cd0feccadb6c5e4ea80497bcf5533c7a" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">9-12</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_944527087cf3de8f40693eb9b2bdcdfc">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>The faculty committees and clubs subseries spans the years 1948 to 1986 and
                        documents Banham's service to a variety of faculty committees and clubs (see
                        folder list at the end of this description). Of particular interest are the
                        Academic council (1983-1985), the Center for Study of the Aging (1982-1985),
                        the Committee on Retirement Housing for Duke Faculty and Staff (1966-1971),
                        the Duke Council on Women's Studies (1985-1986), and the Experimental
                        Dormitory Committee (1961-1964).</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref36_ktm" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Film Society</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_5fea337f789bc497799e1bae5bccfae1" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">9-12</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_9059f76ed5709889450457820200481f">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>The Film Society subseries spans the years 1949 to 1965. These records
                        represent the entire lifetime of the Society whose aim it was to promote the
                        showing of experimental, foreign, or documentary films. Materials include
                        the original mission statement; administrative records; an extensive run of
                        correspondence between Banham and other members, University administration,
                        and film distributors: news clippings; and documentation of the Society's
                        dissolution and support for the student-run group, Quadrangle Pictures.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref38_djg" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Library Committee</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_2a4cd364a18edbaa945930ee300324fe" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">9-12</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_d27d4db17ead7668cdd9330d9fa509d3">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>The Library Committee subseries spans the years between 1935 and 1985 and
                        includes correspondence, memoranda, and acquisition lists. The papers
                        broadly reflect Banham's service within the psychology department as she
                        represented the department to the university libraries as well as concerned
                        herself with the departmental library. Particular areas of interest include
                        Banham's role on the Woman's College Library Committee, acquisitions in the
                        discipline of psychology between the years 1935 and 1985, and the library
                        within the Psychology Department. The subseries provides an example of
                        faculty involvement in library matters and collection development.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref40_0l3" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Scholarship Committees</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_9a5075f6d353e5bb8bcfbb922f798ca1" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">9-12</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_f21ae72c7e15b339434f0aa606ec5e25">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>The Scholarship Committees subseries spans the years 1945-1986 and reflect
                        Banham's strong interest in this element of university life. Materials in
                        this group include administrative records, correspondence, and news
                        clippings regarding scholarships and prizes in several different disciplines
                        including two, the Alice C. Hundley Piano Scholarship and the Anne McDougall
                        Award for Women that Banham herself established.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_bb0" level="series">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Agency and Club Participation, 1924-1986 (bulk 1945-1981).</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_397828446ca8a841aa6b6369dd065299">
                     <extent> [2.7 linear ft.]</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_cb83baee4de51ad048289469e73caa2c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">12-13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d6d5ae21665812e8ad965c1fcb113df4"
                     parent="aspace_cb83baee4de51ad048289469e73caa2c" type="oversize-folder"
                     >1</container>
               </did>
               <arrangement id="aspace_b737c921b0bfb612710b74c9ff603a00">
                  <head>Arrangement note</head>
                  <p>The Agency and Club Participation series is arranged alphabetically by the
                     names of the agencies and clubs.</p>
               </arrangement>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0e60ef466467aa975aeed08b4898875f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Though the bulk of the materials relate to Banham's work for the Altrusa Club
                     (1934-1985), an all-women philanthropic organization, the series documents more
                     than twenty organizations in which Banham played various roles from member to
                     officer to founder. The materials included in this series consist of
                     correspondence, notices, reports, minutes, membership records, agency
                     histories, constitutions, by-laws, mission statements, and news clippings. The
                     records of these agencies and clubs are of particular interest not only for
                     Banham's contribution, but also for the role they played in the history of the
                     city of Durham and the State of North Carolina: the American Association of
                     University Women, Durham Branch (1948-1976); the Coordinating Council For
                     Senior Citizens (1967-1985); the French Club (1956-1965 and 1969-1976); the
                     Golden Age Club (1949-1968); the League of Women Voters of Durham (1980-1986);
                     the North Carolina Psychological Association (1948-1986); and, the Photographic
                     Arts Society (1964-1984).</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_hgh" level="series">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1920-1995 (bulk 1940-1986).</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_0d526fa4732c80df74287a5bbcbc9743">
                     <extent>[3.6 linear ft.]</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_60b2cc57ecefe39e43fab6ddfa384f22" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">14-16</container>
               </did>
               <arrangement id="aspace_2c70cc6c54e0756ef34de2c4213d631c">
                  <head>Arrangement note</head>
                  <p>The correspondence series is arranged chronologically and divided into two
                     subseries: professional correspondence and personal correspondence.</p>
               </arrangement>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref49_zpy" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Professional Correspondence, 1920-1982</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_678430f2bc51207ef5d229918a3dca86" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">14-16</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_bc311837392df93f939bbc55cee003cc">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>The professional subseries, which spans the years 1920-1982, is largely
                        composed of correspondence related to Banham's various academic and
                        professional positions, consultations with individuals, requests by agencies
                        and individuals for her psychological tests, relationships with colleagues
                        at other universities, and letters of reference and recommendation.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref51_lxx" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Personal Correspondence, 1940-1995</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_90ad4ecb4cfcf85b4ed01d1554d5d4ef" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">14-16</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_4948bd67d22039d615ddd049000c91c5">
                     <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                     <p>The personal subseries, which spans the years 1940-1995, primarily contains
                        correspondence between Banham and her family in England with the bulk of it
                        between herself and her sister or mother. The subjects of these letters
                        include announcements of births, deaths, and other family events, details of
                        Banham's many trips and those of various family members, and general
                        correspondence and thank you notes from her nephews. The rest of the series
                        consists of correspondence between Banham and the many friends she made
                        throughout her life and career in England, Canada, and the US. and reflect
                        the close connection between her personal and professional life.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref54_h4u" level="series">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Personal Files, 1910-1986.</unittitle>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_e4da7e9bb083b9b048964363924affbf">
                     <extent>[4.0 linear ft.]</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_eb2f88a3e79f377b64982d562b3de42f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">17-18</container>
                  <container id="aspace_32b7f0407af990a123208b29bda7ca8c"
                     parent="aspace_eb2f88a3e79f377b64982d562b3de42f" type="oversize-folder"
                     >2</container>
               </did>
               <arrangement id="aspace_bf861a79e3846619899554b6ee470660">
                  <head>Arrangement note</head>
                  <p>The Personal Files are a series of subject files arranged alphabetically by
                     subject matter.</p>
               </arrangement>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_91420d05cad6c5375157000da2e8b0f3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Subjects include biographical and autobiographical information; certificates
                     and awards; Banham's collection of materials pertaining to British culture; her
                     favorite camera; legal documents regarding her change of citizenship; materials
                     relating to her courtship with J. W. Bridges; diaries from the 1940s to the
                     1980s; genealogical information about the Banham family; an oral history
                     interview and transcript done with Banham in 1980; journals written by Banham
                     as a part of a continuing education course; newsclippings; materials relating
                     to parties planned by Banham; photographs of family, friends, and colleagues;
                     poetry and other personal writings; recipes; taped recordings by her sister;
                     files related to Banham's religious life and research into retirement
                     accommodation; travel files including two file relating to the excavation she
                     participated in at Winchester, England; and materials she saved from the second
                     world war. The materials in this series are relevant for the perspective they
                     give into the nature of Banham's life when she was not working and her
                     lifestyle during her retirement.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
