<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="https://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uacsb/">uacsb</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Campus Social Board records, 1999
          <num>UA.31.12.0004</num></titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: Sherrie Bowser; machine-readable finding aid created by: Sherrie
          Bowser</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>2007</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003834330</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-03-23 11:11:32
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Campus Social Board records</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Campus Social Board</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>UA.31.12.0004</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1999/1999" type="inclusive">1999</unitdate>
      <physloc id="aspace_80bcff5646c0d057919f843f34748f38">For current information on the location
        of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
      <abstract id="aspace_84452ed64cb22a3536c1ad4ae1ae9803">The purpose of Campus Social Board was
        to "plan and organize innovative, nonalcoholic events that [were] open to and welcome[d]
        everyone on Duke's campus." Collection contains two copies of "Thinking Outside the Box:
        Ideas for Improving Student Life at Duke University." (1999) This report is the result of a
        survey of student opinions on campus social life.</abstract>
      <physdesc id="aspace_5e48a8cb5fd818217a72beb576bbba30"
        label="General Physical Description note"><extent>2 Items</extent></physdesc>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_c6968af5792f3fa9f4eefa447ac10208">Material in English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_9e3766e850ba01200214ac3c48f4c49f">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_8283f377dd4cf03d99cd11c1fbf63ad0">
      <head>Copyright Notice</head>
      <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Duke University; all other copyright
        is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as stipulated by
        United States copyright law.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_8f064185f6f05b6d78e63b5729e9f6e5">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Campus Social Board Records, Duke University Archives, David M.
        Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_d540cb9b3ca7739eb0e6d02e50cd46f8">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Campus Social Board records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in
        1999.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo id="aspace_6eb92c642bdc18e8bbc8432db0aa4fc4">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Sherrie Bowser, December 2007</p>
      <p>Encoded by Sherrie Bowser, December 2007</p>
      <p>Accession A99-14 is described in this finding aid. </p>
    </processinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_6da5cc9ed42cdc4e50f9a95fed5ddb11">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>taken from CSB homepage http://www.duke.edu/web/csb/</p>
      <p>Campus Social Board (CSB) was founded in September of 1997 by Brandon Busteed, Duke '99,
        then a Duke junior. The purpose of CSB was to "plan and organize innovative, nonalcoholic
        events that [were] open to and welcome[d] everyone on Duke's campus." The group was
        originally structured as a forum for student group representatives to plan and collaborate
        on social events. Communication, cooperation, idea exchange, and resource sharing were key
        functions and objectives of the original CSB. Although initial response to the CSB
        idea-sharing model was positive, it became increasingly evident that the group meetings were
        not accomplishing all that was necessary to improve campus life at Duke.</p>
      <p>In January of 1998, CSB moved into a new phase. Because it was clear that the original
        group forums were not adequate to achieve systemic change on campus, CSB adopted a new
        structure and redefined its mission. Thirteen full-time members were recruited, and the
        group embarked on an ambitious journey of "test" social events. The group decided that the
        only way to find out what social events were needed and wanted at Duke was to try them. A
        special emphasis was placed on organizing unique events and events that were either
        nonalcoholic or not dependent on alcohol. The events ranged from dance clubs to outdoor
        movies to comedy clubs, all held at different times in different places. Although some of
        the events were not successful, even the failures gave CSB great insight into social life at
        Duke and showed the members what changes needed to be made in the future.</p>
      <p>In the fall of 1998, CSB found itself at a crucial point on the higher education timeline.
        Colleges across the nation were facing similar problems stemming from alcohol use and lack
        of social interaction. Although these issues captured the attention of the nation, little
        was being done to combat the true problems. Reactive solutions like stricter alcohol
        policies became common, but little attention was being given to the true causes of the
        problems. New and creative social options were needed to attract the attention of students
        who by default had learned to rely on alcohol as the best social option on campuses that
        were far from vibrant. In essence, the entire country needed to focus on college life and
        help students redefine what college needed to be.</p>
      <p>For this reason, CSB designed and launched a major initiative created to examine social
        life at Duke and beyond. First, full-page ads ran in the campus newspaper, asking students
        to really think about their own ideas regarding social life and respond with comments and
        new ideas. Next, CSB members undertook a benchmarking project of twenty-five schools similar
        to Duke in an attempt to learn about social life elsewhere. A social space survey that
        garnered 1,800 responses was used to document the need for physical social space on campus.
        CSB members focused on individual long-term projects that focused the discussions about
        campus life several years down the road. Following this exhaustive look at where Duke was
        and where it needed to go, CSB compiled its results in a notebook that was presented to
        members of the Duke community at a brainstorming session in February of 1999. It was at this
        session that students, administrators, and faculty discussed the future of Duke and what
        would be needed to reinvent campus life.</p>
      <p>Following the local Duke conference, three CSB seniors organized a national conference held
        at Duke in March and also founded a new nonprofit organization designed to take the work of
        CSB to the national level. The nonprofit, CIRCLe Network (College Initiatives to Reinvent
        Campus Life), was publicly launched at the national conference, a gathering of student
        leaders and administrators working to define campus problems and come up with new solutions.
        The Campus Social Board is currently (2007) not an active student organization. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_525d4484419fad9b1f494c5b900b1648">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>Collection contains two copies of "Thinking Outside the Box: Ideas for Improving Student
        Life at Duke University." (1999) This report is the result of a survey of student opinions
        on campus social life.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Campus Social Board</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc.</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Students -- Social networks</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref14_pcx" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>"Thinking Outside the Box: Ideas for Improving Student Life at Duke
            University." (1999) (2 copies)</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_7fc19fc74be92bbf0a6b52f03b8ffd0a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
