<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uadulsa/">uadulsa</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Duke University Library Staff Association records, circa
               1969-2002 <num>UA.08.02.0005</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: University Archives Staff; finding aid derived from MARC record
               using DukeMARC2EAD_ua_record_groups.xsl</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003461530</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 23:28:54
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Duke University Library Staff Association records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="ingest">Duke University Library Staff Association</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>UA.08.02.0005</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1969/2002" type="inclusive">1969-2002</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_8a2b2c65f38d635037c62f7bc2c14d72">Minutes, agendas, announcements,
            committee files, flyers, planning documents, directories, newsletters, and other
            materials created and collected by DULSA, the Duke University Library Staff
            Association.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_068c3c244be0dc1fe4f986701fb9b4b5">Materials in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_123286f9e5e96d5186075df546b6c761">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>Library Committees records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
            &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
         <p>Duke University Library General records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein
            Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_2ae8439dd65fd6b9bddea21cdca83918">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing
            from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After
            twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission
            of the University Archivist. </p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use
            this collection.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <bioghist id="aspace_deba7290a1e81bcbc630a2cd3ef1ba3e">
         <head>Historical note</head>
         <p>The Duke University Libraries Staff Association (DULSA) was formed in May 1938 with the
            purpose of promoting "the development of social, recreational, and professional
            interests of the staff." Developed by interested staff members, the association was
            first named the Staff Association of the Duke University Libraries, and consisted of a
            president, vice-president, secretary-treasurer, and such committees as were considered
            useful and appropriate over time. Membership was initially open to all full-time staff
            who wished to join, and a system of dues was developed. Intended activities included one
            large social function per year as well as business meetings and program meetings, which
            would be informal in nature and as simple to organize as possible.</p>
         <p>From its inception, DULSA promoted employee interests to the University administration
            and the wider University community. Memorandums as early as 1940 lobbied for staff
            salary increases, benefits, retirement plans, a staff lounge, breaks, reasonable working
            hours and schedules, and professional development through classes and workshops. DULSA
            also initiated plans for library building projects and works with the Library Council to
            promote the interests of the staff. Staff bulletins were first published in 1939, and by
            the 1970s were a regular publication titled The Link. DULSA organized charitable efforts
            starting at the beginning of World War II by joining the Merchant Marine Library
            Association and later included Christmas projects, clothing donations to Korea,
            contributions to the North Carolina Library Association scholarship fund, and many
            others. Regular meetings and events were scheduled for employee entertainment and
            enrichment, including visiting speakers, the Lunch and Listen series begun in the 1960s,
            and others. DULSA also regularly engages in fundraising efforts, including the creation
            and sale of a cookbook in 1971. In the 1990s, DULSA formed a Parking Task Force to
            address the Library's interests in campus parking issues.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <userestrict id="aspace_8c2912790140d85d59b0f2a2bb59ccac">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>Copyright for official university records is held by Duke University; all other
            copyright is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as
            stipulated by United States copyright law.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_22e9b54a9bf2919da9b335892db68550">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], in the Duke University Library Staff Association records, Duke
            University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke
            University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_b3cc2c2ba865ca9efb3f6a68d74af7ae">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Initial inventory by Tracy M. Jackson, December 2014. Materials not yet processed.</p>
         <p>Accessions described in this finding aid: UA2005.0053, UA2014.0087.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_0b382805a9195d9986806f0887d89016">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Minutes, agendas, correspondence, financial records, announcements, committee files,
            flyers, planning documents, directories, newsletters, and other materials created and
            collected by DULSA, the Duke University Library Staff Association. Includes a detailed
            history of DULSA from its founding through the 1960s, correspondence related to library
            employee wage and status advocacy, a cookbook produced in the 1970s, materials related
            to "Lunch and Look" and "Lunch and Listen" events from the 1960s and 1970s, and
            financial records, including receipts, bank statements, a ledger, and other materials,
            for DULSA's operations, including dues and events. Also included are some meeting
            minutes, correspondence, brochures, parking maps, clippings, and notes related to the
            parking situation on campus near the libraries and for library staff, as part of the
            work of the Parking Task Force.</p>
         <p>Materials remain in their original housing and order, and have not been arranged.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_af436d77030ce2dfbeaa735b503bef7e">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Duke University Library Staff Association records were received by the David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library as transfers in 2005, 2014.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Campus parking -- North Carolina -- Durham</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Wages -- College employees -- North Carolina -- Durham</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Employee morale -- North Carolina -- Durham.</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Library employees -- North Carolina -- Durham.</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Incentive awards -- North Carolina -- Durham.</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges -- Employees -- Salaries, etc.</subject>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University Library Staff Association</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Perkins Library</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University Library Staff Association</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref25_xnb" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>DULSA records</unittitle>
               <unitdate normal="1969/2002" type="inclusive">1969-2002</unitdate>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_6eu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Accession (UA2005.0053)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1969/1980" type="inclusive">1969-1980</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_2c78a472532903c44ac8654d6a91574c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_5ebc0ec335b716d12f88c8f56cec7bf3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_cc06cc10b4076e6c275aefc90f17cece">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Minutes, agendas, announcements, committee files, flyers, planning documents,
                     directories, newsletters, and other materials created and collected by DULSA,
                     the Duke University Library Staff Association. Includes a detailed history of
                     DULSA from its founding through the 1960s, correspondence related to library
                     employee wage and status advocacy, a cookbook produced in the 1970s, and
                     materials related to "Lunch and Look" and "Lunch and Listen" events from the
                     1960s and 1970s, among other materials.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_6e0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Accession (UA2005.0054)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1986/2002" type="inclusive">1986-2002</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_06a49be72428a13d1ac246d972052f9b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_19b10b90506d98a183098683c05d6e35">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Financial records, including receipts, bank statements, a ledger, and other
                     materials, for DULSA's operations, including dues and events. Also included are
                     some meeting minutes and correspondence.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_mft" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Accession (UA2005.0073): Parking Task Force</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1996/2000" type="inclusive">1996-2000</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_d7ee7b7446e5c58dea79c63572e2dc23" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bbfdc2c2b3f99276860a00c8c7c3d004">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Correspondence, brochures, parking maps, clippings, and notes related to the
                     parking situation on campus near the libraries and for library staff as part of
                     the work of the Parking Task Force.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
