<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uafaculty/">uafaculty</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Faculty Records, 1911-1986 <num>UA.28.01.0009</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Jane Veronica Charles; machine-readable finding aid created by:
               Kimberly Sims</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003839293</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-30 03:47:01
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Faculty records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Faculty</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>UA.28.01.0009</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.5 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1911/1986" type="inclusive">1911-1986</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_e8ae77df3abd95a014c348c6d5ea1ca4">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_ddbff34527e13cb284f9c92add5fef9d">The responsibilities of faculty
            members, in addition to planning classes and providing instruction, included enacting
            regulations necessary to carry out instruction, advance the standards of work, and
            develop the scholarly aims of the school. The Faculty also recommended degree candidates
            and persons worthy of receiving academic distinction to the trustees. The records
            document administrative and academic concerns of university faculty members and officers
            from 1911-1986. They consist of bound volumes of minutes, reports, memoranda, agendas,
            and correspondence. The records also include a few invitations, proposals,
            announcements, newsletters, and newspaper clippings.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_2a892a8e78f51096a9889fd862850085">
            <extent>about 4,000 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_b3f4027b2bded02350ddb5520a4b2433">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_38c61e45c73d3db6312cb39fbff77be0">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>Excepting publicly distributed material, for a period of twenty-five (25) years from the
            origin of the records, permission in writing from the director of the office of record
            and the University Archivist is required for use.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_29738bbe51c9830c50fac56e0842f216">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Duke University; all other
            copyright is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as
            stipulated by United States copyright law.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_47e7e158184a9b59830cd1465b183edd">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Faculty Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein
            Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_4f436ae3538b18fcc353c535fa8a6adf">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Faculty Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in
            1955-1989.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_7274728fda70c9cd7b9181b1c6a636a6">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Jane Veronica Charles, Summer 2000</p>
         <p>Encoded by Kimberly Sims, January 2008</p>
         <p>Accessions A48-2256, A60-203, A73-152, A73-154, A73-155, A74-4, A75-58, A77-180, A79-27,
            A79-76, A80-71, A88-30, and A89-89 were merged into one collection, described in this
            finding aid. </p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_cfe88c7073d12c45617a556c14d0e7f7">
         <head>Historical Note</head>
         <p>In its meeting of January 8, 1892, the Board of Trustees of Trinity College appointed a
            committee to "to collect and prepare a system of Rules, regulations and by-laws for the
            government of the College." In this first set of bylaws, the Faculty of Trinity College
            was defined to consist of "Professors, Assistant Professor and Instructors." The Faculty
            was to assist the President "in the work of instruction, administration, and
            discipline." Ten years later, the Trustees requested President John C. Kilgo to draw up
            new bylaws for the school. In the Constitution and Bylaws of 1903, the Faculty was
            defined to consist of all professors, adjunct professors, and instructors elected by the
            Board of Trustees or its Executive Committee.</p>
         <p> The responsibilities of faculty members, in addition to planning classes and providing
            instruction, included enacting regulations necessary to carry out instruction, advance
            the standards of work, and develop the scholarly aims of the school. The Faculty also
            recommended degree candidates and persons worthy of receiving academic distinction to
            the trustees. The president nominated all members of the faculty, represented them at
            public meetings of the university, and called and presided at faculty meetings. The
            president had to approve all actions of the Faculty, and could veto any action by it,
            but had to submit his reasons to them in writing. When Duke University was founded in
            1924, the trustees amended the University's Bylaws only slightly. The Faculty then
            consisted of all professors, associate professors, assistant professors, and instructors
            elected by the Board of Trustees or its Executive Committee. All other definitions and
            responsibilities of faculty members remained the same. Beginning in 1936 the term
            "General Faculty" is used in the Bylaws. Members of the General Faculty were responsible
            for both instruction and research. Each of the colleges, graduate and professional
            schools had their own faculties with deans elected by the trustees. Each faculty had
            authority to carry out any educational functions within its field. In the Bylaws of 1952
            the General Faculty is defined as the president, secretary of the university, officers
            whom the president designated as primarily responsible for instruction and research,
            full instructors or above engaged in work for which university degrees were awarded, and
            faculty emeriti. </p>
         <p> President Few renamed the Undergraduate Council the General Faculty Council at a
            meeting held on October 28, 1937. According to the 1952 Bylaws, the General Faculty
            Council consisted of the deans and assistant deans of Trinity College and the Woman's
            College, the dean of the Graduate School, and the secretary of the General Faculty.
            Membership also included the chairman and director of undergraduate studies in each
            department offering instruction in the undergraduate colleges of liberal arts and
            sciences, as well as one member elected by each department that had five or more
            teachers giving instruction in arts and sciences. The General Faculty Council met once
            per month. They discussed curriculum in arts and sciences as well as concerns about
            education and policies. </p>
         <p> Although the goals, responsibilities, and membership of the General Faculty remained
            constant throughout the years, by 1952 the term "University Faculty" had come into use
            instead. In addition to the definitions and responsibilities of the Faculty from
            previous years, in the 1952 bylaws the Faculty was also expected to promote faculty and
            student welfare; consult with and advise the president on matters of general university
            policy; and receive information about the affairs of the university. The President
            served as chairman of the Faculty and the Secretary of the University served as Faculty
            secretary. The Faculty met regularly in October and February as well as before the June
            commencement. They also met by request of the president, of the vice-president in the
            division of education, or of twenty members of the Faculty. </p>
         <p> As stated in the 1952 Bylaws, the Council on Undergraduate Teaching consisted of deans
            and assistant deans of Trinity College, the Woman's College, the College of Engineering,
            other officers and appointed members, and teachers of all ranks who devoted fifty
            percent or more of their time to undergraduate instruction. The Council's goals involved
            improving the quality and efficiency of teaching. The Council had the right to take any
            action necessary to secure these goals. The Council on Undergraduate Teaching is
            interchangeably referred to as the Council on Undergraduate Instruction. The origin of
            the Council dates back to at least 1934. </p>
         <p> Only a few minor changes affecting the definition of the Faculty have occurred in the
            Bylaws since then. In the Bylaws of 1962, the provost, vice presidents, secretary,
            registrar, and university librarian were included in the University Faculty. Other
            changes in the bylaws over the years have provided for the carrying out of the Faculty's
            functions through appropriate councils, committees, and other bodies. These have
            included a Faculty Council (to oversee educational matters beyond the purview of the
            individual school's faculties), a Council on Undergraduate Teaching, a Council on the
            Instruction of Freshmen, and other committees. </p>
         <p> Governance and Advisory Councils: As the institution developed President William
            Preston Few prevailed upon the trustees to organize into committees so that Board
            members could become more knowledgeable about and involved. Still, during Few's
            administration he, Vice President and Treasurer Robert Lee Flowers and Dean of the
            University William H. Wannamaker made decisions on matters of general university policy
            subject to board approval. This pattern continued after Few's death, despite several
            formal and informal requests from faculty for more involvement in governance. During and
            after World War II, some faculty began to actively seek a greater role. In 1946 and
            again in 1948, our AAUP chapter petitioned the trustees for permission to form a faculty
            senate that would exercise legislative power. The Board tabled these requests. </p>
         <p> Then, in 1950, the newly appointed President, Arthur Hollis Edens, convened a committee
            to study the organization of the faculty. This "General Faculty's Commission on Faculty
            Reorganization" submitted its report in 1952, and the Trustees revised the University
            Bylaws to incorporate some of its recommendations. In the revisions, the organization
            and responsibilities of the faculty were laid out in specific detail. The 1952 Bylaws
            also created a faculty-administrative liaison committee called the University Council
            (q.v.) as a standing committee of the General Faculty. The University Council acted as
            an advisory body on matters of general University policy and interest. The revisions
            also created an Undergraduate Faculty Council and an Engineering Faculty Council to
            oversee undergraduate instruction. </p>
         <p> In the 1962 revision of the University Bylaws, the Board of Trustees gave the faculty
            authority to organize itself as it wished, thereby doing away with the very formal
            structures of 1952. A report in March 1962 by the University Faculty's Committee on
            Faculty Organization recommended formation of the Academic Council. The University
            Policy Advisory Committee was also formed as a successor to the University Council. For
            additional information about the history, structure and function of the Academic
            Council, see Professor Don Fluke's history, in the Council's records here. </p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_0c72edfce6ba20ab8a670fd321a96ce6">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Members of various faculty councils, committees, and governing bodies of Trinity College
            and Duke University created these records between 1911 and 1986. The records document
            administrative and academic concerns of university faculty members and officers during
            this period of time. The records consist of bound volumes of minutes of the General
            Faculty (also referred to as the Faculty and later renamed the University Faculty),
            General Faculty Council, and the Council on Undergraduate Teaching (also called the
            Council on Undergraduate Instruction), along with folders of other material. The bulk
            consists of minutes, reports, memoranda, agendas, and correspondence. </p>
         <p> These records reflect the actions of the following university bodies: the Commission on
            Faculty Reorganization, the Council on Undergraduate Teaching, the (General) Faculty
            Council, Faculty Meetings, the Faculty Organizational Committee, the Faculty Standing
            Committee on the Curricula, and University Faculty Minutes. These records contain the
            same types of documents as those found in the bound volumes; however, they also contain
            a few invitations, proposals, announcements, newsletters, and newspaper clippings. </p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_120518c8d203131a30b8ac6c5a42a64f">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>
            <archref>
               <unittitle label="Collection">Faculty Reference Collection</unittitle>
               <repository label="Repository">Duke University Archives</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle label="Collection">Undergraduate Faculty Council of Arts and Sciences
                  Records</unittitle>
               <repository label="Repository">Duke University Archives</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle label="Collection">Faculty Club of Duke University Records</unittitle>
               <repository label="Repository">Duke University Archives</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle label="Collection">Faculty Census Reports</unittitle>
               <repository label="Repository">Duke University Archives</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle label="Collection">Undergraduate Faculty Council Records</unittitle>
               <repository label="Repository">Duke University Archives</repository>
            </archref>
         </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Committees</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Faculty</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Faculty -- History</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. General Faculty Council</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Faculty Standing Committee on
            Curricula</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Faculty</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Council on Undergraduate Teaching</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Faculty Organizational Committee</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Commission on Faculty Reorganization</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Council on Undergraduate Instruction</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref13_yyy" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Minutes of Faculty Meetings, 1911-1986</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_22cdce02a95a4df60715ff59c748743b">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>
                  <emph render="bold">Minutes of the Faculty of Trinity College, 1911-1923</emph>
               </p>
               <p> Issues that pervaded the recorded minutes include standing committees,
                  scheduling, funding, student petitions (to drop or substitute classes, for
                  example), examinations, commencement, debates over graduation attire, fraternity
                  regulations, scholarship regulations, extension work, academic requirements,
                  committee appointments, new courses, grading, degree candidates, publications,
                  graduate instruction and research. </p>
               <p> The committees that the faculty served on include courses of instruction,
                  admission, athletics, debating, executive, health and boarding halls, library,
                  publications, public lectures and musical organizations, schedule, social
                  organizations, and student life. </p>
               <p> Other topics include absences or "cuts" from class, literary societies, memorial
                  statements for recently deceased professors, the establishment of Phi Beta Kappa,
                  concerns for Freshman and Sophomores (e.g., grades, distribution of work, etc.),
                  the Glee Club, and lectures from visiting professors from universities such as the
                  University of Chicago, Yale, and Johns Hopkins. The college catalogue, compulsory
                  chapel exercises, cheating, honors, awards (the Wiley Grey and Braxton Craven
                  Medals), the North Carolina Teachers Assembly, Watts Hospital, delegates sent to
                  North Carolina Forestry Association in Raleigh, composition requirements, honorary
                  degrees, student advisors, the Chanticleer, graduate students and athletics,
                  summer school, and alumni reunions make-up additional topics. </p>
               <p> Still others are the abolishment of the valedictory, delegates for the
                  Association of Colleges and Schools of Southern States and the National Collegiate
                  Association, the North Carolina Conference, military drills, accommodations for
                  students leaving for World War I, salary increases, new courses, thesis
                  requirements for Masters degrees, R.O.T.C. courses, and the Durham homecoming
                  celebration for soldiers. The North Carolina Academy of Science, the Roosevelt
                  Memorial Fund, admission of students from junior colleges, tutors for freshman,
                  the grading system, Social Hygiene meetings, curriculum considerations, the
                  National Convention in International Disarmament, representatives for National
                  Conference on Standards of Colleges and Prep Schools, requirements for graduation,
                  entrance requirements, sabbaticals, holidays, Board of Trustees, and committee on
                  moving pictures compose further topics that faculty grappled with during their
                  many meetings, over which President Few presided. </p>
               <p> The few items in the two folders containing loose materials include reports,
                  letters from students and collegiate organizations, and in-house notes that
                  pertain to some of the same subjects listed above. </p>
               <p>
                  <emph render="bold">Minutes of the Faculty, Trinity College and Duke University,
                     1923-1943</emph>
               </p>
               <p> Many of the same issues, including student petitions, grades, and various
                  committee business engaged faculty members during these years. Additional concerns
                  of the faculty during this period involve opening Duke University, better training
                  of high school teachers, protocol for commencement, Saturday courses for teachers,
                  adoption of mid-term examinations, a study revealing that women were behind in
                  Math, honor system violations, certification of teachers, new programs, budget, a
                  speech about Benjamin Duke, and cap and gowns. The Robert E. Lee Prize, Duke
                  Memorial Fund, grade uniformity, Bible and Math requirements, parking,
                  reorganization of faculties, combined arts-law degree, the Dean's list,
                  undergraduate guidance department, University Chest Drive, dedication to President
                  Few, and death of President Few are topics that prevailed during this time period.
                  President Few presided. </p>
               <p>
                  <emph render="bold">Minutes of the General Faculty, 1944-1952</emph>
               </p>
               <p> The volumes in this category contain the same kinds of minutes, correspondence,
                  and reports as in the other categories. The Minutes of the General Faculty also
                  contain documents about the same subjects as found in the Minutes of the Faculty
                  and Faculty Council. Other issues include the relationship between faculty and
                  trustees, American Association of University Professors, retirement annuities,
                  suspension of classes for events, and faculty reorganization reports. President
                  Flowers presided. </p>
               <p>
                  <emph render="bold">Minutes of the University Faculty, 1952-1955</emph>
               </p>
               <p> This series of documents contains the same types of material and subject matter
                  as the other series on University Faculty minutes. Additional issues of relevance
                  here involve the structure of the University Council, academic salaries, and a
                  report of the University Council to the University Faculty. Other topics worthy of
                  note include the secret ballot for an honorary degree for Richard M. Nixon;
                  elections for University Council; president's reports (housekeeping, buildings,
                  finances, enrollment, etc.); off campus centers such as Highland Hospital in
                  Asheville and Duke Marine Lab in Beaufort; President Edens' wish to improve
                  cooperation with neighboring universities (NCSU, UNC, and the Woman's College of
                  UNC) via library cooperation; desegregation (President Edens advocated making a
                  small gesture towards desegregation in 1954 after Brown vs. Board of Education);
                  and medical insurance for the faculty. President Edens presided. </p>
               <p>
                  <emph render="bold">Minutes of the University Faculty, 1955-1969</emph>
               </p>
               <p> Again, the types of materials and subject matter of the correspondence, minutes,
                  and reports in this series overlap with that of the other records. Additional
                  topics include reports of the president on issues such as the need to revamp
                  Duke's policy on segregation, cooperation with southeastern liberal arts colleges
                  via the 3-2 program, the new golf course, new faculty housing, enrollment
                  problems, Faculty Handbook, new degree proposals, graduate school enrollment,
                  college visitation program-traveling faculty members, national recognition
                  (ranking), training inter-national students, faculty involvement in international
                  organizations, international research, religious preferences, long range planning
                  reports, and university expansion. Additional subjects include tuition awards for
                  children of faculty, promotion of Duke University, improvement of public
                  relations, varying views of different presidents on goals of university, awarding
                  Richard M. Nixon Doctor of Laws, tenure, need of facilities, Bylaws, academic
                  freedom, regrouping of departments into divisions, applicants admitted to Duke
                  regardless of race, creed, or national origin in 1962, Academic Council, faculty
                  benefits, Faculty Club, 1968 student vigil and strike by employees in Operations
                  Hall and Dining Halls foments awareness of need for appreciation among faculty,
                  the advancement program, and committee on University Employee relationships to
                  support non-academic employees. In 1969 there was an African American student
                  sit-in in the Central Records Office (Allen Building) that incited much debate
                  among faculty during a meeting. Presidents Edens, Hart, and Knight presided. </p>
               <p>
                  <emph render="bold">University Faculty Minutes, 1969-1986</emph>
               </p>
               <p> Reports, minutes, agendas, and correspondence make-up the bulk of the documents
                  housed in these folders. Topics include degree candidates, programs, the Faculty
                  Handbook, committee appointments, faculty elections, memorials, the Academic
                  Council, a presidential address, and faculty newsletters </p>
               <p>
                  <emph render="bold">Faculty Meetings, 1932-1978</emph>
               </p>
               <p> Correspondence, agendas, meeting minutes, memos, newspaper clippings, and reports
                  are housed in these folders. Participants in faculty meetings reported to the
                  General Faculty. The General Faculty appointed faculty to committees, such as the
                  committee of undergraduate curriculum. The University Faculty determines degree
                  candidates, honorary degrees, curriculum, etc. </p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_f10" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the Faculty, Trinity College, 1911-1916</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_873a0bf3dbbdd78da65a751c2f04ddb3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_vbl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the Faculty, Trinity College, 1916-1920</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_073da535434967938e7af5bb266a117c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_11x" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the Faculty, Trinity College, 1920-1923</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_77baaacff64b41fdd924e58e3dca95c6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_t1l" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the Faculty Meetings, Trinity College/Duke University,
                     1923-1928</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c628a7250039dc12747342ed983e5ace" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref18_b9w" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the Faculty Meetings, Duke University, 1928-1933</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c165f70746e7981ea4d695967cb320ee" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref19_shl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the Faculty Meetings (General), Duke University,
                     1933-1943</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_114f90404c3310818d27e3a37c4401be" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_mi8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the General Faculty, Duke University, 1943-1951</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_dc040b28eb4d91544726cd3fc93ecaf3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_dps" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of General Faculty Meetings-Loose Material,
                     1911-1920</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_34e19d3b536f75125bbafac9bb98af0b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_utx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of General Faculty Meetings-Loose Material,
                     1920-1923</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e6e93ad9f17e06269150acf3e59aebc4" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref23_mvl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faculty Meetings, 1932-1969</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9722ff8aeb34bc10db1cd98433dc6f76" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_yva" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the General Faculty, Duke University, 1951-1952</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f2f5adea7d292ab0a4001358dd282b94" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_2te" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the University Faculty, Duke University,
                     1952-1955</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6e3c46cbe635b782415e66c8fca9202a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_5n1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the University Faculty, Duke University,
                     1955-1960</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_864109a691fd10b5352c3a02b6669ced" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_pia" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the University Faculty, Duke University,
                     1960-1964</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c83788460f195eaea88a2ee7a6b5af49" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_dmf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the University Faculty, Duke University,
                     1964-1969</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5e292f98d8208808c5475bf64dd37dd5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_vsq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>University Faculty Minutes, 1969-1970</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_7368820cafd98dfced0b4698f82e0866" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_6vk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>University Faculty Minutes, 1971-1972</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_054e4aff01ed3f3bf23297daac46e9ea" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_7kj" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>University Faculty Minutes, 1972-1976</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ee119616f02c3dde7864bd44d43faf29" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_nuk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>University Faculty Minutes, 1977-1981</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b22340653bfe0c1d54971fa822ba5212" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref33_04k" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>University Faculty Minutes, 1982-1986</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c6d4d84212df337a4bc695603e82938d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref34_z7v" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faculty Meetings, 1970-1978</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_81989fece54aee927f021dfac8296e38" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref36_3xt" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Records of the Faculty Council, 1932-1951</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_2b8b0162d78d5bceee76fce675b8791a">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>
                  <emph render="bold">Minutes of the General Faculty Council, 1932-1951</emph>
               </p>
               <p> Meeting minutes as well as glued-in correspondence and reports compose the
                  minutes of the General Faculty Council. The same subjects found throughout the
                  pages of the Faculty Meetings are found in these records. The General Faculty
                  Council came into existence by order of President Few in 1937, when he changed the
                  name of the Undergraduate Council, which was also known informally as the Faculty
                  Council, to the General Faculty Council. </p>
               <p> Records concern the Woman's College, deficiency in writing, the function of the
                  council, course listings, formation of the General Faculty Council, reorganization
                  of departments into divisions, lengthening the teaching day, visiting
                  professors-goal involved getting information from them regarding opportunities in
                  American colleges for above average students, and a memoriam for President Few.
                  President Few and Dean Wannamaker presided over these meetings. Other topics
                  include the bookstore, curriculum acceleration, language requirements, freshman
                  achievement and test scores, creation of department of aesthetics, "War Day
                  Exercises," military duty, U.S. military Institute and correspondence college
                  courses, credit for Naval courses, opening of and enrollment in Woman's College,
                  problem with returning service men (credit/graduation), admission of veterans,
                  special veterans services, committee on recognition of retiring faculty, and
                  instituting a degree program for nursing. In addition, the Faculty Council was
                  concerned with class over-crowding, Duke University Day, the no smoking rule,
                  Founders Day, the national situation of American universities, religious emphasis
                  week, and selective service tests. </p>
               <p>
                  <emph render="bold">Faculty Council, 1940-1952</emph>
               </p>
               <p> Correspondence, memoranda, reports, meeting minutes, and agendas. Topics include
                  the teaching load, new courses, curricula, cheating, air science courses, special
                  committees, honorary retiring faculty members, absences, the student rating of
                  professors poll, catalogue, salary studies, finals, parking, attendance, and
                  homecoming. </p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref37_4t3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the General Faculty Council, Duke University,
                     1932-1941</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e33bd1be5fda1c0b741efa4061f026f3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref38_xua" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the Faculty Council, Duke University, 1941-1946</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_485efd30c19b38356333c4321ffeafb5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref39_1jc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the Faculty Council, Duke University, 1946-1951</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0a3b74930d29ce77e5a44b0aa19a8fe5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref40_r45" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faculty Council, 1940-1952</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_98bf4ccc6ca52f07986ff3e842099fe5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref42_ydy" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Committee Records, 1930-1934</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_c2cf451425320a222284b55521a2e061">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>This series contains foldered and bound records created by various faculty
                  committees.</p>
               <p>
                  <emph render="bold">A. Freshman Council and Freshman Faculty, 1930-1934</emph>
               </p>
               <p> Minutes, 1930-1934: Typed and hand-written minutes and reports on a system for
                  reporting absences from class, the campus mail system, extra-curricular
                  activities, freshman dormitories, fraternities, physical education, grading
                  systems, faculty-student relations, examination schedules and related subjects.
                  President Few and Dean Wannamaker attended the Council's meetings from time to
                  time.</p>
               <p>
                  <emph render="bold">B. Council on Undergraduate Teaching</emph>
               </p>
               <p> Minutes, 1934-1949: Reports and meeting minutes on class size, scholarships,
                  study time, tentative degree candidates, student petitions, student publications,
                  educational research (promotion of student scholarship), homecoming, commencement,
                  quality of teaching in prep schools, conference with high school principals,
                  student etiquette (concern with "boot-licking"), grade distribution, cheating,
                  course adjustments, honors, library book accessibility, grade curve, "block
                  system" for exams, absences, future course offerings, scholastic records,
                  placement tests, the Council on Undergraduate Teaching, summer school, lecture
                  system, break-down of grades for all departments, and evaluation of grades and
                  instruction are among the many topics included here. The following committees made
                  decisions: calendar, curriculum, student-faculty relations, schedule, problems of
                  teaching, extra-curricular activities, and other matters. Dean Wannamaker and
                  President Few presided. </p>
               <p> Miscellaneous records, 1934-1947: Materials include agendas, reports, memoranda,
                  questionnaires, and correspondence. Main topics include divisional committees,
                  freshman and sophomore class size, class periods, class schedules, public
                  lectures, examination periods, the grading system, junior and senior courses, and
                  degree requirements. Additional topics also are grade distribution, "cuts," number
                  of freshman, scholarship statistics, vacations, committee lists and nominees,
                  advanced courses, the bookstore, student-faculty relations, the honor system,
                  professional ethics, undergraduate publications, and research. Other issues
                  addressed included transportation, curriculum problems, evaluations of admission,
                  failure, and achievement, the Woman's College, holidays, naval training or the
                  V-12 program, the library, athletics, cheating, and the honor code. Topics remain
                  constant throughout the years. The Report of the Committee on "Adequate Student
                  Guidance," (folder 6) represents an analysis of guidance methods as applicable to
                  undergraduate liberal arts college. The report includes definitions, a needs
                  assessment, and sections on areas of guidance, testing, counseling, and criteria
                  for effective counseling. Tables include testing data for Duke freshman, analysis
                  of personal problems, and reasons for academic difficulty, all based on data
                  collected via questionnaires. </p>
               <p>
                  <emph render="bold">C. Faculty Committee on the Teaching Load of Instructors,
                     1940</emph>
               </p>
               <p> Reports and minutes about the enrollment of students in various university
                  departments are housed in this folder.</p>
               <p>
                  <emph render="bold">D. Faculty Standing Committee on the Curricula,
                     1941-1946</emph>
               </p>
               <p> Materials include correspondence, minutes, reports, proposals, memoranda, and
                  agendas. Topics are degree program requirements, administration of curricula,
                  guidance, admission requirements, honors, fellowships, freshman advisors, and
                  academic probation. Note: Folders 19-20 contain the loose materials, dated
                  1911-1923, from the bound volumes of the Minutes of the General Faculty Meetings,
                  Trinity College.</p>
               <p>
                  <emph render="bold">E. Commission on Faculty Reorganization, 1951-1952</emph>
               </p>
               <p> Materials include agendas, correspondence, meeting minutes, and reports. A report
                  on the chronology of the committee's work and an investigating sub-committee
                  report are housed here. </p>
               <p>
                  <emph render="bold">F. Faculty Organization Committee, 1951-1962</emph>
               </p>
               <p> Document types: reports with cover letters. The contents of this folder include a
                  1951 Report of the Commission on Faculty Reorganization to the General Faculty of
                  Duke. It lists and discusses the chronology of the commission's work, and includes
                  recommendations for the University Faculty, the University Council, the
                  Undergraduate Faculty Council, the graduate school faculty, the engineering
                  faculty school, and the faculties of the professional schools. This report also
                  includes alternative plans for selecting members of the University Council. The
                  additional two reports dated 1962 deal with the same issue in a similar way, and
                  include cover letters. </p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_d6a" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Council on Undergraduate Teaching-Minutes (v.), 1934-1941</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_dd9823997e90fdb9f63947eee1234cae" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref44_t6l" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Council on Undergraduate Teaching-Minutes, 1941-1949</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b814ba392cbc10ecff974326198deb35" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref45_qxo" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Council on Undergraduate Teaching-Miscellaneous, 1934-1935</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3e8d841f59994f4d79fb4544bcd4aaf5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref46_56x" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Council on Undergraduate Teaching-Miscellaneous, 1935-1936</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a530b7e80fc2e3435f3be57ca95bf81f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_f8y" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Council on Undergraduate Teaching-Miscellaneous, 1937-1979</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a317b7bdf194fb250a274d393056f228" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref48_egf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Council on Undergraduate Teaching-Committee Report, undated (circa
                     1930s)</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_de19c766a75882c6c844cd07e795e080" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref49_8du" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faculty-Committee on the Teaching Load of Instructors, 1940</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_81fa7d64731e9d5ccf44fe3b17b711cd" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref50_i3e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faculty-Standing Committee on the Curricula, 1941-1946</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_17835d35590a5890dd941c416f9eacae" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref51_0sq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faculty-Standing Committee on the Curricula-Chairman,
                     1941-1942</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6c095af3b06032fe767464815ba8b790" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref52_do3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faculty-Standing Committee on the Curricula-Secretary,
                     1941-1942</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3b63023c2706d824fda8f54affcc434a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref53_ux5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Commission on Faculty Reorganization, 1951-1952</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_92f3de9879a5915fee387717759a5277" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref54_mq0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faculty Organization Committee, 1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3f097c04adb5df70027fcbdf7642156d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref56_67x" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Mailings and Miscellaneous Records, 1930-1979</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_dd8a5838e7c4dcf3ffb0fdecaac6d53f">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Miscellaneous memoranda, reports, notes, and other records apparently distributed
                  to the faculty, 1940-1979. Materials include correspondence, newspaper clippings,
                  announcements, memoranda, invitations, minutes, and reports. Topics include:
                  applying for grants, the Academic Senate, new degree programs, honoraria, faculty
                  publications, freshman concerns, family educational rights, international
                  students, regulations for final exams and honor systems, degree candidate lists,
                  post-war international problems, salary, commencement, long-range planning, the
                  Woman's Student government Association, Bylaws, University Religious Council,
                  segregation, attendance policies for undergraduates, and cooperative arrangements
                  between Duke and UNC. Another subject involves the appointments of the University
                  Executive Committee, the various departments, new faculty members and tenured
                  faculty.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref57_f2c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faculty-Miscellaneous records, 1930-1953</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2c041c6ced201f28cccdc80c1159ec1d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref58_7ul" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faculty-Miscellaneous records, 1954-1963</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_695f8b7d937b61a0361d6217e4038196" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref59_1dc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faculty-Miscellaneous records, 1964-1974</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_834ea680c64d34a13ffe96b66b9ce492" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref60_tx0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faculty-Miscellaneous records, 1975-1979</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a94142f3220a17b90e56008fbec5c3ef" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
