<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uafodc/">uafodc</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Friends of Duke Chapel Records, 1973 - 1999
                  <num>UA.17.03.0001</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Sarah G. Carr; machine-readable finding aid created by: Jill
               Katte</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003396366</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-30 01:47:28
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Friends of Duke Chapel records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="ingest">Friends of Duke Chapel</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>UA.17.03.0001</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1973/1999" type="inclusive">1973 - 1999</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_52805939bc904dc7460b538ab66f1be0">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult University Archives, Duke
            University.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_6ad6d29563b0e106ce1ea650a5b5007f">The Friends of Duke Chapel was
            founded in 1974 to provide the means for interested persons to organize into an ongoing,
            supportive, participatory group to support the ministry and program of Duke Chapel. The
            records consist of correspondence, official letters to members, advisory board and
            committee minutes and reports, newsletters, and other organization publications.
            Materials are present from 1973 to 1999. English.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_6ef86714c9b274bf68d126af6f27abef">
            <extent>1000 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_657fff4cc8964d3c4d8da08c808d2e36">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_4ed0ace344eeeec0466fc345ddfad507">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>No restrictions.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_de8a44ec581b2b44e5a19d0aaec324c7">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Duke University; all other
            copyright is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as
            stipulated by United States copyright law.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_14fe6a2938ff4e440e3bbfd895b22648">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Friends of Duke Chapel Records, Duke University Archives,
            David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_4cf65ef592d1378b34bbfb4efb6fc469">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Friends of Duke Chapel Records were received by the University Archives as a
            transfer in 1979-1994.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_9ff1d8f6ce7e36e83535dc0855d4881d">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Sarah G. Carr in March 2000. Reduced from 2 document boxes (1.4 linear
            feet) to 1 document box (.7 linear feet). Discarded duplicate copies of correspondence,
            newsletters, and minutes. Removed documents from metal clasp binders and refoldered all
            documents into acid-free folders. Photocopied news clippings and material on highly
            acidic paper onto acid-free bond paper. </p>
         <p>Encoded by Jill Katte, September 2003</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_f4a294e5c2afe93766b97721becd251b">
         <head>Historical Note</head>
         <p>The Friends of Duke Chapel was founded in 1974 to provide the means for interested
            persons to organize into an ongoing, supportive, participatory group to support the
            ministry and program of Duke Chapel. The Friends open membership to anyone interested in
            the Chapel and its program. It grew out of a predecessor group called the Full
            Membership Chapel Group, organized under and continuing the name of Duke University
            Church (Interdenominational). Full Members supported the Chapel program but membership
            was limited to persons affiliated with the University either as faculty or staff. As
            part of its mission, the Friends of Duke Chapel provide funds to aid numerous aspects of
            the Chapel program such as the chapel choir, organ, vestments, renovation needs, and
            provision of televised services. Membership benefits included weekly mailing of the
            Sunday bulletin, announcements and invitations to services, concerts, and music
            programs, as well as a Friends of Duke Chapel newsletter. </p>
         <p> The Friends have continuously helped fund and contribute to numerous initiatives and
            renovations of the Chapel, including the construction of a handicapped ramp access to
            the Chapel, installation of the Flentrop organ, and providing televised access to the
            Sunday services for patients at Duke Medical Center. They also contributed to enriching
            the preaching and theologian-in-residence programs. </p>
         <p> An Advisory Board governs the group. Originally a nine-person board, it was enlarged to
            a thirteen person board in 1981, always including the Dean of the Chapel. Past board
            members include William Stokes, Helen Crotwell, Jack Blackburn, Arthur Kale, William
            King, Ella Jean Shore, Carolyn Penny, and Mary Parkerson, who became the first Friends
            Director in 1980. </p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_0a37ba408ffb4bc29fefdeb271fbb952">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>These records were produced by the Friends of Duke Chapel in the course of their
            activities as a support organization for the program of Duke Chapel. Materials are
            present from 1973 to 1999. The bulk of the records consists of correspondence, official
            letters to members, advisory board and committee minutes and reports, newsletters, and
            other organization publications. There is some material not directly produced by the
            Friends of Duke Chapel but mentions the organization in its publications, or deals with
            the history of Duke Chapel.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_dac238c1bb21088d86536e396d4dfa3a">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>
            <archref>
               <unittitle>Duke University Church records.</unittitle>
               <repository>University Archives, Duke University. </repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle>Duke Memorial records.</unittitle>
               <repository>University Archives, Duke University. </repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle>Chapel Sermons [Sound Recordings].</unittitle>
               <repository>University Archives, Duke University. </repository>
            </archref>
         </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Church fund raising</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Chapels -- North Carolina -- Durham</subject>
         <corpname source="ingest">Friends of Duke Chapel</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Friends of Duke Chapel</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Chapel</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Religious activities</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Buildings</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_ypo" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Minutes and Reports, 1975-1991</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_72efb6e5848157b60e6dd05296e667f2">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>This series chronicles the interests and activities of the Friends of Duke Chapel
                  from 1975 to 1991. It includes minutes and agendas from advisory board meetings,
                  annual meeting minutes, as well as reports from the finance and nominating
                  committees. The advisory board minutes changed name from "Executive Committee
                  Minutes" to "Advisory Board Minutes" in 1981. Some topics covered in the minutes
                  include construction of a handicapped ramp, meetings with guest preachers,
                  brochure on Memorial Chapel, creation of a directorship for Friends of Duke
                  Chapel, air-conditioning of the Chapel, annual Messiah luncheon, photographing of
                  Chapel windows, Advent and Lenten prayer booklets, Chapel window bookmark project,
                  and establishment of a Friends of the Chapel endowment fund.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref13_8s8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Executive Committee Minutes, 1976-1981</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_300bd5fec3c15eeca5f7a86c9d49c3b8" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_5c9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Advisory Board Minutes and Agendas, 1981-1991</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f42dd149fd67ca613ecee292c0b78122" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_kjm" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Annual Meeting Minutes, 1978-1990</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9664d4f96275f7b951f2f5f71986e183" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_p6a" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Finance Committee Reports and Budgets, 1977-1988</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_bf199d3d49c270b941a7a3f495fd0185" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_gpm" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Nominating Committee Reports, 1975-1978</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_7439a061b014dff582acecc64940d206" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref19_kb4" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence, 1973-1999</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_38b06540f16d1fc45268a6d8c10ed079">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>This series contains correspondence relating to the activities and administration
                  of the Friends of Duke Chapel. It includes general correspondence from members of
                  the advisory board to other board members and members at large. These letters
                  include those from Dean of the Chapel Robert T. Young regarding the proposal and
                  implementation of the Friends group in 1973. There is also a folder containing
                  official letters from the Director to the membership at large regarding upcoming
                  events such as Messiah performances, membership renewals, and annual meetings.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_b3x" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1973-1976</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b1383a1d9321f94c1d504e0d60e1a554" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_n0r" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, 1977-1987</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_27660831494091d9156a154bd6ff6c16" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_edh" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, Letters to Members, 1974-1999</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d12c1419d4d9e129333c74016db2157e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref24_tsp" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Subject Files, 1973-1989</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_baf82dcd62ea9d3e1d015c7808bee021">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>This series includes material relating to the function of the Friends of Duke
                  Chapel. It is arranged alphabetically. Material includes by-laws and resolutions,
                  a description and background statement regarding the mission of the Friends group,
                  membership lists, and news clippings relating to the history of Duke Chapel. In
                  addition, there are records from the organizing committee relating to the founding
                  of the group and the definition of its mission. Of particular interest in this
                  series are the oral history transcriptions of interviews conducted by Arthur Kale
                  of Barney L. Jones, James T. Cleland, Howard Wilkinson, and Robert DuBose. The
                  transcriptions are a rich source of historical information on the staff and
                  history of the Chapel and its program. The interviews provide personal
                  reminiscences of chapel history and staff, including Foster Barnes, Mildred
                  Hendrix, Frank Hickman, Ben Smith, and the carillonneurs. They discuss their
                  relationships with numerous campus organizations, athletics, the inter-racial
                  council, and the role of the administrative committee. The men remember visits and
                  sermons by guest preachers such as Ralph Sockman, Martin Niemoller, Henry Crane,
                  and Paul Tillich. They also recall chapel events throughout the calendar year
                  including Religious Emphasis week, the Christmas pageant, and Easter services. </p>
               <p>Other significant materials are several speeches, by Bishop W. Kenneth Goodson,
                  Mary D. B. T. Semans, and Marjorie C. Jones respectively, given during the Friends
                  annual dinner meeting. Bishop Goodson, former Bishop-in-Residence of the Divinity
                  School and trustee emeritus of the Duke Endowment, fondly remembers his
                  relationship to Duke Chapel. Mary D. B. T. Semans speech recalls her mother Sarah
                  P. Duke's feelings for the Chapel, and includes her memories of numerous Chapel
                  ministers and music staff. Marjorie Jones gives insight into the role of chapel
                  hostesses and the life of the chapel during the week. [See also: Barney L. Jones
                  Papers for "Chapel Reminiscences: The First Two Decades," a speech given to the
                  Friends of Duke Chapel Annual Dinner, 1983.]</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_mxb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Advisory Board, 1984-1991</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_cc15978fe9e834e5023cd5cbee4b3371" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_8xy" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Annual Meeting, Speech by Bishop W. Kenneth Goodson, 1981</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9cb0b70997425d3acf5e58f662e8b05a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_vi0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Annual Meeting, Speech by Mary D. B. T. Semans, 1982</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_39c0b47f190ac9bce9a4ea1786eff5b3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_ol1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Annual Meeting, Speech by Marjorie C. Jones, 1983</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0c914eebfd592845d233282755d9aeaf" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_a19" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>By-Laws and Resolutions, 1975-1981</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c6d8bbe2a0003ce0f8cb85f10b9b0f6e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_3v0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Description and Background Statement, 1974</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b93572f220a288570a7e7f07e9a832eb" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_5ib" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Development Committee, 1981</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c4e3ef821201967e35f664138c121794" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_onl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Full Membership Chapel Group, 1973-1975</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2ae0d36e03ec3ee665eee95c0feb19c7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref33_ca0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Membership Lists, 1973-1976</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_afbb750cfd8aec8007c97713445075ec" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref34_5kf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Newspaper Clippings, 1975-1989</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ac3d2375ec9e0885bf266500fc859d3c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_pdg" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Nominating Committee, 1975</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d4d6706d5ea50d8cfb6cc93caddd818c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref36_y8c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Oral history transcriptions of interviews with Barney Jones, James T.
                     Cleland, Howard Wilkinson, and Robert DuBose, 1978-1979</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0f2b15168b479491867c0e50eb0701b9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref37_sh1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Organizing Committee, 1973-1974</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2352cc151ba70574bee9716fd3da1613" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref39_6dt" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Publications, 1975-1999</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_eaebc822caee6e132ffb4f289a657a26">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>This series includes brochures and pamphlets relating to the Chapel and work of
                  the Friends group and calendars produced by the Friends. Brochures include the
                  Friends informational and membership brochures, and a bookmark featuring the Adam
                  Window-South Aisle of the Chapel.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref40_kax" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Brochures and other Publications, 1978-1997</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_70ff1f837189aa10adf0e8fc3eb16682" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref41_niv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Calendar, 2009-2010</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_16bc2fda0802e182cb0a71db31ad7986" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-folder">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref42_zrv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Calendar, 2010-2011</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6d4a30aebd263f6079ddfa4d1ecd4efa" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-folder">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_t2y" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Calendar, 2011-2012</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_53112889b8afba00fc359ef348d67bab" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-folder">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref44_p70" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Calendar, 2012-2013</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b609e6978d5e9496c1d16aa2e2d44a1b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="oversize-folder">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
