<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uajblmddivorce/"
         >uajblmddivorce</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the James B. Duke and Lillian McCredy Duke Divorce Records,
               1904-1906 <num>UA.01.01.0002</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Matthew Shangler; machine-readable finding aid created by: Matthew
               Shangler</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">004325878</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 20:36:16
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>James B. Duke and Lillian McCredy Duke Divorce records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Duke, Lillian M.</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>UA.01.01.0002</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 Linear Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">1200 items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1904/1906" type="inclusive">1904-1906</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_3edb038eecf44bc89377d18ef9aa3458">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_3cede3b728b814247d684c6a663f58b2">Lillian McCredy Duke was the first
            wife of James B. Duke. The two were married in 1904 and divorced in 1906. The papers in
            this collection are related to the divorce proceedings. The materials in this collection
            contain correspondence, newspaper clippings, case exhibits, trial transcripts, and
            envelopes. The material ranges in date from 1904-1906.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_cdcf19b914ebcf2da1bb0898d131cbfa">Material in English
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_a9a830461eeb4645c45864a48f4f35b1">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
            Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
            research use.</p>
         <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use
            this collection.</p>
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_1e03bede46e4dad699d81eed3f53debd">
         <head>Copyright Notice</head>
         <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Duke University; all other
            copyright is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as
            stipulated by United States copyright law.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_a6fe10bc41e75d8d84d363224fe8eddd">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], James B. Duke and Lillian McCredy Duke Divorce Records,
            1904-1906, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript
            Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_7f21fc3ee0bb9f06e0a8258ce03e9372">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The James B. Duke and Lillian McCredy Duke Divorce Records, 1904-1906 were received by
            the University Archives as a gift in December 2009.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_5bb89992c7488339090fb9cc1b9f787d">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Matthew Shangler, September 2009</p>
         <p>Encoded by Matthew Shangler, March 2010</p>
         <p>Accession A2009-038 is described in this finding aid. </p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_edbc259a74979fa975895fc0988d1289">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Lillian Fletcher McCredy Duke was the first wife of James Buchanan Duke. The two were
            married in 1904, but shortly divorced in 1906. Before marrying James Duke, Lillian had
            been married to William F. McCredy. That marriage, too, ended in divorce.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_d87dc6b243dafa27e480cc0fa426f257">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The Duke Divorce records span the years 1904 to 1906. The two boxes contain
            correspondence and media regarding the divorce trial between Lillian and James B. Duke
            and appear to have been part of the evidence submitted at the divorce trial. The bulk of
            the correspondence is letters from Lillian to both James and her aunt G. E. Townes.
            There is one letter addressed to Lillian sent by her aunt. The rest of the material
            includes clippings, exhibits from the trial, trial transcripts, a detective report, and
            a bill of sale to Lillian's brother John A. Fletcher. The collection is grouped into the
            following series: Correspondence, Clippings, Court Case Related, Exhibits, and
            Publications.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_5d1fc443440f1118f2b5dbf85fa32fba">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>
            <archref>
               <unittitle label="Collection">James Buchanan Duke Papers, 1777-1990 and
                  undated</unittitle>
               <repository label="Repository">Rare Book Manuscript and Special Collections Library
                  at Duke University</repository>
            </archref>
         </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Duke family</subject>
         <persname source="ingest">Duke, Lillian M.</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Duke, James Buchanan, 1856-1925</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Duke, Lillian McCredy</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref13_qhs" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence, 1905-1906</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_176ff92054d48bcd3140237df6e82f77">
                  <extent>.3 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_95ee3a63112cbb05ea59d556a90ef9df">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>The Correspondence series is three folders of letters written by Lillian to James
                  Duke and her aunt. The first folder contains the correspondence of Lillian Duke to
                  her aunt. These letters range in date from March 1905 to April 1906 with two
                  undated. The letters cover subjects of money, visiting, thievery, and family
                  affairs. The early letters refer to casual affairs, mostly regarding when she is
                  going to visit her aunt next or the monthly allowance she sends her aunt. Two of
                  the letters, dated March 1906, reflect a heated exchange with her aunt over a
                  supposed theft. Lillian accused her aunt of stealing a wig out of her dresser
                  drawer and closed by threatening the end of their friendship if she did not return
                  it.</p>
               <p>Lillian's husband James is mentioned only briefly in the letters despite their
                  coincidence with her divorce proceedings. However, in her later letters, she
                  refers to her trial and requests the help and council of her aunt.</p>
               <p>Folder two contains one letter, written to Lillian by her aunt in response to the
                  accusation of stealing. In it, she takes great offense at the charge brought upon
                  her. Although undated by the author or recipient, this letter can be dated March
                  1906 based on the accompanying correspondence of Lillian Duke.</p>
               <p>The last folder of correspondence is filled with letters written by Lillian to her
                  then husband, James B. Duke. They range in date from July, 1905 to September, 1905
                  and are of a more personal nature. The bulk refers to the loneliness and hardship
                  felt by Lillian while James was overseas in Europe on business. While James was
                  overseas, events unfolded that precipitated him to bring charges of adultery
                  against Lillian and file for divorce. These letters were later admitted as
                  evidence in the trial.</p>
               <p>The last letter is undated, though it was written after she had been served with
                  divorce papers. In this letter, Lillian implores James to hear her side of events
                  and claims that he has only been listening to unreliable sources. She goes on to
                  beg for him to drop the charges of adultery and to take her back.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_fzn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Lillian Duke to Mrs. G. E. Townes (aunt), March, 1905-April,
                     1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_35a46e8feb0afdc9dab11f3844c5c7c3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_su0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Lillian to James B. Duke, July, 1905-September, 1905,
                     undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_abe87abf7a7dc5e0cd8d66953c3fb3d6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_kz7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Mrs. G. E. Townes to Lillian Duke, March, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a652104734956dc8e2f6a68ea4df3330" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref19_yki" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Clippings</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_efa8eda640c9ce2664d3d6894986f450">
                  <extent>.3 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_0f09a41fda80e1b58279a81a2ce39511">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>The Clippings series contains newspaper clippings taken from various newspapers
                  and were compiled by a clipping service of Ben B. Hampton and Co., New York. The
                  bulk of the clippings are from May 1906. The clippings include excerpts from the
                  trial proceedings and testimony of one of the chief witnesses, Lillian Duke's
                  former servant Miss Sands.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_3xu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Clippings, Sept., 1905-May, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0f31122f3a3547d76a597f370bbcf316" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref22_gs2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Loose Clippings, Sept., 1905-Feb., 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d0ae726968463fde35a7030c367ccae6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref24_mv7" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Court Case Related Material</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_f93b8730a5c1f268fef108f70f290d6e">
                  <extent>.3 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_af97390544b138b682e39b922d4a843e">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>The Court Case Related Material series contains a variety of documents from the
                  divorce. First is a detective report from September 1905 commissioned by James B.
                  Duke. There is a detailed ledger for each day of observing Lillian's house and
                  actions. Also included are trial transcripts of testimony given by witnesses.
                  There is a statement by Julia Schaeffer, the cook for Mr. Duke after the divorce
                  proceedings as well as a note from "a woman" who claims Lillian is a liar and
                  calls her out for ruining her previous husband. Other inclusions are a folder of
                  empty envelopes, and a bill of sale to Lillian's brother, John A. Fletcher. The
                  bill of sale documents Lillian selling all her property that remains at the Duke
                  estate to her brother for the sum of one dollar. Items include a Mercedes
                  automobile, two horses, pillows, jewelry, clothing, and other items.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_p66" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>September 1905 Detective Report</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5253e29ec6e7803a85c3d1ec95f90db3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_arn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Trial Transcriptions, Mar. 30, 1906-Apr. 18, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_03be603b37dd0984bf4ce3cec379eaa7" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_8kf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Julia Schaeffer Statement, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a65c10065894b9ead52d1126c2c59b91" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_kuk" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Anonymous Note "A Woman," undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_267ae2847aff3f55a95b4a8110a6df7b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_m11" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bill of Sale to John A. Fletcher, brother of Lillian Duke, Oct. 28,
                     1905</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a2d07ae0c910fb8d17eb36c46231ec09" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_5r1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Empty Envelopes, June, 1905-February, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3a59bcbc01102915281e7a352f169c20" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref33_bfo" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Exhibits</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_045c80841540918c548e690769d4a541">
                  <extent>.75 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_080cfed9145fa03a0069f8d6ae3e2745">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>The Exhibit series features fifteen folders of documents used as evidence in the
                  courtroom. Listed on each document is the court date, April 27, 1906. The bulk of
                  the exhibits are European issues of the New York Herald newspaper featuring
                  personal ads that were said to be private messages sent between Lillian Duke and
                  correspondent Major Frank Huntoon. These newspapers date from December 8, 1904, to
                  January 29, 1905. James B. Duke is supposedly referred to as "octopus" in these
                  messages.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_q0w" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Exhibit A: Photo of Huntoon, Apr. 27, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_af1c93d1f09aa59928f9fce2c1c8e3af" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref36_za9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Exhibit B, Apr. 27, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1e49a7f7691572bf2739790ef6393064" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref37_xac" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Exhibit C, Apr. 27, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1b63dc1851f54dad19150b4c9f4de841" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref38_gnw" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Exhibit D, Apr. 27, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ec5c77fd811652db339bc9a6662d5cbe" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref39_yb3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Exhibit E, Apr. 27, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1709775786d119e1a2d3883affdec3a3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref40_h6g" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Exhibit F, Apr. 27, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3be09c42619858c2beba7b1557139fd6" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref41_awb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Exhibit G, Apr. 27, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ee283eb552f187f57932701a9831854e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref42_6fn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Exhibit H, Apr. 27, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_40a34fa9669e1580db422ec05524ac71" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_wwv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Exhibit I, Apr. 27, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_af61f6092b65937c4c452c1bff4e2171" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref44_4ky" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Exhibit J, Apr. 27, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ac9249820b39cd5debbf48461e560a76" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref45_2n6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Exhibit K, Apr. 27, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_da1c0fd6318920a5002cc636c999681d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref46_oz0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Exhibit L, Apr. 27, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c254aeb2ec944e81dbb662a46bca4ddc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_9mq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Exhibit M, Apr. 27, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f03d4174dfd70bf1392cb4a664bbfc8b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref48_vpx" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Exhibit N, Apr. 27, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_992546627d7c7cf433ea94f74a53f031" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref49_gn0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Exhibit O, Apr. 27, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8cc2e2da9ef0f6e820024a530f4ce613" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref51_ahx" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Publications</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_98a8776056a954134f93b42d6f7f9878">
                  <extent>.25 box</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_07559277b50ab50862963590c75a1d1d">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>The Publications series contains two issues of the New York Inquirer. One is dated
                  January 26, 1906, and the other is from February 4, 1906. Both issues feature
                  short articles regarding the divorce suit between Lillian Duke and James B.
                  Duke.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref53_wlp" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>New York Inquirer, Jan. 26, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5e84b6de92469ebabcb6d337205ee09b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref54_qqu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>New York Inquirer, Feb. 4, 1906</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_567af0fd464568d19a7525d9af96448c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
