<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
         url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uakramer/">uakramer</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Paul Jackson Kramer Papers, 1856 - 1994 (bulk 1927-1974)
                  <num>UA.29.02.0040</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Linda Daniel; machine-readable finding aid created by: Linda
               Daniel</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2004</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003309402</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-05-25 12:10:52
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Paul Jackson Kramer papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">Kramer, Paul Jackson, 1904-</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>UA.29.02.0040</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1856/1994" type="inclusive">1856 - 1994 (bulk 1927-1974)</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_c075a3e32a23bd46187c1ed99826198e">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult University Archives, Duke
            University.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_40f6c0d870696d98a67839c84b9c6068">Paul Jackson Kramer, a world
            renowned educator, scientist and author, was professor of botany at Duke University from
            1931-1995. The Paul J. Kramer Papers reflects Kramer's career as a university professor
            and plant physiologist, his participation in various scientific and learned societies
            including his service within the National Science Foundation and on the U.S. Air Force's
            Committee on the Disposal of Herbicide Orange, and his involvement in the development of
            the Botany Dept., the Phytotron, and Duke University. Materials include correspondence,
            reports, writings and addresses, memoranda, research and teaching material, photographs,
            and printed matter. Major subjects include Kramer's contributions in the field of
            botany, particularly plant-water relationships, the physiology of forest trees, and
            botanical research in controlled environments. English.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_85bd274fab259fecdb960d48aafc67f9">
            <extent>12000 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_81f1c9f3dadb5137f9c4df9c10a70149">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_2905be7df10575d6bc8094f515542cb4">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke
            University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure
            of personally identifiable information from education records. </p>
         <p>In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use. </p>
         <p>Box 7 is closed pending processing.</p>
         <p>The folder entitled <title type="simple" render="doublequote">Named
               Professorships</title> is restricted by donor request.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_e20a1dca5f0237d82d05091416cbc920">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Duke University; all other
            copyright is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as
            stipulated by United States copyright law.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_780fed3ac1d9775cea2c40cf23cf0374">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Paul Jackson Kramer Papers, Duke University Archives, David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_19d5eeff1219d45fd0e66772a6fac09c">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Paul Jackson Kramer Papers were received by the University Archives as a transfer in
            1962 (A62-629), 1967 (A67-77), 1974 (A74-117), 1981 (A81-7), 1995 (A95-68) and
            (A95-90).</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_1fe5ad4ce03fa91f102c176d67c85e4b">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Linda Daniel</p>
         <p>Completed February, 2004</p>
         <p>Encoded by Linda Daniel, February 2004</p>
         <p>Updated by Sherrie Bowser, May 2007</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_98271cf89ce108e3cdd9fdcd1dd41bf3">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Paul Jackson Kramer was a world renowned educator, scientist and author. Born 8 May 1904
            in Brookville, Ind., educated at Miami University in Ohio (A.B., 1926) and Ohio State
            University (M.Sc., 1929 and Ph.D, 1931), Kramer was appointed to the Duke University
            faculty in 1931, and promoted to Professor of Botany in 1945. Kramer was named James B.
            Duke Professor of Botany in 1954 and became James B. Duke Professor Emeritus in 1974.
            Other appointments included Director of the Sarah P. Duke Gardens, Duke University,
            1945-c.1974, and Program Director in Regulatory Biology, National Science Foundation,
            1960-1961. Kramer served as president for the following professional societies: American
            Society of Plant Physiologists, 1945; North Carolina Academy of Science, 1961-1962;
            Botanical Society of America, 1964; and American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1964.
            He served as Chair, Phytotron Board of Duke University and North Carolina State
            University, 1962-1976. Honors and awards received include National Academy of Sciences,
            1962; American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1963; American Philosophical Society, 1971;
            and the American Institute of Biological Sciences Distinguished Services Award, 1977, as
            well as four honorary degrees between 1966 and 1975. Kramer's publications include
               <title type="simple" render="italic">Plant and Soil Water Relationships</title>.
            Kramer died 24 May 1995.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_2a6a6603a65daa778cc7658b9eb8bc12">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The Paul Jackson Kramer Papers include correspondence, reports, writings and addresses,
            memoranda, research and teaching material, photographs, and printed matter. The
            collection reflects Kramer's career as a university professor and plant physiologist;
            his participation in various scientific and learned societies, including his service
            within the National Science Foundation and on the U.S. Air Force's Committee on the
            Disposal of Herbicide Orange; and his involvement in the development of the Botany
            Dept., the Phytotron, and Duke University. Kramer's prominence within the international
            and national scientific communities is attested to throughout the collection. </p>
         <p>The Correspondence and the Subject Files series document the development of the Botany
            Department; the phytotron; faculty governance; and the Gross-Edens Affair, an
            administrative controversy at Duke in 1960. The Correspondence and Subject Files series
            contain Kramer's correspondence with scientists abroad. The subject files document
            Kramer's role in a number of scientific organizations, the National Science Foundation,
            learned societies, and the government. The papers are particularly useful as they
            provide information on cooperation among plant scientists after World War II and the
            early history of the American Institute of Biological Sciences (AIBS).</p>
         <p>A substantial portion of the collection is comprised of correspondence that pertains to
            Kramer's research, the direction of graduate students, scientific organizations, matters
            at Duke University, and other subjects.</p>
         <p>The Research and Teaching Notes series document Kramer's research and teaching and are
            useful for the study of his contributions in the field of botany, particularly
            plant-water relationships, the physiology of forest trees, and botanical research in
            controlled environments. Research notes and materials are principally located in the
            Research and Teaching Notes series. However, information related to Kramer's research is
            scattered throughout the collection. The Correspondence series as well as the Subject
            Files and Research and Teaching Notes series reflect Kramer's role as a teacher.</p>
         <p>The Photographs series contains pictures of the Botany faculty.</p>
         <p>A folder list of Boxes 5-11 is available as part of the collection file. Please consult
            University Archives staff.</p>
         <p>Box 7 is closed pending processing.</p>
         <p>The folder entitled <title type="simple" render="doublequote">Named
               Professorships</title> is restricted by donor request.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_96b4c650a1dd30fc256fae76558876d2">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>
            <archref>
               <unittitle>Department of Botany Records.</unittitle>
               <repository>University Archives, Duke University.</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle>A. Hollis Edens Records.</unittitle>
               <repository>University Archives, Duke University.</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle>Paul M. Gross Papers.</unittitle>
               <repository>University Archives, Duke University.</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle>Sarah P. Duke Gardens Collection.</unittitle>
               <repository>University Archives, Duke University.</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle>Henry J. Oosting Papers.</unittitle>
               <repository>University Archives, Duke University.</repository>
            </archref>
         </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Forest plants</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Phytotron</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Botany -- Southern States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Forest ecology</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Botany -- Research</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Botany -- Societies, etc.</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Botany</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Botany -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Agent Orange</subject>
         <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Sarah P. Duke Gardens</geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">Plant physiology</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Plant-water relationships</subject>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Administration</corpname>
         <corpname rules="dacs" source="naf">Duke University. Department of Botany</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Kramer, Paul Jackson, 1904-</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">National Science Foundation (U.S.)</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Faculty</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_7gm" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence, 1930-1993</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_345e557ce6c0d24585543748ec6c1dcd">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>The main body of the Correspondence Series is arranged chronologically, however a
                  small number of letters are filed together by correspondent and arranged
                  alphabetically at the beginning of the series. It appears that Kramer created a
                  separate set of files for postdoctoral students, and it is these files that are at
                  the beginning of the series. Comprised of incoming letters and copies of outgoing
                  letters with graduate students, university administrators, and scientists, the
                  series reflects the full range of Kramer's professional life. Letters often relate
                  to research questions, the direction of graduate students, the review of
                  manuscripts, and matters at Duke University.</p>
               <p>The very beginnings of Kramer's career are documented in the 1930s correspondence
                  with Duke University biologists Arthur Sperry Pearse, Hugo L. Blomquist, and Ruth
                  M. Addoms as well as William Wannamaker, Dean of Duke University. This early
                  correspondence is particularly interesting as it reflects the correspondents'
                  views on developing the biology department and Duke University. Beyond Duke, other
                  notable correspondents from the 1930s and the 1940s include F.W. Went, Henry W.
                  Popp, J. H. Priestly, Walter Loehwing, Burton E. Livingston, and Charles A. Shull.
                  Other correspondents during the 1930s include Floyd W. Gail of the University of
                  Idaho, B.S. Meyer and E.N. Transeau of Ohio State University. Kramer corresponded
                  with these botanists, his former professors, throughout a substantial part of his
                  career.</p>
               <p>In the 1940s, the series contains numerous letters from Kramer's graduate
                  students. Letters from Kramer's graduate students during the early 1940s provide
                  perspectives on military life during World War II. John P. Decker and Theodore
                  Kozlowski were among Kramer's students who corresponded with him during the war.
                  Other Duke students who corresponded with Kramer include Wilbur Duncan, William K.
                  Ferrell, Harold E. Young, and Johnson Parker.</p>
               <p>Notable scientists who corresponded with Kramer during the 1940s and 1950s include
                  N.A. Maximov, from the U.S.S.R.'s Academy of Sciences, as well as Henry Oosting,
                  Clifford S. Schopmeyer, Paul Burkholder, William T. Jackson, Herman Wiebe, W.
                  Dwight Billings, and Kenneth Thimann.</p>
               <p>Correspondence from the 1960s to the 1990s reflects a number of matters at Duke
                  including the construction of the phytotron. Douglas M. Knight, R. Taylor Cole,
                  Henry Hellmers, and George Dutrow are among the Duke University figures with whom
                  Kramer corresponded. Correspondence with George Dutrow in 1986 includes Kramer's
                  reflections on the relationship between the Botany Department and the forestry
                  program at Duke. Scientists who corresponded with Kramer during this period
                  include William Lopushinsky, F.C. Steward, and a number of international scholars
                  including Ralph O. Slatyer.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <arrangement id="aspace_e716fc09866f8a538a96884b0023eac3">
               <head>Arrangement note</head>
               <p>The Correspondence Series is arranged in two subseries. The first is arranged
                  alphabetically by the last name of the correspondent. The second series is
                  arranged chronologically by date of the correspondence.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref13_spw" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Names of Correspondents</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref14_ivu" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Barrs, Henry D., [1965-1969]</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_fb9a28839dc97d7e5dce14ca07563667" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref15_lv6" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Brix, Holger, 1959-1963</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_1ce493993ccb31b2bfd608b8fb214afe" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref16_yyr" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Burstrom, Hans, 1958-1959</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_1bc1a69b6a3fb8db457204c5da26efc8" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref17_ce7" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Carlson, William, [1986-1990]</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_7ee3f010e10059866a19eb0e3f52b7d7" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref18_17n" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Chung, Hsu-Ho, [1978-1979]</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_4aef971b7aef75717847aed5ca521550" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref19_1y6" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Decker, John, 1956-1967</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_89ee07dfa3718919c196faa00a991e14" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref20_gxd" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Dove, Lewis, 1964-1969</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_9d4eb0578ceca8666e52f620cb94661b" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref21_8jp" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Loehwing, Walter F., 1945-1947</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_ec92e8ec126b6ed78d3cb9a513f6da48" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref22_qpr" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Knipling, Edward, [1962-1969]</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_6a7ac1b9bc078f967158e30852b8fcec" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref23_6aq" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>McGregor, W.H.D., [1957-1964]</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_15e18339a3fe559e2f088da1d470e5be" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref24_th7" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Miller, Lee, 1962-1967</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_1ebde208ab3f5b8bd3015c14ba445223" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref25_gaz" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>O'Leary, James, [1961-1974]</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_a70723b383cad387c99c5041504e91bb" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref26_sy5" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Pharis, Richard P., 1961-1968</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_9ced1bea29e8d7690b011ef6c481d5f8" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref27_8lg" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Queen, W.H., [1962-1972]</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_a4359132f28c1194c84c8d96ce912b81" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref28_ynp" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Quraishi, Mohammad 1968-1979</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_db51bd7160dbfc8b41c1e3842e71389a" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref29_sa4" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Slatyer, Ralph O.</unittitle>
                  </did>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref30_vrq" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>1957-1968</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_71bbd6b0a52bb3a358163c9cdc82ee57"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref31_3jo" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>1962-1963</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_35e4d22c8dcba7b27930beca583ca983"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref32_bxu" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>1963-1966</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_e4feff68c9e5e52a001c58c94a5f53dd"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref33_m0a" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Smith, Richard T., 1958-1977</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_336a6c84f076b132bf47f24f0b848b1c" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref34_m0x" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Tal, Moshe, 1964-1967</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_5d06e93b8e587fbd4fe1b2a41645e122" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref35_mqi" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Thornthwaite, C.W., 1956-1962</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_48f5c603b9bd6817aad1cf4d80e3dc0b" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref36_jmd" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Verdoorn, Frans, 1942-1949</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_e05ed7df7a1bbda215d7645ae7dcde4a" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref37_0ka" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Yu, Grace Wei-Chi Hu, [1962-1967]</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_ec545764f64ec7206c67bb8a93801128" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref38_565" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Dates of Correspondence</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref39_w2f" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Nov. 1930-January 1941</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_37c5fbdf420290ecc6800dc1b915e64a" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref40_7c0" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Feb. 1, 1941-July 1955</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_c2b3d738304c0560f5a827f1a2915b47" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref41_2b7" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sept. 1955-Dec. 1972</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_98bf0422e079550335eaf2b4f301131c" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref42_fse" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>1966-June 1993</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_815ed01fd5ea849208253e91b842e1de" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">4</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref45_nnd" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Subject Files, 1856-1994 (bulk 1926-1982)</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_292056aad81ec6550b715eb0a697e089">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>The Subject Files series reflects Kramer's involvement in governance and other
                  matters at Duke, his government service, and his service in a number of special
                  committees and scientific societies. It includes memoranda, correspondence,
                  reports, notes, printed matter, and writings. The materials are arranged
                  alphabetically by folder.</p>
               <p>Significant subjects within the materials, related to Duke University, include the
                  development of phytotron research and the establishment of the Southeastern Plant
                  Environment Laboratories, the Academic Council and the University Council, the
                  Gross-Edens affair and the ensuing selection of a new university president. The
                  documents pertaining to the Gross-Edens affair are particularly significant as
                  they document Kramer's observations. Other subjects related to Duke University
                  include early interdisciplinary programs, the Department of Botany and the School
                  of Forestry, and faculty membership in learned societies. Files pertaining to the
                  Sarah P. Duke Gardens include letters between Kramer, who served as director of
                  the Gardens, and Richard Fillmore, assistant director. Also included are letters
                  from Fillmore to Mary Carbonna, who wrote a history of the Gardens, and memoranda
                  concerning landscape planning in the Gardens.</p>
               <p>The principal societies, programs, and special committees that the papers reflect
                  include the American Institute of Biological Sciences (AIBS), the International
                  Biological Program and the Committee to Evaluate the International Biological
                  Program, the National Academy-National Research Council Committee on War-time
                  Modifications in Biology, the American Society of Plant Physiologists, and the
                  National Academy of Sciences. Documents related to the AIBS reflect Kramer's
                  participation and its development. Significant figures reflected among the AIBS
                  material include Robert F. Griggs, Paul Burkholder, Kenneth Thimann, and Detlev
                  Bronk. The series also documents Kramer's service within the National Science
                  Foundation as well as his service on a number of committees of the United States
                  government, including the U.S. Air Force's Committee on the Disposal of Herbicide
                  Orange.</p>
               <p>Scattered throughout the series are manuscripts and notes for Kramer's
                  publications and addresses. Topics of the manuscripts include the need for
                  controlled environments to conduct botanical research, soil and plant water
                  relationships; biological programs during World War II; and the role of science in
                  society.</p>
               <p>Accounts of travel abroad, nineteenth century nursery catalogs, and class
                  notebooks are included in the series. These items along with the biographical
                  information within the papers complement the materials that relate to the various
                  aspects of Kramer's career.</p>
               <p>A folder list of Boxes 5-11 is available as part of the collection file. Please
                  consult University Archives staff.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <arrangement id="aspace_161d8cc3af28f9b40901b86af89096ea">
               <head>Arrangement note</head>
               <p>The titles describe the alphabetical range found within each box.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref46_2p5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Addresses and Papers -- American Institute of Biological Sciences,
                     1964-1966</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e031d778b6398b828c6a89f70f3166b5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_azm" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1965-- Class Notes,
                     Agricultural Chemical Lab Manual</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_92c4f08fc1848b1bd4fc525570a085f0" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref48_i0q" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Contents of Box 7</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_36f86d998707e9411f34e24409a6f47d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">7</container>
               </did>
               <accessrestrict id="aspace_08a2f70219d84c57589396735454bae7">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
                  <p>Box 7 is closed pending processing.</p>
                  <p>The folder entitled <title type="simple" render="doublequote">Named
                        Professorships</title> is RESTRICTED by donor request.</p>
               </accessrestrict>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref50_gqy" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Duke University: Notes and Clippings on Edens Retirement --
                     International Biological Program: Duke University Participation,
                     1967-1973</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0ccd4ea1cd3de0b6cbd3555555a0f978" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">8</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref52_w83" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>International Biological Program: Foreign Participation, 1974-1975 --
                     Phytotron: Proposal to NSF, 1970-1971</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5aa05bc44875ecc7f8e6907ae826b403" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">9</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref53_5y6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Phytotron: Support of Visiting Scientists, 1970-1971 -- United States
                     Air Force: Ad Hoc Committee on the Disposal of Herbicide [Agent] Orange,
                     1972-1974</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_443625af94375d5506ece135916df49c" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">10</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref54_4s9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>U.S. Atomic Energy Commission: Radiation Effect on Plants, 1963-1964 --
                     United States Forestry Service, 1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_d801b208df775bbdec136f7beb3d0bb9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref57_h9k" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Research and Teaching Notes, 1925-1987</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_2691db0825807ccafb02c9b0268d5809">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>The Research and Teaching series contains a sample of the data and notes Kramer
                  compiled during his career. Materials include tables and charts, publications,
                  syllabi, correspondence, reports, and manuscripts. </p>
               <p>The papers within the series document Kramer's views on the government support of
                  science and science education, his work in forestry research, his association with
                  the School of Forestry at Duke, and his work with the National Science
                  Foundation.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <arrangement id="aspace_b3191a495140f3360977566d068caeb9">
               <head>Arrangement note</head>
               <p>The folder titles describe the alphabetical range found within the box.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref58_h56" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Advanced Physiology, 1938 -- Tree Physiology, 1937</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_962368c46fabbd74ed586d85d22bd953" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref61_q8f" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Photographs, 1941-1983</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_dd92a13a63a62679a70b25edbaaec17c">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Chiefly black and white photographs of Kramer, the botany faculty at Duke
                  University, and participants at professional meetings. Photographs of the botany
                  faculty date from 1946 and 1954. This series includes some candid pictures.
                  Subjects among the pictures include Ruth Addoms, Lewis Anderson, Hugo L.
                  Blomquist, Henry J. Oosting, Clarence Korstian, and Theodore Kozlowski.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <processinfo id="aspace_0712456fb6104e409310c87e233a74f1">
               <head>Processing Information note</head>
               <p>These photographs have been removed to the Paul Jerome Kramer file in the
                  Photograph Collection, in University Archives. Please consult University Archives
                  staff.</p>
            </processinfo>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref64_oth" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Oversize</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_4445e8ba0b5d3238a89e63baba9ce78b">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Oversize material is located in map cabinet drawer 8.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref65_6wj" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Catalogue of Fruit Trees, for sale from the large and extensive nursery
                     of George Aupel, Eaton. Preble County, Ohio, 2 February 1858</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_10a026d85b9d6fb3757cdb25ff98b317" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref66_atb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">The Philadelphia Inquirer</title> "Sherman's New
                     Movement," front page, 21 November 1864</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1b65097ff555fdea09909f1dc05674c9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">11</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
