<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="https://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/ualawrc/">ualawrc</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the School of Law Reference Collection, 1930-ongoing
            <num>UA.01.11.0016</num></titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: Archives Staff; machine-readable finding aid created by: Sherrie
          Bowser</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>2008</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003829230</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-03-23 12:42:27
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>School of Law Reference collection</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <corpname source="naf">Duke University. University Archives</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>UA.01.11.0016</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1930/2014" type="inclusive">1930-ongoing</unitdate>
      <physloc id="aspace_c3414f1efffe329f0c9f8dd1b47395de">For current information on the location
        of these materials, please consult the Library's online catalog.</physloc>
      <physdesc id="aspace_7d63ffbadb4d863115ca36d88c9d1880"
        label="General Physical Description note"><extent>2000 Items</extent></physdesc>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_7830a6a081125c1f4e441b37c2da1d48">Material in English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_b8b0333bdf8f97915de60bcfac75254b">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_362b68f7d3d22aa3149865888213b9be">
      <head>Copyright Notice</head>
      <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Duke University; all other copyright
        is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as stipulated by
        United States copyright law.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_ca7cbb2b8f1248700d046dd540622391">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], School of Law Reference Collection, Duke University Archives,
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_550cda9ebfd7c48b2b2eb1dbc0f2844c">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The School of Law Reference Collection was compiled from various sources by University
        Archives staff for reference and research.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo id="aspace_11526f1743dce3e6c029f677fb0fbc3e">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Archives Staff, February 2008</p>
      <p>Encoded by Sherrie Bowser, February 2008</p>
      <p>Updated by Molly Bragg, July 2011</p>
      <p>Accessions were merged into one collection, described in this finding aid. </p>
    </processinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_5e29f59632f0a982a7c3985d91e52e33">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>timeline excerpted from School of Law's A History of Duke Law School
        http://www.law.duke.edu/history/index</p>
      <chronlist>
        <head>Chronology List</head>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1850</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Braxton Craven, President of Normal (later Trinity) College, in Randolph County,
              North Carolina, the predecessor of Duke University, inaugurates lectures on Political
              and Natural Law as part of a liberal arts curriculum; in 1855 these are supplemented
              by lectures on Constitutional and International Law.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1865</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The Law Department is established as one of eleven academic departments in
              Trinity College.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1868</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>A separate School of Law is organized to offer professional training.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1882</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The School of Law closes and legal instruction is discontinued following
              President Craven's death.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1887</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Legal instruction is resumed as an academic course in the History
              Department.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1891</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Trinity College moves from Randolph County to Durham, and the School of Law is
              reopened with Justice A. C. Avery of the North Carolina Supreme Court as its Dean. No
              undergraduate work is required for admission to the two-year program leading to the
              LL.B degree.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1894</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The Law School closes and legal instruction is discontinued for financial
              reasons.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1904</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>James Buchanan Duke and Benjamin Newton Duke provide the endowment to reopen the
              School of Law, and Samuel Fox Mordecai, a Raleigh attorney and part-time law teacher
              at Wake Forest College, is appointed Senior Professor of Law.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1905</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Professor Mordecai, who has been named Dean, initiates a reorganization of the
              School of Law, which is housed on the second floor of the East Duke Building. Trinity
              is admitted to membership in the Association of American Law Schools. Trinity
              withdraws from membership in 1919</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1924</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Duke University is created, and Trinity College becomes its undergraduate school
              for men.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1927</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The School of Law moves into renovated quarters in the Carr Building on the newly
              rebuilt East Campus. Dean Mordecai dies, and W. Bryan Bolich is named Acting
              Dean.<lb/> Miriam Cox, a Duke Woman's College graduate and court reporter, is the
              first woman student admitted to Duke Law School.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1930</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The School of Law moves into its new building on the Main Quadrangle of the West
              Campus.Justin Miller, Dean of the Law School of the University of Southern California,
              is appointed Dean, and the faculty is substantially enlarged. Duke is readmitted to
              membership in the Association of American Law Schools.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1931</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The Duke Bar Association, closely modeled on the American Bar Association, is
              established by the law students to: "1) foster legal science, 2) maintain the honor
              and dignity of the legal profession among law students, 3) cultivate professional
              ethics and social intercourse among its members, and 4) promote the welfare of the Law
              School of Duke University."</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1932</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Clinical legal education is introduced into the curriculum with the establishment
              of the Duke Legal Aid Clinic, the first law school-connected program of its kind in
              the country.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1938</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Dean Horack oversees the construction of five log cabins on the northern edge of
              the West Campus. Built to help alleviate the shortage of housing for law students,
              they are used as dormitory and recreational facilities. The cabins are less Spartan
              than their name implies, and have electricity, central heating and indoor
              plumbing.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1951</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The Law School building is now too small, and lacks space to house the Law
              Library (now over 100,000 volumes). Dean McClain receives a commitment of $250,000
              from the University Trustees towards a new, modern law building.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1959</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The Duke Legal Aid Clinic closes and clinical legal education is
              discontinued.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1961</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The first African-American students are admitted.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1962-63</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The School of Law moves into its new building on Towerview Road and Science
              Drive. The Honorable Earl Warren, Chief Justice of the United States, is the principal
              speaker at the dedication ceremony on Law Day, 1963.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1966</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>To protest the North Carolina Bar Association's denial of membership to an
              African-American graduate of the Law School, the faculty approves a resolution by a
              2-1 margin to sever ties with the Bar Association until applicants are accepted
              without discrimination based on race. The Law School re-establishes its connection
              with the Bar Association in 1969.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1967</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The MD/JD program, the Law School's first joint degree program, is inaugurated
              under co-sponsorship with the Medical School. This program is followed in later years
              by joint degree programs under co-sponsorship with the Business School, the Institute
              of Public Policy, the School of the Environment, the Engineering School, and the
              Graduate School (in disciplines, including anthropology, economics, English, history,
              philosophy, political science, Romance studies, and humanities).</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1968</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The LLB degree is replaced by the JD as the basic professional degree.<lb/>
              Small-section instruction is introduced in conjunction with an intensive research and
              writing program in all first-year courses.<lb/>The Legal Aid Clinic is re-activated;
              clinical legal education is reintroduced into the curriculum in 1972.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1985-86</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The JD/LLM (International and Comparative Law) combined degree program, the first
              of its kind in the country, is inaugurated.<lb/>The LLM program for foreign-trained
              lawyers is expanded and rapidly grows; in the 2007-2008 academic year there are over
              80 international students at Duke Law and almost 1,000 international alumni.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1991</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>A voluntary Pro Bono program is established with 44 students providing assistance
              to programs in the Durham community; by the 2006-2007 academic year there are 368
              students enrolled in 576 pro bono placements.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1993</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The Center on Law, Ethics, and National Security is founded; by 2006 the Law
              School supports centers and programs devoted to the study of a variety of issues:<lb/>
              • Center for Environmental Solutions (launched in 2005)<lb/> • Center for Genome
              Ethics, Law, and Policy (established in 2002 as part of the Institute for Genome
              Sciences and Policy, a multi-disciplinary, campus-wide network of centers and
              programs)<lb/> • Center for International and Comparative Law (founded 2006)<lb/> •
              Center for the Study of the Public Domain and Program in Intellectual Property
              (created in 2002)<lb/> • Global Capital Markets Center (established in 1998, in
              cooperation with the Fuqua School of Business)<lb/> • Program in Public Law (founded
              in 1997).</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>1995</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Clinical education at the Law School is revived with the Death Penalty Clinic;
              other clinics are soon established:<lb/>• AIDS Legal Project (1996)<lb/>• Animal Law
              Project (2005)<lb/>• Children's Law Clinic (2002)<lb/>• Community Enterprise Clinic
              (2002)<lb/>• Environmental Law and Policy Clinic (2007)<lb/>• Guantanamo Defense
              Clinic (2005)<lb/>• Low-Income Taxpayer Clinic (2006)</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>2002</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>The "Great Lives in the Law" lecture series, sponsored by the Duke Program in
              Public Law, is inaugurated by William H. Rehnquist, Chief Justice of the United
              States. Subsequent speakers include: civil rights lawyer Julius Chambers (2002),
              Justice Anthony Kennedy (2002), Justice Sandra Day O'Connor (2003), Dennis W. Archer,
              president of the American Bar Association (2003), Richard Goldstone, former Justice of
              the Constitutional Court of South Africa (2004), historian John Hope Franklin (2004),
              Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg (2005), former U.S. Attorney General Janet Reno (2005),
              and Linda Greenhouse, Supreme Court correspondent for The New York Times
              (2006).</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
      </chronlist>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_42dbab82d0705745328a1b192aef2125">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>The School of Law Reference Collection contains subject files pertaining to various topics
        particular to the School of Law; some subjects/formats include: admissions, clippings, first
        female law student, student produced publications, first year law classes, bulletins,
        reports, and curriculum. The collection begins in 1930 and is ongoing.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_420d7c94425fb768d8ba6bc64286bb94">
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p><archref><unittitle label="Collection">A. Kenneth Pye, Chancellor, records and papers,
            1960-1983.</unittitle><repository label="Repository">University Archives. Duke
            University</repository>
        </archref><archref><unittitle label="Collection">Bunyan S. Womble Papers,
            1900-1976.</unittitle><repository label="Repository">University Archives. Duke
            University</repository>
        </archref><archref><unittitle label="Collection">School of Law records,
            1930-ongoing.</unittitle><repository label="Repository">University Archives. Duke
            University</repository>
        </archref></p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Law -- Study and teaching -- North Carolina -- Durham</subject>
      <corpname source="naf">Duke University. School of Law</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref16_8k1" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>AA-COF</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_b63fa2c4fd2d72a3cbc9c1f37280570e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref17_dws" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Administration, 1905-1978</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_af43b7a47e20ef0f880f4bb56d36ea4b" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref18_ffk" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Admissions</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_bb7611083c9ca1460cabcde5a3f418ad" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref19_oql" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Alumni</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_c7f33c5c44969ddfeb9e2b23f333d19c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref20_b2p" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Alumni Register [Duke], 1938, 1963</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_88814bf7158672f8185255210485c8f2" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref21_0p1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Annual Reports to the President, 1960-1968</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_5467d532e08ccf7503c7f844893808f3" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref22_bfh" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Barristers Club</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_89d3058ae268a2cd6319c8d4b1947cdd" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref23_1ys" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bolich, W. Bryan, <title render="doublequote">A History of Duke Law
                School,</title> 1972</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_02169eea0dc1ce9e2a0af0c9f09a5c7f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref24_ajo" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Law School Building, Dedication, Plans, etc.</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_f6b4fff54a820fcc99dd0d4c3b8ca2a7" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref25_bto" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Law School Building, Addition, Groundbreaking</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_b7fe81e4d8a041fcbfd332735562d8ad" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref26_xav" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Campaign for Duke, Final Report, 1992</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_8c160d5d41856aa313f0cd489120a2a3" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref27_4t1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Center for the Study of the Public Domain, "Bound by Law", 2002</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_34045c9ee94ea2e21903a3f7d8667f3b" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref28_v09" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings, Miscellaneous</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_6eeeaaebe5d0ab14a36367f45d5af6b8" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref29_xk4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings and news releases, 1964-2000</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_62e381b8ba9f1dc4ba061a2fefb45de0" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref30_e9g" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Commencement, Procession, undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_ee9f1a960c100f1bf9d332c218e64c13" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref31_p7w" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Conference on Securities Regulation, 1964 Nov 6-7</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_07cfb63b72bf7baabc2d0256e1110714" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref32_ggl" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Cox, Miriam [first female law student] (A97-51)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_db8fbe8fd0bbd021abfb81562ed62694" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref33_ikk" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>CU-J</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_e860e4f5d55f3a459c7075c3a91bbb0c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >2</container>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref34_gzz" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Curriculum</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_6ecfa0e0c4ccf7017a4167cfef25f530" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref35_qsm" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Development and History</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_3a57b3f371afd3991de2a2fa340235dd" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref36_y69" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Duke Bar Association, 1932-1938</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_0f129201fbda6b0c170b874b5e72069a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref37_c2v" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Duke Bar Association, Memos, resolutions, constitution, 1979-1980</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_753f94a4526f7e1b6506c5392cf01ac6" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref38_5f0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Duke International Law Society</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_82ed6810628e69d2bec2004a73a5b047" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref39_35i" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Duke Law Journal: Symposium, 1980</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_ba4a4721fe0cc463c47fab23045e0199" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref40_0sj" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Duke Law Journal</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_055f8c3dce455668fb04920d2387c8a4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref41_b5f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Duke Law Reporter"</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_f7aba2218e5f6d6608ac3d6f6c539cc3" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref42_zkg" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Faculty Meeting, minutes and memoranda</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_7b6c5a8c58763ba06060a3a836033b41" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref43_0k0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>First Year Law Classes, picture and clippings</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_aeb2bdd9a17fe47f432b0f6b8139ec5e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref44_cov" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Government Contracts Conference, 1964</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_661f0cd2863a2d5196e252e2cb646ad0" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref45_e7v" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Grants and Special Projects Committee</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_40237125ce2bb08424147ab5f2da86e1" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref46_7t4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Hanging the Nixon Portrait: A Perspective . . .," (A98-18), 1998</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_e96dae983477767667f83d4fcee19adc" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref47_lze" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Institutes</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_2d190ecdd306cce5d6208b6c19a497ea" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref48_p4d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Duke International Law Society Annual, 1986-1987</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_aa3c1d59273264a5e1587bfb59ea7a02" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref49_nr9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>International Legal Studies Conference, 1955</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_e43b2b9b6a8f035f4e9f4848e5936ae0" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref50_7p8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"An Introduction to Civil Procedure" by Dale F. Stansbury,
              undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_88a413a3a7281ce89737fc10a091fb56" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref51_wuk" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Introduction to the Duke University School of Law [pamphlet],
              1981</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_eba4c5c9a0b7d4acafcc0f557b9bacc7" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref52_t5r" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>L-N</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_8049f1815e95d412e44f5a1e96e6a9b8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >3</container>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref53_byn" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Law School Bulletin, 1932-1934</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_2bc48f77bd66c37f316dc0b677444379" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref54_63c" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Law and Contemporary Problems</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_4e302c1d6251b1c080040df0a6bc00ac" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref55_pym" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Law Day</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_00d69eb335bfa0f7d0df205f72be2531" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref56_2m1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Law Forum</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_5411a1d179998006a3e09d65f2cde36b" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref57_xrj" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Law School Bulletin, 1934-1941</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_b6b5f1aaac5e64cea597c2130cc081bf" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref58_izr" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Law and Public Policy Program</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_51f506e30fa382d197f2d2581defd1de" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref59_7tt" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Legal Aid Clinic</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_45f99115f52fb9cedbfef0fe6f5d098b" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref60_wqg" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Legislative Research and Drafting Dept., 1931</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_1fc103911c09f65f2e5d6d7948f390e9" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref61_qie" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Library (2 folders)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_0908a27d39b7cd757b74c58eee668f94" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref62_8os" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Log Cabins</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_dd0aa7e8c7b2da1ee765f32bc05b5be9" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref63_8bu" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Long-Range Planning Report, 1958</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_5e2ad9e75b7b6dd78d63140017e3493f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref64_ewl" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>John Marshall Portrait</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_a16cd5d6815344ffe06b0d1dfe816156" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref65_t8v" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Moot Court Competition</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_92170b706b9146077f72da3e5aecd4b6" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref66_hy7" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Mordecai Society, Constitution, 1930</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_993c1293f089f91d6bd15f0c400cba3f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref67_i2d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>North Carolina Bar Association Institute</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_a286969cf4492227b9e734b1a4fc880e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref68_3zn" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>North Carolina Bar Notes, 1973-1980</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_a4254b423f8cf350975817dc9d173fd3" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref69_0ll" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>O-Z</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_5cecc5173e3973d31c471cdce802e77e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >4</container>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref70_ts0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Order of the Coif (2 folders)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_3fb73c093e8e66b5a428343b207d7c31" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref71_67x" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Pre-legal Education Committee (2 folders)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_a269850e370d85aa22213d20a7785fad" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref72_j9o" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle><title render="doublequote">Passport</title> [newsletter], 1997</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_7bd58aa28e3247d5fa1d2e225843f4cb" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref73_qi6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Publications, miscellaneous</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_50de8b8d5313eedc7eae58f11681ca49" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref74_yn7" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Rule of Law Research Center</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_06c2feac314f4b4da83a6cc87ec719d8" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref75_hyn" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Rules of the Law School</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_d6eed1a50bfdf51052ac4075bf396346" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref76_gex" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Scholarships</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_efe7a59cbc99fa8b3e7f3d83021370ac" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref77_ma8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>School Law Conference, 1954-1962</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_47c1d41a72ffe654d21037b4ae0c8a33" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref78_6r4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Self-Study Report, 1965</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_8f8a4e10b6002573f5ba44956b52d6ce" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref79_hdb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Shimm, Melvin G., <title render="doublequote">Reflections on the history of
                Duke Law School,</title> 1995</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_d2f1894d8a22a75f26354945c386c9bf" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref80_3uw" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Soviet International Law Conference, 1964</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_2799b991fb8295a50db7d23ed807edc5" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref81_dax" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Speeches/Symposiums, 1933, 1963, 1969</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_16d677746ba1300a24cb9f4591f9083b" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref82_9nu" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Student Papers</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_3d04a383346a3a9ffecb5b35b8a904ec" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref83_v9v" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Trinity College Law School [see Trinity College (Durham, NC)
              Collection]</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_afe52b5a432644aae2a3138de1234413" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref84_kww" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Weather Modification Seminar, 1976</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_5663476bf323d406c389dff03ff105d6" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
