<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/ualrpc/">ualrpc</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the University Committee on Long Range Planning Records, 1958 -
               1962 <num>UA.03.02.0016</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: Torrence Thomas ; machine-readable finding aid created by: Linda
               Daniel and Jill Katte</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003305627</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-29 22:29:05
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>University Committee on Long Range Planning records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. University Committee on Long-Range
               Planning</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>UA.03.02.0016</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.5 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1958/1962" type="inclusive">1958 - 1962</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_36e76cf39462f87ccd04fdc788e3e2d1">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult University Archives, Duke
            University.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_c17fd7d357fd0d8cef773499ed81e48a">The University Committee on Long
            Range Planning, formed in 1958, was set up to give administrative consideration to
            matters of educational programming and policy at Duke University. The Committee's first
            chairman was Paul M. Gross. Its name changed to the University Planning Committee in
            1962. The collection includes correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, clippings,
            pamphlets, charts, projections, and books. It consists of records relating to the
            academic, faculty, and institutional development of the university. Major subjects
            include university planning administration, student life, institutional development,
            enrollment, admissions, and academic life. English.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_9a932479bf104de6317a4fe23e11af4a">
            <extent>4500 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_72f8903ea34f57642edfe0b12122dc4b">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_9e8055df9d554738fd10f0dfc47c4a73">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>No restrictions.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_c6a69d8973d8d5ba5c56878c571e2016">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Duke University; all other
            copyright is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as
            stipulated by United States copyright law.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_1c4c824377c4ebe6f7b62005cdb0356b">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], University Committee on Long Range Planning Records, Duke
            University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke
            University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_ad3a8b4e5416c211db3d3690b7b3cced">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The University Committee on Long Range Planning Records were received by the University
            Archives as a transfer in 1974 (A74-36), 1982 (A82-127), and 1993 (A93-96). These
            transfers consist of a combination of accession A72-77, which was extracted from the
            files of Presidents Harts and Eden on the subject of Long Range Planning, and accession
            A62-163, from the files of Alan K. Manchester, Dean of Trinity College, and accession
            A93-96, from Professor Frank DeVyver's papers.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_267efdfe2376647cafba0a1341aae7ae">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Torrence Thomas </p>
         <p>Completed December 1998</p>
         <p>De-accessioned thirty-seven bulletins and associated publications not concerned with
            long range planning from other universities; and six duplicate reports. </p>
         <p>Encoded by Linda Daniel and Jill Katte, June 2004</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_64ad86bae6f9cb9ba02bac759d192dba">
         <head>Historical Note</head>
         <p>The University Committee on Long Range Planning was formed in 1958 under President A.
            Hollis Edens. The function according to a letter approving the committee was <emph
               render="doublequote">to give appropriate consideration to matters of educational
               programming and policy where institutional planning and advancement are
               concerned.</emph> The Committee at first dealt with issues dealing with academic
            life, faculty development, and the development of the quality of students and
            intellectual life through admissions and enrollment. During the Committee's initial
            academic year it authorized eleven subcommittees which dealt with the Graduate School,
            Social Sciences, Duke Press, Research Libraries, Science and Mathematics, Religion,
            Undergraduate Colleges, the University Arts Center, the Institute of Contemporary
            Literature, Foreign Student Programs, and the Humanities. The committee issued its first
            report, <title type="simple" render="doublequote">Planning and Development at Duke
               University,</title> in June of 1959.</p>
         <p>The Committee's first chairman was Paul M. Gross, the Vice President for Education and
            Dean of the University. However, on March 23, 1960 in the wake of an administrative
            crisis known as <title type="simple" render="doublequote">the Gross-Edens Affair</title>
            the Board of Trustees stripped Dr. Gross of his committee chairmanship and other
            administrative posts. Vice-Chairman Marcus Hobbs was named to succeed him, but Hobbs
            tendered his resignation on March 28, 1960. Hobbs was in turn succeeded by Joseph E.
            Markee, another member of the committee. These events brought the future of the planning
            process into question. The committee informed the University's faculty and staff that it
            was in <emph render="doublequote">complete and total disagreement with the action taken
               by the Board of Trustees at its meeting on March 23, 1960 in removing Dr. Paul M.
               Gross as a member and the Chairman of the Long Range Planning Committee.</emph> In
            its second Progress Report, (May, 1960) the committee stated that they felt it best to
            suspend activities <emph render="doublequote">until such time as it receive[d] from the
               Board of Trustees and from the President of the University a satisfactory expression
               of their approval of the planning operation as it has been carried on</emph> (page
            73). If approval was given, the committee recommended that the University extend the
            committee's charge until June 1961 and provide a budget to fund it through that period. </p>
         <p>This was done; the committee's third progress report, <title type="simple"
               render="doublequote">Duke University in the Decade Ahead,</title> was issued in June
            1961. It dealt with enrollment projections, personnel and facility requirements, and
            financial projections. The committee concluded that systematic planning was <emph
               render="doublequote">essential</emph> and that <emph render="doublequote">its
               function should be institutionalized so as to achieve continuity and wide
               participation throughout the University</emph> (pages 53-54). In 1962, the University
            Committee on Long Range Planning was reconstituted as the University Planning Committee
            and assumed a stronger role in the University. </p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_7c03d1430765a84cd81c487fd2fdee9b">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>The collection consists of records relating to the Committee on Long Range Planning's
            involvement with academic, faculty, and institutional development of the University.
            Correspondence, memoranda, reports, hand-written and typed minutes, clippings,
            pamphlets, charts, projections, books, comprise this collection. Materials range in date
            from 1958-1962. Although the majority of the materials were created by the Committee,
            some reference materials from other sources were collected by the Committee in relation
            to its work, including letters, reports, booklets and pamphlets about other schools and
            programs. </p>
         <p>Major subjects include University and planning administration, student life
            (dormitories, athletics, and extracurricular activities), institutional development
            (philosophical beginnings and practical implementations), enrollment and admission (test
            data, alumni involvement, prediction equations and geographical distribution) and
            academic/intellectual life (graduate and undergraduate schools and departments,
            curriculum information and planning and faculty development).</p>
         <p>This collection is divided into six (6) series: Minutes and Agendas, 1958-1962; Meeting
            Files, 1959-1961; Correspondence, 1958-1962; Reports and Recommendations, 1958-1962; and
            Reference Materials, 1958-1962; and Subcommittees and Committees, 1958-1962.</p>
         <p> The Minutes and Agendas [1958-1962] series includes minutes, agendas, and summaries,
            and it chronicles the development of planning at the University. Meeting Files
            [1959-1961] is arranged chronologically and includes memos, letters, reports, booklets,
            bulletins, news clippings, and statistical information specifically discussed at
            meetings of the Committee. The materials in the meeting files, in some cases, can be
            matched against the materials delineated in the Committee minutes. The Committee met
            almost weekly during the academic year, from 1958-1962. </p>
         <p>The Correspondence [1958-1962] represents the wide range of issues faced by the
            Committee. Primary correspondents consist of the President of the University, the
            Provost, faculty and staff members of the University, and expert professors and
            professionals from other universities; these include R. Taylor Cole, Marcus E. Hobbs,
            Paul M. Gross, A. Hollis Edens, Daryl J. Hart, Richard L. Predmore, Frank DeVyver, and
            Alan K. Manchester. </p>
         <p>The Reports and Recommendations [1958-1962] series is arranged alphabetically. It
            includes reports and recommendations from academic and non-academic departments,
            graduate and professional schools, visiting experts on academic programs and
            departments, and University faculty and staff. Reference Materials [1958-1962] are
            arranged alphabetically. These folders contain reports, charts, pamphlets, and
            statistics collected by the Committee for use during its work. </p>
         <p>The Subcommittees and Committees [1958-1962] series is arranged topically. The Long
            Range Planning Committee had a number of subcommittees, but this series includes
            reports, recommendations, correspondence and records of a few of these committees: the
            Committee on the Undergraduate Colleges, 1959-1960; the Committee on Faculty and Staff
            Improvement, 1960-1961; and the Committee on Professional and Graduate School,
            1958-1962. </p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_18488dd2b61e8925c708bfbe1d6f5591">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>
            <archref>
               <unittitle>University Planning Committee Records, <unitdate era="ce"
                     calendar="gregorian" type="inclusive">1962-1964</unitdate>, <unitdate era="ce"
                     calendar="gregorian" type="inclusive">1971-1973</unitdate>.</unittitle>
               <repository>University Archives, Duke University.</repository>
            </archref>
            <archref>
               <unittitle>University Planning and Policy Advisory Committee Records, <unitdate
                     era="ce" calendar="gregorian" type="inclusive"
                  >1964-1969</unitdate>.</unittitle>
               <repository>University Archives, Duke University.</repository>
            </archref>
         </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Campus planning</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges -- Planning</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- Aims and objectives</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges -- Administration</subject>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Administration</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- History -- 20th century</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Planning</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Admission</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Faculty</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. University Committee on Long-Range
            Planning</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Students</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Gross, Paul Magnus, 1895-1986</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. University Committee on Long-Range
            Planning</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_4ft" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Minutes and Agendas, 1958-1962</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_a1bbd66cef72f2455194d231d1b61814">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Includes minutes, agendas, and running summaries. This series chronicles the
                  development of planning at the University.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref13_kvn" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes, 1958-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_934905488161814727a8d03b39cba33b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8578f3fcb594106fbf1e2e3c82f5aaf7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Minutes for January-May 1960 are missing, but running summaries are available
                     for these meetings.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_pgy" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Agendas, 1960-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c3a7ce544617fd94b2283c1606c358b3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_ivl" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Running Summaries, 1958-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_4bd6bf1c5938fedb63c029e3249941af" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f6fc6bf6c0807a3dea2a6c38fd4e7688">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Includes transcripts of all official meetings, prepared by the Executive
                     Secretary of the Committee.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref19_n7e" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Meeting Files, 1959-1961</unittitle>
               <container id="aspace_120873f3d59a36702229a02d9da3e766" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_16e37fa5bbe75d7c0629e5dbb2883d24">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>These files include memos, letters, reports, booklets, bulletins, news clippings,
                  and statistical information specifically discussed at meetings of the Committee.
                  The materials in the meeting files, in some cases, correspond to the Committee
                  minutes. The Committee met almost weekly during the academic year, from
                  1958-1962.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref21_uvv" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence, 1958-1962</unittitle>
               <container id="aspace_e45ad4af6b32e900719d2d465cfe61f1" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_9ef34d5605858c9098c4d4ab88fa5cae">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Correspondents include R. Taylor Cole, Marcus E. Hobbs, Paul M. Gross, A. Hollis
                  Edens, Daryl J. Hart, Richard L. Predmore, Frank DeVyver, and Alan K.
                  Manchester.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref23_2eg" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Reports and Recommendations, 1958-1962</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_ggu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Academic Departments, 1958-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a65d210de2049f3263258a64e680aa08" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_df2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Non-Academic Departments, 1958-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e0f22a9ab0cfc06f1b5817315b639f15" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref26_4yw" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faculty, 1958-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ffa1137e23a74faef37ced8f837a0dbf" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref27_d8b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Graduate and Professional Schools, 1958-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_066b4307bfcd13451530f3ae8731af05" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_c3p" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Visiting Experts, 1958-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e93ed73b4940b78ece18e37fc90a4bb0" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0ca85c2bd75cebbd0d7e24a4136871a5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>The reports and recommendations in this file come from experts from Harvard,
                     Rice, the University of Pennsylvania, the University of Illinois, and the
                     University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. The material focuses on the
                     departments of Economics, History, Physics, Classical Studies, English, and the
                     Graduate School of Arts of and Sciences.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_u3o" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Progress Reports, 1958-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_20386822788e7af75d799aac48eb2d4a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref31_n58" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Reference Materials, 1958-1962</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_01m" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Administrative Organization, 1958-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_af1aeb3be3c1bb908ea3791f6ca6287a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref33_ye7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Admissions and Enrollment, 1958-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_dae980db0d1cbab9746ab3118f05c1d5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref34_11d" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Charts and Projections, 1958-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3ee08a3ec6d8083230dc8d598beda3c5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_33827e8599bbf239825d3c28225f3e04">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Includes charts graphs, and projections dealing with academics, dormitories,
                     and faculty appointments. Much of the material in this file deals with Duke in
                     comparison to other schools.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref36_5we" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Curriculum, 1958-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a9df62c1e46d7a4af817f5009fc92663" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref37_ciq" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Departments and Classifications, 1958</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_710e0c3924eea022779741bd2c435af5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_efd99be2c16a8de2a4de4c7e8ad5fbca">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Arranged by classification, includes memos and reports that deal with the
                     systematic approach that the Committee was to use in planning. The
                     classifications are <emph render="doublequote">New Areas and
                        Enterprises,</emph>
                     <emph render="doublequote">Space Requirements and Needs,</emph>
                     <emph render="doublequote">Strengthening What We Have,</emph> and <emph
                        render="doublequote">Administration of Personnel.</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref39_vx0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Facilities, 1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_fea5868b356d4d711ccaa74f0f5fa197" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref40_z3n" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faculty Salaries, 1958-1959</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_aca23dcdca71e84bce4c488a470376dc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref41_g1q" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Duke University, School of Medicine Hospital Administration Program,
                     1958 and 1960</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_97561e890334f82a40532052dcb4fc47" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref42_k44" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Duke University Office of Institutional Advancement, 1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a51f4643beff1870f75adaf6616a83ec" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref43_ea6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>News Clipping, <title render="italic">Durham Morning Herald</title>,
                     June 14, 1959</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9432d2e25eb92270822ca1b20ecc782a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref44_3bu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Progress Reports, 1958-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_789e7d6c601d7bba905bf8b1b1fa5552" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref45_jhh" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Visits of School and Colleges, 1958-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ee520150541b0b24784d9ed11c33aefb" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_515d06f6c1a4e59b372ffca976faa051">
                  <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                  <p>Includes information on other colleges and schools visited by Duke professors
                     and staff. Schools include Harvard, Princeton, Swarthmore, Rice, Vanderbilt,
                     Brown, Columbia, Yale, Tulane, Columbia and Wesleyan Universities, the Carnegie
                     Institute of Technology, the University of Rochester, Union Theological
                     Institute, Perkins School of Theology, the Hartford Seminary Foundation, Boston
                     University School of Theology, Andover Newton Theological Institute, and Austin
                     Presbyterian Theological Seminary. The information in this file deals with many
                     aspects of college governance, academics, student life, and planning. It also
                     includes a pamphlet entitled, <title type="simple" render="doublequote">Long
                        Range Planning for Colleges and Universities,</title> by Arnold F. Emich,
                     1958.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref47_r8z" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Subcommittees and Committees, 1958-1962</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref48_4xs" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Subcommittee on the Undergraduate Colleges, 1958-1962</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref49_5oi" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Administrative Materials, 1959-1960</unittitle>
                  </did>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref50_023" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Minutes, 1959-1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_d0255f15e39f582b135bf2c40fdc529a"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref51_jsa" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>
                           <title render="doublequote">Final Report of the Subcommittee on the
                              Undergraduate College,</title> 1959-1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_bcb5319a2a61ea1f8579615e53c3d5d4"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref52_48w" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Reports, 1959-1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_d6d4217544a65eb5e03c9b90a3e6593d"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref53_lh5" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Recommendations, 1959-1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_fa3f76cee01135829d4a55842937346b"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref54_bg1" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Correspondence, 1958-1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_05ec4eb8b972527a9dfea83ff7aa0dac"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref55_osk" level="subseries">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Reference Materials, 1958-1960</unittitle>
                  </did>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref56_0ga" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Academic Averages, 1959-1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_1872caa56b7f5d9b9951d30f434032d8"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref57_k9t" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Academic Courses, 1959-1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_fc849bd86d9d05fee515638525b2d2a6"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref58_amf" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Application Materials, 1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_6bc6ca8a50e6f32db2288c5d2a0ed965"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref59_z5b" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Athletics, 1959-1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_04c8fe67d4f7433ecc0a3d1879a9bb91"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref60_rhv" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Extracurricular Activities, 1959-1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_1ca351133ad8b9271bfeedad855a757e"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                     <scopecontent id="aspace_6d181ef09998d9065a46c916d50c557d">
                        <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
                        <p>Contains lists of student organizations at the University.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref62_2a3" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>General Subject Files, 1959-1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_0b0b4298d9e97ae9e682bafe2aa36845"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref63_gmb" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>News Clippings, 1959-1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_382c3d69428fae22be9b07bb90c958c7"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref64_zxr" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Placement Testing, 1959-1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_1a37ab9f32dbf03905e96dba10294dfd"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref65_cpk" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Religious Life, 1958</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_ca28aa8e4a8625e0ffa36dfc3c0fcc63"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref66_cay" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>William H. Rice Institute/University, 1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_af8b9adb0158babb31ef4d1d1424593b"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref67_1gb" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Traffic Commission, 1959-1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_5a786a5067dc851ca812b333276755ed"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref68_r8r" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Trinity College and the School of Engineering</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_e2e7a20761e1f960294a912b4addb216"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref69_cw4" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>West Campus Dormitories, 1959-1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_98414a8ba72f7eb18c2605ec9cf37f8f"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
                  <c04 id="aspace_ref70_9wj" level="file">
                     <did>
                        <unittitle>Women's College, 1959-1960</unittitle>
                        <container id="aspace_48150eca13f6ffd19b6d66fa29a3a1d5"
                           label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
                     </did>
                  </c04>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref72_1x4" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Committee on Professional and Graduate School, 1958-1962</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref73_rfc" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Organizational Materials, 1958-1962</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_a52f6fcd90015dc5ca45312d66bbd086" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ref74_t5g" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title render="italic">Report of the Sub-Committee on Matters Related to the
                           Graduate School</title>, undated</unittitle>
                     <container id="aspace_552e936354381af073024bc7251c0290" label="Mixed Materials"
                        type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref75_c4i" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Committee on Faculty and Staff Improvement, 1960-1961</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0705b633352ccaa183a1e4f881da8e5a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
