<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uamitchellwicker/"
      >uamitchellwicker</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Joseph Mitchell Papers on Max Wicker, 1932-2006 (bulk 1954)
            <num>UA.30.01.0087</num></titleproper>
        <author>Erin Ryan</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">007672551</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-10-12 10:37:14
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Joseph Mitchell Papers on Max Wicker</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="lcnaf">Mitchell, Joseph, 1927-</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>UA.30.01.0087</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1932/2006" type="inclusive">1932-2006</unitdate>
      <unitdate normal="1954/1954" type="bulk">Bulk 1954</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_813e24ac570ea6d847eb2d91e771d469">Max Wicker was head of Duke
        University's Baptist Student Union (BSU) in 1953. He was dismissed by the North Carolina
        Baptists’ General Board in 1954, along with state BSU director Jimmy Ray and UNC-Chapel Hill
        BSU secretary J.C. Herrin, after events surrounding the invitation of a controversial
        speaker, Christian theologian Nels Ferre, to the 1953 BSU Convention. Their termination
        followed a six-hour hearing before the Board. The student leaders’ dismissal made the pages
        of the April 12, 1954 TIME magazine. Joseph Mitchell graduated from Duke Divinity School in
        1953, where he met Max Wicker. After his retirement, Mitchell began to research and write
        the account of his friend’s dismissal. This collection contains the materials he gathered in
        the course of his research, including biographical information about individuals involved in
        the controversy; correspondence related to Wicker’s BSU activities, his hearing and
        termination; Max Wicker’s public statement about his beliefs; other documents related to the
        activities of the BSU at Duke and elsewhere in the state; and news clippings that appeared
        in regional and national publications. The collection also contains appendices and drafts of
        Mitchell’s account, and his final bound paper, "The 1954 Firing of Max Wicker and Two Other
        North Carolina Student Directors, Jimmy Ray and J.C. Herrin" (2006).</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_c831c7ea21feefbeeb16955b837e85cc">Materials are in
        English.</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <arrangement id="aspace_dc152032f38b9dbf7da2862d2d14add7">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>The collection is arranged into two series: Research Files and Publication Files.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <bioghist id="aspace_b8aa0b674130797cbe83e57c18ac240b">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Max Wicker was born in Southern Pines, N.C., on August 7, 1924. After his high school
        graduation in 1943, he entered a U.S. Navy officer training program at Duke University. He
        served in the Navy in 1945-46, and returned to study at Duke in 1947. He received his A.B.
        degree from Duke in 1949 and his B.D. degree from Duke Divinity School in 1952. Wicker began
        working as Baptist Secretary at Duke in 1952, and was president of the Baptist Student Union
        (BSU) at Duke in 1953. He was ordained a Baptist pastor that year in Aberdeen, N.C.</p>
      <p>Baptist leaders in North Carolina began investigating the various state chapters of the BSU
        after Jimmy Ray, the statewide BSU director, invited Christian theologian Nels Ferre to
        speak at their November 1953 BSU Convention. Ferre had been accused of questioning the
        doctrine of the Virgin birth of Jesus Christ. Following this investigation, and after a
        six-hour hearing before the N.C. Baptists’ General Board, Wicker, Ray, and J.C. Herrin, the
        BSU secretary at UNC-Chapel Hill, were dismissed from their jobs in Spring 1954 over
        questions about their theology and choice of BSU programming. The dismissal made the pages
        of the April 12, 1954 TIME magazine, which quoted Wicker as saying to the Board, “I do not
        affirm the Virgin birth, and I do not deny it.” Though the Board had fired Wicker from his
        position as president of the BSU, Duke continued to employ him as a Baptist chaplain. He
        officially resigned from Duke in June 1954 and became a Methodist minister. He married Ann
        Stewart in 1955. They had five children, Mary Ann, Edythe Louise, Stewart Wesley, Susan
        Eleanor, and Will.</p>
      <p>Frank Joseph Mitchell (known as Joseph or Joe) was born February 12, 1927, in Fairfield,
        Alabama. He spent time in the U.S. Naval Reserve as a Hospital Apprentice in 1945-46, and
        graduated from Alabama Polytechnic Institute (now Auburn University) in 1950. Mitchell
        graduated from Duke Divinity School in 1953, where he met Max Wicker. Mitchell returned to
        Duke to receive his doctorate in religion in the 1960s. He served as a Methodist minister,
        and taught at Carleton College in Northfield, MN; Union College in Barbourville, KY; and
        Central Methodist College in Fayette, MO; before becoming Professor of Religion and
        Philosophy at Troy State University in Troy, Alabama (1970-1989). Mitchell married Norma
        Anne Taylor in 1959. They had one daughter, Anne Virginia.</p>
      <p>After their retirement, Joseph and Norma Mitchell moved to Durham, N.C., in 2001. They
        lived near Max and Ann Wicker. Mitchell took up the research into his friend’s case and
        dismissal, and used this research to produce his 2006 paper, "The 1954 Firing of Max Wicker
        and Two Other North Carolina Student Directors, Jimmy Ray and J.C. Herrin."</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_d7ec4bc3a30954338c818f425504dba4">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
        research use.</p>
      <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_51cc0eaaa2d76b9859423555bef5e921">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Duke University; all other copyright
        is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as stipulated by
        United States copyright law.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_9de39c6d8d48b7bb38d721609c74538f">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Joseph Mitchell Papers on Max Wicker were received by the Duke University Archives,
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, as a gift in 2016.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_0798c0a32bab59fdd1edaea09db8277c">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Joseph Mitchell Papers on Max Wicker, Duke University Archives,
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_c6594302daabc1df62cf1461d67b6afb">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Erin Ryan, September 2016.</p>
      <p>Accessions described in this collection guide: UA2016-0037.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_f1648d5edd7be93ebe714492f19f6054">
      <head>Related Materials</head>
      <p><extref xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uarlrcol/">Guide to the
          Religious Life Reference Collection</extref>, Duke University Archives, David M.
        Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_3422eaabb59f9bb5504cf6f4699aed77">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>The Joseph Mitchell Papers on Max Wicker include materials collected by Duke Divinity
        School alumnus Joseph Mitchell related to the 1954 dismissal of Mitchell’s friend Max Wicker
        from his position as head of Duke University’s Baptist Student Union (BSU) by the N.C.
        Baptists’ General Board. The collection is arranged into two series. Research Files contains
        correspondence, newspaper clippings, articles and memorabilia Mitchell collected in the
        course of researching an account he wrote about the dismissal of Wicker and two other BSU
        student directors, including biographical information about many of the individuals involved
        in the dismissal, and other documents related to the activities of the BSU at Duke and
        elsewhere in the state. The second series, Writings, contains Mitchell’s bound 2006 paper
        about the incident, as well as drafts, appendices and other items related to its
        composition.</p>
      <p>Materials are largely textual. The collection also includes two black-and-white
        photographs, a Baptist Student Union pin, and two CDs containing Word Perfect files of
        Mitchell’s paper about the Baptist student directors’ dismissal.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Baptists -- North Carolina -- History</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">College students -- Religious life</subject>
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Wicker, Max.</persname>
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Duke University--Students</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Student life</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_d14ffb5fad05592b8830fdca9ea309f8" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Research Files</unittitle>
          <unitid>1</unitid>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1932-2003</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_ef4fcc5ac8f2b2d86c226a77f650b641">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Research Files includes information about individuals involved in the student leaders’
            dismissal; correspondence related to Max Wicker’s BSU activities, his hearing and
            termination, including letters of support to Wicker from Baptist and Methodist students;
            Max Wicker’s public statement about his beliefs; and other documents related to the
            activities of the BSU at Duke and elsewhere in the state. The collection also contains
            clippings covering the three student leaders’ 1954 hearing and dismissal that appeared
            in regional and national publications. The bulk of the clippings are arranged
            chronologically at the end of the series.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_e3f937230c973203a0b2db018395995a" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Research on Individuals</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1932-2003</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3024aa05f21df712fee723144a133c02" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_900dc7a85cc3b1bcea42840928eeba76">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains articles, correspondence, and biographical information gathered by Frank
              Joseph Mitchell about Baptist leaders and other individuals who were involved in
              events surrounding the 1954 dismissal of North Carolina Baptist student directors Max
              Wicker, J.C. Herrin, and Jimmy Ray. The file is arranged alphabetically by last name
              of the subjects, and incorporates the covers from Mitchell's original research
              folders. The file includes material about the following individuals: Henry B.
              Anderson, Douglas Branch, J. Boyce Brooks, James O. Cansler, Warren Carr, Zeb. A.
              Caudle, Ed Christman, Perry Crouch, John Davis, Samuel T. Habel, Ottis J. Hagler, J.C.
              Herrin, Ralph Herring, W.C. Holland, M.A. Huggins, Barney Jones, Broadus Jones, J.W.
              Kincheloe, Roberts C. Lasater, John Lawrence, Mrs. Gordon Maddrey, Mrs. W.K. McGee, Bo
              Medlin, L.J. Phipps, Bob Phillips, Edwin Neill Poteat, Rowland Pruette, Ted Purcell,
              Joseph Ray, Robert Seymour, Elbert Wethington, Bruce E. Whitaker, and Guy Woodlief,
              Jr. In addition, the file contains the covers of Mitchell's empty research folders for
              Gloria Blanton, Harrie Brewington, Maxine Garner, Pitts Hughes, Francis Nicoll, Arnold
              Smith, and Ruth Swann.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_0adda177cee1cf14e8e5f8f3fc18c82b" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Photos and Memorabilia</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1943, 1952-1955</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_475a275fb82962e95c2e25d096920ab9" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_17a28b1709a89ace703b245b6fb85585" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>BSU at Duke</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1944-1957</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_37f2ed8fc547cd2518a3f70fb5e790cb" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_8644a630b6ff91a79041ab315d769980" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Nels Ferre</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1948-1961, 1971, 2003</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e814c262aaa859cc4e6306a63a153d01" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_33fd482fe9d335f7ea29c16e05aeb907" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Duke BSU</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1952, 1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_461aa9b88becdcb3b79e1281d5f60b6a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ba7202cae61d09a5ccc33c5f11b836ad" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Wicker and Ray Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1952-1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_f0bc39004b67417f5819419136c54119" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ee1f72a69791a627db8cf73614ae895f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>NC Baptist Meetings</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1953-1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_5c9ee6df36659ff474b1a2d08433a131" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_95118987714aa616c13416b661f41383" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Wicker Ordination</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1953, 2003</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d446d6aa95df761c31d694efbab8b9a2" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_085ef25c56c78fb6e6d385bcd6cfda13" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Wicker Speaks at VA BSU</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">November 1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_fefeb28f5c22adc160f3bb727b8ebc40" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_c153db25a6bff79207f0547bec6209ec" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>UNC BSU - Resolution</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">March 22, 1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_5ce63717428401994643991d7b892b5a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_01fc47c81d7c5838190a62ea0a8bd16a" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Meredith College Letter</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">March 23, 1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_1be160fdf143336dab22025d6862532f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_7c12d84cea49a8a6347780d042496ca3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Wicker Family Letters</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_8beb04f604fd8ab9ad10ea9d34e61038" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_be0ab388ee2a789d745e1c297943ead9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Letters of Support</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e2df754e8ec1ba432dffe224a0c15682" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_3d2c8ca774a9f8f482778bc323721850" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>General Board - NC Baptists</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_5e93e2499cc1ad22753a29c6ade1c9bb" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_067495fbad5c9751304fc3e1b8816d15" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Max Wicker's Statement to the Board</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3420baa769a406a1e9a32cbc6404e057" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_9fee2e9bf68f99bb5f27597045608453" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Official Discharge</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_7efd9ef8b659b8b66cbb18a8150a75ca" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_d78cd5b1dafc1dc4a1ff0a8368cb722c" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Resignation from Duke</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">May-June 1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_567c9ea2f8a0290f3e4600021b5f681c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_4db5ab9456b61167d2e102370b7cecff" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Max Wicker's Dismissal - Duke (TIME Magazine)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954, 2000</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_6f2c5be39b74d691f054ca0dcf07e9ed" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ece8c034ca9b59eabac81baed0ca6040" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>BSU - Ray - Reports</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_18654b36f858b4bcba473a8458bc4365" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_3d2b7976c1d6ae93ae759830bfd445fd" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>BSU Student Leaders - Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954, 1959</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d689fda135195e42e77eee529d636f28" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_a2ce5fcd3731bd4da1b4fa6037ab7e69" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Copies from J.C. Herrin File at UNC</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c43b26331804fa483175b754eea16f8e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_d7912a5edb30c6f5b2c1dd472c640418" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Former BSU Presidents</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">2003</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_cc276295222f15f8b5e29f43f22600b2" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_5d79a1d1d9e66eccc40724d49251957d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1932 Buick</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">2003</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_daf74f314e7ec9d82ceb5c68cbf7c923" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_883c3a8f7a1f53116164f4f1e66d333c" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: Biblical Recorder Copies</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1947-1954, 1967</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_7edabab68347bd98003f104a10b6a8f8" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_4f2f8fcf0578457e7a906b54606f678a" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: Wicker Case - Rocky Mount Case</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1952-1955, 2003</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e818730d75b4d8d61497dbe71968e6dc" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_92bb3befdc7127b3b48d415361b5ffda" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: BSU - Ferre</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3da886f152353d4bd447a5397ad7b58a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_99eeb297ce026b6a2279b879e7159ade" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: BSU</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">January 1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_1f57ef8fa97aa83a4f8049145e6f9991" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_b031ff111c9fabcd3b5370086e86a250" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: Wicker Case</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">March 1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_6fb949c795a2252c1324eceb68166430" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_8bb41275da502c92cc799fa69a379afb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: BSU Firings</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">March-April 1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_6989aae35a8483fffe09a34729514fa7" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_03123d89855602967917629b69813a42" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: BSU - Charlotte Observer</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">March-April 1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_74b65c9e9711086d43f1409cdebff530" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_bdce3db1cf7edefbf0a67cdef9cdcf7e" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: Marie Wicker Nurse Scholarship - The Sandhill Citizen</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">May 20, 1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2c43ab098252b1f270a39502753171de" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_c746015fa5a9beb7e347eeae5de0bba5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: Biblical Recorder</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_53c0c9662568db66cdbe811136e03efa" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_f5283e6ba7c38f297bdf4abb343fb10f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: Christian Century on BSU</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3889b6a8e90ecedf865ad78600f9a82b" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_c1ac65ae3c33432f5579421965bcb65e" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: Daily Tar Heel</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3f66c6d464934c4b548476506d34478d" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_dd794aaaeb2dff0b90979c9764b9c769" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: Mixed Editorials</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_890049791162e56f0b61896670e6de12" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_f009d82b54b4ce8625223524a4f835aa" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: Piedmont Bible Schools</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_111c1fee24641bd1bbe75b7acf4dba01" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_e57da60795d8b1f9a0d5de81cddc7e4b" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: Miscellaneous - Not about Wicker Case</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_0f0827250cc31561323d5a6047fffed8" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_5b2b01a59d9285ae4be7cddc8aaff383" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: Wicker and Income Tax - Richmond Times-Dispatch</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">April 16, 1955</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_8996b58869308aae55e2990683f1988e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_8296f6a0d9efae571a8ac8929c6c8a3d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings: Conservative and Moderate Baptists in NC - Samuel Hill</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1963</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a724c9b493ddb007198804d35c5dee19" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_04e1cb1094896ecccc92350d27bccc1d" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Writings</unittitle>
          <unitid>2</unitid>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1954, 2004-2006</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_a98023deda8acd4b1e4fdf6dc89d618b">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Writings contains drafts, appendices and other items related to Frank Joseph Mitchell’s
            2006 paper, "The 1954 Firing of Max Wicker and Two Other North Carolina Student
            Directors, Jimmy Ray and J.C. Herrin." The bound paper is included at the end of the
            series.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_8a3381856e90fa08c7f3973d724e30b6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Wicker Original (Joe's)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3125701516211b1512a798584c38a420" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_6fe92be48465d626db43e9c1bfd22191"
              parent="aspace_3125701516211b1512a798584c38a420" type="optical-disc"
              >UA30010087-OP-0001</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_d819871353b9eabdf4360c86f1c16af8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Wicker MS Final</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_4af7faaae4bcb1ca017d18bafe587304" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_6a72ab1a7a951bd488eb59c761b4e42e"
              parent="aspace_4af7faaae4bcb1ca017d18bafe587304" type="optical-disc"
              >UA30010087-OP-0002</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_fd4c15fa7e1c53685de977b4fe24cdb4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Wicker Appendices</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1954, 2004-2006</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_4c3f52eb6c0bcf22be2ae2cf0948b4ad" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_f9b1ba0bc6b4ad2a85c106537c17d9bc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Wicker Appendices: Max Wicker Becomes a Methodist</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">2005</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a5b5f188ac05b4b03dea8e3e29c6a0d4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_f2a31d154567836ac8d157473cb3b9b6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>The 1954 Firing of Max Wicker and Two Other North Carolina Baptist Student
              Directors (Book)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">2006</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_686bfbaf63de5756994f134821e8a8f6" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
