<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uasharoff/">uasharoff</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Barry Sharoff Papers on the Duke Vigil, 1968-1988
            <num>UA.30.01.0090</num></titleproper>
        <author>Tracy M. Jackson</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>March 2017</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">007806870</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-08-07 13:59:49
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Barry Sharoff Papers on the Duke Vigil</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname rules="rda">Sharoff, Barry</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>UA.30.01.0090</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1968/1988" type="inclusive">1968-1988</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_9357df808ae1e9735e016a3cf82c61e1">The Duke Vigil was a peaceful
        demonstration, sparked by the assassination of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., that occurred at
        Duke University in April 1968. The Vigil involved students, faculty, and non-academic
        employees of the university and called for racial equality and improved wages for hourly
        workers. Barry Sharoff organized publicity for the Duke Vigil Strategy Committee. The
        collection includes fliers, newspapers, press releases, statements, notes, correspondence,
        and publicly distributed materials regarding the Duke Vigil gathered by Barry Sharoff in his
        role in charge of publicity for the Vigil, as well as materials related to the 20th
        anniversary of the Vigil in 1988.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_62cf00c1a35c267270d3b370ddf9117c">Materials in English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="aspace_66d8f1496e946d72e7405fb95561f7d7">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Barry Sharoff was a Duke student from 1964-1968. He lwas in charge of publicity for the
        Duke Vigil along with Reed Kramer. As a part of the Strategy Committee and other groups
        organizing the Vigil, Sharoff helped organize the distribution of fliers and other materials
        regarding the Duke Vigil, including activities and background information on the causes and
        demands of the Vigil.</p>
      <p>Barry Sharoff graduated Duke in 1968 with a BA in Political Science. He currently lives in
        Colorado.</p>
      <p>The Duke Vigil: Sparked by the assassination of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. on April 4,
        1968, Duke University students organized a peaceful protest for racial equality that left
        few students, faculty, administrators or employees unaffected. Up to 1,400 students slept on
        the Chapel Quad, food services and housekeeping employees went on strike, and most students
        boycotted the dining halls in support of the employees. </p>
      <p>The protest began Friday evening, April 5, when 450 students marched three miles to
        University President Douglas Knight's House with the following four demands:</p>
      <p>• That he sign an advertisement to be published in the Durham Morning Herald calling for a
        day of mourning;</p>
      <p>• That he press for the $1.60 wage for University employees;</p>
      <p>• That he resign from the then-segregated Hope Valley Country Club;</p>
      <p>• That he appoint a committee of students, faculty and workers to make recommendations
        concerning collective bargaining and union recognition at Duke.</p>
      <p>Knight met the students and faculty members on his front lawn, and began negotiations.
        Several students spent the night in the president's house at his invitation. Saturday
        afternoon, Knight attended and spoke at a memorial service for King in Duke Chapel.
        Following the service, 350 students and faculty marched to Knight's home to support the
        students still inside the house. Knight promised to release an official statement within 72
        hours, but Vice President for Student Affairs William Griffith and Knight's physician
        William Anlyan told the group the president was about to collapse from exhaustion and could
        no longer participate in the negotiations.</p>
      <p>The Duke Vigil officially began the next morning, Sunday, April 7, as protesters moved onto
        Chapel Quad. Coordinators demanded strict adherence to a set of rules for the demonstration.
        In their straight rows of 50 people, the students were not allowed to talk to each other or
        the press. Rigidly ordered, the quad protest was meant to symbolize the non-violent
        intentions of the group. By Tuesday night more than 1,400 demonstrators assembled for the
        Vigil. </p>
      <p>On Wednesday, April 10, professor Samuel DuBois Cook addressed the students, and then
        Wright Tisdale, chair of the Board of Trustees, told the crowd the trustees and students
        shared the same concerns. He said the University would begin paying a $1.60 minimum wage and
        mentioned Knight's proposed committee to examine racial concerns. The demonstrators filed
        into Page Auditorium, where professors read an Academic Council resolution and tried to
        persuade the students to end the protest since the Board of Trustees had met the major part
        of their demands. The students agreed to drop their insistence on Knight's Durham Morning
        Herald advertisement and resignation from Hope Valley Country Club. After midnight on
        Thursday, April 11, 1968, the students decided to continue their boycott of the dining halls
        and pledged to support the workers' union, Local 77.</p>
      <p>Members of the Duke Vigil Strategy Committee continued to organize activities after the
        official end of the Vigil. Seminars were held on the main quad (now Abele Quad) April 18-21,
        and another boycott of university dining halls was called for May 10.</p>
      <p>[Portions of this text from 'Profound History': Students answered violence with the Silent
        Vigil by Laura Trivers, published in The Chronicle, April 4, 1988.]</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_537269f0a3d89dff07dd1ca465c490d6">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_db4dfeb0882e9b6e63ebec3dcb42bda9">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Duke University; all other copyright
        is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as stipulated by
        United States copyright law.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_f2361cfbebeb71308d3acf71b1ff60ca">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Barry Sharoff Papers on the Duke Vigil were received by the University Archives as a
        gift in 2017.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_a6f5fe585d075912077ad077a6b7944f">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Barry Sharoff Papers on the Duke Vigil, Duke University Archives,
        David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_586a7ad7fc460408e3667e7387b2ee6a">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Tracy M. Jackson, March, 2017 Accessions described in this collection guide:
        UA2017.0006</p>
    </processinfo>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_56abeab7ae726b0843e457106664569b">
      <head>Related Materials</head>
      <p><extref xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uavigil/">Duke Vigil
          Collection</extref>, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      <p><extref xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uawdbs2/">WDBS
          Collection</extref>, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_3da4d6bef29b828a1ea646c76f214a0c">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>The collection includes fliers, newspapers, press releases, statements, notes,
        correspondence, and publicly distributed materials regarding the Duke Vigil gathered by
        Barry Sharoff in his role in charge of publicity for the Vigil.</p>
      <p>Included are a number of fliers for Vigil activities, particularly meetings and boycotts;
        statements and press releases, including statements from Board of Trustees Chair Wright
        Tisdale, the general faculty, and the Special Trustee-Administrative Committee, and press
        releases from campus radio WDBS and the Office of Information Services; Barry Sharoff's
        notes on publicity and organizing efforts; a list of Vigil participants; newspapers,
        especially the Chronicle, featuring articles on the Vigil; and materials related to the 20th
        anniversary of the Duke Vigil, celebrated during the 1988 20th reunion of the Class of
        1968.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Civil rights demonstrations</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Collective bargaining -- College employees -- North Carolina --
        Durham</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Students -- Political activity</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Student movements -- North Carolina</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Student participation in administration</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Wages -- College employees -- North Carolina -- Durham</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">Durham (N.C.) -- Race relations</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Publicity -- North Carolina -- Durham</subject>
      <persname rules="rda">Sharoff, Barry</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">Cook, Samuel DuBois, 1927-</persname>
      <corpname rules="dacs" source="local">Duke University--Administration</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Presidents</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Students -- Political activity</corpname>
      <persname source="ingest">Knight, Douglas M., 1921-2005</persname>
      <persname rules="rda">Tisdale, Wright</persname>
      <persname source="ingest">King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968 -- Assassination</persname>
      <corpname source="ingest">WDBS (Radio station : Durham, N.C.)</corpname>
      <persname authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no90017671" source="naf"
        >Strange, John Hadley, 1938-</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_efbdc9d4c6f7fd2dc1563d8d88ce9636" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Articles, draft writings</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">circa 1968</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_63de6b9950e60295fcab55db0050eb22" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_6243d047a66eaf17b3e8792f4c45eae9">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Includes narrative accounts of the Vigil, discussion of activism and politics at
            universities, and a pamphlet called "The Duke Trustees and Labor" discussing individual
            trustees and their corporate activities. The authorship of one item is given (Huck
            Gutman and Richard Carro), others are undated and uncredited; it is unclear if any of
            these materials were later published.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_57b92662829a972c64e83d4d4eccba13" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">April-May 1968</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_15f768acfcfe6d8daaf5f7d1bfd7ef41" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_dcf63615266e783ca6383197892e6d2b">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Includes one handwritten contents of telegram from Nelson Rockefeller to Dr. John
            Strange on April 19, one unsigned typed letter with handwritten corrections from a
            leader of the Vigil (probably Barry Sharoff) to Mr. Herblock of the Washington Post
            regarding a political cartoon that appeared in the Durham Morning Herald (includes a
            copy of the cartoon), and a copy of a letter from Peter Klopfer to the Editors of <title
              render="italic">Science</title> regarding an article published in that magazine on the
            Duke Vigil.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_aebd292efe961f299a7b3d739c1a9008" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Faculty Statements</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">April-May 1968</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_acf33cc5118f0864fff0768636fccbd6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_02dee56d23a26a5ab7e8f58b255ddc06">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Includes drafts and final copies of the statement given by the General Faculty on April
            19th, a statement from the Divinity School Faculty on April 8th, an excerpt from an
            article in <title render="italic">Science</title> on faculty and administration, and a
            statement presented to the General Faculty on May 31st.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_7c82cbd7fa812d93e458665ecc053a01" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Fliers and publicly distributed materials</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">circa 1968</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_5dead6a783822eff96916040f950bda8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_e6c5d231ce3d6ea0a4805b6babcb2a92">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Includes fliers on participating in the Vigil, the dining hall boycott, and other
            events, as well as information on the Vigil, on Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., on
            distributing fliers and information, statements by University officials, and other
            materials.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_b0c16490f4db10224f04cb5a81d5ed98" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Local 77 materials</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">April 1968</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_d98b54dc8ce0213603ac002b1023d1f4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_4de223a9f80ee108762bff40b3a4ab44">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Includes copies of a letter from Edward McNeill, President of Local 77, to R. Taylor
            Cole, Provost of the University, on April 14, 1968, as well as three handouts or fliers
            on Local 77 and the activities surrounding the Vigil.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_04d421cf3af42febff5a0744db3edef1" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Notes and Vigil Committee materials</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">circa 1968</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_0906230c9e06236929bab32d16c4f4b0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_cad01a505332c35b35d13455bd3c4702">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Includes handwritten notes, lists of Vigil participants and committee members, and
            information about the Duke Alumni organizations.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_3637cad22382312a8180f5dfc4828787" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Statements, addresses, and press releases</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">April-May 1968</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_45f6634070edd1627d525e1f702eec7c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_c82d5fdf93b2d7f1e8e52cc654fb74cf">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Includes statements from Wright Tisdale, the Duke Divinity School Community, the
            Special Trustee-Administrative Committee, and a statement to the Special Committee, most
            likely from the Vigil Committee; an address by Samuel Dubois Cook; press releases from
            WDBS and the Office of Information Services; a flier presenting an opposing argument on
            non-academic employee wages; and an interim report to the Academic Council from the
            Committee on Non-Academic Employees.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_4e7c90212339daab99c6d4a57270f906" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>20th anniversary materials</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1988/1988" type="inclusive">1988</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_7abbe6f073e8957120e93bf715055b0e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_d380d3d2c579dce21b7980fa010b074c">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Includes materials related to recognizing the 20th anniversary of the Duke Vigil during
            the Class of 1968 20th reunion weekend, including mailings, schedules, a newspaper, and
            a letter to attendees.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_2681a8e0e39ce63ff44223a4b9f564fd" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Newspapers</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">April-May 1968</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_8665895002e371ab7ee7ccd9c95e92dd" label="Mixed Materials"
            type="oversize-folder">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_f23aa9b68ce05eca1a35bdf121d72260">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Includes issues of the Chronicle and other newspapers regarding the Duke Vigil and
            surrounding events.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
