<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD"
      url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uastewartphilip/">uastewartphilip</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Philip Stewart Papers on the Nixon Library, 1979-1990 (bulk 1981)
            <num>UA.29.02.0258</num></titleproper>
        <author>Erin Ryan</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>2016</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">007539352</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-08-26 15:23:29
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Philip Stewart Papers on the Nixon Library</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="lcnaf">Stewart, Philip, 1940-</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>UA.29.02.0258</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1979/1990" type="inclusive">1979-1990</unitdate>
      <unitdate normal="1981/1981" type="bulk">bulk</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_d83459b4a7e264d2dc91b2eb108f28ed">Philip Stewart is a professor emeritus
        of Romance Studies at Duke University. Stewart served on the Subcommittee on Library
        Relations, which was convened by Duke’s Academic Council in September 1981 as part of a
        faculty initiative to study the potential impact of locating the Richard Nixon Presidential
        Library on the university campus. Materials in this collection primarily relate to the
        research of the Library Subcommittee, and include correspondence from Duke President Terry
        Sanford, who initiated the Nixon Library proposal in August 1981; correspondence from Duke
        faculty and trustees; press clippings; Academic Council meeting minutes; and the Library
        Subcommittee’s report to the Academic Council. The collection also contains research and
        reports from the Academic Council’s Subcommittee on Governance, another group formed in the
        wake of the Nixon Library proposal.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_d4aca066554c6822d22ad748e9748762">Materials are in
        English.</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="aspace_2f729081ff9fd4ed20976dc7c5556c08">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>In early August 1981, Duke University President Terry Sanford told Duke faculty that he had
        opened negotiations to house the Presidential Library of Richard Nixon – a Duke Law School
        alumnus – on the Duke campus. In response, Duke’s Academic Council, which represented
        faculty interests, formed two major committees to discuss how the decision was made and to
        propose the direction of future negotiations regarding the Nixon Library: the Subcommittee
        on Governance and the Subcommittee on Library Relations.</p>
      <p>Philip Stewart, then a professor in the Department of Romance Studies, served on the
        Academic Council’s Subcommittee on Library Relations, charged on September 17, 1981, to
        answer the question: “Can a Nixon Presidential Library be developed at Duke that does not
        compromise the integrity of Duke University?” The subcommittee examined several areas of
        Duke’s intersection with the proposed library, including use of land, the library’s
        potential scholarly value, and whether the library would have a museum component. The
        Library Subcommittee submitted its report to the Academic Council on October 21, 1981, with
        recommendations on conditions to be met in order for negotiations to proceed.</p>
      <p>Philip Stewart was born May 21, 1940. He received his Ph.D. from Yale University in 1967,
        and came to teach at Duke in 1972. Stewart’s books include <title>Imitation and Illusion in
          the French Memoir-Novel, 1700-1750</title> (1969), <title>Engraven Desire: Eros, Image,
          and Text in the French Eighteenth Century</title> (1992), and <title>Editer Rousseau:
          Enjeux d'un Corpus, 1750-2012</title> (2012). He has also produced and edited a number of
        translations and critical editions in the field of French literature. Stewart is a former
        president of the American Association of Teachers of French and was selected for membership
        in the Ordre des Palmes Académiques, a French society that honors educators in French
        language and culture. As of August 2016, he is Benjamin E. Powell Professor Emeritus of
        Romance Studies at Duke University.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_42b961d85853692116b958d7ad60a3d3">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library
        Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for
        research use.</p>
      <p>Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library to use this collection.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_c2c292e7379860caf9b4b1d234cc12ca">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Duke University; all other copyright
        is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as stipulated by
        United States copyright law.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_caf2b6c01ea160aa48061397ea6cf54c">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Philip Stewart Papers on the Nixon Library were received by the Duke University
        Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, as a gift in 2015.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_2fe93426922d7547decaa3315335b126">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Philip Stewart Papers on the Nixon Library, Duke University
        Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_cbe6abfc76bf83a66eec6708cae56f6b">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Erin Ryan, August 2016.</p>
      <p>Accessions described in this collection guide: UA2015.0032 </p>
    </processinfo>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_dab43cbb15bb4d9d9f146dbc40559338">
      <head>Related Materials</head>
      <p><extref xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uanixonlibref/">Nixon
          Library Controversy Reference Collection</extref>, Duke University Archives, David M.
        Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      <p><extref xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uawoodpeter/">Peter Wood
          Papers on the Nixon Library Controversy</extref>, Duke University Archives, David M.
        Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      <p><extref xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uacandl/">Committee
          Against the Nixon-Duke Library (CANDL) Records</extref>, Duke University Archives, David
        M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      <p><extref xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uapressanford/">Records
          and Papers of Terry Sanford</extref> (Box 96-99), Duke University Archives, David M.
        Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_ed25f97f91949ee1b2c93ab570c64e00">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>Materials in this collection primarily relate to the research of the Duke University
        Academic Council’s Subcommittee on Library Relations, which was formed in September 1981 as
        part of a faculty initiative to study the potential impact of locating the Richard Nixon
        Presidential Library on the university campus. Materials also include research of the
        Academic Council’s Subcommittee on Governance, formed at the same time, which was to examine
        the authority of the university president and the faculty’s role in making decisions at the
        university.</p>
      <p>The materials include correspondence from Duke President Terry Sanford, faculty, and
        trustees; press clippings; minutes of Academic Council meetings between August-November
        1981; research, drafts, and the final report from the Library Subcommittee; and research and
        reports related to the Governance Subcommittee. The collection also contains documents
        regarding the Faculty Compensation Committee and some press coverage of the opening of the
        Richard Nixon Library and Museum in Yorba Linda, California, in 1990.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Presidential libraries -- United States</subject>
      <persname source="lcnaf">Stewart, Philip, 1940-</persname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Faculty</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Nixon Library Committee</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Academic Council</corpname>
      <persname source="ingest">Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994</persname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Richard M. Nixon Presidential Library</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_9f992e6a132822a4e13cba8cca2645eb" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Library Committee (Nixon)</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">September-October 1981</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_d23603eb91ef37e119ed10c79607649c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_af4e9abbf9bf5373fceb9a43292c0976">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Contains correspondence, research, and drafts leading up to the Subcommittee on Library
            Relations’ report to the Academic Council about the potential impact of having the Nixon
            Library on Duke’s campus. Also includes some news clippings about the Nixon Library
            controversy.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_8fecf4e8b3f36f30605765859fd86a9b" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Nixon Library</unittitle>
          <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
              folders</extent></physdesc>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1979, July-November 1981, 1982</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_226d3c7a1461b2352fc44e1a0920eb3b" label="mixed materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_b7339241c95ba890cfd87dee003dbb1b">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Contains correspondence; research relating to the Library Subcommittee and the
            Governance Subcommittee; minutes of Academic Council meetings; a chronology of the
            proposal to house the Nixon Library at Duke; and the subcommittees’ reports to the
            Academic Council. Also includes some news clippings about the Nixon Library
            controversy.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_bca4f83f130a340fcf9464b0db75a609" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Nixon Library, California</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1990</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_8139af21aa8f4dff9f9edcb4afe7a413" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_150e988bfe9365547243b361ffcec34f">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Contains news clippings related to the opening of the Richard Nixon Library and Museum
            in Yorba Linda, California, in 1990.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_a56d013abd769ce4fa6253878391c933" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Faculty Compensation Committee</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive">1981</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_5408273acbd52fb0e51b41db96bcf5ca" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_a3ce9bc07801a9c859ad50e97deba9cb">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Contains memos, agendas, correspondence and other papers relating to the business of
            the Faculty Compensation Committee.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
