<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NcD" url="https://idn.duke.edu/ark:/87924/m1271p"
      >uatrinpark</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Trinity Park School Collection, 1898 - 1922
            <num>UA.01.04.0001</num></titleproper>
        <author>Processed by: Valerie Gillispie; machine-readable finding aid created by: Valerie
          Gillispie</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
        <p><date>2004</date></p>
        <address>
          <addressline>411 Chapel Drive</addressline>
          <addressline>Duke University</addressline>
          <addressline>Durham 27708</addressline>
          <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
              xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/" xlink:type="simple"
            /></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003396385</num></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-03-01 10:52:41
          -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2016</date>
        <item>Added two grades books and index to grade books removed from Office of the Registrar
          records (Box 6), added Bible previously accessioned but not added to finding aid.</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Trinity Park School collection</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <corpname source="ingest">Trinity Park School (Durham, N.C.)</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>UA.01.04.0001</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.5 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1898/1922" type="inclusive">1898 - 1922</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_ec5ccd4743117b1890df9f63f0ffe18a">Trinity Park School was established in
        1898, under headmaster J.F. Bivins, to better prepare students for admission at Trinity
        College and other institutions. The school operated on the campus of Trinity College until
        1922, when it was permanently closed. The Trinity Park School Collection includes bound
        volumes, print materials, the papers of headmaster F.S. Aldridge, and photographs, and
        financial information. Annual Trinity Park School catalogs have been removed and cataloged
        separately.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_e9e7893654180686c76fe99c18bacb31">English.</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_20e1f809aa8dfc02a91ad2c779de8db1">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>The Trinity Park School Collection includes bound volumes, print materials, and
        photographs. The Bound Volumes Series contains accounting ledgers, a grade book, minute
        books, and a roll book. Trinity Park School's annual catalogs have been removed and
        cataloged separately. These materials offer insight into the students at the school, their
        courses of study, and their financial situations. </p>
      <p>The second series, Print Materials, contains financial information, correspondence,
        illustrated booklets, and other documents related to Trinity Park School. </p>
      <p>The third series, F.S. Aldridge Papers, contains the correspondence of the headmaster of
        Trinity Park School. It dates primarily from 1921 and 1922, when the school was closed. </p>
      <p>The final series, Photographs, includes photos of students, faculty, buildings, and other
        images from the school. Oversized photographs can also be found in this series.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <bioghist id="aspace_d18a926cb2225e803fc93ca54f1acd3f">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>Trinity Park School operated from 1898 to 1922 to better prepare young people for
        undergraduate work at Trinity College and other institutions. In a prospectus prepared prior
        to the opening of the school on September 7, 1898, it explains, "Very many young men apply
        for entrance to Trinity and are found upon examination unprepared and hence are not
        admitted. The idea of providing for this class of students at the college and under the
        immediate direction of the college, originated at the Western North Carolina Conference [of
        the Methodist Church]." According to the 1898-99 Trinity Park High School catalog, the
        Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees of Trinity College supported this proposal, and
        agreed to oversee the new school in June of 1898. In only three months, the school had
        several new buildings for its use and it opened its doors.</p>
      <p>The Trinity Park High School, as it was then known, was located on the northwest corner of
        the present-day East Campus of Duke University, where the Mary Duke Biddle Music Building
        and the Branson Building now stand. Trinity College President John Carlisle Kilgo oversaw
        the new headmaster, J. F. Bivins, but the school operated semi-independently. From the
        start, the school had high aims, and in the 1898 catalog, the hazards of ill-prepared
        students were spelled out: "The period of a boy's life between the ages of twelve and
        eighteen is the most important one in his educational career. In most cases his habits of
        study and his character itself are fixed at the age of eighteen. If he has had slack
        preparation and loose discipline, he becomes disheartened, and abandons all hope of entering
        college and properly fitting himself for life."</p>
      <p>The school had a junior class, one or two intermediate classes, and a senior class. Among
        their required subjects were arithmetic, geography, Latin, English, Greek, algebra, history,
        and physics. Because the school was located so close to Trinity College, the students were
        allowed to use the college library and attend lecture courses, as well as have use of the
        gymnasium. Wh n the school opened in 1898, 71 students were enrolled, including 11 girls.
        Two students came from Virginia, one from Tennessee, and the rest arrived from points across
        North Carolina, although most came from the Durham area. According to Earl W. Porter's
          <title render="italic">Trinity and Duke, 1892-1924: Foundations of Duke
        University</title>, the school quickly became a success, and increased its enrollment and
        became financially stable within a few years. New buildings had also been added to the
        campus, providing more dormitory space. Trinity Park School (the name was changed from
        Trinity Park High School to differentiate it from public schools) was a source of pride--and
        students--for Trinity College. According to Porter, "As late as 1907 only eight secondary
        schools in the Carolinas even offered as much as fourteen units of work"--the minimum
        required to be considered for admission to Trinity College.</p>
      <p>Two major courses of study were offered: the classical and the Latin-scientific. Both
        courses were quite similar, with classical students required to take several languages and
        Latin-Scientific required to focus on natural and physical sciences. Students were expected
        to attend school from approximately 9am to 2 pm, and to study from 7pm to 10pm. Afternoons
        were reserved for physical activity.</p>
      <p>Students were expected to periodically make declamations pertaining to their courses of
        study. Two organizations, the Grady Literary Society and the Calhoun Literary Society,
        offered their members the opportunity to practice their declamation and debate skills. An
        annual competition between these two societies occured each year at commencement, when the
        top speaker was awarded a medal. Other extra-curricular groups included the Young Men's
        Christian Association, the Athletic Association, and the Park School Gazette. Mandatory
        chapel services were held daily. Although Trinity College had a Methodist affiliation,
        students could select the church of their choice in Durham to attend on Sundays. </p>
      <p>Students were expected to behave properly at all times, although "Foolish and unnecessary
        rules are avoided; only as such are necessary to the safety, peace, and well-being of the
        whole community are adopted," according to the 1904-1905 Trinity Park School catalog. Most
        students conducted themselves with decorum, but those who "are addicted to loafing or
        disorderly behavior at night and who are careless in their study are required to attend the
        'Night School' and study under a master's [teacher's] direction." In rare cases, when
        warnings and Night School did not achieve their desired effect, a student would be asked to
        leave Trinity Park School permanently.</p>
      <p>Over time, the public school system improved in North Carolina. As these schools improved,
        fewer students attended Trinity Park School. In summer 1922, the Board of Trustees decided
        to close the School, and use the buildings and space for the growing undergraduate class.
        Trinity Park School was remembered fondly, however. As Porter writes, "It had held the line
        for Trinity until the public schools could arrive."</p>
      <p>Although the school no longer exists, several buildings still stand as part of the East
        Campus of Duke University. The Branson Building was constructed in 1899 with funds from
        Benjamin N. Duke. Its original use was a dormitory for Trinity College, and in 1915 it was
        remodeled for use as a dormitory by Trinity Park School students. After the School closed,
        it again became a College dorm. In 1935, the building was torn down, but some of its
        materials were used to create a new Branson Building, used as an engineering laboratory. In
        1950, the building was again remodeled, this time becoming the present-day Branson
        Theater.</p>
      <p>Bivins Hall, built in 1905 and named after the first headmaster, J.F. Bivins, was used as a
        dormitory for Trinity Park School students. In succeeding years, it has been used as a
        college dormitory, then the headquarters of the Departments of Botany, Zoology, and Civil
        Engineering. Today the Bivins Building houses several arts departments.</p>
      <p>The main academic building used at Trinity Park School, the Asbury Building, was torn down
        in 1974. It stood on the site where the Biddle Music Building stands today. The other
        buildings that comprised the School were also torn down: Lanier Hall, a dormitory, was taken
        down in 1937; the York Dining Hall in 1928; and the Harnett and Drummond buildings, both
        dormitories, were destroyed by fire in 1928 and 1932, respectively.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_521427af875a74800531e6b3d0278432">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_a67e3c4e58cb8fedb0cad65c11027925">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Duke University; all other copyright
        is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as stipulated by
        United States copyright law.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_22d34b7f943561f2b0fc8ae62a8a817a">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], Trinity Park School Collection, University Archives, Duke
        University.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_45ea5f1c657acfa3d3d8fefe8e4d8fb8">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by Valerie Gillispie</p>
      <p>Completed July 1, 2004</p>
      <p>Encoded by Valerie Gillispie, July 6, 2004</p>
      <p>Updated (addition of grade books from Registrar's Records and Holy Bible) by Tracy M.
        Jackson, June 2016.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_9c9450c399dc47a5f0219094ea57782c">
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p><extref xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uabuilding/">Building
          Reference Collection</extref>, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book
        &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      <p><extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE001555855">Park School
          Gazette, 1901-1911</extref>, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      <p><extref xlink:href="http://search.library.duke.edu/search?id=DUKE002225004">Trinity Prep,
          1921-1922</extref>, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp;
        Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      <p><extref xlink:href="https://find.library.duke.edu/catalog/DUKE001557401">Trinity Park
          Annual Catalogue, 1898-1922</extref>, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare
        Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_68573628740d3ebe948c23810813311c">
      <head>Provenance</head>
      <p>The Trinity Park School Collection was received by the University Archives as a transfer in
        1973 (A73-106) and a gift in 2001 (A2001-8). Other materials were added to the collection
        for which a donor and provenance cannot be established.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bibliography id="aspace_8415ca1778a9e0f320b8b4129665093e">
      <head>Bibliography</head>
      <bibref>Earl W. Porter, <title render="italic">Trinity and Duke, 1892-1924: Foundations of
          Duke University</title>, Durham, N.C.: Duke University Press, 1964</bibref>
    </bibliography>
    <controlaccess>
      <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
      <subject source="lcsh">High schools -- North Carolina -- Durham</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Preparatory schools -- North Carolina</subject>
      <genreform source="aat">Catalogs</genreform>
      <genreform source="aat">Financial records</genreform>
      <corpname source="ingest">Trinity Park School (Durham, N.C.)</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Trinity College (Durham, N.C.)</corpname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Trinity Park High School (Durham, N.C.)</corpname>
      <persname source="ingest">Bivins, J. F. (Joseph F.)</persname>
      <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Buildings -- History</corpname>
      <persname source="ingest">Aldridge, F. S. (Frederick Soule)</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref12_npq" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Bound Materials, 1898-1922</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref13_ggc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Accounting ledger, 1910-1916</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_e604f1876c8b66b517d817a565a6a5a4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref14_ami" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Accounting ledger, 1910-1917</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_43d04f920ef5ba3eef77e2e46bc926c3" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref15_s7p" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Accounting ledger</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1917/1920" type="inclusive">1917-1920</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_4f35828993cd1777f6b439a2ee364956" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_4f99768d2a079c9c644318cd27945551" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Grade record book</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1904/1908" type="inclusive">1904-1908</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d85157d032032b99e316bc5e82a32ea4"
              label="Mixed Materials [D04851364V]" type="box">6</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_dd01354e07163328aba8c2ab38522013" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Grade record book</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1909/1914" type="inclusive">1909-1914</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_835e8790593945ebff3bd5bb048e48cb"
              label="Mixed Materials [D04851364V]" type="box">6</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref16_rrf" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Grade record book</unittitle>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1915/1920" type="inclusive">1915-1921</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_20a2600792d714d088ace0e2a18610f8"
              label="Mixed Materials [D04851364V]" type="box">6</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_e7e6073728f1009af2053c880abd3640" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Index to grade books</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_adb42b36b58eefa110f9ae3ac5b86f79" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref17_3eq" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Minutes</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_e4c5f7f78cf0ca594da8c873a1faf79c" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref18_skg" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Calhoun Literary Society Minutes, 1900-1909</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_926a57010568027f1ab99f134a75a8e7" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref19_7ag" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Calhoun Literary Society Minutes, 1916-1919</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_5a180f1d4d24e2946cd3688cd651c9fd" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref20_sd8" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Grady Literary Society Minutes, 1907-1909</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_fc0c4c11444e36d56250b7837cb6eff8" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref21_nb5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Roll book, [undated]</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_351f3f9453b6f7184ab717a561c8b582" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref46_1j1" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Print Materials 1898-1922</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref47_su9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clippings, 1915, [undated]</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_7b322a1af5ab18e07153974e7c72ba9b" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_600ab5a629b2f985d2ecc11f894e427d"
              parent="aspace_7b322a1af5ab18e07153974e7c72ba9b" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref48_myo" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Columbian Literary Society Constitution and By-Laws, 1901</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_b9e68614cc46ab057cbc9228fd94ef2e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_662957c24ceb46fd4f2597dbcb82019c"
              parent="aspace_b9e68614cc46ab057cbc9228fd94ef2e" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref49_h85" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Commencement Programs and Materials, 1904-1919</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_9bf5c5a8a894354734580dac19cb0878" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_5a5eeae05f33e298a1169051fe62baae"
              parent="aspace_9bf5c5a8a894354734580dac19cb0878" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref50_s5u" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence, 1906-1919</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_f685a55c03e225d1cbfdaa6b6590c7bb" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_664431e63da7e8d7f63ad5e251c0bc92"
              parent="aspace_f685a55c03e225d1cbfdaa6b6590c7bb" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref51_3bj" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Financial Records - Grady Literary Society, 1914-1916</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_2dc8a3d0e69cb890aecb78aebd259166" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_9602f90f4bebdc6262d44d677330105e"
              parent="aspace_2dc8a3d0e69cb890aecb78aebd259166" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_76190e3a1130b1e4413dcda4258d067f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Holy Bible</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_212a00c9dc76d7fa66aa9ac9d881fcb4"
              label="Mixed Materials [D04851364V]" type="box">6</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref52_8mr" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Prospectus of Trinity Park High School," 1898</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_52bcfbf8473cc391d8327374ebfd5f57" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_78607d8b15fb0245d1ba92c29ce16d9a"
              parent="aspace_52bcfbf8473cc391d8327374ebfd5f57" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref53_dl8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Trinity Park School illustrated booklet, 1911</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_af8a6a7a283928ec373ec39292dee708" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_1c6de1bcc54c0dd63e805f1bf965e03b"
              parent="aspace_af8a6a7a283928ec373ec39292dee708" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref54_srd" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Views" and "Souvenir" of Trinity Park High School, 1901-1903</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_68746f8ecbc62332b7c58bfa34fa55d4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_c3260e50ed9ffc0e10cedb575c66a703"
              parent="aspace_68746f8ecbc62332b7c58bfa34fa55d4" type="folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref55_yrc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"What Others Say About Trinity Park School" pamphlet, [1914]</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_caa6ccdf5dbe8018c7fafc20aa5a276e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_a85622e520bcff34895e4ed12d944c88"
              parent="aspace_caa6ccdf5dbe8018c7fafc20aa5a276e" type="folder">9</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref56_7xb" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>F.S. Aldridge Papers 1911-1922</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref57_six" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref58_wny" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1911</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_9188ba6e7a629b3bac078e8773a059e7" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">5</container>
              <container id="aspace_b6a1368fd6db01d72b76db666373daf2"
                parent="aspace_9188ba6e7a629b3bac078e8773a059e7" type="folder">10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref59_dx0" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1920-1921</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_de511873c9bf04a7db52ab3ef7ab8f5d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">5</container>
              <container id="aspace_2eb6ba6518a899c7acf76cb5351a6a93"
                parent="aspace_de511873c9bf04a7db52ab3ef7ab8f5d" type="folder">11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref60_mli" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>January 1922-May 1922</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_0b06d4060ce8e419d060b380979568b9" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">5</container>
              <container id="aspace_4b50a9947da30c79e4d132d5be637e4b"
                parent="aspace_0b06d4060ce8e419d060b380979568b9" type="folder">12</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ref61_w83" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>June 1922-September 1922, [undated]</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_96573482ba2ea7da0480d54610a1e1be" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">5</container>
              <container id="aspace_7da540f4204257effbe38a5b24c6ada3"
                parent="aspace_96573482ba2ea7da0480d54610a1e1be" type="folder">13</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_ref62_3au" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Photographs 1898-1922</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref63_9kd" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Campus Views - Buildings, Rooms, Classes, Teams, circa 1912-1921
              <lb/></unittitle>
            <physloc id="aspace_ce14a3b28df6df5cf2cd3f458f60e2ae">[Note: These photographs are
              located in the University Archives Photography Collection.]</physloc>
            <container id="aspace_a89a051c71dcd0071b30a4b2e3738120" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref65_ggl" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Faculty, [no date]<lb/></unittitle>
            <physloc id="aspace_5c764c5fbb320904588c9a2b35288956">[Note: These photographs are
              located in the University Archives Photography Collection.]</physloc>
            <container id="aspace_b4c22e49b3d3f222c1cc20c9aa3a13b2" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref67_sby" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Students, 1901, [undated]<lb/></unittitle>
            <physloc id="aspace_3073f23b344c887947681717890bd50e">[Note: These photographs are
              located in the University Archives Photography Collection.]</physloc>
            <container id="aspace_32816bc92d0669040c45b4cc5b3b21e6" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ref69_im1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Oversized Photographs - Classes, Teams, Buildings, circa 1899-1922,
              [undated]<lb/></unittitle>
            <physloc id="aspace_c3f1212d49d530ecc946e3cc5df5aad3">[Note: These photographs are
              housed in the University Archives Map Case 2.]</physloc>
            <container id="aspace_0a39890561a814619594c57942d124eb" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">5</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
