<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uawhite/">uawhite</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Preliminary Guide to the Newman Ivey White papers, 1915 - 1948
                  <num>UA.29.02.0028</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Processed by: University Archives staff; machine-readable finding aid created
               by: Jill Katte</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003258659</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-30 04:12:49
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Newman Ivey White papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">White, Newman Ivey, 1892-1948</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>UA.29.02.0028</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7.9 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1915/1948" type="inclusive">1915 - 1948</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_d06e4e2e5dfe7704b8a7d23789d9307a">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult University Archives, Duke
            University.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_f0f4ba05c046697cb74a66feb499abbc">Newman Ivey White was an educator
            and Percy Bysshe Shelley scholar. He served as Professor of English at Trinity College
            and Duke University from 1919 to 1948. The papers include correspondence, lectures,
            research materials, including notecards, copies of letters, manuscripts, and photographs
            along with printed matter, miscellaneous writings, and other papers, with bulk dates of
            1936-1948. Most of the material reflects his work on Shelley and the English Romantic
            poets; a small amount of reprints and lectures concerns folklore. Much of the
            correspondence is between White and other scholars of the English poets; correspondents
            include T. J. Wise, Frederick L. Jones, and George L. Kittredge. H.L. Mencken and George
            Bernard Shaw wrote to congratulate White on his publications. Several folders of
            correspondence with members of the publishing firm of Alfred A. Knopf regard the
            publication of Shelley in 1940. A letter from Duke faculty member Calvin B. Hoover
            describes Nazi Germany in 1932, and several of White's European correspondents comment
            on conditions in Europe during World War II. English.</abstract>
         <physdesc id="aspace_68a0b02ed778428b7889d0812e52b85b">
            <extent>5,500 Items</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_1c2116835197dec257b5139a084f76e7">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_4025c4898bdb9eb28a5ef42833849d1e">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>Portions of these materials are restricted by donor request.</p>
         <p>Unprocessed materials are closed pending processing.</p>
         <p>In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.</p>
         <p>Restrictions on the use of <title type="simple" render="doublequote">The Book of Shelley
               and Mary</title> (Box 5) are explained at length in the folder containing Volume
            1.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_3a6654f3b9bf49aa961aac2845cd2b34">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>Copyright for Official University records is held by Duke University; all other
            copyright is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as
            stipulated by United States copyright law.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_0390f3d3be47ed573f3af9b0fe4a8b94">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Newman Ivey White Papers, Duke University Archives, David M.
            Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_c7b4e013a9e09a6574d3e98ec54d6168">
         <head>Provenance</head>
         <p>The Newman Ivey White papers was received by the University Archives as a gift in 1949,
            1980, 1989.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_5ffba03689ac0f5d7e8177a9d2cd0ff3">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by University Archives staff, completed June 2, 1989. Correspondence and
            research notes were refoldered; however, original acidic paper folders have been
            retained, as notes on them make up an index to the correspondence. These are stored in
            Box 6. Deteriorated photo negatives were removed, as prints of the images exist within
            the papers.</p>
         <p>Encoded by Jill Katte, June 5, 2003</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_2803185e394099f97eb15ef9e8833a4e">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Educator, Shelley biographer. Professor of English, Trinity College and Duke University,
            1919-1948. Author, <title type="simple" render="italic">Shelley</title> (1940) and
               <title type="simple" render="italic">Portrait of Shelley</title> (1945), and other
            works. B.A., M.A. Trinity College, Durham, NC, 1913, 1914. M.A., Ph.D., Harvard, 1915,
            1918. Married, 1922, Marie Anne Updike. Died Cambridge, MA, December 6, 1948.</p>
         <p>Known in his time as an eminent Shelley scholar, Newman Ivey White was born in
            Statesville, North Carolina on February 3, 1892. He grew up in Greensboro, where his
            father, James Houston White, died in 1912. White entered Trinity College in Durham in
            1909, graduating magna cum laude in 1913. During his student days, he was a member of
            the varsity tennis team for three years; he later coached the school's teams. White
            entered the graduate program at Trinity, obtaining his M.A. in 1914. He then went to
            Harvard, where he acquired another M.A. (1915) and the Ph.D. (1918). His dissertation
            was on Percy Shelley's dramatic poems. While at Trinity he had served as an assistant in
            English and Latin; he later he filled an instructorship at Alabama Polytechnic institute
            (1915-1916), and taught English at Washington University in St. Louis. He returned to
            Trinity in 1919 as a member of the English Department. In 1922 he married Marie Anne
            Updike, a fellow member of the department from 1927 to 1955 who taught modern literature
            and drama. </p>
         <p> Mr. and Mrs. White shared an interest in folksong, and as a scholar, Dr. White authored
               <title type="simple" render="italic">An Anthology of Verse by American
               Negroes</title> (1924, with W.C. Jackson) and <title type="simple" render="italic"
               >American Negro Folk Songs</title> (1928). In 1943, he became the general editor of
            the Frank C. Brown Collection of North Carolina Folklore. It was as a Shelley scholar
            that Dr. White was best known, however. Leaving aside scholarly articles, his first
            published work on the poet was an anthology, <title type="simple" render="italic">The
               Best of Shelley</title> (1932). This was followed by <title type="simple"
               render="italic">The Unextinguished Heart: Shelley and his Contemporary
               Critics</title> (1938), in which White argued that the poet was not neglected in his
            own time. Finally, he completed in 1940 his two-volume biography, <title type="simple"
               render="italic">Shelley</title>, and followed this with a shorter popular biography,
            the 1945 <title type="simple" render="italic">Portrait of Shelley</title>.</p>
         <p> Aside from scholarship, Newman and Marie White were known for their interest in
            progressive causes. Professor White took an interest in election reform, and in child
            care facilities for working mothers. He was associated with the West Durham Nursery
            School (1934-1936), and later the Child Care Association, of which he was chairman and
            member of the board of directors (1944-1946). He was also a moving force behind the
            establishment of the Durham Labor and Materials Exchange (1933), a clearinghouse for
            information about jobs, goods and services available to Durham's unemployed. During
            World War II, Dr. White served on the Duke University Defense Council, and arranged for
            publication of articles promoting national unity in the crisis. </p>
         <p>White was a member of Phi Beta Kappa, the American Association of University Professors,
            the American Folklore Society, the Modern Language Association and other scholarly
            associations, both in the United States and in England. His service to Duke University
            included membership on the University Research Council and on the Executive Committee of
            the Friends of Duke University Library.</p>
         <p> During the last year of his life, Newman White was engaged in doing research for a
            biography of William Godwin. He was at Harvard when he died suddenly on December 6,
            1948. Mrs. White died in 1975, and is buried in Statesville with her husband. </p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_f9d3fd2f294548097963b7dee69fca18">
         <head>Collection Overview</head>
         <p>Correspondence, lectures, research materials, including photostatic copies of letters,
            manuscripts, and graphics, along with printed matter, miscellaneous writings, and other
            papers, with bulk dates of 1936-1948. There is little in the collection that relates to
            Prof. White's early career. Most of the material appears to have been collected in the
            course of his work on the English Romantic poets; a small amount of material, comprising
            reprints and lectures, concerns folklore. Much of the correspondence is between White
            and other students of the English poets; subjects of the letters include differing
            opinions and disputes over the interpretation of events in Shelley's life. Other
            correspondents, among them H.L. Mencken and George Bernard Shaw, congratulate White on
            his publications. Several folders of correspondence with members of the publishing firm
            of Alfred A. Knopf concern the publication of <title type="simple" render="italic"
               >Shelley</title> in 1940. A letter from Duke faculty member Calvin B. Hoover
            describes Nazi Germany in 1932, and several of White's European correspondents make
            comments about conditions in Europe during World War II.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <genreform source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Europe</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Folklore -- United States</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 -- Correspondence</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">English literature -- 19th century -- History and
            criticism</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Nazis -- Germany</subject>
         <geogname source="lcsh">Germany -- History -- 1918-1933</geogname>
         <persname source="ingest">Wise, Thomas James, 1859-1937</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Wise, Thomas James, 1859-1937. Ashley Library</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">White, Newman Ivey, 1892-1948</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">White, Newman Ivey, 1892-1948</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- Faculty</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822 -- Criticism and
            interpretation</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Kittredge, George Lyman, 1860-1941</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Department of English</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Jones, Frederick L. (Frederick Lafayette), 1901-</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Hoover, Calvin B. (Calvin Bryce), 1897-</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Faculty</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Alfred A. Knopf, Inc.</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_jod" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence, 1915-1948, bulk dates 1936-1948.</unittitle>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear Feet</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_8bb6ad74e10c759b62b47e0d394fe58e">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>With a sub-series, letters received after the publication of his biography of
                  Shelley, 1940. Arranged alphabetically by correspondent. One folder of
                  miscellaneous correspondence is filed under White, N.I. The major correspondents
                  include Frederick L. Jones, editor of Mary Shelley's letters, Lord Abinger, the
                  Marchesa Enrica Della Robbia, Payson G. Gates, Ellsworth Barnard, artist Mrs. W.
                  Murray Crane, Thomas J. Wise, and members of Keats and Shelley societies. There
                  are several folders of correspondence with people at Alfred A. Knopf, Inc.
                  concerning publications; among these correspondents are Blanche Knopf and Sidney
                  R. Jacobs. The publication contract is also in this file. Other correspondents
                  include George Bernard Shaw, George L. Kittredge, Percy Long, of the Modern
                  Language Association, H.L. Mencken, Sir John C. Shelley- Rolls, John H. Smith, and
                  L.C. Thompson. The letters concern book reviews, and interpretations of the
                  Romantic poets, research requests to libraries, archives, and booksellers, and
                  include correspondence from other students of literature at institutions in the
                  United States and in Europe. Indexes to the correspondence can be found in Box 6
                  and in the University Archives collection file.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_h2p" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, A-M</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_ce940507c3cf9397186bd87149ffa431" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_ndu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, N-Z</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5f657e423454899118851bb4f72a6f26" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_t3d" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence received on the publication of <title render="italic"
                        >Shelley</title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_561563868acd1179a2832c15f432836a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref18_6ud" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Miscellaneous writings, 1918-1944, n.d.</unittitle>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.6 Linear Feet</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_5e47499132db2a5114911605f8997b42">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Poetry, limericks, lectures, and reviews. White's Ph.D. dissertation (1 vol.,
                  bound, <title type="simple" render="italic">Shelley's Dramatic Poems</title>.
                  Harvard, 1918). "Adventures of a Biographer," "War Relief" (1944), "Dr. Frank C.
                  Brown and his Collection of Folklore" (1943), "Legend and Fact in Biography"
                  (1943), Duke limericks, book reviews, and other writings.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref20_yu2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous writings</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_52abc32fd6fe79dc905436783ed42fbe" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref22_pyf" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Printed matter, n.d.</unittitle>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.3 Linear Feet</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_1935f86f988320a262310101623c6a6d">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Periodicals and reprints, including issues of the <title type="simple"
                     render="italic">South Atlantic Quarterly</title>, <title type="simple"
                     render="italic">Min Y Traeth</title>, <title type="simple" render="italic">The
                     Lion</title> (1829), <title type="simple" render="italic">English
                     Studies</title>, <title type="simple" render="italic">Studies in
                     Philology</title>. Reprints of articles by White and by other writers. A list
                  of printed materials within this series can be found in the University Archives
                  collection file.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref24_c1r" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed matter (periodicals and reprints)</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_e18eed2ee79229d516c804cb842978b0" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref26_kju" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Manuscripts and research materials, n.d.</unittitle>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.6 Linear Feet</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_bf6658026da0e901c6c7c1611c5124d8">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Photostatic copies of letters, paintings, illustrations, etc. pertaining to
                  Shelley and to William Godwin; bibliographies on the Romantic poets; typed copies
                  of diaries of Claire Clairmont and Jane Clairmont, Maria and John Gibson, ca.
                  1814-1825; page proofs and index for the <title type="simple" render="italic"
                     >Portrait of Shelley</title>; clippings. Also in this series are four folders
                  containing paper copies of a photostatic copy of <title type="simple"
                     render="doublequote">The Book of Shelley and Mary</title>, a four volume,
                  unpublished work described by Dr. White as "the most important single source for
                  the biography of Shelley." Use of this material is restricted.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref28_36n" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photostats</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6d0792be2c018c0e5fe994ca2060ee73" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref29_42b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Notebooks</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3c23cdb8206dcf765f52260ae2425db5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_mxy" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Clippings</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6079d6f40cc5cf78599e12b97c06e471" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_5om" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Diaries</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_8fb48afbbbc8c4f5dafc4dad73b8a83d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_uxb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Diaries</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_371d133d4ddff4fa161feb96f7a668cf" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref33_5l0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bibliographies</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_55063cc3327c3e377b44c070530625ce" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref34_6f1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">Portrait of Shelley</title> materials</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a184b4068d0afe0aead5c1551e16dc6f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref35_e1q" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="doublequote">The Book of Shelley and Mary</title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_27cb6e72e09d9959e64802a5c440bcdc" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">5</container>
               </did>
               <accessrestrict id="aspace_5c636dfc659a1ba1f51d4966011976b8">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
                  <p>This copy of <title type="simple" render="doublequote">The Book of Shelley and
                        Mary</title> is a reproduction of the copy in T. J. Wise's Ashley Library
                     used and annotated by Edward Dowden. Permissions to publish material from this
                     copy must be sought from the Bodleian Library. For further information, see the
                     "Statement Relative to Restrictions on the Publication of Material from the
                     'Book of Shelley and Mary'" in the collection.</p>
               </accessrestrict>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref38_c2u" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence Index</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_0a71c2fbde79a74a6d0587f6989ff3a8">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>This correspondence index provides a record of all incoming and outgoing
                  correspondence within the collection. Additional indexes to White's correspondence
                  can be found in the University Archives collection file.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref39_vju" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence index</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_df1e1072198b3ab63a8eb2f8cf4412fe" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref41_f5g" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Oversize</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref42_f1m" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Resolutions relative to subscription towards the Tremandoc Embankment,
                     May 1812</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_24efff1b8897b856333c6b3d433499ce" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="map-case">8</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
