<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
      langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/uawhiteduchy/">uawhiteduchy</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Order of the White Duchy Records, 1925-1968
                  <num>UA.31.03.0002</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Machine-readable finding aid created by: Joshua McKim</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>103 Perkins Library, Duke University</addressline>
               <addressline>Durham 27708-0185</addressline>
               <addressline>919-660-5822</addressline>
               <addressline>special-collections@duke.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/"
                     xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>Aleph Number: <num type="aleph">003185234</num>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-07-30 05:27:48
               -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014</date>
            <item>Converted from dtd to schema, transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl, and imported
               to Archivists Toolkit</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Order of the White Duchy records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Order of the White Duchy</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>UA.31.03.0002</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.7 Linear Feet</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1925/1968" type="inclusive">1925-1968.</unitdate>
         <physloc id="aspace_d101ca2cb67b766b886b34d2971c141d">For current information on the
            location of these materials, please consult Duke University Archives.</physloc>
         <abstract id="aspace_75b400fd59ba630be7d59aece70edcc1">The Order of the White Duchy was a
            secret women's honorary at Duke University. The group was formed in May 1925 by the
            Order of the Red Friars, a secret men's honorary, to recognize members of the Woman's
            College of Duke University. The members of the Order of the White Duchy voluntarily
            disbanded the organization in 1968. Records include constitution, initiation ritual,
            minutes, correspondence, photographs, membership and alumnae lists, financial records,
            clippings, issues of the Lucky Number alumnae newsletter, and two scrapbooks. Major
            subjects within the collection are collaboration between student leaders and college
            administration and student opinions concerning sororities, social standards, and the
            honor code. Prominent members include Mary Duke Biddle Trent Semans, Margaret Taylor
            Smith, Elizabeth Hanford Dole, Dorothy Newsom Rankin, and Dorothy Battle Rankin.
            English.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_eaa9154489d36159a414a79529979ea4">English. </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_6d39af90de76d63790d91026542fcfab">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
            collection.</p>
         <p>When the records were accessioned by the library in August of 1968, a restriction of 25
            years was placed on them. This restriction expired in 1993 and the records are now
            open.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_e1de1147f25d8c980afd819433a0f0f5">
         <head>Acquisitions Information</head>
         <p>The records were received as transfers in 1968 and 2001 (Accession numbers: 68-348 and
            A2001-16).</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <prefercite id="aspace_e66f652e6870ba5302a3816809e587e7">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Identification of item], Order of the White Duchy Records, Duke University Archives,
            David M. Rubenstein Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, Duke University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <userestrict id="aspace_7c2c749b7ba610267553cf2837af1284">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>Copyright for official University records is held by Duke University; all other
            copyright is retained by the authors of items in these papers, or their descendants, as
            stipulated by United States copyright law.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <processinfo id="aspace_a10257e23ac0cf2f28eefe0d6a7e7870">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Minutes were removed from damaged books and divided into folders by class year. Original
            fasteners were removed from correspondence and other records and replaced with stainless
            fasteners. It appears that some processing had been previously done, particularly in
            correspondence. All material was ordered chronologically even when divided into subject
            categories. White Duchy Organization materials were removed from their original binder
            due to rust and placed in acid-free folders. Scrapbooks were interleaved with bond or
            glassine paper to prevent more acid transfer and to protect the contents. As many
            photographs as possible were enclosed in Mylar sleeves for protection. All records
            except scrapbooks were rehoused in acid-free folders.</p>
         <p>Processed by Sarah Nerney, June 1999</p>
         <p>Encoded by Joshua McKim, December 2002</p>
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_3d49f5f4e15bc991d1da8423a9299ab5">
         <head>Historical Note</head>
         <p>The Order of the White Duchy was founded in May of 1925 by the secret senior men's
            honorary the Order of the Red Friars. They chose seven women whom they felt were the
            most outstanding members of the class of 1925 to organize a similar organization,
            although it was not to be a sister organization. From 1925 on, new members were chosen,
            or "tapped" into the order, by the seven members of the White Duchy from the previous
            year. New members were chosen based on their character, qualities of leadership, and
            outstanding service to the university. The tapping ceremony was held first at the last
            meeting of the Student Government Association of the Woman's College, and later during
            the final Class Night of the school year. Although the student body knew of its
            existence and who its members were, the activities and projects of the order were
            secret. The only public notice given to the organization by its members was the wearing
            of a white carnation on one day of each month. Officers consisted of Grand Duchess
            (President), Petit Duchess (Vice President), Custodian of the Records (Secretary) and
            Custodian of the Funds (Treasurer). Its members voluntarily disbanded the order in 1968
            because it was felt to be too elitist and no longer representative of the leaders of the
            Woman's College or the university.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_2a09d39f2ff3d2d22195eea23bcdd6f6">
         <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
         <p>These records were created by the Order of the White Duchy in the course of 43 years of
            activities as a secret women's honorary at Duke University. Material is present for the
            years 1925 to 1968, although it is most copious in the 1950s and early 1960s, and
            consists chiefly of minutes and scrapbooks. There are no minutes for the years
            1960-1961, 1961-1962, or 1964-1968. Records of any sort for the years 1964-1968 are
            limited to "Lucky Number" alumnae newsletters, some correspondence, and a study abroad
            pamphlet in the reference series. Physical types of materials include the constitution,
            minutes, correspondence, photographs, membership and alumnae lists, a cloth-bound volume
            of financial records, alumnae newsletters, clippings, reports, pamphlets, and two large
            scrapbooks. The scrapbook materials consist of photographs, correspondence, clippings,
            and one artifact, a fabric crown belonging to Mary (Eskridge) King, class of 1925 and
            founding member.</p>
         <p>The history and activities of the order were kept secret from the student body and much
            of the faculty and administration. A history, copy of the constitution, and the
            initiation ritual are preserved in the order's records. The minutes detail the
            operations and projects of the Duchy, and also contain information on student life and
            opinion. Financial records show the expenditures of the order for the given years.
            Correspondence relates mainly to Homecoming Breakfasts, although there is some important
            information related to integration, and to alumnae post-graduation activities and life.
            White Duchy Organization records include the "Lucky Number" alumnae newsletter and
            existed mainly to keep members informed of campus activities of current members and of
            alumnae doings. Project folders relate to undertakings of the order that may or may not
            be mentioned in the minutes. Reference folders contain materials not produced by White
            Duchy, but which its members either found interesting or useful in their other
            activities, or which they felt White Duchy should be acquainted with. The scrapbooks
            contain information about members' activities during the year they were active, and also
            updates about work and family life after graduation. The scrapbooks are divided by
            school year, each member having a page for donated items, letters, and photographs.</p>
         <p>White Duchy worked within student activities and government to influence policies and
            bring about campus improvements. They seem to have been fairly important to Deans Alice
            Baldwin and Florence Brinkley of the Woman's College as a means of discovering and
            influencing student opinion. White Duchy met and communicated over the years with many
            university administrative officials such as Herbert Herring, Alan Manchester, Mary Ellen
            Huckabee, Mary Grace Wilson, Anne Garrard, Robert Flowers, William Allen Tyree, Douglas
            Knight, Hollis Edens, and Paul Gross. One of the research strengths of this collection
            is the evidence of interaction and in some cases collaboration between the leaders of
            the university and the leaders of the student body, and the opinions of both that can be
            found on issues such as integration and desegregation, sororities, social standards
            (student life regulations), overseas programs, and the honor code, among others. For
            material related to integration and desegregation see particularly Minutes 1962-1963,
            and Correspondence related to the "Lucky Number" of March 15, 1963. Duchy members were
            very involved in campus elections, and in some cases appear to have decided amongst
            themselves which girls should be appointed to certain positions or should run for a
            particular office. There is little evidence that the White Duchy and the Red Friars
            worked in concert on many issues, and interaction between these two groups seems mainly
            limited to social functions.</p>
         <p>Members of White Duchy were student leaders and held leadership positions in the Young
            Women's Christian Association (YWCA), Judicial Board, dormitories, Women's Student
            Government Association (WSGA), class offices, Social Standards Committee, the Chronicle,
            and so on, during their senior year. Members had been involved in student government and
            activities since their arrival on campus in such organizations as Freshman Advisory
            Council (FAC), Sandals and other honoraries, sororities, publications, and Hoof'n'Horn.
            Members of particular note are Mary (Biddle) Semans, class of 1939; Margaret (Taylor)
            Smith, class of 1947; and Elizabeth (Hanford) Dole, class of 1958. Dorothy (Newsom)
            Rankin of the class of 1933 was the first member to have a daughter honored by
            membership in the order: Dorothy Battle Rankin, class of 1959.</p>
         <p>Achievements of White Duchy are the establishment of the senior women's honorary Phi
            Kappa Delta in 1944-1945; helping to establish a campus and university honor code;
            organization of a White Duchy alumnae group and newsletter; campus improvements such as
            paths, benches, restroom improvements, trashcans; improvement of East-West Campus
            relations; working for integration and desegregation particularly in 1962-1963; and
            influencing major student and to some extent university policies such as the cut system,
            drinking rules, sorority evaluations, "Who's Who", and Mortar Board honor society. The
            White Duchy was a very social organization and held many dinners, parties, and cabin
            weekends away both for themselves and for alumnae. The seven members of each year held
            an alumnae breakfast on every Homecoming Weekend, and stayed in touch with the majority
            of alumnae. The seven members of a given year tended to be close friends, and referred
            to each other as "ducks" or "ducklings" and to their secret campus office as "the pond."
            Evidence of daily student life and opinion is present throughout the minutes
            particularly, and is another area important for research.</p>
         <p>White Duchy was voluntarily disbanded in 1968 because its then members objected to the
            secrecy and elitism of the organization. They felt it was no longer representative of
            campus leaders and was doing more harm than good due to its selective nature. The order
            has never been reestablished at Duke University. See article from the Chronicle of May
            3, 1968 in History, 1925-1968, and also various discussions of the role of the order and
            problems of secrecy in the minutes of the 1950s and 1960s.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Initiation rites</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Secret societies -- Social aspects</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Secret societies -- North Carolina</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Women college students -- North Carolina -- Durham</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Student participation in administration</subject>
         <persname source="ingest">Rankin, Dorothy Newsom</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Semans, Mary Duke Biddle Trent</persname>
         <persname source="ingest">Smith, Margaret Taylor</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Administration</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Alumni and alumnae</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- History -- 20th century</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Societies, etc.</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Students -- Attitudes</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University -- Students -- Social life and customs</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Order of the White Duchy</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Order of the White Duchy</corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">Dole, Elizabeth Hanford</persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Woman’s Student Government Association. Social
            Standards Committee</corpname>
         <corpname source="ingest">Duke University. Woman’s College</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref12_uj6" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>History and Ritual, 1925-1968.</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_7a5bb25a1741cdaf2744bdd7e987248b">
                  <extent>[4 folders]</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <arrangement id="aspace_bfb6ad1fe4a2f0ca3b52aa01cc88b2f7">
               <head>Arrangement note</head>
               <p>Arranged chronologically by subject.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref14_77v" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>History, 1925-1968</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f63b8c3a90325ca8e84b9cec23ac1b91" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref15_z8h" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Constitution, [1925]</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_36e3f148eb181794f68c4338d8c3d9b9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref16_wwu" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Initiation Ritual, [1925]; [1948-1949]; undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_19595296a2af92a1fcc5c51918766c79" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref17_iqs" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Membership Lists, 1925-1954</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_737058bf88a9b0c35b2aeb1b5cda8f5d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref19_d8j" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Minutes, 1925-1960; 1962-1964; undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_6b3c1578731ee8996051510cea01208e">
                  <extent>[39 folders]</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <arrangement id="aspace_56169dc2ab492d0170f6ba301ef5f729">
               <head>Arrangement note</head>
               <p>Arranged chronologically by school year.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref21_bmt" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes, 1925-1964; undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_507e2ef807a185b97ebe2f7454e9092a" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref23_hoi" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Financial Records, 1947-1961.</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_8c97fa4cf707f2c9e5acf280141e6815">
                  <extent>[1 bound volume]</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <arrangement id="aspace_1ce1823832d68befd3afc70ec0fa762d">
               <head>Arrangement note</head>
               <p>Arranged by members' last name for dues, and chronologically by school year for
                  financial reports.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_6b9177fb1bb0b6c3a167f76387df8e7b">
               <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
               <p>Financial reports from 1925-1926 through 1938-1939 are included in the
                  minutes.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref25_8rp" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Financial Records, 1947-1961</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_655698653082ba40b654dcfe0e9262e0" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref28_inv" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence, 1952-1963.</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_156ea20ad8bbaaae9be8a111411be432">
                  <extent>[4 folders]</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <arrangement id="aspace_7348a72f8d15f5f44f4c41d0212b8f10">
               <head>Arrangement note</head>
               <p>Arranged chronologically by subject.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref30_gh0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence, General, 1952-1968; undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_2613339e318abd2dd752e0fa30bdc06b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref31_l0s" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence Related to Homecoming Breakfasts, 1952; 1953; 1958;
                     1959</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_aa53148a9e732a8be41a24bdf1aff13b" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref32_8xb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence Related to Homecoming Breakfasts, 1961; 1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_62117b604480ec3fa8c0f35e36d7b6ba" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref33_9gr" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence Related to "Lucky Number" of March 15, 1963</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_5b3104fde1729d8b8f9305930a284606" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref35_0zx" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>White Duchy Organization, 1942-1967; undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_6be23facbed7ca11e1ce23545067beca">
                  <extent>[5 folders]</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <arrangement id="aspace_6559c0d7739faaab2ea002b7316b26b8">
               <head>Arrangement note</head>
               <p>Arranged by subject.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref37_krz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>White Duchy Organization [Alumnae Organization], Constitution and
                     Policies, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_a9ea590e804cf306bca9c7fd12107ab5" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref38_q0f" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>White Duchy Organization [Alumnae Organization], Stationery,
                     undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_6e5601420457595bb8f8888d510cf552" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref39_4cv" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Clippings of Alumnae, 1962; 1963; undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_99469564cb44a25e1026dd913f9a695e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref40_g12" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"The Lucky Number" [Alumnae Newsletter], 1942; 1945-1949</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_7beafd6d68c2803ba8f8738ea3fed021" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref41_thf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"The Lucky Number" [Alumnae Newsletter], 1950-1951; 1953-1958;
                     1961-1965; 1967</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_1f7a0ea00f78981b746204fcd3ecff71" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref43_zxa" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Projects, 1944-1945; 1948; 1951-1952; 1961; undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_9a7a7c62955cc9910257251f855b1304">
                  <extent>[6 folders]</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <arrangement id="aspace_2abc62c86052f472bc6c83b29f2f0c8e">
               <head>Arrangement note</head>
               <p>Arranged by subject.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref45_vdb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Project, Phi Kappa Delta, [1944-1945]</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_209e05e6cb57bfaca71d77acbaad077d" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref46_567" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Project, Curricula Evaluation, 1948</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_85dbf77dab8a2488aa340e6143f96667" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref47_m0o" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Project, Sorority Evaluation Committee, [1951-1952]</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_c1c65a3be37c2a4bbbd3ad1e41a25023" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref48_7uz" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Project, Revision of System of Cuts, May, 1952</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_51cca7da1e8e947ed5729b9d4f9757e3" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref49_nij" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Project, "Unofficial Guide to Courses for Upperclassmen",
                     1961</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_84666240142d17d82a1b07f01dc2ae29" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref50_5p1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Project, The Honor System, undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_740cc860e25b55068f4fb3bbadfc9e61" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref52_fel" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Reference, 1956; 1961; 1964; 1965; undated</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_f3537ecc4126734d1a2567f1d7a0a3cc">
                  <extent>[8 folders]</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <arrangement id="aspace_70d7f2e03a73cfd74211cb4b8333ea8d">
               <head>Arrangement note</head>
               <p>Arranged by subject</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref54_nh3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reference, General, 1961; 1965; undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0eb1441048f63356ba7510d65bd0dbba" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref55_l11" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reference, "Report of the Ninth National Student Congress", August
                     21-31, 1956</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9042ec27d7769815268e8a469929439e" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref56_62y" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reference, Class Night, 1961-1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_11fd9c1bab1dd2ee22568ed966790336" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref57_2si" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reference, "Design for a Duchess", 1962</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_76cf401a618690fa241203dae91a88a2" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref58_no4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reference, "Student Perspective: The Student Philosophy",
                     1964</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_9d90782b6946885a4844355d97fcdc19" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref59_kio" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reference, "The Woman's College and the Eastern Areas at Duke
                     University", 1964</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_880aca55ae900f4a06ff4ad1676eda18" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref60_y60" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reference, The Lansing Agency, "The Lansing Campus Letter",
                     undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_3c9b4ed9c6687c5e47d0857c9d42292f" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref61_l2i" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reference, "Student Government Theory and Philosophy",
                     undated</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_f4246fb7e86163dc4e93613acb3e3731" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref63_wzs" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Scrapbooks, 1925-1954; 1954-1958; 1964.</unittitle>
               <physdesc id="aspace_84a0d859b81c3deaf71ff6c9c7fd6473">
                  <extent>[2 oversized volumes]</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <arrangement id="aspace_7ea157947bf76a9d6a9f8445ebd782bd">
               <head>Arrangement note</head>
               <p>Arranged chronologically by school year.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref65_2p6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Scrapbook, 1925-1954</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_0620f2ca93d7ae28ce583babfdbb70f9" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref66_yvj" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Scrapbook, 1954-1958; 1964</unittitle>
                  <container id="aspace_b5d87ea0871902300028fd47d23cba27" label="Mixed Materials"
                     type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
